
   
   
      
         This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladys Shamblin</ENAMEX>.
         She is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese-American</ENAMEX>.
         She has lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> area for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX>, and she is going to talk about growing up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese-American</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when I grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, um, it was like it was backwards compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> area.
         It was just, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were just so different there, a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> and, uh, there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on welfare.
         It was just a different place to live.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\ Uh</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         \\ Where were you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>?
         \\
      
      
         We were growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, and prior to that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>.
         We lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, uh briefly.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, and we call him "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Redneck</ENAMEX>," and
         my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and when she came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, she couldn't speak any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> or anything.
         And, uh, so she spoke broken <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and as we were being raised we learned to interpret everything she said.
         And no matter what anyone, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would say, no matter what she would say to someone, we would understand exactly what she meant, exactly what she was saying, and they couldn't believe it.
         It was like speaking a different language.
         But, um, as we grew up, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught us a lot about respect and how important it is to be good and kind to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, be courteous, uh, be thankful for all the little things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do for you.
         I didn't realize she had implanted that in my head all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> until I grew up and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wondered why I was being so
         nice.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, they thought I had a hidden agenda but it's, it was just the way I was raised.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         And then growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and being part <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in that area that was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, it was kind of difficult.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, especially when there was just a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>, then there were some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX>, just a handful of them, and then there was us.
         So we were the minority, and we were very different than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         When they would start to cover like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX> stories at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and in history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, we would, uh, kind of shrink under our seats because, you know, everybody would start yelling "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jap</ENAMEX>."
         And, uh, we, until then we didn't feel like we were different, and then we realized after that, well, we looked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> although we were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would look at us and know we were different, so they would treat us different.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         But we would go home and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would always reassure us that uh, it's OK to be different.
         It's what is in your heart that matters.
         So as we grew up, I, I thought it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>, when I was younger, being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, went around with, not so much a chip on my shoulder, just, uh, an inferiority <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> and didn't realize until I got older that I was very much proud to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, got to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> a couple of times, and realized that's the best thing God could have given me was to be different because I'm able to help other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go through the same situation.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Um</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         What kind of stories did your, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> used to tell you?
      
      
         Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> used to tell us stories, when she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years old</TIMEX>, um, when <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> did hit, she looked up, which her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> was not far from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And, uh, she looked up and could see the bombs and everything.
         And she remembers being scared and thinking that she was going to die, and she said it was just one of the hardest times of her life.
         That, but, uh, they made it through that, and um, she really never showed any bitterness or anything towards <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but, uh, she was always just grateful for her life.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
         And then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, I have, had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
         And she raised us with speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">broken English</ENAMEX>, and she eventually did learn English fairly well.
         She took <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> just after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but she was, she never worked outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         She raised us; she said that was her job.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Um</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         How did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> meet?
      
      
         They met, my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and working part-time at a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had gone there to buy some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX> for his mother, and, uh, he met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and just fell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> over heels in love.
         And she thought he was a crazy
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, he just kept being nice to her,
         and she, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> couldn't believe she would leave them and move to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to be with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
         but she did.
         And, uh, they, they were pretty happy.
         I mean she went from being fairly wealthy, though, to being poor--
      
      
         Hum.
      
      
         And that was difficult.
         But when she started having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, she said that, that's her life.
         Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were her life.
         So, um,
         as we got older we really appreciated that, and, uh,
         when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> got sick, she had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, it was our turn to take care of her.
         So for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX>, we, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I both, we just kept, we just stayed beside her bed and we took care of her and it was wonderful, it was like us giving back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Hum.
         Did she ever go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         She went back twice.
         She went back right after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died.
         He died of a massive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>, and, uh, she went back that time and stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple months</TIMEX>.
         She was able to see her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and um, get to know her family again because it had been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years</TIMEX>.
         So, uh, that was wonderful, and then she went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other time, which was her last time, uh, and stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX>, and she came back.
         My <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, although it was a sad trip, it was a watershed in my life.
         It was uh, after she died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I had her cremated and we took her ashes back to be with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Hum.
      
      
         So that was my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
         My <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> trip was um, to take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> when she turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>, which was a wonderful trip, and helped her understand her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s culture.
         And then we plan to take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> when he turns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> just so we can, uh, show him <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
         And we feel like travel is one of the best things you can give your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         Money, clothes and all that can go away but travel is in your memories and that when I'm dead and gone I want them to remember that
         .
      
      
         You mentioned that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> talked a lot about her older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.
         What were some of the stories she told about him?
      
      
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> came from a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> um, where the Number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> does take over after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> get to be a certain age.
         And then when he gets to be a certain age, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> takes over.
         So it's gone that way for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 200 years</TIMEX>.
         And, um, right now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> is
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 90</NUMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is taking care of him.
         He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>.
         So that's the kind of story she'd tell us.
         She would tell us about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> always took care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because they were so well respected, and they lived in a beautiful place, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would bring them gifts because they just appreciated their presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
         And um,
         we, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> would tell us these stories, we would laugh.
         We would think "Oh yeah, right, you were rich."
         And then when I did go over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, I did see what she was talking about and really felt guilty that we didn't believe her, totally believe her, that, that she had all this, but um, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> standards, uh, they are just very wealthy.
         And then they come here and they look at my house
         and they, no really, land over there is so very expensive so they are very wealthy, and then they come here, and I live in a very basic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and they think I'm rich, so uh, that's kind of comical
         which we're not, we're very middle class
         .
      
      
         That was a drastic change for her--
      
      
         It was.
      
      
         I mean, to go from there to, wow--
      
      
         She was pretty much treated like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>, pretty much, I mean they catered to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, they adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Wow.
         What did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Actually, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> for the telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Hum.
      
      
         Which is, I guess, why I love being around telephones and fixing phones, and I love what I do now.
         I guess it's almost to honor him.
      
      
         Why was he in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, he was in the uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK
      
      
         Yeah, and that's where he learned all his telephone skills.
         He, uh, learned a lot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, and then I think I'm the only one that kind of pursued an interest in telephones and communications and such--
      
      
         That is interesting that it would come back around that way.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, was there anything else your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> used to do or talked about that you wanted to include?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we used to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, which was very unusual for my mother
         .
      
      
         Oh, I bet.
      
      
         I mean she was kind of comical.
         She was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Prissy</ENAMEX>" out there, trying to camp
         .
         We used to, uh, we used to try to act like a normal
         <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, but we would have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> at the campground
         .
         I never remembered a day in my life that I didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>.
         We always ate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX>.
         If you got sick, she would ball up little balls of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> and, you know, "Just eat this you'll be OK."
         So she thought it, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> was a cure-all.
         But uh--
      
      
         Do you eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> now?
      
      
         Yes, I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice cooker</ENAMEX>, and I pretty much keep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> on all the time.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has learned to like it, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> love it.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is pursuing a career in uh, political science and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> studies--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         So she can go over there and teach <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
         And her junior year in college, she is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furman University</ENAMEX>, her junior year she plans to go over there and spend the whole year, studying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
         So I really feel like she's doing everything I wished I could have done
         .
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um huh.</ENAMEX>
         Is there anything else you want to include?
      
      
         No, not really but I appreciate it.
      
   
