
   
   
      
         You can just answer them and feel free to respond however you want to, OK?
         What stories or books do you remember reading as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>?
         Little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         My <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorite books as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curious George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jungle Book</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curious George</ENAMEX>.
         That was the little red <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> with the black and white-?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Did you have that doll?
      
      
         No.
         I didn't have the doll; I just had the books.
      
      
         Who told, did, did, is that story your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> read to you or did you like-?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> started reading it to me when I was small and, and I picked it up on my own reading and I enjoyed the illustrations as much as the book.
      
      
         So you liked the pictures?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Were they bright books?
         Or did they have bright pictures?
      
      
         They all had yellow covers and they were all paperbacks.
         And they had just little, uh, cartoons.
         Not vivid pictures, just-
      
      
         They weren't real bright colors, were they?
         And the whole page wasn't colored.
      
      
         No.
         It was just individual pictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> himself and his immediate surroundings.
      
      
         
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>, I didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curious George</ENAMEX>.
         That's neat!
         All right, um, well, what about that book that your mama bought you that time that, she told briefly that story.
         That book that she bought called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In One Light</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That's why I have such fond memories of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jungle Book</ENAMEX>.
         Because she purchased a book for me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and, um, it was a publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that could add your names and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s names and family names into the, into the plot of the story.
         So you became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.
         And it really brought home, um, events of the book to you because it was personal and it was, it was, individualistic.
      
      
         Who were you?
         Do you remember what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> you played?
      
      
         I was just one of the jungle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>-
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         -who went through and had interaction with each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jungle Book</ENAMEX>.
         There was the snake and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I remember <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jungle Book</ENAMEX> but do you remember the book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Black Sambo</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No I don't.
      
      
         OK.
         That was a story that I have fond memories of.
         Who would you consider the best storyteller in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         The best storyteller would be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemmie</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemmie</ENAMEX>.
         Because he, he grew up, um, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and so that just adds to his storytelling and imagination and his, he's always had interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so that just adds to how he interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now.
      
      
         Do you remember any one particular story that he told?
         You can't think of a story?
      
      
         Not, um, right off.
      
      
         I know the story he tells about, well he's always telling about going to play music and how they'd play when he was young.
         So can you think of a story?
      
      
         I can remember a story that really is humorous in a way because he always tells a story about how he used to double date with his future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, which is his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> because, unfortunately his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> passed away when, when she was really young so-
      
      
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen</ENAMEX> and him double dated with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Right.
         He would talk about how he would ask, um, he would always try to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> to end up paying for all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them's dinner.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And how they used to ride around together some.
         That, that to me is just something.
         It's hard to imagine your, your grandparents double dating with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, but, you know, that was a unique situation.
      
      
         
         So he's always been tight?
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, how does he tell, when he tells those stories, like does he usually tell them at family gatherings?
         How does he do it?
      
      
         Most of the time it's during family gatherings.
         He's always got a story to tell, regardless if he sees you or if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gathering.
         He's got, you know, he's going to be the one that's got, the one who is keeping the crowd up, or, or, you know, just being himself.
      
      
         
         What about you?
         What do you, when we, you and I, since we are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, when we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, do you imagine yourself as that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>?
         Like that kind of storyteller?
         Like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grandpa George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemmie</ENAMEX>?
         Do you see yourself like that?
      
      
         Probably, I don't know, some, to a degree.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he's probably the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who's like that.
         The rest of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is pretty laid back and goes with the flow.
         So I think I'd probably be a little bit of him, yet a little bit of everybody else, and I'm not really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to steal the, steal the show at gatherings or what have you.
      
      
         If you were going to tell a story to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about your childhood, what story would you tell?
      
      
         It would probably all be sports related stories, um, because sports to me has been such a big factor in my life whether it teaches you the value of competition or the value of sportsmanship or the learning from mistakes of, um, in sports you are sometimes forced to make quick decisions and sometimes those decisions are not necessarily the right ones.
         You may end up being thrown out of a game for something stupid you do.
      
      
         Well, I think maybe you are, ah, trying to preface some story about getting thrown out of a game.
      
      
         Well, um, there have been times when me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have gotten into a little bit of trouble.
         But we'd play our archrivals in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game.
      
      
         Who was your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">archrival</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from the northern part of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Stokes</ENAMEX> and we were the southern part, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Stokes</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> in particular who didn't like us and he was scheduled to pitch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> and after I had been hit the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time and my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> had been hit the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, we kind of decided that we were going take it upon ourselves to hit back.
         Only not with baseballs but with fists, so we charged the mound.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so, you know, things like that are learning experiences where you learn to grow up and mature.
      
      
         So what you going to tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> if someone from away hits them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with a baseball?
         Charge the mound?
      
      
         I've been there and I know what isn't necessarily the right decision.
      
      
         What about, what is your worst memory, not your worst as in bad, but just the worst kind of memorable memory you have about playing sports all through your life?
      
      
         Well, the good thing about sports is you can remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that occurs or it, or it can be a collection of memories.
         And a lot what I have are a collection of memories because when you play for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> of your life in sports like I have, um, really what stands out is just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX>.
         So many things can happen over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> that, or over the course of that many years
         nothing stands out in particular it is just bunch of fond
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, we have a phone call.
         We have an interruption.
      
      
         OK, sorry about that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, back to the sports thing.
         You were talking about how you just had a collection of memories.
         Well if you had, how do you think you got started in sports?
         What was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s connection to you in sports?
         Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise</ENAMEX>, and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, the funny thing is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were both athletic in high school.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, with her hook shot.
      
      
         With her patented jump hook shot.
         But, when it came to my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, neither one of them part-, participated in sports.
         And I wasn't, um, pushed by either one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to play sports.
         It was just the kind of thing where, um, in kindergarten or even before kindergarten, it just, it just came to me that I wanted to play tee ball and from there it started.
         And after that, I asked to put up a hoop in our backyard and luckily I had plenty of, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my age to play with and that used to be the ritual: have the neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come over to my hoop and we'd play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and it ended up I was playing with a lot of older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so I developed an athletic ability through playing with the neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and just starting so early and continuing on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>.
         So it's kind of just evolved.
         It wasn't something that was, you know, forced upon me.
      
      
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff or Denise</ENAMEX> neither one, you don't have any memories of playing with them in the yard?
      
      
         I would play with them in the yard, but they never played any organized sports.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is quite older than I am so, she and I, as far as playing sports together, you know, that was few and far between.
      
      
         She was dating when you were playing sports?
      
      
         Right.
         But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and I would play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> or play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, and we used to play a lot of kickball in our yard, because we had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, so we were always coming up with something.
      
      
         What about, hmm, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would always play too, um, he was always just one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, because we had, you know, when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 12</TIMEX>, we'd play against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 16</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years older</TIMEX> and he would come out and play, and so it was just kind of natural for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> to fit in and play along.
         And, uh, he was always good too, and he was one of the reasons, he made me good in what I was doing because he would challenge me.
         Of course he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 6'2</NUMEX>" when I was growing up at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 12 years old</TIMEX>, so, he, he would challenge me to get better.
      
      
         Did he let you win?
      
      
         Sometimes, but not usually.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, what's the best memory you have with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> and sports, because I know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>'s<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">- MS: Well</ENAMEX>-
      
      
         -important to you.
      
      
         Well, they always say that some of the bad things are what stands out and not necessarily a bad thing but it is one of my best memories is, ah.
         Well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> right before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">baseball season</TIMEX> my senior year and it didn't keep him from coming to any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> games though.
         I can remember him just in, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> prior, just prior to when he died, it was like it took <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every ounce</NUMEX> of energy he had to show up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> games, but nothing kept him from showing up.
         Like I said, you don't remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing in particular, you remember things collectively and I remember that season collectively and him making that effort to show up at the games.
      
      
         So, it meant a lot to you that he did that for you?
      
      
         Absolutely.
      
      
         He always videoed all your games too, didn't he?
      
      
         As many as he could.
         That <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> I don't have any of those because he wasn't able to do it, but all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball and basketball</ENAMEX> games prior to that he wanted to videotape them for-.
         It kind of started out in a funny way.
         It started out as, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, if I videotape them and we take them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and watch them you can watch each tape and you can analyze what you need to do to get better.
         And you can also show those to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> and, you know, he can view the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and see what they need to do to get better."
         But, you know, it just turned into something that I will always have, those collection of tapes, such memories.
         Both hearing his voice on them, screaming at the refs or screaming at me, cheering, and what have you.
         So, it's, it's become something that been unique as a collection of tapes.
      
      
         You said your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and that was the sport you were best in.
      
      
         Yeah, probably.
         I mean, relative to everybody else I was good in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> but, you know, that can't really compare to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Stackhouse</ENAMEX> or anybody like that.
      
      
         
      
      
         When you add <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six inches</NUMEX> to me it makes it a little bit tougher for me to compete.
      
      
         But you are good at baseball?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I was decent I guess.
      
      
         So is that going to be the sport you push on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I'm probably not going to push any sport on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, although I have always said when I was in college and, right after I gave up my sports career, I always said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, I'm going to teach him more and work with him all the time.
         But as I've grown older and matured I've decided I'm going to let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> be who he wants to be.
      
      
         So if we have a-
      
      
         Or she!
      
      
         Or a she, exactly.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, well, hmm, since, you know, this, I'm interviewing you, and you are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
         I want you to tell me the fondest story you have of me and you together.
         Something that we have done.
      
      
         Well, it's kind of a, of a defiance story probably .
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the stories I remember most.
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s always been real, or kind of protective of you.
      
      
         Yeah!
      
      
         Especially when we first started dating and you didn't necessarily have the most reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
      
      
         Your little wrecked `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> wasn't necessarily the thing you were going to drive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> away, especially <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> to come and see me.
         But, um, one of the things I remember was you putting it, putting yourself getting in trouble, and really probably wasn't one of the wisest things we have ever done.
         Putting your personal safety on the line when you took off <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> up to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> against your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s knowing.
         I guess your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> may have known but your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> didn't know.
      
      
         Yeah, I think I told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And, uh, and we had a nice dinner and we went out to a movie and-
      
      
         What movie did we see?
      
      
         I don't even remember the movie.
      
      
         I think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pelican Brief</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I just remember you coming up and that was one of the best times we have had.
         And of course one of the things I remember most was going out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Farmhouse</ENAMEX> which was our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official, unofficial date.
      
      
         
      
      
         
         And by our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official, unofficial date, should I go into that, too?
      
      
         Yeah.
         You can tell that.
      
      
         OK.
         Well, we ah, I had just broken up with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> of, on and off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, and you were supposedly dating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>-
      
      
         
      
      
         -stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         ( )
         kind of a long distance relationship!
      
      
         And my, um, fraternity was having a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX> and I, of course, needed someone to go with since I didn't have a, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> at the time.
         And all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> said, "Why don't you ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristi</ENAMEX>?
         Why don't you ask <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kristi?</ENAMEX>"
         Because we had a bunch of mutual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the fraternity and-
      
      
         Which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> pushed you the most?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Collini</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hum</ENAMEX>!
         Morgy!
      
      
         And, um, so we ended up going out but I didn't have any idea that you did have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         But I told them to tell!
      
      
         Nobody told me.
         And so I was looking at it as a date, whereas she was looking at it as a, a night out just to get out and do things.
         I don't know, I don't remember if you ended up telling me at some point during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> if you had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, um, but it really didn't slow me down any.
      
      
         
      
      
         I kept hitting on you, kept trying to charm you.
         I guess it got to you a little bit, because we ended up eventually-
      
      
         Eventually!
         Yeah I told you I had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> remember?
         You listened to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> music too much maybe a little bit too much.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, tell me, uh, about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandpa Willis</ENAMEX> because I don't know him that much.
         Tell me something about him.
      
      
         He was one of the most reserved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you will ever meet and ah, he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84</TIMEX> when he passed away and he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5'10</NUMEX>" and he never weighed over a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred thirty-five pounds</NUMEX>.
      
      
         You take after him.
      
      
         He grew up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>, and the thing about it is that he smoked non-filtered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camels</ENAMEX> since the time he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years old</TIMEX> and he passed away at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 85</TIMEX> with the cleanest lungs, but I'm sure it didn't make the rest of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> too healthy.
         But, um, but he was just an average hard working rural <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.
         With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and he loved his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> dearly.
      
      
         That's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         When my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> passed away in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> it wasn't long after that he deteriorated.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, pretty much to nothing because he, ah he had lost a major part of his life and it really brought him down but he didn't necessarily, he wasn't one of the most talkative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         If you talked to him, it was like pulling teeth sometimes, but he would do anything in the world for you.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he would always go the extra <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mile</NUMEX>, he just didn't do it with words, he did it with actions.
      
      
         Did you ever remember him playing, was he a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>?
         Did he play sports with you or anything?
      
      
         Not really, hmm, he grew up on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and, you know, playing sports was, um, and he was so much older that I was, he wasn't really in the best of health when I was growing up.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, of course, we would go up there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Sunday</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX> and, uh, he would get out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> with us and watch us climb <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and throw rocks and play, but he never really participated because he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> older, you know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> older than I was.
      
      
         So your grandpa was fairly old when you were born?
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         I didn't know that.
         I didn't know your grandpa was a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>.
         It's the main economy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stokes County</ENAMEX>, is farming.
         So there's no big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> whatsoever in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stokes County</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I know that you used to do that when you were little didn't you?
      
      
         Yeah.
         All of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> grew up on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and, and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> when you weren't playing sports, you were farming or working in tobacco to make money.
      
      
         What did you do?
      
      
         You primed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX>, you'd chop it, and you'd plant it.
         You know, all the things necessary to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And then did you sell it?
         I mean, is that what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX> did?
      
      
         Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> would take it to the, to the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> and then they would auction it off and sell it per pound.
         And that's what their, uh, that's what their way of living was, was to sell that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Hmm, that's all your grandpas ever did?
      
      
         Well, that's what they did until they became <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55 or 60 years old</TIMEX>, and then my late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemmie</ENAMEX> went to work in a textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> went to work in a furniture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>.
      
      
      
      
         Industry.
      
      
         Industry, industry came in there.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, what about your, um,
         childhood with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>?
         What is the funniest story that you remember with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
         I've heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple</TIMEX>, but-
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was always the little tyrant.
         She is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX> older than me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 years</TIMEX> older than me.
         And during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> when we were home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six years old</TIMEX> when they were both still home.
         She was responsible for making sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> got clean and the chores got done and to make sure we played a part in that, and of course she was going to make sure we did our part.
         So she was the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave driver</ENAMEX> I've ever seen, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was always the rebel, and I, you know, as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six year old</TIMEX>, I did what I could and she didn't really have a lot of trouble with me, but with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> being, when she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> so you can imagine what kind of battles they had.
         She always had this thing about when we rebelled she would lock us in two separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s idea of rebelling was to escape out the window and run around.
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, what he did was, we got locked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know what we did necessarily <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, but he climbed out the window and was running around.
      
      
         Which <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> was he locked into?
      
      
         He was locked into the front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And you were locked into the-
      
      
         I was locked into the back.
      
      
         Which back?
         Your back?
      
      
         Well, that doesn't really mean anything to anybody who's listening.
      
      
         Well, it does!
         Me!
      
      
         But anyway, he climbed out a window and came by my window, and my window was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several feet</NUMEX> off the ground so it wasn't like I could escape.
         But he would throw rocks up to get my attention and he saw me look out the window and he was jumping up and down waving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and laughing because he was out and I was still in.
         Well, about that time he, he jumped on a honeybee.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And, and the first thing I saw him do was hit the ground holding his feet so he kind of got what he deserved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, showing off a little bit, hmm, base, but they had their share of fights.
      
      
         Did he get caught?
      
      
         Yeah he got caught!
         And got locked back in with a, with a sore foot.
      
      
         Well, you were perfect, you never did anything?
         What about the hole in the wall?
      
      
         Well that's a different story!
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>!
         Yeah, that's what I thought!
         All right, uh, what about, um, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>?
         Tell me some funny stories about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
         She doesn't really tell many stories about her childhood or anything.
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s got plenty of stories to tell I am sure.
         The funny, I think one of the most humorous things about her if you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, she's, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56 now</TIMEX> and to imagine her with this patented hook shot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">all-star of the</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stokes County Basketball League</ENAMEX> as a senior in high school is pretty funny!
         And she used to demonstrate that for me, too.
         We would go out and we would play <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and she would kick my butt because she had that hook shot that nobody else could do!
      
      
         
         In her high heel shoes!
      
      
         In her high heel shoes!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, well OK.
         I guess that is probably about enough.
         Anything else that you want to add to your interview?
         OK thank you and now you are always on tape!
      
   
