
   
   
      
         OK.
         Have you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> your whole life?
      
      
         Yes, I have.
      
      
         Is there anything you want to talk about in relate-, relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> or any particular stories you would like to share?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, well, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 15</NUMEX> I had to move from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> to another and it was a very hard experience for me because, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had, was remarried, um, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> prior to this.
         So, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life was already kind of disrupted, so being pulled away from all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, um, really tore part of my life up because I was leaving, you know, the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that I'd even known and I'd grown up with them from like elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to high school.
         And, um, so I was really upset.
         I was angry with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
         We didn't speak.
         She sent me to like a frigging shrink to, um, help maybe, you know, sort through my emotions or whatever.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so, uh, but what, but actually, my move was probably one of the best things that ever happened to me, oddly enough, um,
         because when I moved, um, I met like, you know, close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that, actually, now I go to college with and who I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> with for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so even though it was kind of a scary experience being uprooted from everything you knew, um, it gave me the chance to see that change is good and that, um, seeing a different part of, you know, just different parts of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, it's still very beneficial because it gave me the chance to realize how to adapt to different situations, into a different environment, relatively quickly.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, because I ended up making a lot of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and, um, really loving the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that I moved to and really adapting to, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> there, um, and getting involved.
         And actually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that I made there are the ones I ended up going to college with and not the ones from my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         So, um-
      
      
         Do you feel it made it easier for you to adapt to college life because of the move?
      
      
         Definitely.
         Because I was already, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, ready to for another change.
         Whereas a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had never even been in a different situation, in a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> from the ones they had known from elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         They couldn't imagine being uprooted and not seeing the same faces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.
         Whereas I'd already had this type of thing in my life, so I was more, I think I was quicker to adapt to a different college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surroundings</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Do you feel that it was hard being the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>?
         I mean were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really, did they I don't know how to put it.
      
      
         They didn't like me
         at first `cause I was the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and where, you know, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, if a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> comes in, of course they're going to be friendly just because
         it's new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or whatever.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> did not want to have anything to do with me, they're catty.
         It was like I was, you know, invading their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> or whatever.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so it really took them, probably, I'd say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least three months</TIMEX> before I'd actually consider them my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> because I'd have classes with, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie</ENAMEX>, who is one of my good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> now, but she did not talk to me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three months</TIMEX>.
         I mean, and she even admitted that she didn't like me because I was new.
         Even though I don't think it was because of anything I'd done because I had hardly said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words since I didn't know anybody, but, um, they were real coy towards me, you know.
         But it-
      
      
         Why do you think that is?
         Why do you thing do you think that's just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in general?
      
      
         Actually, I think it is most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in general.
         It's just a natural thing if you, if you have certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy friends</ENAMEX> that you become very possessive over and you see someone, whether it's their new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> or their new best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or whatever, comes in and takes up some of your time, I think it's just human nature to get jealous and to kind of put up a, you know, an offensive front to whoever the invader or the intruder is.
         So, I think I've probably done the some time in my life, so I don't have any hard feelings towards them.
      
      
         And you feel it was a good thing, overall, the whole experience of moving and being the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and-?
      
      
         Absolutely!
         I wouldn't trade that experience for the world because there are too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that I know who are very sheltered from not only new experiences, from like new ideas and new situations, and so I think it's kind of a blessing that I had the chance to go through this in the kind of, um, be the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and see what it was like to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> and to not be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">in crowd</ENAMEX>, you know.
         Because, I mean, I think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have never been on the outside don't understand what it's like to be kind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that's, you know, not "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popularity</ENAMEX>," you know?
         Who doesn't have all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and who doesn't get all the attention, and so it was nice because, you know, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, like, I had a good circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> I was always, you know, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX>, or whatever, so, you know, I received the attention.
         But for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those few months</TIMEX> that I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>, I really got to see what it was like, you know, to not be, you know, cool, or whatever.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Now I understand.
         Is there anything else you'd like to say or?
      
      
         Umm, other than it was a good experience, that's about it.
      
      
         Well thank you so very much for sharing your experience with us.
      
      
         You're very welcome.
      
   
