
   
   
      
         Hi how are you?
      
      
         Fine.
      
      
         What's your name?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivonne Silva</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How old are you Ivonne?
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX>.
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX>.
         Ivonne, I'll be asking you some questions.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, what stories do you remember family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> telling you?
         Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, about their life, and like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> used to tell me about when she lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and she used to go really <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the mornings</TIMEX> with a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, with a group of older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, and they would go on the bus and they would drink hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>.
         And then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> told me about a time when he climbed up on the window and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> came out and look at him and scared him and he fell down and rolled down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> because it was steep.
         And
         and, he talked about a time that he was trying to cut a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> or something and he cut his knee open.
      
      
         With what?
      
      
         Like an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
         
         Do you remember maybe your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> telling you stories?
      
      
         No.
         But I remember when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> said he fell down and he hit his head in the, like a river because he dived in, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> dived in the same place and she hit herself there too.
      
      
         When she did that, when she was older?
      
      
         When she was young like teenager.
      
      
         And then later on in life her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> did the same?
      
      
         Yeah.
         Yeah.
      
      
         In the same place?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Do you remember the name of that place?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poso Azul</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Which means?
      
      
         Blue
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pond</ENAMEX> or something.
      
      
         Very good.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you remember stories being told by other family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, maybe your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> told me stories.
         She would make up stories for us, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I, at bedtime when we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> and she would tell us stories like, including like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> that were like us but we had different names and stuff, or we would be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and they would have morals to them at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and, or we would read books at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before going to bed.
      
      
         So this was in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         It was just your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Or somebody else's?
      
      
         No.
         Oh, oh it was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s and my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you remember how it looked like?
         Can you describe it?
      
      
         Yes.
         It had a bed where you pull another bed out from under it and it had one of those
         like porch outside of it and it was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and when you came in the front door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> it would be down the left <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>.
         It would be the first door on the right.
      
      
         And do you remember stories about maybe somebody else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?
         Maybe that you can tell?
      
      
         
         Oh yeah!
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> when she was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, she went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">walk-in closet</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and she put baby powder all over herself and all over the clothes.
         And also in that same walk-in closet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I, we would go in there and hide from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and when he got home from work and we would wait for him to come in and turn on the light and then when he walked in we'd scare him.
         Because we'd be hiding on the shoes and behind the clothes.
      
      
         Very good.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         Do you like reading?
      
      
         Yes.
         I read a lot.
      
      
         What kind of books do you like to read?
      
      
         All type of books, but I have a collection.
         I collect um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Gables</ENAMEX> because I like it.
      
      
         Why, is there a favorite book?
         Or are those your favorite ones?
      
      
         I like those, yeah.
      
      
         
         All right, um.
         
         Do you like to tell stories?
      
      
         Yeah.
         I like writing stories and poems and I write them for school a lot and I'm part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to write stories and poems and we draw too, to put stories that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> write in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         Do you have books now?
      
      
         We have a lot of books.
      
      
         At home?
      
      
         Yeah, we had a lot of different types of books and we have some books from when we were little too.
      
      
         Where do you keep them?
      
      
         Downstairs we have like a playroom is like a big TV <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and we keep them down there on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one half</NUMEX> of it.
      
      
         What about your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>?
         Now do you share <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No, I have my own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and I have some books in there but not many because most of them are downstairs.
      
      
         Can you describe your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes.
         There is a bed, it's a full bed and it's got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> and a dresser and a closet and a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         \\ Oh.
         \\
      
      
         Because I like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX>, and it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> windows, and when you walk in, the bed is to your left and so is the dresser and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> is to your left and right.
         Like, like--
      
      
         What things do you have on your desk?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I have a bunch of things.
         I have pictures of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and I have books and I have medals and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, um, anything else that you would like to tell us?
         Things you like to do?
      
      
         I like to play my flute in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh that is nice.
         OK, thank you very much.
      
      
         You're welcome.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bye</ENAMEX>.
      
   
