
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Smith</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 59</TIMEX> and I'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What kind of stories were told to you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         We have a family picture of me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> sitting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> reading us a story.
         I do not remember what the story was about.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the stories I remember the most was listening to the radio.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I don't remember stories from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> reading them
         .
         It was a stand up big radio, we didn't have a TV at this time, and I sat leaning on the radio listening to my favorite, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Shadow</ENAMEX>, Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow Knows</ENAMEX> a mystery story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>.
         I do not remember being read to with books.
         I remember <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>, though, having to walk up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.
         It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christmastime</ENAMEX> and it was cold, and being bundled up, I walked at nighttime slowly up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
         There was a full moon.
         I slowly looked up at the moon and saw a gold sleigh and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> approaching the left side of the moon.
         I was surprised and did not believe what I was seeing, so, I paused and I gazed in awe that I actually saw <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> and the sleigh!
         I couldn't get it out of my mind as I continued my walk.
         When I got home, I told everyone and don't remember any responses.
         I was told by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>, that really bothered me so I asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX>.
         He had a way of speaking, with a strong voice that we never questioned when he used it.
         And when he, when I told him what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> said he sat me down saying, "That is not true, there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>," in that voice we never questioned.
         "Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is wrong and let me tell you why."
         And he just proceeded with his loving logic and questions to prove to me there really was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>.
         Everything he said made sense to me and I could feel myself well up inside with pride and love for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and I felt so good and happy that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> was now wrong and I was right and there really was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> was in my heart and mind now.
      
      
         Which one was your favorite story?
      
      
         That was my favorite story, it was the most impactful story.
         And to this day, I can still remember feeling so proud that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> convinced me and all those feelings of believing that that was true and I can still feel that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Did you read books or tell stories to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes, I did both.
         I read books and told stories.
      
      
         What kind of books did you read to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
         Where did you read them?
         Why did you read them?
      
      
         Well, uh.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s books, um, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seuss</ENAMEX>, and I did a lot of books on feelings, about being sad, happy, neat, and angry and things like that, um, so they could understand the feelings at those levels.
         And um, I got books, like transactional analysis, which they called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA for tots</ENAMEX>, and "I'm OK, You're OK," um, a gamut of fairytales, uh, like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Three Little Pigs</ENAMEX> and things like that, every, I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books and every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book I could get, I brought for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I had many, many books for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, the books were always available to them.
         I read to them at bedtime uh, in their beds, other times they sat in my lap during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, um, like going over the pictures, the sounds and the tone of voice, uh, through me, um, as to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> was feeling, scared, happy, angry.
         When I felt like it um, it would be effective and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s behavior said, "They were really into this story," at that point then I would add my own words and make up more of what had caught their interest.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, being each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> myself as I read added, added more excitement for them and for me.
         Sometimes we'd lay on the carpet and read and I'd follow their interest, when to stop and when to start, and when sometimes, to turn the page.
         It was all up to their interest.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I read at bedtime as a calming down for all of us, being together and ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our day</TIMEX>.
         Sitting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> with them, uh, gave me the feeling of closeness and the uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s closeness or bonding with me.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and when we read was whenever anybody wanted to read and sometimes I would introduce a new book to them and say I have a new story for you.
      
      
         OK.
         What kind of stories did you tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
         Do you recall any of them?
      
      
         Oh yeah, oh yeah, I recall them.
         I made up stories, um, that I told to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> also.
         They were older and enjoyed scary, uh, scary stories at that time.
         So, I told them scary stories that chilled them.
         At bedtime, um, when all were in the same bed, and that's where they had to be for these stories.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I usually made up a story according to what they were feeling at different points in their lives.
         Their favorite was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wood-Monster</ENAMEX>," uh, sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> felt like running away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and whatever I would pick up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that they were issuing is what I would make a story out of and to get my point across to them too.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, this, this story involved, this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wood-Monster</ENAMEX>" story involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that uh felt like running away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and this story involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who decided to do just that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one late night</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, they sneaked out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> windows and they all met and went into the woods.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, as they thought this was really cool, and they were sitting under a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in the woods, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> started moving, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> thinking, uh, that the wind was doing it, but when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> started to slowly come down and start touching them, they got scared, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> were trying to wrap around them, then the trunk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> started bending also.
         And they all started screaming, running away.
         They discovered as they ran by each <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in the woods that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> were alive and wanting to attach their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> around them.
         There was nowhere they could go to free themselves of this nightmare except home.
         So they finally all decided that this was not the thing and they got back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, uh, through their window and felt the safe, warm comfort of their beds and vowed never to do that again.
         And also certain stuffed animals my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had were, um, were also made alive by me.
         When they got thrown on the floor and not cared about, I made up a story about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> felt being treated that way when it loved them so much and wanted to be snuggled up by them at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, I played the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> of course, and then with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around it, I still do this once and awhile with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult children</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> was really drawn into this story and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> she is very sensitive and compassionate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I also sent my young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult children Easter bunnies</ENAMEX> and the loving message that went with it, uh, was from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bunny</ENAMEX>.
         Like, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bunny</ENAMEX> talked with me at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and he was so sweet and loving and really wanted to be with one of you, one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and not left on the shelf in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> all by himself, so I would create that kind of story and attach it to the bunnies and send them to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you read stories now?
         And If so, what kind?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I some of them are made into stories, um, see for the past maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25,30 years</TIMEX> I've read many new age books, uh, from channeling to personal stories by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> relating to their major life changes.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I have read many self-awareness books and management books and books on raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         All of my reading basically involved self-improvement at each level of my growth, um, including spiritual growth.
         I read all of these books to help me be a more effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, and spiritual being.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my best reading time was in bed where I had no interruptions, um, and then I could focus on the information.
         And I still send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult children</ENAMEX> books on topics I think they could gain deeper insight to.
         
      
      
         What's your favorite book now?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my very favorite book is God on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, it, through that book it was me going through all the same experiences as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and I saw more clearly what I needed to do.
      
      
         OK, well thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         You're welcome.
      
   
