
   
   
      
         This is the story of how I met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
         It's kind of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady Bunch</ENAMEX> story.
         I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>.
         We had each been divorced for a while and we each were too busy to do any dating or meeting of perspective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>.
         So my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> had a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, affectionately called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Quail Girls</ENAMEX>," and his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>, had a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, I won't tell you what we'd name them, but anyway, they were normal high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, and both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Mecklenburg High School</ENAMEX> at the same time.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> interacted a lot, they were, uh, they were all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michaela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelle</ENAMEX>, just got an inspiration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> when she was staring out a window riding down the road, and she said, "Chaela!
         We need to get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Speckman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>!"
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Really?</ENAMEX>"
         `Cause she was, of course, very protective of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
         So finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> said, "Well maybe that will work."
         And all of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are saying, "Yeah, yeah, yeah!"
         So that was when the idea was born.
         And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> kept saying, "You know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, you need to meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>."
         And I said, "Now why do I need to meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>?"
         "Well you need to meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> because he's single and all he has time for is his job and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.
         He's really cute and he's a really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and he's real involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>."
         I said, "Well if he is really cute and he's a really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, then I'm sure that he's got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>."
         And she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, no, no.
         I know he doesn't.
         I just know he doesn't because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> say he doesn't and he never goes to the games with anybody, and you need to meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>."
         So I said, "All right, whatever.
         I'll meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>."
         So then I would forget about it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> would come over and they would say, "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX> you need to meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>."
         And I'm like, "Yeah, yeah, yeah.
         I'll meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>."
         So, um, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> game would come up because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speckman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michaela</ENAMEX> would say, "How about it?
         Can you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> game on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>?"
         And I had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> job and I would say, "Well no I can't go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>."
         So then a few more games would go by, um, I could go to the game, but she couldn't go to the game and next time she could go to the game then I couldn't go to the game and she would say, "Well Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> wasn't there anyway."
         So this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fixture</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> became this Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         So, um, there was, at the end of the sports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, the fall sport <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> sport <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Mecklenburg</ENAMEX> there was always, a what they called, a banquet and they didn't serve any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, but for some reason they called it a banquet.
         They had all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> sports up on the stage to be introduced, get whatever recognition were appropriate, and, um, there was going to be one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early December of 1995</TIMEX>.
         And, uh, that was when it was decided since I was going to be there, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> played tennis in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>, and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> was going to be there, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX> played soccer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> that was when this meeting would take place.
         So in order to make sure that I would be there one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quail Girls</ENAMEX>, who lived right around the corner from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speckmans</ENAMEX>, said she would come and she would pick me up.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michaela</ENAMEX> couldn't drive me because she had to be there early to be in this program.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> helped me pick out what I was supposed to wear and, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> came to pick me up.
         And you have to understand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> is this, she's a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> but she's kind of a silly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         She's always like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ha</ENAMEX>, uh, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha</NUMEX>, uh!"
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> came to pick me up and I was all nervous and everything, which was ridiculous.
         I was, I felt like a high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> myself.
         And, um, when we got there, uh, we s, sat with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who, again, live around the corner from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>.
         They said, this is, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said to me, "Oh!
         You're going to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Speckman</ENAMEX>!
         Whew!
         I hope this works out!
         You've got good taste!"
         I'm like, "Oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>!
         What am I getting myself into?"
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> and I sat down and were just kind, you know, of chatting.
         She's squirming and looking all around and everything and the program started and it's quiet and all of a sudden she says, "There he is!
         Right over there, right over there!"
         I said, "Sssh!"
         So anyway I got, I got a chance to take a look at Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> and, um, he looked just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> had described, so through the whole thing I kind of did an analysis of, you know, do I or do I not want to meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>?
         And if I do, you know.
         Basically, do I or don't I want to meet Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>, but I felt like I would let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> and all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> down if I did not.
         So after the program was over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> came down off the stage.
         And she came and, uh, came with me to the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of the auditorium where they were serving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
         So all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quail Girls</ENAMEX> and I were together and we were having punch and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> or whatever, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> were over kind of in another area.
         So, uh, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX> was saying, "How are we going to do this?
         How are we going to do this?"
         And I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, you know, if it happens, it happens.
         If it doesn't happen I'll, I'll, you know, it can happen at another time I'm sure.
         We'll be in the same place another time," because <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> went by and nothing happened.
         So I said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five or 10 more minutes</TIMEX>, "You know, maybe this isn't the right time.
         Let's just leave and, and, you know, I'll, I'll just meet him another time."
         And all of a sudden I got this tap on the shoulder and I turned around and I looked up into the eyes of this high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Speckman</ENAMEX>.
         And he said, "Don't you want to meet him?"
         And I fell in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Speckman</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, and I said, "Well sure!"
         So he went and he got him and I walked in that direction, and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> came over and said, "Hi!
         You must be Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX>."
         And I said, "You must be Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>."
         So we introduced each other and had a few awkward <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> and then we left.
         So the next, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>, OK that was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving week</TIMEX>, so I had to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> in the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> where I worked, and it was a crazy, crazy, crazy day, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> called me in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the day</TIMEX>, this was on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, and she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guess</ENAMEX> who called and left a message?"
         And I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who?</ENAMEX>"
         And she said, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX>!"
         And I said, "You're kidding!"
         And she said, "Are you going to call him?
         Are you going to call him?
         Are you going to call him?"
         So I said, "Yeah I'll call him."
         So I went <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>, called him, left him a message, he wasn't there.
         So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days later</TIMEX>, I get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work again in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and there was a message that said, "Call me back, whatever time."
         So I called him back and we arranged to have dinner on that following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
         So I called and talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michaela</ENAMEX> and I said, "Well we're going out to eat."
         And she said, "I knew it!
         I knew it!
         I knew it!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> came up to me at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and he said, `He called her!
         I think they're going to go out!
         ' " And apparently another one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quail Girls</ENAMEX> worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Market</ENAMEX> and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> who were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> crossed the serving line and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> called her and he's going to ask her out!"
         So everybody knew before I knew that he called me and was going to ask me out!
         So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> came and we were supposed to go out.
         I came home from work so there was a message and on the voice mail was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who had this brainstorm to begin with, and she said, "Hi!
         This is Shelle!
         Just wanted to tell you good luck <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.
         Don't be nervous!
         You'll be fine!"
         And I'm like, "I'm old enough to be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, I'm sure I'll be fine!"
         So everybody's eager to find out what's happening on this date.
         So, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> was going out and I had instructions to call her as soon as I got home, to beep her as soon as I got home so we could discuss the date.
         So we went out to dinner at a place where, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> had asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> where we should go and he said that's where we should go, and so we went there to eat.
         And the whole <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> was talk, the discussion the whole <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> was how all the preparation, and all the discussion that was going on with me and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quail Girls</ENAMEX> was also going on with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and with all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         And they had cleaned out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, they called him at work and made sure that he was there in time for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date</TIMEX>, so, I mean, we had a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lovely evening</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lovely evening</TIMEX>.
         And, um, just talked about how funny it was that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were trying to, to make us meet.
         So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michaela</ENAMEX>, yeah, I called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX>, and she said, "What did you think?
         What did you think?"
         I said, "You know, he's a very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but he is so busy with his business and with his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that I don't even think he's even got time for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another date</TIMEX> but he, he is very nice.
         But if he asked me out again I'd probably go out again."
         So this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, early, so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> I went out and I bought a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and I had a lot of errands to do.
         In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> calls and said, "Really had a good time <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>."
         I said, "I did too.
         It really was fun."
         He said, "I'd like to do it again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime</TIMEX>."
         And I said, "Yeah I would too."
         So we're talking some more, and I said, "I went and got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>."
         He said, "What are you going to do this <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>?"
         I said, "I'll probably put the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> up."
         He said, "You know I would really like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAdenville</ENAMEX>."
         So anyway, I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool</ENAMEX>!
         You want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McAdenville</ENAMEX>, we'll go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAdenville</ENAMEX>."
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> came home and I said, "Guess what?
         I'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAdenville</ENAMEX>."
         And she said, "Oh my God!"
         She called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shelle , Shelle</ENAMEX> was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>!
         "I can't believe it she's going out with him again!
         You're going out with him again!"
         So we went out again and we went out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, and meanwhile, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are in absolute shock that we liked each other and we were going out, I don't know what they expected.
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> said to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michaela</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, "Wouldn't it be weird if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speckman</ENAMEX> got married?
         And like, you moved into that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and you were taking a shower and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s your stepbrother and he's going to knock on the ba-, how weird would that be?"
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michaela</ENAMEX> told me that and I said, "That is so weird."
         She said, "That is so weird!"
         Well it wasn't long before, um, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or two later</TIMEX>, she said to me, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> he's wonderful.
         Would you ask him to marry us?"
         Anyway, to make a long story short, about, we met in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> of `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>, he asked me to marry, No!
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> of `<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">97</TIMEX> he asked me to marry him.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> of `<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">97</TIMEX> we got married, and our wedding party was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX> girls and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speckman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, and the guest list was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quail Girls</ENAMEX> and all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and they all lived happily ever after.
      
   
