
   
   
      
         OK.
         My name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmen Stack</ENAMEX> and I'm just going to tell a little bit about myself.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> and I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX>, um, which is about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty-five minutes</TIMEX> east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, um, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX>.
         And I've grown up there pretty much all my life.
         I moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> to go to college and stayed there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and am still there.
         But, um, OK, but I live with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> right now.
         I moved back in after I graduated college and I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, she lives there, too.
         She's in high school.
         Her name is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivy</ENAMEX> and she's going to turn seventeen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks</TIMEX>.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> lives next door and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> works across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from where we live so, we're all really close and pretty tight and, um, I'm real, I'm closer with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, um, which is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, and, um, we do a lot of stuff together, go shopping, and go to lunch, and stuff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX>.
         So, um, but anyway, I guess I can tell a story about when I was little.
         I, OK, I, um, I have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and I have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and so I love <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> a lot.
         And, um, when I was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years old</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and I, um, well we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, one was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfhound</ENAMEX> and one was just a little mutt-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.
         But, um, we left them there by themselves with, uh, well like a bowl of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> out, which usually we don't do, but we were going to go get some lunch and, um, we were gone for probably about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX>.
         And we came back and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mongoose</ENAMEX> was the little one and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanya</ENAMEX> was the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, uh, but when we came back, we saw that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mongoose</ENAMEX>, uh, was bleeding from her eyes.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tanya</ENAMEX> had ripped her eye out, had bitten her eyeball out, um obviously over the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that we had left out on the floor.
         And so, obviously I was totally devastated and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was, too and so we rushed her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> and, um, they, everything was OK.
         Like they were able to save her but they couldn't put her eye back in, so they just kind of sewed it up and eventually it grew hair back over it.
         
            And, uh, she just had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> with hair covering the other side.
         So it was pretty, it was funny, but she lived for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another six years</TIMEX> at least.
         So, but she was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.
         And, but she did fine after that with just one eye, but, um, let's see I guess-
      
      
         Do you have any memories about many trips you used to take when you were little?
         Like to the beach or something?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yeah, well, um, we, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe</ENAMEX> had a beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         Well, they always had like a condo that they had rented, or they owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, um, when I was little.
         And, this was on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s side, and we would always, it would be like my aunts and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         My, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> died before I was born.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, he died when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was probably about eighteen so I never got to see or meet him.
         But, um, all of us and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and everybody would go to the beach and, um-
      
      
         What was it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah, we'd go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, we would stay for probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> and we just had, we all had the best time.
         We, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> were just really close, like we all were probably about the same age except for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, she was, she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> younger than me so-, and everybody else is older than me.
         I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> that's, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 now</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tara</ENAMEX> is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tara</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>, I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>.
         So, but, anyway, um, we all, we all got along really good and it was just, it was like one of the better times that we all had, that we all spent together for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
         And when it was time to go to the beach together it was just like, it was like great!
         We couldn't ever replace it.
         So, but, uh, I guess that's the-
      
      
         What would you do when you were at the beach?
         What was your favorite place?
      
      
         Well, we would all, well our favorite place, I mean we were pretty young, so our favorite place was like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pavilion</ENAMEX> or going to walk on the strip or something.
         But, um, we, you know, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> it was always the beach, going to the beach and playing on the beach, and laying out and then going shopping at the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX> or, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barefoot Landing</ENAMEX>.
         And we'd usually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and then at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we'd sit, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is like the main thing for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         We center everything around eating dinner so, or eating a dinner, breakfast, dinner, or lunch.
         So, but, um, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we'd always go to dinner and, um, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pavilion</ENAMEX> or else to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grand Prix</ENAMEX> or, is that what it's called?
         And, um, stuff like that.
         Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> would always take us places and let us go and ride rides and stuff like that and we'd all go together as a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and it was just a lot of fun.
         We were all really close and we still are.
         But, um-
      
      
         Was it, your, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> does she, she sort of, you said, she kind of heads up the whole thing?
      
      
         Oh yeah.
      
      
         Sort of the matriarch?
      
      
         Yeah, she definitely is.
         She's like, she heads everything, like-
      
      
         Is she from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah well, yeah.
         She's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         She was born and raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, so, you know, she had all her, she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was, he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, too and all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, but yeah, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, she's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of everything.
         She makes sure that we're all together for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year's Day</TIMEX> and everything.
         She just always wants everything to be at her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and kind of be centered around her.
         So after she's gone I don't really know what we're going to do.
         It'll be kind of hard for us.
         But, ah, she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX> and she's still going strong but actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> she had a small stroke but she's, she's OK.
         She's better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         She's been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, but, um, she, they're just kind of giving her some physical therapy and stuff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>, just to kind of make sure she'll do OK.
         But she's strong.
         She'll make it through.
      
      
         You said, uh, you were telling me, she's, uh, got some funny sayings that she says and stuff?
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         She's got some funny, like when-.
         You tell it!
      
      
         
         Oh wait, I'm trying, I think.
         I can't remember.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, like-
      
      
         It's not worth something, something-
      
      
         Oh, um, yeah, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> she, yeah, she's got some funny sayings.
         Like she'll, well she, when she's referring to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, he's kind of like, he's kind of the, I guess, the black <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         You know, just, he's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> and he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> older than me but he can't, he can't keep a job and he's just got a-.
         He fails a lot at pretty much everything he does.
         But she always says that he's not worth the powder to take to blow his ass away!
         
      
      
         So, But, um, you know, it's pretty funny, of course, he doesn't, he doesn't think it, it's funny but she, that's her favorite thing to say.
         But she, she'll about anything to anybody and it's kind of embarrassing sometimes.
      
      
         Straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         But, yeah, she's just, she's straight on with you.
         She'll tell you like it is and if you don't like it then that's just too bad.
         But we've come to realize that's her and that's just the way it's going to have to be.
         But, um, um, so my next story, I guess I want to talk about, uh, I guess I'll move on to kind of high school era.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we were, it was, I guess there were probably about maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of us, but I was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         I hung out with a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy friends</ENAMEX>.
         We were always out kind of doing "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> stuff," and I guess I wasn't really like a tomboy but I did like to go fishing and hang out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and stuff.
         But anyway, um, we were riding, um, there were probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> of us, and we were riding in the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.
         And I, I was in the back.
         And, uh, you know, I just kind of, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and he was driving.
         And, um, we were going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Twitty</ENAMEX>, and I kind of just got volunteered into going with everybody.
         So we were going <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> fishing, but, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> had some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, so anyway, we were just riding along and we pulled into, uh, and, oh!
         Something that I left out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> had a light that he had, would, like a big flashlight that he was shining, and, um, not a flashlight, a spotlight and it had a blue light in it, and he was kind of flashing it around and just playing around with it.
         And, um, we pulled into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that takes us to the lake and all of a sudden we, a car followed us, uh, followed in behind us and it was like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">300ZX</TIMEX>.
         And, um, we pulled in and we stopped and he got out and but, just he was just kind of, we couldn't see him because he had, he had his lights on, his brights.
         And, um, he said, "Why don't you, why don't you point that thing over here to see what I got?"
         And, uh, he had, he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>.
         And well, come to find out he was a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> but he was off-duty and he was in an unmarked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh-
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monroe</ENAMEX>?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, so he had pulled us over because we were flashing the light.
         And, um, so, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> said that, you know, he was sorry.
         He didn't realize that we were causing any trouble.
         But, um, he had told us that, um,
         .
         So, he says to us that, um, he shows us his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and he said that he had, he almost shot us.
         And he acted really nervous and jittery and he acted like, he came up to the car kind of close and he acted like he did want to shoot us.
         And, um, he, but he didn't really care that we had, that we had, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and he didn't mind that we were all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under age or</TIMEX> he didn't even know because none of us were of age.
         And so, you know, he didn't act like he really wanted to fill any papers on us or anything.
         It was kind of, you know, it was just like it was really scary.
         We didn't really know, really know what to expect from him.
         We didn't know that he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>.
         We didn't find this out till probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 or 15 minutes</TIMEX> later, until he was about to leave.
         But, um, he just was really nervous acting.
         He, he was definitely scaring me because he acted like he wanted something to happen.
         He was really mad at us for doing that.
         But yet he wasn't calling any backup or anything like that.
         And he was alone and he just seemed kind of scary.
         But we found out probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year later</TIMEX>, or we saw on the news that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>, he had been arrested for, um, murdering a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, um, in, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX>.
         And he pulled her over and murdered, and found out or got arrested for murder.
         And, uh, now he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penitentiary</ENAMEX>.
         So I guess we were lucky <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>.
         But-
      
   
