
   
   
      
         I've never been timid in my life.
         This is a change of pace for me.
         I grew up in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>?
         There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50</TIMEX>'s it was a great place to grow up.
         It's a railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work for the railroad, including my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.
         So we're all pretty much on the same economic plain.
         There wasn't too much difference between anyone.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were not integrated at that time, which was just a way of life.
         We didn't think of it as right or wrong, it was just the way things were.
         The biggest prejudice that we saw exercised at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that lived out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> were called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and they were brought into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on a bus, and they were grouped together in a class.
         They had to come earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and had to stay <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later in the afternoon</TIMEX>, and most of them were poor, because if you tried to farm in the sand hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, it was pretty hard to make a living.
         The soil is not particularly fertile.
         The freedom that we had as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is unheard of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         There was nowhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that you couldn't ride on a bicycle or walk, as long as you told your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> where you were going and you were home by dark.
         I wish that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, growing up in a different age where they didn't have this kind of safety and where everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> didn't look out for them, could have had this experience of this much freedom.
         To be able to go into the woods on the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and play without anybody worrying about me was a wonderful gift.
         And we had time to explore and imagine and do things, without adult supervision, which were totally innocent and great fun.
         
         There were many interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in this small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of whom lived across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from me.
         They were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lann</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>.
         These were identical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> who had dressed alike probably since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the</TIMEX>, they day they were born.
         By the time I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, they were well into middle age and were the most incredibly nosy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         They went to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> we went to, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Methodist</ENAMEX>, and they sat on a certain pew and woe be unto the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who sat, that chose to sit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lann</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>' pew.
         They watched everybody's coming and going when we, we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on the street became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>.
         They could tell you who everyone was dating and, if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, whether or not you got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goodnight kiss</ENAMEX> under the porch light and probably reported it at every bridge table they sat at for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several weeks</TIMEX>.
         Probably my most memorable occasion with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lann</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> was when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was very adamant about never telling her age.
         She was a good deal older than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought she was and she just didn't ever want that to be made public.
         She had made me promise that when she died that her age would not be put in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>.
         She had been with us during her last illness, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six or eight weeks</TIMEX>, where we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, and died there.
         When we came home for the funeral we had not been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> and here come the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lann</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> words out of their mouths, or out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them's mouths and their names were <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, and I never knew who was who, so I don't know who asked the question.
         The first thing one of them asked was, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kitty</ENAMEX>'s age was not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, how old was she?"
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kitty</ENAMEX> didn't tell her age when she was alive and I just don't think we're going to start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>."
         They were not even put off and did not even slow down.
         The next thing they wanted to know was I going to sell the things in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and how much did I want for the mirror above the fireplace.
         It, I guess it was somewhat reassuring even then, that it didn't matter that they didn't express sympathy, but that some things never change and always stay the same.
      
   
