
   
   
      
         ( ) I hope it come out well.
      
      
         Well, we will tell a story about the, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chattanooga</ENAMEX>, where they had been raised in a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sequatchie Valley</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX>.
         Uh so they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and they would go back and forth and visit and drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chattanooga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> and back.
         Now it takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five hours</TIMEX>; used to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a day and a half</TIMEX>, I suppose.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, were coming back, coming down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, uh they ran into some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and evidently hit a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and drove them back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> some distance, and when they go home from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, coming back through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, they got out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, uh dead up against the radiator of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         So naturally they got out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, took the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, and plucked the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, and boiled, uh, it, and cooked it, and had it for supper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>.
         
         The other is a story about our history of, I was married, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX> and she seemed a quiet young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> from well-reserved family <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Presbyterian</ENAMEX> heritage.
         And later in life I found that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> when he was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> rode a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>.
         And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> people that rode <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> were probably more rambunctious sort.
         He had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> out in CA, and so he rode his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> up to CA, um, not sure but maybe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> area.
         And there he went in search of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>.
         His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> had been into some kind of mischief and had been put in jail.
         He was serving on what we used to call chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> and take your leg, put a clip around it and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> a ball on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one end</TIMEX> and then give you a shovel or rake or a pick he'd go out and maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>.
         Well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> found where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> was located and where he was working So in an opportune time he rode his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and got his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> to hop on the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and they headed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         And so, he helped his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain gang</ENAMEX> and after they got back in NC his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> became sick, and within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three months</TIMEX>, uh died from tuberculosis.
         And that's a story of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> side of family not a story from my side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RECORDING PAUSED THEN RESUMED</ENAMEX>
      
      
         In the early part of.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         To, uh, that didn't have orphanages and things and so when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would die or someone couldn't take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         They would, uh, give them to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to raise.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, uh, adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         --by common law.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         He had some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, and they went to other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, but when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> died.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         My great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> did not have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> did not have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so they adopted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> and they had a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, uh, and my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was very industrious.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And so they farmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and then they set up a touring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and they bought <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and they would go up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX> and pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up and drive them down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         For vacation back and forth and it was a time when they didn't have glass windows in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they had what we called "isinglass" which was not plastic but was made out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\</ENAMEX>material <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">\\</NUMEX>.
      
      
         \\ Oh.
         \\
      
      
         That rolled up.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Or that they could hang a--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So they would drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> back and forth from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> and then he created a construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Went out and built the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> to go to a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> that was here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> at that time, uh, were in involved in laying the, putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Into a military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>.
         Uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> so they had a very large family
         they all worked on the farm
         and he educated his, most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> went to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade and quit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But his other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> went on through school and went to uh, uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\One\\</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\Uh</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> studied to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, there was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electrician</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         There was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, and so they had different positions but the tradition of my great, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> carried on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who was not very well education.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Was an industrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and he developed his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Made his own way in life and became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         He went to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade and quit, and yet when he, um was older, and in business--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         --he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school board</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Where he went to school, although he never graduated
         , and also the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         He was on those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
         
      
      
         He used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and say that he went to, uh--
      
      
         Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         No he, he would go they would ask him, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> would ask him what fraternity he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And he would always say "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hodskins</ENAMEX>" which was the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where he where went.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Up to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade.
         
      
      
         And they'd say, "What <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> letter is that?"
         and he'd say, "It's not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>."
         
         Hodskins fraternity.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         They kidded a lot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, played practical jokes on one another.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> bought a mule that wouldn't--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         --work for anyone but him.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And he would rent out the mule for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to plow their gardens and they would be so frustrated they would take the mule off to plow their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> and the mule wouldn't do anything.
         
         And they would bring him back home and fuss at him.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Then he would laugh and give them their money back
         .
         My great, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         --developed the farm they were using into a residential area.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And he was good at doing things with his hands and some business but he took a lot tried to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> and he couldn't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> because he built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> then financed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And uh he took the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mortgage.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And when the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> came along back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>'s, uh, all those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> were taken over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and he was left without anything and he was destitute.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         When he died he was very poor.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         But he had been fairly wealthy along the way.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         In that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> ( ).
      
      
         And he named the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> he named, the name, the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> was Thomasborough which he named after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         They had, uh, a large, uh, home on the peak of the hill.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And, uh, they would ring a big dinner bell.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would prepare for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and maybe they would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> come back and eat lunch behind the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Out on the grass so when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> died the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> came through.
         He took the dinner bell and carried it off to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he never used the dinner bell but it was a large bell like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> bell.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, they met together as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and they founded a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and they met in a place called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannery</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         They built a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> put in pots to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> with and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> could go there.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And cook their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and put them in cans and jars.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh- huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And so it was a cannery and they started meeting at the cannery.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX> and then later built, built the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
         It seems I don't know much about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s history tree because since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose not to tell stories I hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to preserve the history and tell the stories so since that everybody here could tell stories about their family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather great grandfather</ENAMEX> well.
      
      
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> his great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> lived in had a step.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Out front that was made of slate.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slate</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         And it that it's carved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1785</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         That it could have been well that's what was that's what's in it and that's our front step at the front door.
      
      
         Oh.
         You move it here the slate?
      
      
         Uh-huh you'll have to look at it.
         It's a step and it has in it is it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1785</TIMEX>?
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         Not quite sure.
      
      
         That would have been your great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         It would have been before me.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>, way back but it was at your great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> yeah.
      
      
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> burned down.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And that was one of the few things that uh.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>KT: A piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slate</ENAMEX> couldn't burn.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had it at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> just on the ground at a tree
         .
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So when we built this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we made our, we planned it so.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         It was the length of this piece of slate so that's from his great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in front of the it's like a yard square yard and at the end at the gate there is a pair of stone <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         And that's are very popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions</ENAMEX> seem to be the--
      
      
         The male and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">\\ female</ENAMEX> with the paw?
         \\
      
      
         \\ Yeah the male and the female<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">\</ENAMEX>\ yeah with a ball.
      
      
         A ball.
      
      
         Yeah One is, uh, holding the ball with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">\\</NUMEX> a paw.
         \\
      
      
         \\ A paw.
         \\
      
      
         The other is--
      
      
         Holding it.
      
      
         Having the ball in the mouth.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         Or it seems to be like it seems to be protecting the prosperity and also, uh, just a sign of peace and prosperity and dignity for the, the family I think we have long history but nobody tells the story.
         
      
      
         I'm sure they do ( ) much further back than our ancestors.
      
      
         That's because the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the</ENAMEX>, you remember, uh, I don't know whether you went to that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or not.
         That park very small but with a lot of, of handwriting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> handwriting carved on, on slate too you, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>you didn't go\\ to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         \\ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">In.</ENAMEX>
         ( ) \\
      
      
         Not it has a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         \\ ( )\\
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\ Lotus\\</ENAMEX> it should it should be called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus Park</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         \\ Oh yeah we did not go there.
         \\
      
      
         \\ We did not go.
         \\ because when we were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the</TIMEX>, the greenery and all was gone.
      
      
         Oh, oh yeah not the right time <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\ summer</TIMEX> should be the right time<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>.
      
      
         \\ So we did not go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lotus Park\\</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That's a that's a--
      
      
         I've seen \\ several pictures of it \\ in summertime.
      
      
         \\ Well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we went<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\ to the other night</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> took that picture and she, she published <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\ that article\\</TIMEX>.
      
      
         \\ Newspaper.
         \\
      
      
         \\In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> \\ we saw that.
      
      
         Yeah in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX> that is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">600 and 72</TIMEX> or something like that it's even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> more year
         .
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more thousand
         but nobody tells a story about that it's just not the tradition anymore.
      
      
         Well I think part of that is when you had the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural Revolution</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah I , I think so because--
      
      
         So many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't want to \\ let their history be known.
         \\
      
      
         \\ So many is feudal <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX> because a lot of things like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were saying is the symbol of feudalism because it protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> or empress--
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         In some things so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just choose not to tell stories it seems that as soon as, uh, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is was established, everything should take a new look and--
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         We just a cut off and say bye, bye to the history.
         
      
      
         Ooh I loved hearing the stories of the emperors though.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And all the concubines.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concubines</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wives</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
      
   
