
   
   
      
         Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Afternoon</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I understand that you are interested in some stories that I heard as a very young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, thinking of some of them now uh, one of them was uh, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Bears"</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mama Bear</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa Bear</ENAMEX>, and uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby Bear</ENAMEX>, and of course they struggled a long competent from each other.
         I heard that story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX>, and it is, uh, it has stuck with me.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, also another one was uh, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Raven</ENAMEX>," the poem "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Raven</ENAMEX>" uh, that we read in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh, we had to determine what it was about, and um, it wasn't easy at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for us to do that, and that, that story or poem went something like this, "Once upon a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> dreary, while I pondered, weak and weary, over many a quaint and forgotten lore, while I nodded, nearly napping, suddenly there came a tapping, as if some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gently rapping, rapping at my chamber door, it is some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> I said only this, and," uh, "nothing more."
         Of course the story went on for several pages.
         And we were to tell what it was about and uh, and uh, I don't think any of us in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> really came up with the answer.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teacher</ENAMEX> finally told us that it was, it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> did not uh, all they
         told were some stories but, but they usually talk about past experiences uh, when they were growing up uh, when they were courting, and uh, during their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX> of marriage, and uh, this kind of thing.
         I can remember uh, some of those stories now, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would tell the story of a my uh, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> sitting in the door of living room, when uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> would go to see her, before they got married and, and of course she would sit there until they leave, and sometimes she would act as though she was sleeping and got rather quiet, she would ( ).
         In other words, I went to the conclusion that there was strict supervision of, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> uh, while they were under the influence of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh,</ENAMEX>
         I would like to tell you about some traveling that I've done.
         I've been to uh, to counseling conferences at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>, no it was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan State University</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Lansing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, and the purpose of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> visits was a conference on counseling <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
         And, of course, the goal of this, uh, these sessions was to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to become more familiar with uh, some of the uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> and problems that uh, they may have due to language uh, new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and ability to uh, interpret what's happening around them.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we had a lot of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and we had representation from uh, a large number of different ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and uh, this proved to be very beneficial, and the most important thing to me was while I was there I read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a</TIMEX>, a book that listed scholarships that have been listed and given out by the ( ) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, and they listed uh, a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan State</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> as uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who had served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> for uh, the proposals that were sent.
         So, immediately, as soon as possible, rather, I got on the phone and I called over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justine Morrow School</ENAMEX> and I got a chance to talk with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> who knew about the uh workings of ( ) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundations</ENAMEX> and grants.
         I went in to conference with them, and I went over to uh, talk with them in person and explain to him what I wanted to do and showed me how I could incorporate the mandates of uh, scholarship that I was trying to get, the fellowship.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, and to a study uh, an experience related event.
         So it boiled down and I ended up working on uh the national design of uh, experiences that would help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> make the transition from rural to uh, to larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> and of course I based that on the basis of high percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who left the area after college and went to larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> many of them succeeded more than we would like to.
         I guess basic problems in the transition from uh, small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and rural areas to uh, the large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
         So, I wrote this proposal to do this and I got an interview from one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and I met him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greensboro</ENAMEX>, he interviewed me.
         In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four weeks later</TIMEX>, I was notified that I had received, which was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> of study at uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple University</ENAMEX> and it offered a stipend of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000</NUMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, this was quite helpful uh, to me and also uh, while I was there I received a grant to uh, improve minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> on uh, predominately minority campuses which was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advancement of Education</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personnel</ENAMEX>, and of course this was given out on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different campuses, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowie, Coppin, Livingstone</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth City State</ENAMEX> uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and maybe one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others and we would, they would send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> for study and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> would return for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> would stay and by doing this uh, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was able to get in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> residency and continue studies.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, by uh, taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least one semester</TIMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> with continuous education and of course uh, returning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that were taken off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> when we return to our respective campuses had to be approved and they sent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> to these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> to uh, interview us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> as to the progress that uh, we were making toward the uh, plan of study that we had made.
         OK uh, so guess you've decided by now that, that I did not have it easy growing up, in fact I did not expect to get the opportunities that I received but by making necessary contacts, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX>, and uh, meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were movers and shakers and could influence my career, I was able to build on that and uh, and to get a terminal degree at uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Education</ENAMEX>, which helped me when I returned to my own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> to move from counseling to uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Science Education</ENAMEX>, and uh, study in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society professor</ENAMEX> moving into the position of professorship uh, with tenure before I left.
         So uh, these are some good things that I think I uh, happen to good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         There is a book I've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> lecture upon and I've read some of it myself, Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Things Happen to Good People</ENAMEX>?
         And this is true, everybody does not uh, deserve unfortunate things that happen to them.
         But it is my philosophy that a lot of good things happen to uh, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that more than likely they will happen to good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, because they will be on the right track.
         Now, um, uh,
         these, these ideas have stuck with me through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and I guess there is a combination of stories that I've heard, speeches that I've heard, and uh, and of course books that I've read.
         But I remember when I was in college at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&T State University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.O. Kerrington</ENAMEX> speaking uh, and he used for a subject that for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> open its own way ( ).
         And he went on to say that high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> chooses the high way, the low <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> chooses the low way.
         And in the midst, is the misty flats which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose, and then he went on to talk about the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> being crowded uh, the low <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> meeting destruction, and disappointment, tragedy.
         But, the high <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> leading to success and opportunities and even then, though we were quite young, he challenged us it seemed to get through that if we selected the high <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that benefits had the possibilities of being numerous and sometimes when I'm out alone, when test and trials come, those words come to me,
         a group of words were uttered by ( ) that we were expected to learn and we were expected and required in high school to learn poems, to read poems and try to interpret poems that we could think of, and one of them was by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kipling</ENAMEX>, which was "If" and I don't recall all of it now, but it went on to say that "if you can dream and not make your dreams your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, if you can think and not make your thoughts your aim, you can meet with triumph and disaster.
         Treat those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">imposters</ENAMEX> just the same" and it goes on the say that if you can do all these things, yours is the world and all that is in it.
         And what is more that you will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in life.
         ( ) That was meant to be nonexistent language at that time.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, so that has been a source of inspiration to me.
         Sometimes when I might have a, have exploded, used other approaches, I sought to keep my head when it seemed like everybody else was not thinking at the moment.
         What inspires <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> individual uh, may inspire another and may inspire something else.
         These, these are things that, that I would like to share with and I will tell you look at about my background.
         Let's see, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 some years</TIMEX>, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> uh, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> and uh, I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and have always wished that I had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> so that I can understand maybe girls a little bit better than I do.
         Ladies but, uh, that's the way it came out.
         We were a loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         We did a lot of, most things together, worked together, we grew up in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> and we worked together, we ate together, we uh, went shopping together.
         We went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> together and uh, that bonded us to the extent that we have remained relatively close though gone our separate ways to different parts of country uh, because of that early loving and care, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.
         We were taught and soon acquired being concerned about each, each other.
         Played with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, grew <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>.
         This has helped me uh, as I've gone out on my own to be able to grow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and find enjoyment and relaxation, working in that area when I can find time to do so.
         I would not want to get anyone to cut my grass and thought they would do it free because I enjoy doing it myself.
         I did go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>.
         When I graduated from uh, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple University</ENAMEX> as a present for my graduation.
         I spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> there, I visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>, I met some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
         I got an opportunity to uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with them.
         Which they would go out into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, I think they called it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> I spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one weekend</TIMEX> there I had a chance to taste the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>, uh, to sleep under the uh, net, see little bit of a cock fight.
         To go to the swimming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> and to make um, very beautiful pictures.
         And I found uh,
         I found everybody was very warm toward uh, me as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know why I would do that by myself.
         I went by myself, basically without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, in a tour <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and my visit after I got there.
         I didn't have any problems except uh, when I was getting ready to leave it was in the monsoon season.
         It was raining very hard.
         When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> to take me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> I had my pull off my shoes and socks and wade halfway up my legs to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.
         Once I got to there, I dried them up and put them on.
         It wasn't very long before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was in and we headed back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> through the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX> and laid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> and uh, back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norfolk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VA.</ENAMEX>
         So, that I shall always cherish and it helped me to understand other cultures and helped me to appreciate the uh, opportunities that I had in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I hope to return to work uh, the in an embassy level position with some of those that would go on the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and so forth.
         But uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iranian Crisis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> crisis, took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> after that and I was never able to get that, that off, but I had a vision, I had a desire to return again.
         Well, never done anything like this before but I hope that I said something like that uh, will help you to understand what it is like to grow up in uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and uh, the values that are perpetuated are taught, by good, well-thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and the love and concern for each other that is expressed in many ways.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, nobody, nobody had lost to make us treat each other right.
         But at that time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were put on a pedestal and treated with the highest degree of respect and they were devout and loving to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and they didn't feel anybody was putting something on them and becoming unnecessarily agitated uh, because somebody didn't do something according to term.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we had ( ) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> was a happy place, place for play, we had limited supervision at a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> basically uh, loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, primarily; they visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>.
         And sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> went to.
         So, they saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in non-academic settings as well as in academic settings.
         They knew the parents and of course they had the confidence of the parents and um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> tried to do the right things because they did not want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to tell um, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on them.
         Because if they did, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wouldn't curse the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> out, she, she would penalize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in some way and um, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> didn't even have to go through that because they did the right thing because it was the right thing to do.
         And never heard of fights, well we had some little fist fights but not with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing uh until very recently in the area I grew up and I still haven't heard of it happening there, but I've heard of it happening in other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
         But uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spent a lot of time at that time with um, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         I think this is, this is the key and missing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX>, many of them are busy working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX>.
         They have other problems, they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> while they are young.
         They want to socialize and many times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> left to fend for themselves and to make choices and of course they fail to make the proper choices.
         Role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, certainly are needed in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and uh, in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> also uh, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> mirror what they hear and what they see.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, and if they see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> doing some other things they we, accuse them for, uh, they figure that this is cool.
         These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> become their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, and uh, they try to emulate them.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, one final thing that I must mention is religion was more of an important factor in the lives of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when I was a teenager.
         Growing up, almost everybody went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> went with them and it sure didn't make them perfect, but it seem to uh, place some fear in their minds, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I think have no fear, even fear of death.
         They think they're going to come back, it's some temporary vacation and they don't realize when they use violence or they when they overdose how permanent it is.
         So if we don't, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have different tendency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and religions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hinduism</ENAMEX>, ( ), Christianity and then you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atheist</ENAMEX>.
         But if we don't use any of those, uh, we need something that can cause us to think and let us know that we are not really masters of our own fate, captains of our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>, but uh, that we are dispensable, that we are passing through here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short period of time</TIMEX>.
         It's important to make our mark in the sand and one way to do it certainly is to live a decent life and uh, if we can do that and add education competencies and skills that we can help lift someone else then uh, we would come to the end of the road with joy and happiness I think uh, saying that we have helped to make the world better.
         Thank you.
      
   
