
   
   
      
         OK, this is my second interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Wentz</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
         He is also living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX>, but he's originally from, but, um, I mean
         , he's living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, sorry but he's originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buckhannon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX>.
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX>, um, what was it like growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buckhannon</ENAMEX> for you?
      
      
         Buckhannon was uh, uh, a very small and close-knit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, what I enjoyed the most growing up was, uh, was the college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>.
         It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesleyan College</ENAMEX> and that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>, that was my own, the place where I spent so much of my childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">playtime</ENAMEX> and, uh, running through the different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, having a free reign, going and coming as I pleased almost, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean of the College</ENAMEX>.
         And, and everybody knew me so nobody really tried uh, to uh corral me, so I was sort of free to go and do what I wanted, you know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were open.
         And uh, just uh, using that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> to, um, have war games and, and do all kinds of adventurous, uh, you know, hide and seek times and things like that with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>; a lot of roller skating, a lot of raking leaves in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> and to making leaf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and all kinds of things like that is uh, very memorable.
      
      
         OK
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, what was it, the, what were some, what are some of the main things that you remember about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesleyan</ENAMEX>?
         I think his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandfather Schoolcrafts</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandfather Schoolcraft</ENAMEX>.
         Sorry.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, some of the things that I remember is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that, uh, we would go into a lot.
         He had one of those old-fashioned, uh, recorder machines that, uh, had a cone on it where the needle would imprint your voice onto a cylinder cone.
         I don't know the technical name for the machine now.
         But, uh, I would always hide is his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> a lot in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, you know, or maybe he put me in there for disciplinary reasons.
         I don't know, I just remember being in there a lot.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>, and um, they were always nice, and, um, it was just a fun thing to see his name on the door and to know that he was an important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but he was also my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, Thank you.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckhannon</ENAMEX> is a place that you will ever want to return to live in the future?
         And, why or why not, or why did you like living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> so much?
      
      
         As far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Buckhannon</ENAMEX> being a place I would want to retire in or retire back to, uh, I don't see that in the future to me.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, not that it's not a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, there are a lot of good memories and so forth there.
         It's more of a place in my life now that I like to visit, um, I don't see the change in it that I do in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         As far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, I don't see the change, um, and maybe the change is something that I enjoy and, uh, that's why I sort of tend to think that if current change, intend to think I'll be retiring, um, in, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> or TN.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Someplace</ENAMEX> like that, that is more south.
         But, I enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> and I enjoy going back and meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and uh,
         stirring up memories.
      
      
         OK, um we're certainly not doing anything for promoting tourism for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         But uh, with my last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> interviews, but I digress, anyway.
         
         ( ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, um, do you remember going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Audra State Park</ENAMEX> a lot when you were a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenager</ENAMEX>, and if so, what kinds of things would you do there, including snake hunting, drinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, etc?
      
      
         Jess, I never hunted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX> because I don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we did see them in the water occasionally and screamed and yelled and ran, you know.
         There was the occasional bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> consumed, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, around the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, um.
         I'm glad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> are gone, way gone.
         But, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Audra State Park</ENAMEX> was a fun place, we would get on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> and in our teenage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before we could drive and that was a good <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-11 miles</NUMEX> over hill and dale to get there and we would definitely ride our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> there and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, even walk, uh hitch hike, and walk the railroad tracks which cut the distance down considerably, just to, uh, spend a day in the water and, uh, hunting, uh, you know, exploring, and uh, just enjoying seeing new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you never saw before.
      
      
         OK, um,
         , do you remember any ghost stories or scary stories, from uh,
         around the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buckhannon</ENAMEX>?
         Or Audra?
         Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Sago</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Or come up with a different question.
         No I don't remember any scary stories, because I don't believe in scary stories.
         And there weren't any really, except <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">headless</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> that would come out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> on certain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of the year</TIMEX> and throw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> at you!
         
         If you were walking the road <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Yes, I think that's a favorite for lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, oh, I, um asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> the same question because we are getting ready to move into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a new century</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX>, what is your fav,
         what is your favorite movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> and why?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound of Music</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Put that on pause.
      
      
         My favorite movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ Well, a few of them, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         Would be, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Here to Eternity</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I did like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Creature</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black Lagoon</ENAMEX> when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
         That was one of the scariest movies I ever saw.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mummy</ENAMEX>, because that was a good one too.
         I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>.
         I liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Werewolf</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> made me see all these scary things that's why I'm warped and hairy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      
      
         What is a favorite movie since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 30</TIMEX> or above?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my favorite movie uh, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 30</TIMEX>, I sure do like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX>, before I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>.
         Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 30</TIMEX> I guess it would have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiddler</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX>, I love that movie.
         I also enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um, Scarlet Pimpernel and Hook</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> Beauty.
      
      
         
         OK.
         We all understand why you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scarlet Pimpernel</ENAMEX> because
         it was such an intriguing story of
         revolutionary proportions, but why do you identify so much with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> plight portrayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fiddler</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, well my favorite part was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staircases</ENAMEX>, one going up and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> coming down, or there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> actually, one going nowhere, in between.
         
      
      
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX>, come on, you're making no sense at all.
      
      
         I know I'm at the no sense time of this interview.
         I don't make any sense now.
         What do you want me to say?
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         Fiddler on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX>, I like the story, I like the fact that-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         Oh yeah, I like old what's his face's voice, I like to sing like he does.
         I like the song, I like his beard, I like his prayer shawl.
         And um, I like the fact that, um, it's a wonderful story about the some of the traditions, some of the type of holocausts that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had to go through living in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and at that period of time and, um, just, uh, just, uh something in my heart, that, uh, maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> roots from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> back or something that, uh, tends to make me feel the way I do about the movie.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, being um, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> born again myself, I have that tendency to uh, know about the plight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and sympathize with them.
      
      
         OK, thank you.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Um Dad</ENAMEX>, we're getting close to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has had such a fun time the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX> talking about shopping on the Internet.
         In this new age of technology with e-mails, websites, um, downloading this and that, do you feel overwhelmed with those kinds of terms?
         Um do you feel like you are able to get on a computer and understand it?
         Or does it sort of scare you?
      
      
         It sort of scares me, I am so confused.
         That's all I can say, that was a horrible question.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>, did you think that was a horrible question?
      
      
         No.
      
      
         I thought it was.
         I mean-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ Do you like computers?
         I mean you're going to, you are opening a new business-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ I am computer illiterate, so I don't have a like or dislike for them because I don't know what they can do for me.
         \\
      
      
         \\ You're getting a new retail business started and-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         And someday I'll like computers.
      
      
         Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sell a lot more on the Internet.
         Do you think that with this business, um, you're going to have to learn how to do it-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ Sure.
         \\
      
      
         \\ And become acquainted with the-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ Sure.
         \\
      
      
         Internet, where you can sell your tree <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
         That is water from the made from the maple.
      
      
         \\ Squeezed from the might maple.
         Squeezed we are talking hand squeezed.
         Milked from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         \\ It's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of a kind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>.
         Anyway-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ My hands hurt.
         \\
      
      
         \\ Straight from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX>.
         So there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good thing about WV we can talk about-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         We got strong hands.
         Milking them <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Okey-dokey.
         \\ Um, we-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ How much did you say you were going to pay me for this?
         \\
      
      
         You're not getting paid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>.
         OK, um, what, uh, what is your favorite show of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> and why?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> show of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX>, what do you think about that?
         \\
      
      
         No, I like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Archie Bunker All in the Family</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith</ENAMEX>.
         That's my favorite time of growing up.
         I can remember it very well.
         In fact I was humming the tune <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         ( )
      
      
         I'm not a bigot.
         But I enjoyed the TV series.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         I'm sitting looking at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kitten</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cordelia</ENAMEX>, who I've named after a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in a TV show, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Buffy the Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX>.
         Um what do you think about the rise of occult, occultic matters or TV shows, movies about the occult.
         Why do you think they're becoming so trendy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> basically is a spiritual being <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and he is always trying to get to the root problems of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> and his surroundings.
         God creates in the spirit, creates in the natural and, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> does the same, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s trying to find his creativity of the spiritual realm and I feel he's just, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and age is getting closer and closer to end times, as far as I believe, the word of God says, and so the days are drawing closer to where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will be harboring more and more blackness in his heart, it will prevail.
         And, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will be trying to find, uh, you know, the cause of life, so I don't know.
         It's just, um, it's a deep subject to talk about, a very broad subject to talk about, but being spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>, I guess the shortest way of saying it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX>'s fantasy and tendency is to go into the occult, into black magic and the dark side because that's where he dwells and that's where his heart is, uh, settled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and until you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and know the true meaning of life and your purpose you're always searching in the dark side for the, the meaning of reality and the meaning of life, always trying to find out about the future.
         I remember when I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, I was always trying to, uh, find out about the future because of the fear that it brings.
         But, uh, by knowing the Lord those fears are all removed.
      
      
         OK, and also we think goodness for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy</ENAMEX> that we have her to fight back against these evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         Especially the vampires and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>.
         Now--
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         Um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last question <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, um
         , what is your favorite time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and why?
         Do you like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> or fall and why?
      
      
         What's my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> choice?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hum</ENAMEX>, my favorite time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
         I enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> and I enjoy fall, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> is the best.
         I'm a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         I love warm weather, I love the colors that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> brings.
         And uh, life, I just enjoy everything is alive and at its peak in the summertime.
         And, um, my favorite time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> because, uh, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> I really enjoyed myself more during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> I wasn't a, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that got into sports so it wasn't like a fall thing or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> type mentality but, uh, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> sports, so um, I just enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
      
      
         OK, I lied and said that was my last question.
         I have a few more actually.
         \\ Um.
         -- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ Repent!
         \\
      
      
         I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> what she, if she could remember meeting you in junior high and why she fell in love with you.
         
         Can you give me some feedback on your first encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Stonicker</ENAMEX> in junior high or high school?
      
      
         My first encounter with her was by phone, when I called her up to ask her out for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>.
         He was a dweeb.
         And so I call her up knowing that she probably wouldn't go out with him, hoping she wouldn't.
         But, and she didn't hallelujah!
         And so I asked her out and she said, "Yes!"
         And that was my first encounter.
         My second encounter was kissing her rosy lips.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>!
         
      
      
         Oh forget it, I got overwhelmed by my first encounter.
      
      
         OK, and also one last question and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> I promise this is the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         What do you think about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?
         
         Since he's not here to defend himself.
      
      
         What do I think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?
         Well, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, everybody I've ever met that we've talked to about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, I've right from the start said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> was the one I would have picked out for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
         Of all the jerks that she ever paraded through my living room, or some of them wouldn't even parade through my living room, they just would stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because they knew better.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he had to be the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, best looking, the most appealing for her.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> he's blooming, but, uh, I always say that to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that he would have been the one I'd pick and I'm happy and very glad that I have him for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">in-law</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, and we're sure that he appreciates that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, once again that was an interview with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Wentz</ENAMEX> who is originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buckhannon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> and now resides in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
      
   
