
   
   
      
         OK.
         This is the first interview for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4260</TIMEX> with my step <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Wentz</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         
         Sorry, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> grew up in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Buckhannon</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>, what did you like
         think about living there?
         What did you think about living there?
         Sorry.
      
      
         Well, I, when I was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> I didn't really think a whole lot about it, except that was my home.
         I loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that I lived in when I was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, and it was very small, and I lived on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayette St.</ENAMEX>, and it had a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">maple tree</ENAMEX> in the front and I liked to climb it, I was a tomboy.
         So one of my favorite things do to was, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roller-skate</ENAMEX> and climb <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.
         I had a little, I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, at the time when I was smaller I only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> because my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> hadn't been born yet.
         So my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> and I, and the next door <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> would play, and I guess, really <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckhannon</ENAMEX> was like a very wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to grow up in because there wasn't a lot of crime it was just very safe, a very safe place.
      
      
         How long have you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nine years</TIMEX>.
      
      
         
         OK,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you're now married to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that you dated in high school.
         How did you meet him in high school?
      
      
         Well, actually I met him in junior high.
         And I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade and he was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade.
         And, um, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> what we did was we would go to the gym and everybody would eat their lunch in the gym on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bleachers</ENAMEX> and they would have, they would play records and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would dance.
         Of course, you know, I was very skinny, I was cute but not the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were looking at, and, I but I used to watch your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> dance with all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and he was a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX> and I really liked him.
         Used to sit and look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> dance and I'd listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beetles</ENAMEX> songs.
         I would look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> and I had picked him as the one I'd always wanted to dance with and it wasn't until we got into high school that he noticed me.
         And I was in a
         a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> show with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> and we did a modern dance to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink Panther</ENAMEX>," and after that my phone didn't stop ringing for awhile.
         And your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> called me and asked me if I wanted to go out with is best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rigger</ENAMEX>, and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never</ENAMEX>."
         This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was not my type and so he said, "Would you like to go out with me?"
         and I said, "Yes, I would," and so that's when we started dating.
      
      
         Why did you like him?
         Besides the fact that he could dance?
      
      
         Well, he was very handsome and I, um, loved his smile, had a beautiful smile.
         And he was, you know, just tall and thin and there was just something about him that I found very, very attractive.
         And he was funny and I liked to laugh.
         Well we just, I really fell kind of madly in love with him,
         at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>.
      
      
         What do you miss most about not living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buckhannon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Nothing.
         
         As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> I loved it, but as I grew up there just really wasn't a whole lot that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckhannon</ENAMEX> had to offer other than the fact that, you know, was where my memories of childhood are and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
         And I like going home to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and seeing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but as far as wanting to live there, I wouldn't.
      
      
         OK, I think y'all have a phone call.
         Let's pause for a moment.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RECORDING PAUSED THEN RESUMED</ENAMEX>
      
      
         OK, we're back.
         What are some funny words that you first heard in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> that you'd never heard before that made you laugh?
      
      
         Well, I guess the first funny world I heard was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX>!"
         And I couldn't figure out what everyone was talking about.
         You know, they'd say "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, how you doing?"
         \\ And you know, we always say-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hay</ENAMEX> is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         Or "hi" or "hello," and so that, that, this was kind of funny to me.
         Another one of the things that everyone says here, you'll say something to them and they'll say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>."
         They say, "well" a lot, it's just a, I don't know what, something that they use to say when they don't know what else to say--
      
      
         It's a hesitation.
      
      
         A hesitation.
         Yeah, well, and, uh, another interesting word was "picking".
         I went right into the school system and I was teaching and, um, it was a little awkward at times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were, they would tease, and instead of saying, you know, I'm teasing, they would say-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ Hello <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>!
         \\
      
      
         They would say, "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wentz</ENAMEX>," and a, you know, another thing they'd make syllables where there isn't even any syllables at all.
         They would, they would make syllables, for instance, my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wentz</ENAMEX>.
         It was, "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">We-ntz</ENAMEX>, just picking Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">We</ENAMEX>-ntz."
         And "ill" to me that is when you're sick, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I was just really ill," which means they were upset or angry or something like that.
      
      
         OK, what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sundrop</ENAMEX>?
         Do you like it?
         Does--?
         Is it a drink of your choice?
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here seem to think it is
         it's a, what's it called,
         drink of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, well, I, you know, I think it's OK, but it's nothing that I was, that I would want everyday.
         That or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cheerwine</ENAMEX>.
         Those, those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> that I don't crave.
      
      
         OK, Oh, what do you think is, uh,
         best, movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>?
         Since it's almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>.
         
      
      
         
            Oh, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound of Music</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Why?
      
      
         Why?
         Well, I guess I, well I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Andrews</ENAMEX>, and I like, I really love the music that's in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound of Music</ENAMEX>.
         I like the whole background, the plot.
         And everything.
         And, um, it just makes me feel good.
         In fact, I watched it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past Christmas</TIMEX>, because, I hadn't seen it in awhile, and I loved it so much, that I had to watch it over and over again.
      
      
         OK, um, since we are talking about a movie based in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
         Where are your ancestral roots, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
         My last name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stonicker</ENAMEX>.
         And, um,
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> was also from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
         So there's, there's sort of a mixture there.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, her last name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corley</ENAMEX>.
         And she was, I think.
         -- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>?
         \\
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>, yeah, so I guess it would be kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you miss your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> who lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buckhannon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX>?
         And what are some special qualities about him that you can talk about?
      
      
         
         Yeah, I miss my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.
         I miss my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
         But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is in heaven.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is a very, very special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         He, um, he grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> and he, um, played football when he was in high school and he went right into the service and he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX>, he was a medic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.
         And he was over in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
         In fact, I was just talking to him this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thanksgiving</TIMEX> about some of the things that he went through when he was in the service and, and traveling across the sea on these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> that had flat bottoms and they would go way up in the, in the water and then smack down, you know, it was very rough.
         They left out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX> and went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, he said you would look out if you were up on deck and the waves, the swells were way up higher than, than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> itself and looked like you were going to drown.
         But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Mary</ENAMEX> was right beside to them.
         They were in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WACs</ENAMEX> were on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Mary</ENAMEX>, and, you know, they just had a smooth sailing trip when these poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, you know, they were just so sick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every day</TIMEX> because of the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> and everything.
         But I, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is, um, he's just a very sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         You know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s been gone for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>.
         And he has, he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81 years old</TIMEX>.
         And he takes care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> wonderfully.
         When we came home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> dinner he had everything prepared, had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> in the oven and everything ready.
         He's just a really fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81</TIMEX>?
      
      
         He's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81 years old</TIMEX>.
         
         He's a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driller</ENAMEX>.
         He drilled wells all of his life all over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KY.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         
         OK.
         That's nice.
         
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, did
         um where, where did you go to college at?
         And why did you want to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, ( ) I wanted to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> when I was little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> painting that I did that I really remember was a finger painting that I did of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my dolls.
         And it was just so exciting to me and I was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about five years old</TIMEX>.
         But I propped my doll up and I had my finger paints and I looked at her and I did this portrait of her and it was just really good to me, I'm sure to anyone else it was like, "Yeah right."
         But I wanted, that was just something that I really enjoyed doing.
         That and dancing.
         I wanted to be a ballerina.
         The ballerina part never came about, but I, I did go on to college and I, um, transferred a lot and ended up going to a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> which was kind of fun.
         I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall University</ENAMEX>, and I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, and I ended up graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> with a major in printmaking and a minor in art history and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> literature.
      
      
         Did you ever visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>?
         Because that is where he was, he grew up.
         And do, do you enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, you know, that's really funny, but I don't remember visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol Museum</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Did you know that was where he was from?
      
      
         No.
         But I didn't, I studied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX> briefly.
         I mean I didn't go an in-depth study of him or that type of art.
      
      
         I think he took his first art lessons at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Museum</ENAMEX>-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Mellon</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         \\ Yeah, whatever, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         \\ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Mellon</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         When he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and that's how he got interested in art.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-hmm.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But he, I think that his
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-hmm.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And they were like, lived in the nasty little section where all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> were and stuff.
         But anyway.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, who's your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well I really liked the Impressionists, I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renoir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Cassatt</ENAMEX>, I, um, loved studying all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
         I loved art history.
         I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelangelo</ENAMEX>'s sculptures and his paintings and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> era.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX> did the etchings and, you know, that was interesting to me because, you know, that's what I ended up doing, was printmaking.
         But I, I like the light and the pastels, colors that are in the Impressionists.
         
      
      
         What do you think about the current trends in art, modern art?
         Which some conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might consider offensive and disturbing?
         Especially the anti-religious art.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um-hmm</ENAMEX>, well art has always been controversial and has always reflected what is going on in the world.
         You know, and, um, so, you know, having studied art history, that doesn't, it doesn't shock me or surprise me that much.
         And I, you know, I don't like it, personally, because,
         you know, it does offend me, what, what I have seen, and I don't like the idea that we are giving the money to create extremely offensive art, but, um, again, that, that's, you know, is, art reflects what's going on and art is, is very spiritual regardless of whether its content says, you know, something about God or not, there, there has a very spiritual quality about it.
         It's very powerful
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, OK.
         I watched a special on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Rockwell</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and some consider him not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> but just an illustrator.
         What are your comments on that?
      
      
         
         Well, that is a, a statement that I've heard used in art a lot.
         I, personally, I was accused of being an illustrator, which it's interesting that I would even use the word "accuse" because it seems like there is a lot of prejudice in art and of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say is art with quotation marks around it.
         And, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Rockwell</ENAMEX> was a tremendous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.
         He was a, he was a, you know, he was a realist.
         And regardless of whether someone calls it illustrative or not.
         It, it is art and it is wonderful art and he has captured a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, you know, he captured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that, who you could look into their faces and you could tell everything about them.
         You know so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, in my experience, when I was in college, one of the things that I exp, you know, had to deal with, was other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s opinion of what art is, and especially my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> saying, "You need to be more cryptic," or "You need to be more esoteric, your art is too transparent or too happy."
         You know, well that's me.
      
      
         ( ) All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have to be suicidal in order to be considered brilliant, I'm so sick of that.
         Why does everyone have kill their selves or be moody, just to be considered a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well one of the things the art world is looking for is, you know, um, emotion.
         They want an emotion to be evoked, you know, when you look at something.
         Art, art whether it's writing or, or, um, drama or visual or music, you know, there's a term that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> used.
         It was catharsis, you know, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to exper, they want to experience something.
         And I guess even in writing, um,
         , there's so many unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world and it seems like, you know, when they read something and can relate to it then they get some kind of release or relief in their emotions by identifying with it and that could be why there seems to be such a demand for that sort of thing.
         And, uh, but, on the other hand, there's the happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, you know, and I am one of them.
         I'm just a happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and my art reflects that, and I think that I, you know, love to read stories that are written and everything that also, you know, have a good moral background to them, and something where you can learn something of value and virtue in it, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louisa May Alcott</ENAMEX>, you know, her work, I love her work.
         So, you know, there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> to that coin.
         We just have to find the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, thank you for your comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>.
         Again, her name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Wentz</ENAMEX> and she's my step <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> who lives a quick <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
      
   
