
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Female Voice TAPE 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDE A</ENAMEX>
      
      
         This interview is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Maurer</ENAMEX> interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Werth</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>, can you tell us what stories or book you remember reading as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Probably the most, uh, well-known books would be the, uh, uh, a series of books called, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>, and then it would give a name.
         For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meet Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meet Daniel Boone</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>, uh, things like that.
      
      
         Why were they special?
      
      
         Well I was always interested in biography as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, um, so I guess because they told me about things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>.
         I've always had, had an interest in history, so it was a chance to learn more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So it's, uh, it's the history, historical part and learning about the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that interested you the most?
      
      
         Probably the biography, you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the times they lived in.
      
      
         And what age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, what age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> were you?
      
      
         Umm, I don't know.
         I would probably say sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, maybe, uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Wow that young of an age you were interested in other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, huh?
      
      
         Oh yeah.
         I've always been interested.
         It's a, it was a good way to find out what was going on outside the world that I was living in.
      
      
         So do you remember any particular ones that you really liked, or anyone?
      
      
         No.
         I think they were just all interesting books, uh, you know, I had a whole collection them and I only got rid of them when I was in high school.
         Now I hear they're pretty valuable books.
         
         As usually the case.
      
      
         Yeah.
         That happens, yes.
      
      
         But, um, you know, they were interesting and they talked about the, not just the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, but they also talked about, um, you know, the times they lived in and things like that.
         Pretty nicely illustrated,-
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         OK.
         \\ Did you have-\\
      
      
         \\ -easy to read.
         \\.
      
      
         -special feelings when you read them, or-?
      
      
         Just tried to imagine what life was like in those times.
      
      
         Oh I see, so you would like-
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         -go into the imagination, go into the imagination of-
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         -this is what it must have been like being this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or living at that time or-
      
      
         Yeah, or knowing some things.
      
      
         -something like that?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         So, OK.
      
      
         No.
         Just, just generally.
      
      
         OK.
         So where, uh, was this?
         Was this-?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well home</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
         
         So, um
         , anything else you can think of for us?
      
      
         No.
         I just think they were just fairly well-illustrated, you know.
         Simple to read compared to some of the other stuff I was reading.
         But they were pretty simple to read.
      
      
         Oh, OK.
         Can you remember some, uh, any other stories that you might have read or stories your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, someone maybe in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, told you?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-</ENAMEX>
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Hi
         .
         Do you need the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah.BREAK
      
      
         Can you think of any stories that, um, that you remember from growing up or anyone in the family telling you?
         Anyone in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> telling stories?
      
      
         The only story I might remember would be, um, as I got older, um, you know, asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> what it was like, uh, living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> occupation, what it was like growing up before that, and that type of thing.
      
      
         So your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> came over here?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> did in `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         After the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was born here then?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was born here.
         So maybe asking her what it was like growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WW II</ENAMEX> or during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>, or that type of thing.
      
      
         Oh, I see.
      
      
         But as rule, storytelling was not something that I grew up with like some traditions and some cultures and some places there were-
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         -you tell stories about things, you have to ask for those, that information.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         Maybe because the memories were so pitifully painful.
      
      
         Right.
         Was it difficult?
         Do they, do they, uh, share about what their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> was like?
         What <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was like?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX> doesn't talk too much about what life was like, other than talking about how good times were before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>.
         But during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> he doesn't, he's got, a lot of stuff has been blocked out.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Because I imagine that life was pretty tough.
         Mom remembers a lot of stuff, but, uh, you know, details of everyday life, but, uh, she also remembers a lot about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX> and then the rationing during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> and things like that, but she doesn't go into much detail either.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         It must of have been pretty hard.
         That's all I can think-
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         -since it wasn't talked about.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Or still isn't talked about unless you pry it out of them.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And even then you don't get a full story.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Do they ever talk about good memories they had back then?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, they have some good memories but it's just not talked about, period.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Just, I, I didn't not grow up in a tradition where storytelling about life, you know, or heroics, uh, were talked about, or it just, you have to pry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s information, I guess, pull from their information.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, just don't go there, huh?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Yeah, yeah, I understand.
      
      
         I know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> freely talked about their, about exploits, you know.
         That's just, that's just not part of the family tradition, I guess.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, OK, all right.
         Is there anything else you'd like to say?
      
      
         No.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, just that, um, you know, that as far as, you know, stories, you know, most of the stories I, you know, if I remember anything it's about the books I read and stuff.
         But oral storytelling is not part of, you know, as I say, the family tradition.
      
      
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> didn't talk much around the dinner table about stories?
      
      
         Well we talked about what happened during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your day</TIMEX> and, you know, what happened at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, what happened at work, but as a rule, um, and maybe that's because, for, you know, from the time I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, um, you know, I didn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> living nearby, and aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh, OK.
      
      
         So-
      
      
         So that really made a difference?
      
      
         Yeah.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were both dead by that time, well before I was born, and so I never knew my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and there would have been stories, maybe, there.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, I moved away from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, who already, uh, I think he was already dead by that time, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was definitely, you know, way away and we didn't talk to her.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Un</ENAMEX>, o, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> may have talked to her once a week on the phone.
      
      
         Where did she live?
      
      
         In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, but we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> by this time so-
      
      
         OK, OK.
      
      
         So maybe, you know, it was just, you know, you know, when I would physically see her for a while, it was like once a year.
         But there was never any storytelling going on.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Until she got maybe much older, and then I started prying into the family history.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         But that was only because I was doing a research project in which you talk about things.
      
      
         OK.
         So do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, younger.
      
      
         Uh-huh OK.
      
      
         No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, good.
         Well, thank you for sharing your story with us.
      
      
         All right, thank you.
         Good luck on your project.
      
      
         Thanks.
      
   
