
   
   
      
         This is an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy White</ENAMEX>.
         Where were you born?
      
      
         I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How long ago?
      
      
         Hmph, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38 years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39 years ago</TIMEX>.
         
         I was there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>.
      
      
         So, you are a native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlottean</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Until I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaston County</ENAMEX>, which was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX>.
      
      
         I guess you pretty well seen that town grow up.
      
      
         I still work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         
         I still feel like I live there since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaston County</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only five minutes</TIMEX> next door to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What's changed the most about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> since you've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         ( )
      And add more.
         
         Didn't used to be so dangerous to drive and now it is very dangerous to drive.
         I don't think they should let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> drive anymore.
         Not until they're about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 19 years old</TIMEX>.
         I think they should have a learners permit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.
         
         We've had so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move in from everywhere.
      
      
         I guess you don't even recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> anymore it's changed so much.
      
      
         I recognize it because it changes with me each and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX>.
         Don't look like it used to.
         
      
      
         What where were you born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian Hospital</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'60</NUMEX>.
      
      
         
         Yeah.
         I was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> granddaughter born.
         There were a bunch of grandsons on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         So I was named after each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> liked "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tammy</ENAMEX>" and stuck it in the middle.
         So I had a real long name when I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade before I found out what my whole name was.
      
      
         What was your whole name?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Tammy Marie Watkins</ENAMEX>.
         I lay my head down on the desk and cried because I had to learn how to write a long name and everyone else's was short.
         I'd been writing "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Watkins</ENAMEX>."
         
         I could read and write before I went to school, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> had a lot of time to spend with me.
         My next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> wasn't born until I was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX>.
         [Long pause] The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were upset because I was way ahead of everybody else.
         
         They didn't know what to do with me.
      
      
         Like a misfit.
      
      
         And I got in trouble all the time.
         
         They still liked me though; they still helped me.
      
      
         What do you remember as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
         Tell me the story about the coat.
      
      
         Which one?
         The big furry blue coat?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         That was like in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> grade, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade.
         Blue was my favorite color.
         Everything I had was blue.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama and Daddy</ENAMEX> bought me a big blue furry coat for my birthday or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>.
         I don't know.
         Birthday and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> run together.
         Usually what I got for birthday was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> for birthday.
         Because my birthday was so close to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> I only got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> present.
         It was a big old ugly blue fur coat.
         I felt like a big blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">polar bear</ENAMEX>.
         So I hid it under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bushes</ENAMEX> on the way to the bus and pick it up on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         Same things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do now, except they pick out their own coats.
         They just change their mind after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.
         [Long pause] I was a tomboy.
         I only had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> to play with.
         
         When I was little I used to want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.
         
         When I grew up I wondered why?
         Why you want to be something that was so inhuman?
         
      
      
         Why do you say that?
      
      
         
         
         Well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s are all right, as long as they're your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         
         
         I still have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy friends</ENAMEX> than girlfriends.
         Even after all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
         
      
      
         Remember anything else as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
         
      
      
         
         Jumping off high <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
         Swinging a swing as far as it would go and jump out of it and see who could jump the farthest.
         Or, we'd take the swing and pull the swing out all the way around until it, until it dunked and we'd swing all the way around the top of it.
         We'd build playhouses out in the woods, tree <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> out in the woods.
         We dig a, we dug an underground cavern out of the mud <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and stole a bunch of stuff from all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around.
         We had carpet in there, and rugs, and furniture and everything.
         We played in it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> found out and then they had a fit, they said we could have smothered to death if it fell in or rained or anything.
         That was neat.
         You had to climb down in it.
         It looked real neat too it looked better than some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.
         Dug it out little by little, made it bigger.
         Of course it probably wasn't as big as I remember it to be.
         
         I used to love to go up to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aunt Sandra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and she'd let us run wild through the neighborhood.
         When I was at home with, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> wouldn't even let me out of the yard.
         They watched me like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra</ENAMEX> was scared to death when it was time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> to come pick me up because I'd be muddy and dirty from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> to toe.
         
         Mama hated it that I was a tomboy.
         
         She always bought me dolls and everything.
         She knew I didn't want dolls.
         They'd just sit there in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What about them <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>?
         Hum?
      
      
         Oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>.
         I don't, I don't really remember some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, but I remember more what she told me.
         I remember being and having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> all around.
         That was before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie</ENAMEX> was born.
         I was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX>.
         And there's pictures, pictures of me with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> said there was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that run through the neighborhood.
         And she said, she was always playing with me, that, and she said she never worried about them hurting me.
         She said that I was up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> or something and she told me to come to her.
         
         And she started, started pulling me or something, I don't remember exactly, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> circled her and snarled and growled at her and she got, backed back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         And I wouldn't come in because I knew I was going to get a whipping for climbing up in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
         And later, I guess I forgot and she knew I would.
         I guess she bribed me to come in with some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX> and, and then she tore my tail up.
         She said it still didn't stop me
      from hanging around with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> or anything she felt like they, because, protected me I could stay out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and she'd check on me like every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> and I was taken care of.
         She said nobody else would bother me either.
         Said never occurred to her that those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> might hurt me but they never did.
         Said I always had a gift for animals
      I guess because I was never afraid of them.
         Now that I'm older I've grown afraid of them and they can tell it.
         
      
      
         What about your secret garden?
      
      
         Oh yeah.
         I was, when I was in junior high, in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade.
      
      
         Hum.
         What happened?
      
      
         Went through, we'd ride <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> through the woods and everything.
         I loved to ride <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX>.
         Rode <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> for a long time until I was a big old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         And we went into the woods and there was bunch of vines that covered like a blanket.
         And I'd walk through those vines and it was real shady and cool.
         It'd be like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 or 15 degrees</NUMEX> cooler than it was outside.
         And there were big rocks and a nice creek, big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> rocks.
         I'd sit our there and read
      or whatever.
         It was just peaceful.
         And I took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX> out there one time and asked her if she'd spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with me.
         Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time because she always worked she didn't have much time to spend with us.
         That was after she left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daddy</ENAMEX>.
         
         I got her a bicycle; I borrowed a bicycle for her.
         She pushed it most of the way.
         She couldn't ride it.
         It hurt her legs.
         I couldn't understand that.
         I thought it was a whole lot easier to ride that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> than walking.
         Fixed us a picnic lunch and she brought a book and we went out there.
         And she still talks about that.
         She really liked it.
         She said it was really just as beautiful as I always said it was.
         It's gone now.
      
      
         Bulldozed over.
         A new project slapped up.
      
      
         I don't know who it belonged to.
         It was out behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That was over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">on Arrowood Road</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         No that was, um, that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntersville</ENAMEX>.
         When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daddy</ENAMEX> we went and moved out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntersville</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         For a little while.
         We used to go in the woods back by, back off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrowood Road</ENAMEX>.
         I lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Windsong Trail</ENAMEX> that's right across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> when we lived on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrowood Road</ENAMEX>.
         We didn't move very far that time.
         We'd go out there and pick blackberries and sell them, out in the woods.
         I had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine, he huffed a can of ( ) and died when he was camping out.
         And uh, one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> that was with him just got sick and ended up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
         [Long pause] I think everybody cried.
         
         He was a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> just don't know how easy it is to die.
      
      
         Well so huffing is nothing new, they did it when I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>.
         I didn't hear about it as much then as I do now though.
         
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he'd take up for, um, all the underdogs.
         So a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were sad.
         
         I hung around with, uh, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and, um, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and then later we, uh, had another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> join our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
         I hung around with them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to through</TIMEX> to high school.
         But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> and everything and we moved away and then moved back I still went to school with them.
         
         Kenny, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenny</ENAMEX>, huh
      .
         He died not too long ago on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Didn't you go up in the mountains for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> or something, with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One week</TIMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>.
      
      
         \\Where they live\\?
      
      
         \\ ( )\\ They lived in, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Mountain</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and then they moved to ( ) another mountain.
      
      
         That's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Uh huh.
         
      
      
         So you never did leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, did you?
      
      
         Um uh.
      
      
         I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> use to take y'all to the beach didn't he?
      
      
         Yeah, we went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> to the beach.
         That was the highlight.
         We went to the beach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX>.
         Go fishing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         What did you do up in the mountains?
      
      
         Everything.
      
      
         Did you make a quilt?
      
      
         No.
      
      
         Did you churn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No.
         They were more modern up there than we were down here.
         
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>.
         She had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that was about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debbie</ENAMEX>'s age.
         And she'd take me to, uh, not, not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, but there were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> she'd take me to a day <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> because she wanted me to play with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my age and she didn't have any.
         And she'd take me out shopping and buy me all kind of new clothes.
         She wanted a little girl
      and I was it.
         Because all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy cousins</ENAMEX> got to go up there and stay every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> too for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.
         And she said they about run her crazy.
         She said I was the only slow time she got.
         She said I'd help her and everything and I enjoyed helping her.
         Went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Did you ever go horseback riding or anything?
      
      
         Yes.
         
         I didn't go horseback riding up in the mountains.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> paid for my lessons down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         And then she couldn't pay for them anymore so I started working in the stables to continue then.
         It was <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> style, back riding.
         
         I used to skip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> during junior high and steal a pony and return it and go back home.
         Did that a lot.
         [Long pause]
      
      
         Remember anything else as a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I remember a lot of things I'm just not going to put it on this tape.
         
         
         Then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will hear it and then try to pull it too.
         
         I'm still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>, elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and junior high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         I see them about once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
         Some more often than that.
      
      
         Who was your best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> were my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> until I met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie</ENAMEX>.
         Angie, was, I've known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie</ENAMEX> as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>, but she was more into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> for other reasons than what I was and I was just not mature enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> yet except to play with.
         So she kind of bored me.
         She ended up having like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> later with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
         I really don't know.
      
      
         So I guess you haven't talked to her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Not since um, I had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>.
         I seen her the last time when I had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>.
         Not since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> was born.
         Worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP Oil</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Rd</ENAMEX>.
         , she used to come in there all the time.
         That was on the south side of town.
         We were raised on the south side of town.
      
      
         That side sure has grown up hasn't it?
      
      
         There are still parts over there I still don't recognize.
      
   
