
   
   
      
         This is a conversation between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Slavich</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fran Worthington</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 16, year 2000</TIMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, what, what would you like to talk about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?
      
      
         Oh, when I was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         And we'll begin at the beginning.
         I was born on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3rd, 1937</TIMEX>, which was shortly after the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36 years old</TIMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>.
         And I was an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, the reason being that, I know now, she was probably an RH Negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> because she had had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> stillborn, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> before I was born and miscarried in her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighth month</TIMEX>, when I was, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> before I was born.
         So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> told her she should never, ever try to have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
         And her comment was, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Watch me</ENAMEX>!"
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         So, she kept trying and got pregnant with me, and carried me to full term and so, since she was, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> were both much older, I was a terribly spoiled brat.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Because I was their only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and they knew I was going to be their only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and, within reason, I got just about anything I wanted that they could afford, I got.
      
      
         Oh wow!
      
      
         But, um, being an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was sort of a lonely life, but it was interesting, because I spent a lot of time with grown-ups.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was, never, ever knew her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
         He died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three months</TIMEX> before she was born.
         He was a railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>, and he was working on the, down on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pee Dee River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> and got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> and died.
      
      
         I never knew that.
      
      
         Yeah.
         So my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, whose name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances</ENAMEX>, raised her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all by herself.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, whose name was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius</ENAMEX>, she was named for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> since he died.
         Her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius</ENAMEX>, which in, I mean which was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s name.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         Her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Wellington Culbreth</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That's a very masculine name.
      
      
         Yeah, exactly.
         And she was the youngest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> died when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX>, so I never really, really knew her.
         But everyone called her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama Frank</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And that's where I got the name, \\"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mama Fran</ENAMEX>"\\ for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> to call me.
      
      
         Oh!
         I never knew that!
      
      
         Yeah.
         And I didn't think about it until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> started coming along and we were thinking about what to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it suddenly popped in my mind, that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s name was, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama Frank</ENAMEX>.
         And I was named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Jeanette</ENAMEX> for both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette</ENAMEX>, and she was, had died long before I was born.
         And neither one of my grandfathers were alive.
         So I never had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>.
         And I really missed that.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the</ENAMEX>, uh, next to the youngest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         So since he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> when I was born, all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first cousins</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> older than I was.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         So I would go out and see my second <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX>, not my first <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> because they were all old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as far as I was concerned.
         But when I was, I think one of my earliest recollections, was when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> and I went down to, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>.
         And I remember, going through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> where we stayed at with my bathing suit on and with one of those God-awful swim caps that everybody that you see when you look in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 40s</TIMEX> movies and it felt like I was in a vacuum when I was walking!
         I could hear my feet in my ears!
         Going clunk, clunk, clunk!
      
      
         Was it one of the swim caps with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No it didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, just the swim caps with the, the strap that hooked all the way under.
         And no matter what you did, your hair still got wet!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         I think you were supposed to be totally vacuum-proof and all that stuff!
         But it still got wet.
         But that's one of the memories I have of walking across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of the hotel and going clunk, clunk, clunk as I was walking across and then going swimming.
         And another memory I have is, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had a terrible, severe sinus condition.
         So every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, up until I was, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven</TIMEX>, we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire summer</TIMEX> down at, at, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina Beach</ENAMEX>.
         And I would get so tan!
         I mean I would just get absolutely, totally dark brown!
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would say to me, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Jeanette</ENAMEX>!
         If you get any darker, they're going to make you sit in the back of the bus!"
      
      
         Oh my gosh!
      
      
         Because that was when segregation was still on and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>, uh, department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, they had separate water fountains and separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> for colored and white.
         And when you rode on a bus, the colored had to sit in the back and the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sat in the front.
      
      
         How did that feel?
         I mean seeing that happen?
      
      
         Normal.
         Because it was the way things were.
         I mean, that's just the way it was.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         And we had, a<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, a</ENAMEX>, uh, a colored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> who came, gosh, about twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, whose name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie</ENAMEX>.
         And she was just like my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
         She, she bathed me and played with me and took care of me.
         Even then when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died, she came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>.
         I mean, she was just like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         But um, let's see.
         When I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>?
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, yeah, was when they had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And since we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayetteville</ENAMEX>, they decided to immediately expand <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX>.
         So, um, we lived on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg Rd</ENAMEX>, which, at that point, was the only road between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX>.
         And with all the added construction and all that, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning until nine</TIMEX>, it was bumper-to-bumper traffic on this little two-lane road going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         From <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four o'clock until seven</TIMEX>, coming back, it was bumper-to-bumper traffic, coming back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         So, you couldn't cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, you couldn't turn in or turn out or anything, it was just really, really crazy, because they were doing such incredible construction out there.
         And I remember all the headlights on all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were painted black for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the top semi-circle was black so that when if you went out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the light would shine just down on the road and not straight ahead.
         Everybody had window shades, you didn't have blinds back then, but everybody had window shades that were blackout shades and you had to pull them down at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before you turned on any of the lights, because everyone was deathly afraid that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> were going to come bomb us.
         Not that they ever did or--
      
      
         \\
         \\
      
      
         \\ --I don't think \\ they ever planned on it, but everyone was quite sure that that was going to happen.
      
      
         Looking back it almost seems silly.
      
      
         Yeah, it does but yet, yet there's, they have found evidence that there were, um, uh, submarines off the coast down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But um, you know, we were all pretty, pretty much panicked.
         And everyone, when you got chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>, you saved the aluminum wrapper.
         It was waxed paper with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> on the outside.
         You always peeled off the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and made great big balls for, that was the earliest recycling.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Everyone saved all their tin cans, um, and crushed them and put, took them to be recycled and be reused.
         There was rationing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, flour, any of, of the real, uh, staple things that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would use a lot of if they could.
         And you had a, it looked like a book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&H</ENAMEX> green stamps.
         You got a booklet of stamps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> and several pages would be for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, and several pages would be for flour or for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> or for, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, and you could only use <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> number of stamps to buy whatever you wanted to buy that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that month</TIMEX> and then you had to wait until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next month</TIMEX>.
         And since your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, your, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>, this was a critical job because he had to get the mail in and out, and he got an extra ration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> because he had to drive back and forth to work.
      
      
         Oh, wow!
      
      
         So that was pretty special.
      
      
         Yeah.
         Now did you notice, did you have a wanting of things during that time?
      
      
         No, no.
         We had, um, we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> raised <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, and uh, we'd always get them at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>, well you know, dyed pink and blue and green and all that sort of thing.
         I'd get the little biddies and they'd become full-grown <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and, uh, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> would gather the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and sold them to a lot of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>.
         We had, uh, I mean we didn't, I didn't know that I was supposedly being deprived of stuff because there was plenty to have because we had all, all of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>, we were the only ones that lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayetteville</ENAMEX>, it was the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But we'd go out and get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> and, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and, you know all that kind of thing from them.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sausage</ENAMEX> and pork <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chops</ENAMEX> and so forth and such, and any kind of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>, so we always had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
         And your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">granddaddy</ENAMEX> had a huge garden in the back and he grew, never could grow carrots, they were always awful, but he grew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and collards, spinach and green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>, and those yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>-necked squash.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         You remember those.
      
      
         The squash and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> recipe.
      
      
         Exactly.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         So he, he had a very successful garden and he'd go to work at probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and he'd be home by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four in the afternoon</TIMEX>.
         He'd go out and work in the garden until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark</TIMEX>.
         So we really didn't, I mean I wasn't aware of<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, of</ENAMEX>, wanting for anything.
      
      
         Except for the piano lessons.
      
      
         Oh, well, yeah because we, there was gas rationing.
         Well, to back up, when I was just learning to walk, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> told me that when we'd go down to the beach and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> at the beach, back then there was no air conditioning whatsoever, and so all the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and everything on the boardwalks would have screened-in, screened doors on the front.
         And any place we'd go by when I was walking with them, I'd have my hands up in the air and they'd be holding either hand--
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         --and when we'd go by any place that had a juke box playing, I had to stop and jog up and down in time to the music.
         When I was little bitty, so they knew I loved music.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> sang in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>, and uh, in fact that's where she met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leola</ENAMEX>.
         She and Leola best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>-- <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">altos</ENAMEX> and all that, but she knew I'd probably love music, and when I first learned to walk, she said I'd walk over to the piano and reach way up and start playing the keys.
         And I never would bang; I'd play <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> key at a time, with one finger.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And she'd put me up on the piano bench and would know for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least 30 or 45 minutes</TIMEX> exactly where I was because I was sitting there playing the piano.
         So when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, all my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were going take, ballet and tap dance lessons and I wanted to, but they encouraged me to play
         take piano lessons because the piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> lived right around the corner and the dance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> was all the way on the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, where her dance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> was.
         So, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty cents</NUMEX> and hour, I took piano lessons.
         And I went around once a week, because I could walk.
         She, Mother would cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> with me and then I could walk to the piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, whose name was, oh gosh, what was her name?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Russell</ENAMEX>.
         And she taught for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
         I took from her until I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And I think she taught just about everybody in town who wanted to learn to play the piano because she had, she had this
         I never will forget, she had this great big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the kind with the black tongue, and I was petrified of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         She always kept him in the backyard, so I never went in the backyard.
         I'd always go in the front door there instead of going around to the back.
         I hadn't thought about that until just now, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.
         But it was, it was fun playing the piano, and I, and then when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>, no when I was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five</NUMEX>
         the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, I was actually in the recital.
         And I couldn't play any pieces that, where the notes spanned an octave because my fingers weren't long enough until I was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about nine</NUMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But I was in the recital and, every time, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, it seemed like before, right before recital time I'd be out playing with somebody and fall down and skin my knees.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would make this great big, fancy dress with a real full, fluffy skirt, and she'd make a bow to match to wear on my hair, and I'd have Mercurochrome scabs on both knees.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         So, she always would get real upset with me with that, but that's life.
         Because since I didn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> to play with, we lived right next door to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westlawn Elementary School</ENAMEX>, and when I started school, the bell would start ringing and I could leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and run across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> and get there before it stopped.
         So I was never late.
         But I'd come home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and sit down and had to practice the piano for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would knock on the door and they'd say, "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances</ENAMEX> come out to play?"
         And she'd say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, there, she's practicing her piano.
         Wait for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another hour</TIMEX> and then she can."
         But I played out on the, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> because we had swings and we had tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, and, up until I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 12</NUMEX>, I played tackle <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>.
         And we had basketball goals and I played basketball with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, which was detrimental because at that point when you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> rules were different from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.
         Instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>.
         And there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> and three forwards.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> could not cross the centerline and the forwards could not come back across the centerline either.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So you'd get the, if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, you'd get the ball and dribble.
         You had to stop at the centerline and pass it over to a forward, which was very unwieldy!
         Now they, I mean, I forget when they changed the rules, but finally they started playing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> ' rules.
      
      
         So when you played with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that would mess you up for playing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah.
         Well, I much preferred playing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> because I liked to dribble all the way around and go up for a lay-up or something.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         And I was, since I was tall, they always liked for, to have me on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.
         But uh, that, that was fun, and, let's see--
      
      
         What did you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, in, in, in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, with a, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granddaddy</ENAMEX>, I mean, what kind of trips did you take when you were little?
      
      
         Oh, let's see, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we went up to, oh, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skyline Dr.</ENAMEX> We went up, I re--, something, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX>, I think.
         We went up, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, was trying desperately to get back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.
         He wanted to serve and do his duty.
         He had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWI</ENAMEX> but he wanted to get back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.
         And he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> at this point in time, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>.
         And we went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> for him to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there and they told him that they couldn't do anything so if he really wanted to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> he needed to come back and go up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>.
         So we drove up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and he went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and tried really hard for them to take him back and they said that what he was doing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> was in the best interest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and he could serve much better by getting the mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>.
         So they told him, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>," but while we were up there, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> and I rolled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Easter eggs</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> lawn.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And that was, that was when, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and he and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> came out and shook hands with all of us.
         All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         It was really, it was an interesting experience.
      
      
         Oh, I bet.
      
      
         And then coming back, we came back through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roanoke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> and then were on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Skyline Drive</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> said, "We're going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roanoke</ENAMEX> and there's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roanoke Mountain</ENAMEX> there."
         Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roan Mountain</ENAMEX>, anyway, there's supposed to be a mountain right in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roanoke</ENAMEX>.
         So I was thinking, having looked at all my books, school books, that it was going to be like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockies</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         --with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> and, you know, crags, a, and rocks and all that sort of thing.
         And I was so disappointed when we got there because we drove up and up and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well where's the mountain Daddy?</ENAMEX>"
         And he said, "We're on it," and it was, of course, covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and there were no rocks and there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         --and I was so disappointed.
         It just really burst my bubble.
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RECORDING PAUSED THEN CONTINUED</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Well since we were interrupted by the phone, now we're continuing.
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Um
         let's see, where were we?
      
      
         We were driving up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roan Mountain</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, but then we, after we left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roanoke</ENAMEX>, we did get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Skyline Drive</ENAMEX> and it was absolutely a beautiful, view, but there just weren't any mountains with rocks on them.
         So, that was one of the trips we took.
         A lot of times
         most, I guess most of the traveling we did was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> down to the beach.
      
      
         Right, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina Beach</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         To <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina Beach</ENAMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every summer</TIMEX>.
         And that was fun.
         And, uh, oh!
         I've got to tell you
         .
         Remember the, the birthmark I have on my leg?
         (Looks for birthmark) It's that little brown spot.
         
         Well, where is it?
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Anyway, I have a birthmark on my leg.
      
      
         I think I remember.
      
      
         Yeah, it's just a little brown
         right there.
         (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Points</ENAMEX> to birthmark)
      
      
         Yeah, yeah.
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> told me that it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> mark.
      
      
         \\ A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> mark?
         \\
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\ Because \\</ENAMEX> when she was pregnant with me, she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> would go down to the beach, because, again for her sinus condition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> air was really good for her, and she said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> would not stop because she wanted to stop and get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> and he wouldn't stop.
         
         And she held her hands right behind her knees, I don't know why, but just in anxiety or something so he would stop and get her a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>.
         So she swears that little mark is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> mark.
         And that may be why I like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> so well.
      
      
         You inherited the addiction?
      
      
         Yeah, yeah, I guess I did.
         But, um, growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> was fun.
         It was a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that's grown a lot since then, but we had a lot of fun with all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> riding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> and, just hanging out together.
         They'd come over and we'd just hang out in the driveway and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roller- skate</ENAMEX> or play with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> or whatever.
         I had a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, a toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">terrier</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fifi</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I never knew of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifi</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, I got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fifi</ENAMEX> when I was, gosh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX>, and that poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> was one
         I put her through so much!
         I'd dress her up in doll clothes--
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         --and make her ride in, in the doll <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carriage</ENAMEX>, and I'd pick her up, with her front paws and make her dance with me, and we'd walk all over the place.
         I mean, she just, she was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> because I didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
         And, but the only time I was really, really, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> epidemic.
         And that started, I think that was in, gosh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'46</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'47</NUMEX>, and, uh, everybody was quarantined.
         You couldn't go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> could not go downtown, and, and this was long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salk</ENAMEX> ever did the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> epidemic, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got Polio they had to be put in iron lungs that would breathe for them.
      
      
         Oh, wow.
      
      
         You may have seen pictures of them.
      
      
         I've heard of it.
      
      
         They were, they were great big, uh, metal tubes that opened, uh, and the only thing you could see was, uh, your head and your feet.
      
      
         Oh, wow.
      
      
         And it was pressurized so it would make you breathe in and out because they really were paralyzed.
         They called it <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Infantile Paralysis</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX>.
         But anyway, everybody was quarantined, we could, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> had, could not go out of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX>, they
         we couldn't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, couldn't go to movies, we couldn't go anywhere.
         We could ride in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         I could ride in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX>, we'd go for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> drive or something, but, I had nobody to play with.
         But fortunately, there was a, another only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child girl</ENAMEX> who lived right across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from us.
         So, her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy Teeter</ENAMEX>, and she would come out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> with her dolls and I'd come out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> with my dolls, and we'd play dolls together across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from each other!
      
      
         
         Across the street!
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Oh, that's so sweet!
      
      
         Yeah.
         And we'd also, we'd draw hopscotch things on the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> and play hopscotch together, and, you know, just any kind of little games we could devise.
         And we did, we'd do that for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours a day</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And that was our only contact with any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How long were you quarantined?
      
      
         
         I think, it started right after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, and until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following September</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Was it scary, any time you would get the sniffles, or--?
      
      
         No, I was always healthy, so nothing happened, but several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in, in town did get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> and, and had to spend time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Lung</ENAMEX> as they called it.
      
      
         Did they recover or, was it fatal?
      
      
         I think they all recovered, but a couple of them had a, a recur, recurring touch of paralysis.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you know, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, in particular, I remember, had a, always had a limp after that.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         So, it was, it was scary.
         And, of course, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> panicked more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> did.
         
         We were just pissed off
         because we couldn't go play with anybody else or see anybody or anything.
         That, that's the only time I really, really regretted being an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do during that time, I mean, to make it more fun for you, or--?
      
      
         Oh, bought me lots of coloring books and, uh, Mother made clothes for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> dolls and uh, we'd, like I said, we'd go for rides, it was a long way out from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX> at the point in time, and now there's, you know, they, they're, have the same, uh, boundary, but we'd ride out and listen to, on every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army band</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> concert.
      
      
         Like at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Park</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, like at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Park</ENAMEX>.
         And we'd ride out and I'd have to stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, but we'd ride out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> would <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and we'd roll down the windows so I could hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.
         And obviously we didn't, nobody had TV, it wasn't
         nobody had it at that point in time, so I listened to the radio a lot.
         There were, uh, The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lone Ranger</ENAMEX> and all those serial programs.
         The<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, The Green Hornet, and The Phantom</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sparky</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos</ENAMEX> and, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>, and uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fibber McGee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>, and--.
         
         There were a lot of radio shows, um, uh, oh shoot, what's his name, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that just died not recently, not too long ago, the uh, the comic, the one who did Oh God--
      
      
         Oh, um--
      
      
         (Long pause) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Burns</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Burns</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Burns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracie Allen</ENAMEX>.
         They had a show.
         So there were a lot of radio shows, and I, I read a lot.
      
      
         What, yeah, what, what would you read?
      
      
         Oh, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Drew</ENAMEX> books, and all the um, I read a lot of sports books about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football and baseball</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> would go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and just bring home a whole stack of them.
         So I did a lot of reading, and, uh, playing out in the yard, I'd help, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> would come home, I'd help him out in the garden.
         So, I, I really didn't lack for things to do but they just were sort of lonely things.
      
      
         Right.
         How did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> feel about, you being a tomboy?
      
      
         She
         , well, she said I was her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and I was, I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX>'s little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         --or little "tomboy", because he taught me how to, he was, he was sort of a jack-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-trades, so he did a lot of, he built, when we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, he built the chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.
         He'd bring home all the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two-by-fours</NUMEX> and the siding and the shingles and stuff, and he'd build them all himself.
         And I'd help him.
         I'd hold the ladder or whatever.
         And then I, graduated to nailing this and that and sawing this and that and so forth.
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time he was building a, a chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX>, that would make a great playhouse for me."
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And so, instead of putting it up on stilts, like he did the chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, he made it into a little playhouse.
      
      
         Ooh!
      
      
         It had a door that opened and shut and locked.
         It had, uh, a window in the front, had a front porch, had a window that went up and down in the front, and a window that went up and down in the back.
         And had shelves and, it was a pretty interesting little playhouse, and I'd go, I kept all my dolls and stuff out there and I'd go out there and play for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, and all my, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would come over and we'd have such fun, and we'd had a couple of little rocking chairs and we sat out on the front porch.
      
      
         Oh, that's sweet.
      
      
         It was, it was a neat little playhouse.
         When we sold the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that bought it had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and they were just delighted because they had somewhere for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to play.
         And something else you probably don't know
         .
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that we lived in on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg Road</ENAMEX>, was, um, very modern for it's time and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> built back then had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
         But it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and on the front, on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> level, you'd come in the front door.
         On the left was a living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with a fireplace.
         On the right was a dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and there were stairs going upstairs between that.
         And behind the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was a little, small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that they called a breakfast <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, which was just because they had a wall between that and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>.
         And there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>.
         Behind the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that we could, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we call them `dens,' but back then they called them, `sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
         ' Then it had a wrap-around, um, screened-in porch--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         --and a bathroom between the sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and also the door to the stairs to go down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>, because we had a coal-fired furnace.
         And then upstairs there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on either side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and a bath at the top of the stairs.
         So when they completed all the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, building out at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX> and brought in so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> when we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, Mother and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> would bring home <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX>, and usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> who were there in their uniforms and looked very forlorned; they would bring them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> dinner.
      
      
         Oh that's nice!
      
      
         And finally, um, Daddy converted the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> efficiency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>.
         So <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> had a stove and a refrigerator and they had to share the bath.
         And, well, each, each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> had the separate stove and refrigerator and they shared a bath.
         And we would rent them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who were just going to be there while their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> were going through training.
         And that was interesting!
         So
         they turned the, the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and the breakfast <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         --which was just about big enough for a bed and that was about it.
         But that was fun for me because I had somebody else to talk to.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of</TIMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that lived there had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, if you could imagine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sleeping, sleeping in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That would be tight!
      
      
         It was!
         It was necessary because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were going off to war and the, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> didn't know when or if they would ever see them again.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So they absolutely thought that every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> was precious.
         And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> afterwards we heard from these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         The sent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards and would write--
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         It was just really nifty.
         And, um, something else I remember was, and you've probably seen this in the movies.
         Everybod y who had someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> had a star in their window so you'd always know.
         And then if, I think there were with a cer, a certain color, maybe a red background, and if, if the, the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> was liked, it became a white background.
         Something like that: I can't remember which colors there were, but there was a distinction.
      
      
         Yeah.
         I've heard of yellow ribbons.
      
      
         No.
         That was way longer
         , that was, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tie a Yellow Ribbon `Round the--</ENAMEX>"
      
      
         
            Right.
      
      
         That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time after</TIMEX> that.
         But everybody had
         , they called them `<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Victory Stars</ENAMEX>' or `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Service Stars</ENAMEX>.
         ' And if you see any movies that were, well in, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX>, and when they were showing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>, they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.
         You probably didn't recognize or even know what it meant.
      
      
         Oh.
         I haven't seen it yet.
      
      
         Oh.
         OK.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Well, when you see it, when they show the stateside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, you'll see the stars in the windows and that means that they have, how, how, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they have in the service.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ooh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         But, um, let's see.
         What else do you want to know?
      
      
         Hmm
         
         
      
      
         Did you know about me winning the piano competition?
      
      
         No!
      
      
         When I was, we sold the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, uh, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg Road</ENAMEX> and moved over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle Dr.</ENAMEX> And your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was, she had a, had a, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart condition</ENAMEX>.
         I'm sure it was a congenital something or other because she always had to, to rest in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX>.
         She was never very, very healthy.
      
      
         I knew she died when you were young.
      
      
         Yeah, And, um, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>, she had a, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, or actually a blood clot and it went to her brain.
         It partially paralyzed her right side.
         And I was practicing the piano, doing all that sort of thing, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> entered me into the competition for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Classical Music</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> and under.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         For the whole, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What an honor!
      
      
         And the competition was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX> and it was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 17th of March</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Ides</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, and so, uh, she drove me down there, and, at that point <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> had had a stroke and was back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
         So I went down and I played.
         And I won.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years old</TIMEX> and I won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> and under for the whole state of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Classical Competition</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What'd you play?
      
      
         Ooh,
         I can't even remember.
         I've got in this vault something or other.
         I can still play it.
         But it was fairly complicated.
         And I was, nervous and all that sort of thing, but anyway I won.
         And we got back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayetteville</ENAMEX> and, I went, the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> took me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and I went up to see, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> was there, he'd gotten off work and was there, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had slipped, she was sort of in and out of a coma and I told him I had won.
         And he went in and told her, and she regained consciousness enough to say, "I am so proud!"
      
      
         Oh my God!
      
      
         And, she died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days later</TIMEX>.
      
      
         What a great thing that, you know, she came back long enough to--
      
      
         Yeah, exactly.
      
      
         --to know that.
      
      
         Exactly.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
         That's powerful!
      
      
         And I was, I was really proud of that!
         I still have the little cup.
         I think on of the handles is broken off of it.
         But I still have it!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But I was pretty proud of that!
         And then
         I discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and I didn't want to play the piano as much any more!
         
      
      
         Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> had delusions that I would even go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juilliard</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastman School of Music</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         But <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> just kind of--
      
      
         Hormones kind of interfered, yeah.
         I wasn't dedicated enough to practice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours every night</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But I had a good time with my piano!
         I played for all of the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glee Club</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choral Group</ENAMEX> in all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ensembles</ENAMEX> on school.
      
      
         Yeah?
         
         What kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> were you in?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, let's see
         .
         I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-High Y</ENAMEX>, which is, I have, no idea, they probably don't even exist anymore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Y</ENAMEX> was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-High Y</ENAMEX> was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.
         And I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Honor Society</ENAMEX>, and I was in, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glee Club</ENAMEX> and everything that went along with that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when I took <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>.
         I was on the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>; wrote a column for them.
         And, let's see, what else was I
         oh, I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist Youth</ENAMEX> Fellowship in church, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MYF</ENAMEX>.
         And that's about it.
      
      
         So you were pretty busy!
      
      
         Yeah, I was.
         And I was, when I graduated from high school, I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valedictorian</ENAMEX> and I also won the um, what the heck did they call it?
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, I think it was a business award, no, commercial award for being number one in the shorthand and typing classes.
         And I got that gold bracelet that I have, I was awarded for that.
         But back to, back to my birth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius</ENAMEX>, everybody called her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daddy</ENAMEX>, he called her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But she died in, in, gosh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>?
         Yeah, I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years old</TIMEX>, and, she died, then I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 May</TIMEX> after she died.
         And that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, her best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leola Harvey</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And so that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leola</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years before</TIMEX>, came down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX> to visit for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual summer</TIMEX> visit.
         She came down and stayed usually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX>.
         And she and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leola, Leola</ENAMEX> brought her over to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> for a condolence call, and sparks flew and they started going out and that's when they decided to get married and she became my stepmom.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And they got married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.
         Which at that point was highly, highly incensing!
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         I mean, you just, you had to mourn for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
         And I mean it was scandalous!
         So she had a lot of talk going on about her when she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daddy</ENAMEX> and came down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayetteville</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, cried a lot about it because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were very spiteful to her.
      
      
         It's hard to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> being seen as a tart!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yea</ENAMEX>, yeah!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But I mean, and, you know, she had the best intentions and I really needed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
         I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13 years old</TIMEX>, and I needed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and there was even talk of putting me in a foster <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or in an orphanage because it was scandalous that I was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> living alone with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Which, I mean, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>, yeah.
         But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> there's nothing wrong with it.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> was I think, he loved her a lot, but she also answered a lot of his prayers for how to take care of me and deal with me.
         Because I had just started my period, and I was, you know, having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acne</ENAMEX> and he didn't know how to deal with all that stuff!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         So he needed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to take care of me.
         And she was very glamorous and wore gorgeous clothes and dressed beautifully!
         And she taught me a lot and did a lot for me.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And because my birth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5'2</NUMEX>", and weighed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 145</NUMEX>.
         So she was short and chubby.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweetheart</ENAMEX>!
         A wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> but it had, she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leola</ENAMEX> had a lot of fun together and, but she was not classy.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         She was a little country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         Born and raised down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cumberland County</ENAMEX>.
         Never lived anywhere else.
         And here was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille</ENAMEX> from the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>--
         --Who wore high heels and stocking with the black seams up the back, and hats and had jewelry to go with every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> and all that sort of thing.
         So, I mean, she just really swept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> off his feet!
         And he was just absolutely, astounded by her because she was so incredible.
         And she entertained for him and, taught me a lot.
         She was just a great, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>!
         And had always wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, so there I was.
         And when they got married I was her only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> and, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That's sweet!
      
      
         Yeah.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Harmon</ENAMEX> gave her away.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.
         I didn't know that.
      
      
         Yeah.
         So, what else?
      
      
         I think that's all.
      
      
         OK.
         Then turn off the tape.
      
      
         OK.
         Thanks for talking with me.
      
      
         You're welcome!
         My pleasure!
      
   
