
   
   
      
         I'm being interviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Umar Rashid</ENAMEX>.
         I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, but my ethnicity is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>, and I'm a student going to college, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Umar</ENAMEX> wanted me to talk about stories of culture and childhood.
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has told me about stories about when he came, when he came, just to go, back and see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> for after coming back for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> and even be before he left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> about the quote unquote "hicks."
         They're not necessarily hicks they're just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really didn't know any better.
         A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who never experienced electricity, um, went to school and so they never knew things like the earth rotated.
         My, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was telling me a story about when he rode on the train this one time, and he was sitting next to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was all giddy and all excited, and, um, he was telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, "Do you think we're moving?"
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> said, "Of course, yeah."
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> replied, "Well no we're not moving, see?
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> rotates and we're just staying still.
         So that as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> is rotating and we're staying still, we're moving from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point to the other."
         And that was one of the examples he told of how much education was important when he tried to explain things to me.
         Things like that.
         It was not that it was his fault.
         It was just that he didn't know any better and that was how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, those poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> there was no real middle class.
         You were either extremely poor or you were extremely wealthy.
         There was very little so-called middle class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         Then, of course, as time went on, he started talking to me about dating.
         And, of course, you know, dating was a cool thing if you were smart about it.
         When he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> early on in this time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">of the</ENAMEX>, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of the, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were really strict on, you know, should, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX>.
         And the answer to a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> was not a chance in hell.
         If you wanted to date a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> you would have had to take them outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> because a lot of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, or even their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, may either kill you or beat you up or force you to marry her.
         Of course neither was a, uh, option.
         He just wanted to, you know, enjoy a good time with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, not necessarily, you know, anything intimate but have a good conversation with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and that was heavily frowned upon in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>.
         Another thing that happened would be told me about, um, was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, you know, stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> cheating on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>.
         In the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> when a, uh, if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> were to come over, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> would even leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> or even leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because if there wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> accompanying her, of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> could not converse with her because of, you know, the temptation of whatever.
         And when this, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> would come over, it may or may not be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> because this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has left the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
         The, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would tell me stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he knew who would, uh, dress up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothing, with the full, you know, coverings and walk in and uh have sex with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and walk out.
      
      
         Do you remember anything specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well he wouldn't give me any specific names because, obviously I wouldn't know who these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were, but, uh, he would tell me stories like that.
         He also told me stories about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> went to the movies.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         They would go into separate doors.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would drop off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in there from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, they would go and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and they would eventually walk together, and, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would walk behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Now</TIMEX> when they were to go pick up, you know, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the night</TIMEX>, the, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would stand in the corner and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> would go get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> really pretty much had no idea who their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> were because they were covered up.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Basically whoever opened the door, that was their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
         and that's when they drove off.
         And uh, it was kind of rather interesting.
         The differences in a culture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>.
         Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you know would have to walk behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world not necessarily in the cultural world, not necessarily a cultural, not necessarily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> --
      
      
         I'm sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>.
         How old were you when you started hearing these stories?
      
      
         Uh I don't know.
         I think it was about, well the whole dating thing was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 13</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> so --
      
      
         Do you remember any from when you were around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven</TIMEX>?
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six or seven</TIMEX>?
         Well that was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX> thing.
      
      
         Oh OK, OK.
         Sorry.
         
      
      
         Yeah I'm sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Umar</ENAMEX> was not paying, he had left the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> so I could continue telling the story just so you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> don't know.
         Now he came back so he's a little out of touch.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, now we're going to go onto education.
         And, of course, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was, was very strict on education and education was very important for anybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, and of course nowadays anybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
         You had to know your education.
         You had to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> told me a lot of times when he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX> in college he had to proctor an exam.
         And a--
      
      
         Sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>.
         How old were you when you heard this?
      
      
         Tst, tst, tst.
         Well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>.
         Yeah.
         And, um, he told me the story of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he would not let take this exam because he didn't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> taking that exam was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
         You know, I mean because she would, it was very unusual that she would cover up more than was usual.
         And he wasn't sure if that was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> taking the exam.
         And so there was a whole commotion about it.
         The, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> had to come in and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> had to get a female to come in have her take a look at her and check her ID because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> women didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ID's</ENAMEX>.
         You couldn't just, you know, here's an idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with a face covering, you know.
         That didn't really work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, of course education was very important.
         He told me stories of the educational system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.
         How very different it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> as opposed to here.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> test determines whether what college you got to what profession you go into.
         There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exams that you will take in your life in your junior year of high school and then in your senior year.
         The junior year is pretty much a practice exam and it's not based upon how well you do.
         It's based upon how well you do overall, everybody else.
         And what percentile you get determines what college you can get into because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> is free.
         So, uh, last time I heard, if you made a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX> or higher on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> point, this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> point exam, you can go into an engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         But you couldn't go anything higher than that, not doctorate.
         You had to make a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> to go into a doctorate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         Now, of course, you can go below that if you want another profession, but that's why education was very important in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.
         Because what you know you had to do.
         In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> everyone competed against each other for the better grade, so everyone studied on their own, and, um, and definitely had different study practices and mental practices towards education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>.
         You know, stuff the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> was well respected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> as opposed to here.
         You know, in the high school, where they can pretty much considered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>.
         This was no joke.
         You could be asked to leave in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> if you were told to.
         And those are the stories about education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> cheating dating, and the quote-unquote hicks.
         Thank you.
         Have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX>.
      
   
