
   
   
      
         
            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX>

            Although international affairs lead all papers, above-the-fold photos of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena Williams</ENAMEX> celebrating her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Open</ENAMEX> victory dominate the front pages. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with
the restarting of negotiations over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>; the other papers refer the story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with an exclusive: In an interview a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> general
threatened to reenter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> does not allow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s softening stance on
allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> into violence-torn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>; the other papers also
front the story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s armed forces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiranto</ENAMEX>, expressed willingness
to accept an "accelerated deployment" of peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> later
Wiranto reframed his message by saying that he would consider "security
cooperation." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> asserted that it was not time for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military might offer
logistical support for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>-led peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports
that a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> to help plan for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> boldly heads its story "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta Concedes</ENAMEX> A Loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>,"
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> makes clear that no coherent message is emanating from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> underscores that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiranto</ENAMEX> made his comments in informal
talks with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> he was escorting around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The general
acknowledged that some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> might be allying themselves with violent
anti-independence militia <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that during the high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> no shots were heard, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> could
see that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was in ruins. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> compound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cowered</ENAMEX> in fear of the next paramilitary onslaught. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reviews
evidence of atrocities tied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military. A human rights group
reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> have been shot or hacked to death,
including: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> instructed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> to resume
talks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>. Negotiations soured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rejected a promising deal. Espionage allegations and the bombing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> further stalled relations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> assesses the
meeting as a significant sign that the rift between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is
healing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sharing a
good-natured laugh, but its inside account emphasizes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> made "no
tangible progress." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cautions that it remains unclear whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
will recommit to cutting its tariffs to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> and phasing out import
restrictions in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> membership.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> claims it might invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> has failed
to protect non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
paramilitaries may already be infiltrating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-protected
sector of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. A senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> acknowledged that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peacekeeping</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramilitaries</ENAMEX> are permeating northern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and stirring up unrest.

            A political brief in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that during a recent trip to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> announced a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> aid package for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>'s fishing
industry, even though the program was approved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. The piece is
ostensibly based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> story. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> sent news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> two press releases highlighting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> story. The releases are the latest in a series of "World According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>" faxes that cast the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-president</ENAMEX> as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> brief cited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> condemnatory quote from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> story, the
same quote that the RNC underlined and boldfaced in its attack fax.

            All papers note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena Williams</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> to take
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX> title in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 40 years</TIMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martina Hingis</ENAMEX> beat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena</ENAMEX>'s sibling in the semi-finals, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena</ENAMEX> defeated Hingis
in straight sets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had predicted an all-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> final. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that his comment provoked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martina</ENAMEX> to call Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> a "big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mouth</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena</ENAMEX> volleyed by attributing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hingis</ENAMEX>' remark to her "lack of formal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
