
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Track</ENAMEX>

            Breaking stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> push softer
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> stories to the margins. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with the signing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> accord at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">resort</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> hope the agreement
will develop into the framework for a peace treaty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front accounts of increased violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> by
anti-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , which rewrote almost its entire front page
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX> editions, and the WP front <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement
encouraging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to take back his offer of clemency to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will transfer to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> full or partial control of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> stages--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13, Nov. 15</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 20</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negotiators</ENAMEX>
will try to hammer out a plan for a permanent peace treaty by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>, although
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> on both sides (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> in his speech) said that will be a
tough deadline to meet. The new agreement also addresses a water dispute and
calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to release <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. Coverage of the ceremony
in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> eclipses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX>, where she could
not resuscitate talks between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. The latter wants the border
redrawn to its position on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4, 1967</TIMEX>, before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> captured the Golan
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heights</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s insistence on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> boundary, which
does not reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX>. This point, bumped to an inside story for
the late edition, could have used further clarification, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> did not
exist until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>.  The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> border was acknowledged internationally after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nations 1922 Mandate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to set up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> west of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan River</ENAMEX>.

            Anti-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> terrorized rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> yesterday
after voting showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> favor independence
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rushed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> and dock hoping to
flee.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> did little or nothing to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>, and the
government has not made any guarantees to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> that it will act.
 The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the campaign has "no logical political
objective," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> suggests militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> may be trying to sweep
out an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>independence sector in the west. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would most likely
come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> at first: "It's their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . A full-page spread in the  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" summarizes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> national dilemma: how to hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX> islands together.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> police in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Frankel</ENAMEX>, the "nebbishy" (
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> accused of stealing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $350 million</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least half</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankel</ENAMEX> had eluded international investigation
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>, and it will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> more before he is
extradited.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should drop his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX> decision to offer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clemency</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> because they have not renounced further
violence. Her criticism, and that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>, prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
office-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>, and top law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, has forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
to reconsider its stance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report. Consequently,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to accept the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s gesture, which includes restrictions on their travel and political
activity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , suggests that the story is
really about the developing fissure between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> business and the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lady</ENAMEX>'s need to maintain political independence for her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bid.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s on-again, off-again <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuri Skuratov</ENAMEX>, told the LAT
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">780</NUMEX> current and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are under investigation for
illegally trading government securities that were suspicious to begin with.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skuratov</ENAMEX> said top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, acting on inside information (not a directly
punishable offense), yanked cash out of treasury bills before the ruble's
collapse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX> and then sent it abroad. A sure sign that something is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amiss</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $10,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> had invested more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> in the securities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money & Business</ENAMEX>" section
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiles Mikhail Khodorkovsky</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are being investigated in
relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> money-laundering operation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that some medical ethicists and consumer
watchdogs are faulting former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Everett Koop</ENAMEX> with blending
public service and commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DrKoop</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. 
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, this criticism has already led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to drop the part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX>'s contract that allowed him to receive a percentage of the money brought
in by products and services sold through the site. Critics also charge that the
site sometimes fails to distinguish between its advertising and the products
and services that it describes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX> says he's not in it for the money.

            
               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> walk into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> ...
                <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> celebrity
columnists prove that the anecdotal is "in."  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX>, writing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s need to recognize its sometimes subtle commercial dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
starts out,  "So I was having lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> with a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX>
news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> ..."  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, ostensibly reviewing the new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$785 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>-themed hotel and casino in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, writes,  "I'm strolling down a
cobblestone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, beneath a cloud-speckled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> sky."  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way or another,
each draws attention to the oddities (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>) or pitfalls (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>) of the
global economy.

         
      
   
