
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Well, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were expecting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of summer</TIMEX> to bring a return to
high-volume trading and sharp price swings on Wall Street, they were certainly
disappointed. The languor of the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> carried over into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, as
the stock market meandered aimlessly (is there any way to meander aimfully?).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> is now just about where it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early May</TIMEX>. Interest rates are higher,
but inflation looks just as dead, and corporate earnings are booming, and when
you mix all that together, what you end up with is a market that looks to be
about where it should be.

            Of course, this could all change <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

            There was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>--and unfortunately it was
a story that got written <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five hundred</NUMEX> times without anything really
changing. So now we all get to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> and wonder how long it'll be before
it snaps up or is snapped up by a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> or something. It's almost like
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX>, but thanks to 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Karmazin</ENAMEX> it's not. So on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when the dreaded 9/9/99 bug was supposed to
strike and mess up computers everywhere. But the bug was a nonstarter .
There were no &<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">$%</NUMEX>@<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX>($$$@<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX>(( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">… Mayday</ENAMEX>! Mayday!"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> had planned to sell <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 billion</NUMEX> of
its gold stash to finance debt relief for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, but has given up
on that plan because the gold industry was worried that the sale would force
down prices . It must be great to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX> full of a useless metal
that's valuable only because other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's valuable and then find out
that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's so valuable that if you sell it, the value will
disappear."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX> introduced its 'revolutionary enterprise desktop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appliance</ENAMEX>,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Ray</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, with a print ad featuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> lines and more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> words of copy . Whatever happened to<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: 'Coke--It's the Real Thing'?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhadey Bhattacharya</ENAMEX> , home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Bengal</ENAMEX>, told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : 'We discuss the great questions: What is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postmodernism</ENAMEX> ? What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX> have to say about this or that? Was
Green Acres a televisual enactment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jennings Bryan</ENAMEX>'s 'Cross of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX>' speech?'"

            4a. "OK, joke's over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhattacharya</ENAMEX> didn't really say that 'What is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postmodernism</ENAMEX>?' was a great question."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> raised its securities repurchase rate by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> basis points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, essentially taking back a rate cut it had
pushed through in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. Markets everywhere shrugged."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "Among the competitive concerns raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
deal was the possibility that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Runaway Bride</ENAMEX> , which was produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>, is sold to television, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> will have the inside track .
Apparently, concerns about just this kind of situation spurred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to pass
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sherman Antitrust Act</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>. Who knew anyone could have
that much <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">foresight?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Jenson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief financial officer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Air Lines</ENAMEX>, is leaving
his job to become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFO of Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> . Among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenson</ENAMEX> would
like to work on making <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s stock price 'more stable.' It's lovely
to dream big dreams, isn't it?"

         
      
   
