
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Trudeau</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Boy</ENAMEX>

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, at the
height of his popularity immediately following the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, whining to his
diary about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> who wrote jokes about his manhood. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Trudeau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
wrote, was "a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elitist</ENAMEX> who is spoiled, derisive, ugly and nasty." I'm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rubber</ENAMEX>, you're glue, bounce off me and stick to you!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doonesbury</ENAMEX>" much, either. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
remind yourself why, click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flashbacks</ENAMEX>," and when the little box with the
search engine appears, enter "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is especially fond of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> installment of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Lady Deal With a Rat</ENAMEX>," dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 1989</TIMEX>.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s case, however, there's a little history to the
relationship. Here is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>:

            

               
                  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Trudeau</ENAMEX> questioned [the elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s] manhood, I didn't like
it. I didn't like it at all. And I made it absolutely clear to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX>, who
was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> behind me at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale University</ENAMEX>. And if he didn't like me telling
him that, I didn't care.
               

            

            Curious about the old-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> tie between the likely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s preeminent comic-strip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX>
for his recollections of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>. Specifically, Chatterbox
wanted to check out a rumor that, while at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX> to quit
fiddling with that infernal liberal comic strip. Apparently, the rumor is not
true. In an e-mail, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX> explained that he didn't start writing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bulltales</ENAMEX>"
(as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doonesbury</ENAMEX>" was called before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX> syndicated it) until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> had graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous spring</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX> also pointed out that not
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were calling his comic strip "liberal" during its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>:
"Indeed, when I first started syndication, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Doonesbury</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reactionary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> !"

            "The only story I can think of that comes close," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX> wrote,

            

               
                  is one my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> tells: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> approached him and warned him that the
crowd he was running with was trouble--the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>, the dress, the
antiwar agitation, etc. There was no question that we in the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'70</NUMEX>
regarded most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'68</NUMEX> as the last of old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>--they
belonged more to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' world than to ours. The Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'69</NUMEX> was caught
in the generational riptide--torn in two directions--but the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'70</NUMEX>
(which had a radically different demographic--far fewer preppies) thought of
itself as being in the vanguard of the counterculture.
               

               To be fair (not usually my strong suit), a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> says he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remembers Bush</ENAMEX> being open-minded and curious as to what this new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> class
was about. My own impression of him was formed almost entirely from our joint
service on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davenport College</ENAMEX> (a residential college) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armour Council</ENAMEX>, to
which I was elected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my freshman year</TIMEX> under the mistaken impression it had
something to do with student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In fact, it was the social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>,
and our chief responsibilities were to arrange for bands and kegs of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. All
I can tell you about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was that he showed a lot of command presence during
our deliberations. Indeed, he famously went on to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deke</ENAMEX>,
where his talents blossomed.

            

            Fast forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>:

            

               
                  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more recent times</TIMEX>, the various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bushies</ENAMEX> have repeatedly snarled at me
from afar for all my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Geo the Elder</ENAMEX>. I have always suspected that their
antipathy for me was heightened by a certain "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>-to-his-class"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incomprehension</ENAMEX>. On paper, I'm one of them, so what's up with the
manhood-in-a-blind-trust stuff? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> once drew me aside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX>, stuck his finger in my face and told me he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> words for
me--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walk softly</ENAMEX>." A particularly productive suggestion. That's about it. Sorry
I can't give you anything more substantial--I just didn't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dubya</ENAMEX> all that
well.
               

            

            But wait a minute, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thought. What about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s telling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX>--making it, in fact, "absolutely clear"-that he "didn't like it …
didn't like it at all"? A possible future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> roughs you up and you don't
remember it? Chatterbox queried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning</ENAMEX>
News quote. "OK, we're getting into a shaky territory here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudeau</ENAMEX>
answered, "because I have a notoriously bad memory."

            

               
                  I have only seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubya</ENAMEX> once since graduation-I think it was at some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command NBC</ENAMEX> event my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Pauley</ENAMEX>] dragged me to. We did talk
briefly, but I remember it as being completely non-confrontational, that if
anything I was subjected to a charm offensive. That was back when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushes</ENAMEX>
were still trying to woo me over from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dark Side</ENAMEX>. Early on, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar</ENAMEX> even
purchased an original, making a nice contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition for the</ENAMEX>
Homeless. She hung it on the wall at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> compound, but things got ugly
shortly thereafter …
               

            

         
      
   
