
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Rochefoucauld</ENAMEX> Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Laugh</ENAMEX>
            

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent</ENAMEX>,

            Well, it's almost as good as an old-fashioned morality tale, isn't
it-something from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grimm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Rochefoucauld</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX> tries to have
it both ways: breakfast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, maybe, and lunch on their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. But
somehow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> foils the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>'s scheme, and he ends up with
nothing-neither <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, nor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. So, now, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>
have accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s clemency offer, and she ends up with nothing but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> on
her face. Downstate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> will never forgive her for
opposing the commutation deal, but she has nothing to show to more conservative
upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, either. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> go free, and not
only is she proven utterly powerless to stop them, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> suspect that
she was responsible for the clemency offer in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            It's a happy ending for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like us-and you and I do seem really in
agreement on this-who think that one of the worst things about politics these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> is all these gutless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> trying to have it both ways. The moral of
the story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">à la La Rochefoucauld</ENAMEX>: Trying to have it both ways usually gets you
neither. But all this brings me back to where I started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: I know I
could be gloating, but somehow in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the whole thing is just depressing.
Surely, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> deserves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who can do better than this?

            But the truth is, when I think about it, I wonder if that's so. Maybe we get
precisely the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> we deserve-because, after all, we usually reward the
ones who pander to us or try to have it both ways. And those who take on thorny
issues or take strong stands or-worst of all-try to find a truly honorable and
principled middle ground are usually only punished for their trouble.

            Think about the presidential <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> beauty contest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> have got
themselves into a shameless <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race, each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trying to outdo the other in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flattering</ENAMEX> and cajoling minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. They've trooped around to the
civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> meetings. They've sworn emotionally how much the
race issue means to them-how searing it was to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> bigotry against fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> (that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, of course) or, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s case, to watch his father
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battling Jim Crow</ENAMEX>. Both have promised to do just about anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>
asks them and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> even paid an homage visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX>. It's
pandering of the worst kind-and neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has taken on a single tough issue.
But both will be rewarded for their unctuousness by minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>-while they
would get absolutely nothing for staking out more thoughtful positions.

            Surely, to take the most obvious example, there are better ways to open up
opportunity than with preferences. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> claimed he wanted to "mend"
affirmative action. But neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> would go near that now: It
just wouldn't pay off with black or white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. There's more to be
said about this-I'm sure you and I could have long discussion of preferences.
But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, I think, we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> we deserve. It's easy to
criticize them, but really we ought to be looking inward.

            All best,
Tamar

         
      
   
