
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browning of America</ENAMEX>
            

            A gray morning looking north from my office windows over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>.
Listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kind of Blue album</ENAMEX>, er, excuse me … the
Kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> compact disc) with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coltrane</ENAMEX> blowing glissando on my
favorite composition, the smarty pants "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So What</ENAMEX>," written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>. A genius
was Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, adding depth and beauty even to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less-than</NUMEX>-stellar music by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lauper</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> ( I write to jazz, always have; it smoothes the
flow). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles Davis</ENAMEX>, as you may recall, maddened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> by playing with his
back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Never pandered. He said, instead, accept what I am-or I
will give you nothing

            Yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> (and gals?) have accepted the clemency. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> caught
now? Well maybe yes, maybe no. Remember, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tamar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cops</ENAMEX>. Now she can reasonably say to the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>: That was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>;
I did not do this . Last night's Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>) had a police union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> pretty much swallowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s line
that it was Bill not her who pardoned these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was saying: "My
community'' will make her pay dearly for this, we will make her walk the
line-which is a laugh, really-because they have nowhere to go. Think a moment,
Tamar: She has foxed them. She can now look clean to the cops and upstate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> get to rant a while-and look good to
their more radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, as I said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
is telling them through that razor smile that they have no choice except to
vote for her.

            Speaking of clouds. I was waltzing around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this summer</TIMEX> when
the political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> swept through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Unity Conference</ENAMEX>-the big confab of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black, Latino</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, as you may recall, said no
at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-then rushed over to pass through and shake a hand or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. (Wasn't
someone fired from his campaign for issuing that initial "no"?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was right
to come; in a segmented market like this one, you need every vote you can get.
It was healthy for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, too; which is too white by far. Don't be so hard
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> for making the rounds in the colored neighborhoods. It's good for
business.

            Look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb</ENAMEX>, with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> called "the little brown ones"; quite an asset on the hustings. How do you
think he won <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>? You've got to face it, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tamar</ENAMEX>, we are a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">browning nation</ENAMEX>. A
room without some brown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in it looks awful funny to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-probably
even to you. No?

         
      
   
