
   
   
      
         
            Broad <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brushes and Sticky Enthusiasm</ENAMEX>
            

            Groan, groan. If I had a buck for each tired reference to cornfed Midwestern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> books, I'd buy us a retro-chic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jaunt</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niagara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX>.

            But how would you write an introduction to such a vast topic for such
a vast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>? Because of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>'s universality--and the prohibitively
high cost of printing books in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-country languages such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>--these guides are used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> of every imaginable age and nationality.
They have to appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>
from the hinterlands of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. I bet the specialized guides--the ones for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX>, ethnic food <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>, and so on--are
better-written, because they don't have to cast such ridiculously wide nets
over subject and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            What really irks me about the writing is its relentlessly upbeat tone. My
books coat every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, and hotel with a sticky layer of enthusiasm,
making the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> uniformly and unrecognizably wonderful. Flipping through
my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> guidebooks, I found not a single negative restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review</ENAMEX>. I just
can't trust anyone who's this nice.

            And I shouldn't: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant</ENAMEX>, which screams "tourist trap!"
so loudly that it should be carrying a camera, gets rave reviews. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor</ENAMEX>'s
recommends its "high-quality" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> and touts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>'s "rather frequent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appearances</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> calls the food "surprisingly good." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zagat</ENAMEX>'s guides--which, unlike any of the guidebooks we're
covering, relies on actual reader feedback--gives the restaurant a
stomach-turning food rating of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13</NUMEX> (out of a possible <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>) and laughs that it
"might be deserted if it 'were named for anyone else.' "

            Which brings us to a dirty industry secret: Guidebook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, unlike travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, are allowed to accept free meals and lodging. Actually, since
their publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> generally don't provide food and hotel costs, they must
rely on complimentary dinners and stays, which means that they notify the
establishment ahead of time that they're coming to write a review. Can you
imagine the succulent steak, the impeccable service, the free pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordans</ENAMEX> to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was probably treated at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s?
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX>, the least fawning of my books, coughs that its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> do
not accept discounts or payments in exchange for positive coverage." Ah, so
they can't auction off good reviews to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>! But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> can
still accept said discounts, no?

            Discounts or no, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX> is proving to be my most trusted guide. This
surprised me; generally, I'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in matching the guidebook to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">destination</ENAMEX>, and I probably would have chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX> to wander real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jungles</ENAMEX> instead of urban ones. But the book is far more practical than any
other, dishing out such goodies as city bus routes, the best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> stands at
Midway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, names and programs of favorite local radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>, and
even the phone number of an notoriously aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-towing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. It's the
one book to provide more than a quick mention of the riots at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX>, or to explain how redlining segregated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> by race.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX> is also the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> with a discernible sense of humor. (On
snowstorm cleanup, it comments, "Any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> can tell you that snow
is a substance sent by God to ruin political careers, and because of that, each
and every delicate little flake that falls on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is seen as an invader to
be eradicated, whatever the cost.")

            The guidebook-to-destination theory is why I was so harsh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer</ENAMEX>'s shoddy survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> architecture (and for the record, it's a
difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> pages, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times the amount of detail).
Architecture is arguably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s greatest offering, both to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life in general. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has pioneered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> landscape-alterating
methods of construction (the balloon frame and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX>), fostered two
distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of design, and nurtured talents such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd Wright</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Mies van der Rohe</ENAMEX>. I agree that true pilgrims will purchase an
architecture-specific guide. But by failing to devote much extra copy or care
to the subject, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer</ENAMEX>'s demonstated that it churns out guidebooks according
to a set formula, regardless of what is unique about its subject destinations.
Travel is all about distinctiveness, but I bet that the table of contents for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> book is depressingly identical to that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX> guides.

            I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> your call for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> to appreciate our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> (not to
mention the riches they bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>). Of course, we are defending ourselves
here, since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are generally considered to be the most obnoxious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> on earth. I like the theory espoused in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essayist Clive James</ENAMEX>. He said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> weren't actually any ruder
or cruder than those from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Rather, it's that international
travel used to be a luxury reserved for the rich and ultra-mannered, and ours
was the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> wealthy enough to export our middle class.

            Now the middle class has been traveling for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. Air travel is an
everyday activity, entire cable channels are devoted to travel, and we buy
enough guidebooks to support ever-deepening niche titles. Doesn't this suggest
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> are simply getting better at going places, and that it's time to
dispense with the stereotype that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> are uncouth, unchic, and generally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unbearable</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
