
   
   
      
         
            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vacations Kill</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> riding "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shockwave</ENAMEX>" stand-up roller coasters at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>--one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanover County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Clara</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> (To read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>'s account, click here.) There is the usual back-and-forth about whether the
injuries were the fault of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> or the amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is
more interested in the broader question: Is leisure time more dangerous than
work?

            The answer, of course, varies depending on what type of work you happen to
do. "In my world, anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, sitting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, are obviously not at risk
very much," observes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Hadley</ENAMEX>, a research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Injury Research and Policy</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins School of Public Health</ENAMEX>. A coal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miner</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> himself to a lot of risk on the job. The
type of leisure you tend to prefer is also a factor. "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go on
vacation and lie on the beach," notes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadley</ENAMEX>, "and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do things that
are more exciting, like skiing and rock climbing." Presumably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who
seek physical thrills in their leisure activity tend not to get them on the
job, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get them on the job don't seek them out while on vacation.
But probably there are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> out there who go hang gliding in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.

            There's no question that vacations can cause harm. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Injury Fact Book</ENAMEX> , sports and recreation account
for "the majority of drownings, many firearm fatalities, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10 percent</NUMEX> of
all brain injuries ... <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> of spinal cord injuries ... and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of
facial injuries treated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>." Overall, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 6,000</NUMEX> deaths each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> are associated with sports and recreation, not including the many
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> that occur in connection with recreational use of motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> in
traffic," the book says; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of the sports-and-recreation deaths
"result from water recreation." (The most dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> sports, in declining
order, are swimming, boating, and scuba diving.) But are vacations more
dangerous, in the aggregate, than normal life? Chatterbox, alas, couldn't pose
this question to the book's principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan P. Baker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins School of Public Health</ENAMEX>, because ... she's on vacation!

            But her book includes a chart that sheds a little light on the subject by
comparing the percentage of "unintentional injury deaths" in various categories
(drowning, falling object, etc.) in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, "public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>" such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>,
industrial settings, and places where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> engage in recreational activities.
Thus, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.6 percent</NUMEX> of drownings occur during recreation ,
compared with 
                  12.8
                percent at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or resident
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.2 percent</NUMEX> in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> ,on a
farm, or in an industrial 
               setting or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> . (A hauntingly
large <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68.4 percent</NUMEX> of drownings, however, are attributable to
other or unspecified causes.)

            On the other hand, if you're going to die by falling , it's much more
likely to happen to you while you're at home: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51.5 percent</NUMEX> of deaths as a
result of falling happen in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or residential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> , compared
with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 0.8 percent</NUMEX> during recreation , and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.9 percent</NUMEX> in
a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> ,on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> ,or in an industrial 
               setting
or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> . (Presumably those who die from falls at home are mostly old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 65</TIMEX>, falls are responsible for more recreational deaths
than any other recreational activity except swimming.)

            
               Falling objects are most likely to get you at work
(
                  33.4
                percent in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> ,on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, or in
an industrial 
               setting or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>, of which fully 20.1
percent is attributable to an industrial 
               setting or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> ). But
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is pretty dangerous, too ( <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25.8 percent</NUMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or resident
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> ). Vacations are pretty safe in this regard; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1.1</NUMEX>
percent of falling-object-related deaths occur during recreation .

            However, lightning is more likely to kill you while you're engaged in
recreation ( <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.3 percent</NUMEX>), with the workplace a close second
( <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> , on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> ,or in an
industrial 
               setting or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> are the biggest risk here,
responsible for 
                  8.6
                percent), and home placing third
( <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.4 percent</NUMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or resident <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Collision with an object or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> (apparently not one that's falling
on you)is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-biggest vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> (after drowning and
lightning ); <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.2 percent</NUMEX> of these deaths occur during
recreation , though most such deaths occur at work ( <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.6 percent</NUMEX>
in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> , on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> ,
                or in an industrial

               setting or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> ; industrial settings and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> are the biggest risk
here, responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.9 percent</NUMEX>) and at home ( <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23.9 percent</NUMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or resident <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> ).

            It's important to remember, of course, that not engaging in certain
kinds of leisure activity (read: exercise) will also kill you; heart
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> remains the No. 1 cause of death in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. So the question,
"Are vacations more dangerous than work?" (which, on reflection, should really
be "Are vacations more dangerous than work or hanging around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?") is a
complex <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will continue to collect data on this subject in hopes
of reaching a definitive conclusion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            [Correction, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 29</TIMEX>: Chatterbox misidentified both the amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and
the ride where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Clara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, death occurred. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and the ride was Drop Zone, which apparently isn't a roller coaster.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominion</ENAMEX> share a common parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s general alarmism about amusement-park dangers was, if
anything, understated; according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>,
emergency-room visits attributable to amusement-park rides have increased by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
percent during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX>.]

         
      
   
