
   
   
      
         
            Canister of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worms</ENAMEX>

            The top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times is a major development in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> controversy: the discovery by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> that all this time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has harbored audiotapes suggesting that
pyrotechnic gas <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX> were indeed fired at a bunker within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>
Davidian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. This is also the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> doesn't have this--its front <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX> effort is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to have somebody from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> up
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> investigation (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> folds this into its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> piece), and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s top non-local story, which makes everybody's front, is the
creation of significantly smarter <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> through a minor genetic alteration.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s front is mum on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> and its lead is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> audit revealing
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s public water systems are stricken by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of
cases of previously undocumented unsafe drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The story refers to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> Web site that lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> check up on their local water systems, but
there's a slip <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">between cup</NUMEX> and lip--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> says it came across the audiotapes "in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> say they were discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hostage Rescue Team</ENAMEX>, the unit
that spearheaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Waco</ENAMEX> assault. All the stories say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> then brought the
tapes back to its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. Then comes the most
surprising step: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> marshals over to seize the
tape. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says she intended the move as a harsh rebuke of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has the most on the tape's contents, said by the paper to be a soundtrack of an
infrared video made from an aircraft when the tear gas canisters were launched
at the bunker. This suggests an orchestrated use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, although the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes a law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> saying that its deployment was "spur
of the moment." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> issue relevant here, which the press hasn't gotten to yet:
Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI/DOJ</ENAMEX> have written-down rules of engagement governing the use of
incendiary devices? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> cites law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> saying that
the tape supports their account that the canisters bounced harmlessly off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bunker</ENAMEX>'s roof and hence could not have started the subsequent lethal fire, and
also points out that nobody in law enforcement, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>, has suggested
that the tear-gas devices contributed to the fire. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lay out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meta</ENAMEX>-issues now put in play by the tape: Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> contravene a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX> ban on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pyrotechnics</ENAMEX>? And did it wage a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year</TIMEX> coverup against her and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>?

            The smarter mouse stories are occasioned by a write-up of the
research coming out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. In the experiment, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra</NUMEX> copies of
a gene associated with recognizing something or remembering where something is
were inserted into mouse embryos. The result: The enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> grew up better
than control <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> at remembering say, that a tone was associated with a shock
or where a resting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> of opaque <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
quotes the research's lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> as saying that the experiment raises
issues of equal access to perfecting technology and that it's an example of
biology outpacing the culture's capacity to deal with ethics.

            A story running inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on a study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> civil
cases that went to trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. The chief
conclusions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> are more likely than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> to rule for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>, but
juries generally award larger damage amounts.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to always note the credit line accompanying an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Op-Ed</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> effort titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"China's Subtle Spying</ENAMEX>" is a case in
point. The piece claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has successfully devised a new espionage
strategy that can "consistently defeat our ability to investigate or prosecute
spying offenses." The key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> doesn't
normally pay an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for information, request the provision of classified
documents, use intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to elicit information, or engage in
clandestine activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. All this, he says, usually means no
smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> of the sorts found in other espionage cases. Interesting, but the
snap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bio</ENAMEX> tells us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul D. Moore</ENAMEX>, was, during the whole time of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> troubles, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in charge of defeating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> spying.
In other words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> needs to wonder, would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> be making these
arguments if he didn't desperately need them to try to save face?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , following up on a brief item in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> recently received a form
letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legal defense fund asking for a contribution.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> wrote "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Return to Sender</ENAMEX>" on the envelope, adding, "You must be morons
to send me this letter!"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cliffs Notes</ENAMEX> will soon come out with shorter
versions of the guidebooks in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">...For Dummies</ENAMEX>" series. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX>
deplores society's vapid need for ever-briefer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substitutes</ENAMEX> for actually reading
something.

         
      
   
