
   
   
      
         
            The Return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L-Word</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Brent</ENAMEX>,

            Well, I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s formal announcement is hardly news--he's been running
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now, hasn't he?--but I was struck by the stories this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. Never mind the "aw shucks" stuff: We expected that. Also the now de
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rigueur</ENAMEX> claims that he'll restore the dignity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, won't be
driven by polls, etc., etc. What interested me was his unabashed,
old-fashioned, capital-L-liberal pitch. He's really running on the idea of
helping poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--"strengthening the weak" and "challenging the strong" and
spreading the new stock-market prosperity to the least among us.

            I'm not complaining: more power to him if he can pull it off. But it sort of
amazes me that he thinks it will work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a few years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, the very word "liberal" was taboo. And the ever astute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would no
more claim to be a liberal than he would try a tell a story about himself
without spin: Remember all that stuff about "triangulating" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of the suburban middle class? I didn't think I'd see another
declared liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in my lifetime (outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, of course).
And what I really wonder is: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Could Bradley</ENAMEX> be on to something--politically?

            Is the me-too generation finally growing up and looking beyond itself? Is
the comfortable middle class so comfortable now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel they can
afford to be liberal again? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX> always told us this would
happen: that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics run in cycles of conservative constraint and
liberal largesse--and, I suppose, in his own way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> too has signaled that he
sees a new mood dawning. With "compassionate conservatism," he, too, is banking
on a sense that the public wants to think of itself as generous again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>:
generous, caring, altruistic and--yes, let's face it--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>. The question
remains, of course, how ? What can we as a nation really do to help the
poor and the left out? And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s ostensibly conservative ideas could turn out
to be more effectively liberal than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s more conventionally
liberal ones. But I must say, I'm struck by the shift in rhetoric--and what it
says about both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s readings of the national mood.

            Which brings us back to where we were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: Are there other means of
achieving equal opportunity than with preferences? It sounds as if you and I
agree completely on that: The answer is education and what I call
"development." Narrow the gap in black-white school achievement and you won't
need to put your thumb on the scale of college admissions or hiring or
promotions or anything else. (And yes, I agree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX> took a principled
stand for just that long-term solution when he endorsed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> suit pressing
for better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in poor areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.) But the question here, too, it
seems to me, is precisely how do you do it. How do we make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> really
work for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? What do we do about the parenting that doesn't prepare them
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>? How do we counteract the peer pressure that tells them not to
bother in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> because it's "acting white"? And who exactly should be doing
all this--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or the charitable private sector, or some combination
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>?

            I'm sorry if I sound like a broken record, but I always come back to the
same question: the means. I'm thrilled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> may be feeling more
compassionate now. But that's only the beginning of the conversation, not the
end of it. The devil--and answer--is in the details. We may all be liberals
again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, but what exactly are we going to do about it?

            All best,
Tamar

         
      
   
