
   
   
      
         
            Life as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moebius Strip</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Nora</ENAMEX>:

            I didn't watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX>, if by "Open" you mean this big tennis thing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>; I don't watch sports, except the very occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> playoff or
World <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series Games</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 5, 6</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.

            I did watch some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmys</ENAMEX>, although not as much of it as my youngest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>, who at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> is as deeply and weirdly interested in celebrotainment
(e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy Awards</ENAMEX> shows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ) as I was at
her age. I got over it, more or less, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> that she will, too. The
conventional wisdom is correct: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> deserved to win pretty much
every award, and the fact that it got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> is a travesty, to the degree
that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy</ENAMEX> injustice can be a travesty. Since you are a housemate of the world's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great Mafia</ENAMEX> chronicler, I've wondered what you think of the show.

            Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emmys</ENAMEX>-wise: I adore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenna Elfman</ENAMEX>. Why do most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientologists</ENAMEX> seem so appealing? Maybe we should convert.

            The fundamental problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">qua</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmys</ENAMEX> (aside from the fact, as I
learned from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>,
disproportionately elderly, and unemployed) is that most shows on television
are series--and so the same shows and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors-</ENAMEX>playing-the-same-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Emmys year after year</TIMEX>. This makes for
bad ritual. Of course, this is also the problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Magazine</ENAMEX>
Awards lunch, which has the additional problem of being, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Correspondents Dinner</ENAMEX>, the most depressingly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>-like assembly I have
ever attended.

            Do you find the ongoing anti-mosquito spraying of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> with
malathion, neighborhood by neighborhood, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and from the air, as
charmingly quaint as I do? It seems like something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiorello La Guardia</ENAMEX> would
have ordered done, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weegee</ENAMEX> documented.

            Speaking of charmingly quaint, and speaking of (literally) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> things,
how about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melita Norwood</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">87-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> asset in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>? "I would do the
same thing again," she said, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> shouted "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Traitor</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traitor</ENAMEX>!" And triply quaint--unapologetic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pro-Soviet</ENAMEX> communism, little old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> with a coffee-filter <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name photographed smelling her <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>,
righteous anti-granny indignation about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> politics. And everyone
concerned, on both sides, acting more or less honorably ... so unlike, say, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> thing, where everyone concerned, on both sides, acted more or
less dishonorably. (The same new book that exposes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melita</ENAMEX>, The Mitrokhin
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archive</ENAMEX> , says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> manufactured a forged letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Hunt</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 22</TIMEX>, and leaked it to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> conspiracy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. Although I'm sure the conspiracists would tell me that
this new story is just new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disinformation</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Salter</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> on the decline of civilization and the rise
of pop culture: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine</ENAMEX>, I wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> read books more, too, but didn't it read
like a parody of a windy, pretentious old fogey? "When I wrote movies ...
thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham Greene</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Steinbeck</ENAMEX>, who were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> as well as film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> ..."

            And finally, just to nip at the hand that's feeding us, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
antitrust trial story: How perfectly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">postmodernistically</ENAMEX> apt that e-mails sent
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> during the trial (back on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 22</TIMEX>, in fact) are now being introduced into evidence at the same trial.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more way in which life has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moebius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX>.

            Over to you.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
