
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timorous Reporting</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">at-long</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last independence</TIMEX> elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> puts that inside and
leads instead with the apparent readiness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to fight for a treaty banning all nuclear testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurricane Dennis</ENAMEX> hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolinas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gives the clearest, highest account of the context of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> election, starting right off with mention of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> rule of the region followed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 25 years</TIMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military occupation. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> doesn't mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
invasion until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five paragraphs</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is also alone in
mentioning that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winked</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> invasion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>. But the
paper squanders a bit of this edge when it writes that the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> "has for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> remained a largely invisible problem closed off to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and the scene of some of the world's worst reported human rights
abuses," thus falsely suggesting that poor coverage of the topic was somehow
mostly caused by something other than press inattention.

            The gist of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> pieces is of a long-oppressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> finally getting their say, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes rather more
postmodern, noting that "though the anti-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> have clearly had
the upper hand in terror, the pro-independence forces, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years</TIMEX> of
experience in both war and propaganda, have seized the role of well-intentioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>."

            Everybody mentions that a much-violated nonviolence pact between pro- and
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> seems, at the very last minute, to be finally holding
up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that if violence is avoided, "most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>" say the
residents will choose independence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that, armed with polls and the support of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are threatening to bring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to a standstill unless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> agree to hold hearings on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>, which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have already signed and
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed and sent on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The biggest
obstacle, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, whose main interest in the
area of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weaponry</ENAMEX> is not traditional arms control, but enhanced
anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front-pager distills <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>' early thoughts about what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> earthquake portends for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s seismic future. The main findings:
The overriding explanation for devastation is bad building practices, soft and
loose soil (as opposed to rocky soil) amplifies a quake's effects, as do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valleys</ENAMEX>. Biggest new puzzle: Previously, it was thought that a quake couldn't
jump a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to activate a fault line on the other side, but in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, this seems to be precisely what happened--across <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three miles</NUMEX> of lake.
Which could mean that several areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">functionally</ENAMEX> have much larger
fault lines than had been thought.

            The papers all note <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> chat show calls by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schumer</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>, for a full-bore outside investigation of federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' use of incendiary devices at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>. None of these stories note that
these calls come right after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> let the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lapse</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story inside reporting that a new study shows that the
pay gap between average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and top corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> has exploded
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, going from a ratio of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42 to 1</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980 to 419 to 1 last year</TIMEX>.
Why didn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> assign this at least the same priority as such
front-pagers as organic school lunches and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>?

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> mystery: A brief inside item says that in defiance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> objections, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff members</ENAMEX> have visited
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> on a fact-finding mission, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. Why doesn't
the paper identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, or more importantly, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>?

            Even though handgun deaths are actually down a bit from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>, says
a piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>," recent well-publicized
shootings tend to stimulate lawful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> purchases for household protection,
which may be bad news for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>, since according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> quoted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, "the odds that a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> will be the scene of a homicide are substantially
greater if there is a gun in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature points to an
interesting reason why established large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> haven't exactly reaped
the Internet's rewards: The large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> are used to insular, if not paranoid,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decision-making</ENAMEX>, and Internet operations force them into all sorts of relations
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> they can't really control.

in on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s proposal to devise a television special of an airplane purposely
crashed into the desert with a resounding, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NO WAY</ENAMEX>!" But in a separate story
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also notes that a recent study shows that surviving a plane crash can
profoundly improve one's mental health. Let's hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX> doesn't connect the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dots</ENAMEX> and pitch his show as psychiatric social work.

         
      
   
