
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Journalistic Integrity</ENAMEX>, and Other Oxymorons
            

            I'll do you one better: Let's pose as guidebook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and get someone
else to pick up the tab for our visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niagara</ENAMEX>. I'll impersonate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lonely</ENAMEX>
Planet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, and recommend seeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX> the "authentic way," by
barrel.

            It's true that listening to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guidebook</ENAMEX>'s cheerleading gets tiresome. But a
travel guide full of panned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> is useless. If a book doesn't like a
place, they shouldn't list it. The exception, of course, is in small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> or
isolated locales (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liberty Island</ENAMEX>) where a forgettable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or hotel
might be the only option. Another factor that discourages negative reviews is
the risk of a libel suit.

            The real problem is that none of the guides sift through all the stuff and
tell you what's right for whom. Even in a general guidebook there's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specialization</ENAMEX>: the best green spots, the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, etc.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor's</ENAMEX> has suggested itineraries, Access and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> have rating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>,
but it still seems that you've got to read the entire book to make sure you're
not missing something that you'd enjoy, and that can be wearisome no matter how
well they're written.

            When I worked for Let's Go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> cobbled together a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>,
hostels, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and sent them complimentary service vouchers, which they
would sign and return. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> could then visit the establishments
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anonymously</ENAMEX>, and present the voucher when the bill arrived. This method does
prevent preferential treatment, but I do think that a free lunch can compromise
your review whether your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> pays--footing the bill is
an integral part of the dining experience, and it's harder, if only slightly,
to rate the value of a meal someone else buys. In general, though, I've found
travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to be honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>. And even the unscrupulous are more
interested in eating for free in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> they have no intention of listing
than in taking kickbacks from low-quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX> in exchange for
inclusion. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way or another, the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> are served.

            It's wrong to say that these guides don't take reader feedback into account.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX> (and Let's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Go</ENAMEX>) usually acknowledge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who wrote them
helpful letters in the back pages of the book. This feature is strangely absent
from my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New York Lonely Planet</ENAMEX>, but the most recent edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> book
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' names. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zagat's</ENAMEX> may be good for finding a culinary
sure thing, but you'll have to stand on line with the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (or in
line with the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>). And I think it's na√Øve to use their ratings as
an absolute measure of restaurant quality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Locals</ENAMEX> have different interests,
attitudes, and palates than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, and would be accordingly harsher on theme
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. And before taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor's</ENAMEX> to task for praising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chops</ENAMEX>, admit it: You've got to look pretty hard to find a bad steak in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>.

            As for theme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in general, they're merely indicative of the fact
that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> travel with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The theme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, as a
pacifier, is a stroke of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. The overdone d√©cor gives the short of
attention plenty to gawk at. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is bland enough for even the most finicky
adolescent palate. And celebrity sponsorship is a behavioral modification
technique rivaling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus: Kids</ENAMEX> shape up quick if you can con them into
thinking that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sly Stallone</ENAMEX> might show up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any minute</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Mediocre food</ENAMEX> at inflated prices is (I imagine) a small price to pay for the
respite these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> provide for the harried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, and guidebook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
feel duty-bound to include them. All the same, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX> gets extra credit
for noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley-Davidson Caf√</ENAMEX>© is "so commercial the menu's available
for sale at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>."

            Having spent so much time defending my former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, I'm afraid I've
left you little new to work with. I'd still like an explanation: Why are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> titles multiplying, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> should be pushing them into
extinction?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, I doubt that I've done much to advance the science of travel guide
writing, but I've thoroughly enjoyed our discussion. Rumor has it that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronkite</ENAMEX> is opening his own theme restaurant on West <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">57th Street</ENAMEX>.
We'll toast your safe return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> with a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX> (That's the way it)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fizz</ENAMEX>" (complimentary, I hope).

         
      
   
