
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harry the Savior of English Literature</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Polly</ENAMEX>,

            Thanks for the tip about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sylvia</ENAMEX> Townsend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>. I'll check the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> for
Kingdoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elfin</ENAMEX> , which sounds marvelously creepy. And imagine
confusing a succubus with a lamia! I'm so ashamed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> points from
Gryffindor!

            I see that the question I lobbed casually in your direction on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> has
bounced back like a bludger (or do I mean a quaffle? I'm still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quidditch</ENAMEX>) to knock me off my rhetorical broomstick. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, why now? An
obvious answer, which we've gestured toward in various ways <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, is just
that the books are a lot of fun to read. Your analysis of their narrative
structure, by the way, was incisive. The sonnet sequence analogy is inspired:
With each book you become newly aware of the tight structural constraints
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX> is working in, and freshly amazed at the dazzling variations she
manages. Each time, for instance, I'm sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snape</ENAMEX> is the link to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Voldemort</ENAMEX>,
and each time I'm stunned when he turns out to be nothing more than a
garden-variety classroom sadist. And yet I know I'll fall for this trick again
and again, and that the moment I don't will be the moment his true evil--or his
unsuspected goodness--is revealed. I'm impressed with how effortlessly Rowling
balances the genre requirements of predictability--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> will prevail, the
school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> will end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voldemort</ENAMEX> will be foiled (but only temporarily!)--and
surprise.

            But as we know, a book's quality and its success are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different things.
Some of the hype about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> seems a bit wild: You'd think, reading
newspaper stories about these books, that they had single-handedly rescued
literacy in the English-speaking world, and also bridged the gulf between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Talk about magic! Nearly every article I've seen quotes a
parent or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> saying something to the effect of "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> never showed any
interest in reading until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> came along," with the implication that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> will now trade <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pokemon for The Illiad</ENAMEX> and our civilization will
be saved from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of darkness. The jacket flap of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> edition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azkaban</ENAMEX> sports a handwritten letter from an 8-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">begging Rowling</ENAMEX> to write more books. It's a bit much, really.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> partake of a great deal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> culture, voluntarily
or not, and inevitably develop tastes and interests of their own. I'm as
obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> as I used to be with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">schoolteacher</ENAMEX>, has developed an insatiable appetite for young-adult historical
fiction quite independent of the professional requirements of keeping up with
what her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are reading, finding new texts to assign, and so forth. Part
of the fun of having (or teaching) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is the vicarious reliving of one's
own childhood--reading the stories aloud that you remember having read to you,
renting videotapes of the movies that enchanted you or gave you nightmares,
reconnecting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert</ENAMEX>.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX>'s books, which are so smart and so bracingly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> (I think
you're right to keep bringing up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.L. Travers</ENAMEX> as a reference point--she and
Rowling both manage to be at once subversive and starchy, anarchic and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commonsensical</ENAMEX>), have resonated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> is no surprise. She quite cannily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sets Harry</ENAMEX>'s adventures in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> whose culture and geography are entirely
literary. This is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di or Martin Amis</ENAMEX>,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> we remember from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> somehow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perpetually Edwardian</ENAMEX>, notwithstanding certain concessions to modernity like
telephones and coeducation.

            In an earlier posting you speculated that our enthusiasm for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX>
may arise from our anxiety about technology, and it's striking (this is
something my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> called to my attention after she read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books)
how technologically underdeveloped the muggle world is in these books, in
particular with respect to information technology. No e-mail, no faxes, not
really any television or movies. And of course the wizard world is a world of
artisanal handicraft, ancient wisdom, and small, local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. Hogwarts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX> don't buy their textbooks from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>
superstore but from a quaint old bookshop on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagon Alley</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flourish</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blotts</ENAMEX>. They don't have e-mail; they have owls. They don't play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>; they
practice spells. (They do, however, collect famous wizard trading cards, which
move, just as all wizard photographs do. But, curiously, wizard photography
seems to be exclusively black and white.)

            So there is a double nostalgia involved in reading these books--nostalgia
for one's own childhood and nostalgia for the timeless realm of classic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s fiction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX> has cleverly, and subtly, modernized these realms
with respect to matters like gender equality and multiculturalism--not that she
makes a big fuss about such things. Of course, this being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s-book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, there's still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant class</ENAMEX>. But though there's plenty of cruelty,
corporal punishment has fallen from favor. (The death penalty seems to be
reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wayward magical beasts</ENAMEX>.)

            Of course, none of this explains why these books have crossed over not only
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> but also to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. This
seems genuinely unprecedented, and it may be one of those inexplicable
phenomena the culture likes to toss our way every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>. (Our seeker
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks the bludger</ENAMEX> and sprints for the golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">snitch</ENAMEX>!) Or it may be a symptom of
our present obsession with childhood and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--the simultaneous detonation
of the postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom and the fin de siècle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom. All I know
is I haven't had such a purely escapist reading experience in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.

            As much fun as it was to read these books, it's been even more fun
discussing them with you. I'm quite dazzled by your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insight</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erudition</ENAMEX>--bewitched, in fact.

            All best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
