
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Idiots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Their Boats</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is grateful to the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wrote in to share personal
stories and their views about methodological challenges as a way to help
Chatterbox figure out whether vacations are more dangerous than work life and
hanging around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. (To view most of the comments, scroll down to the
bottom of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> and click on the link to 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s reader
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>." Be warned that, as is the case with most chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, you
have to wade through a lot of ill-tempered bluster to find the occasional entry
that's genuinely thoughtful or informative; but a recent 
                  Slate
               
redesign makes it easier to zoom through to the good stuff.)

            As several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> noted, the percentages <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> cited in his previous
item ("
Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vacations Kill?</ENAMEX>") overstate some vacation dangers in the sense
that, say, the higher incidence of drowning 
               deaths compared with
falling 
               deaths reflects the much greater number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
swim as compared with the number who climb mountains. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Similarly</ENAMEX>, the recent
increase in the number of amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> deaths may show not that
amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are more dangerous than they used to be, but that more people
go to them; though if more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are spending vacation time at amusement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX> , as compared with, say, spending them at art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> , that may
be making their vacations more dangerous in the aggregate.) On the other hand,
several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> noted, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spend a lot more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> at work than they do on vacation , on a per<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-hour</TIMEX> basis
vacation dangers may be understated by the data in the previous
item.

            Given these difficulties, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> still feels unequal to the task of
proving that vacations either are or aren't more dangerous than ordinary life.
(Perhaps inspiration will strike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX>.) But that doesn't mean
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is done with the topic of vacation dangers. Today, he turns his
attention to the ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> can kill you.

            We take for our text "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boating Statistics</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, whose expertise
on these matters is unmatched. According to the report, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700 to 800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> die
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>-related fatalities (which, significantly, do not include
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drownings</ENAMEX> and other water-related deaths by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who go out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, unless
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> itself is somehow responsible--as would be the case, for instance, if
someone died from falling off a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> rather than dying during a
deliberately planned swim or scuba dive; though if, during a deliberately
planned swim or scuba dive, someone were struck by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat propeller</ENAMEX> and killed,
that would count as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>-related fatality). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> , the number
who died in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>-related fatalities was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">821</NUMEX> . That comes out to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7</NUMEX> deaths per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> (this is approximate; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>
doesn't have data on every single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>). During the
previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, the fatality rate varied from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 6</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 8</NUMEX> deaths per
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> , even as the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> counted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> rose
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 10 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 12 million</NUMEX>. (The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">worst year</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> ,
when there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,036</NUMEX> boat-related fatalities , or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.4</NUMEX> fatalities per
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> .) But if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> was a not-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bad year</TIMEX>, relatively speaking,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>-related deaths , it was a terrible year, relatively speaking,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>-related injuries
               : there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,555</NUMEX> , a record
high.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Eighty-two percent</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>-related fatalities occurred on
boats shorter than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26 feet</NUMEX> in length. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than half</NUMEX> of these occurred
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than 16 feet</NUMEX> in length. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> percent of
boat-related fatalities occurred when someone who did not own the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> was
operating it. Open motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> were responsible for the vast majority of
boating-related fatalities , with canoes and kayaks ranking
a very distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. ( Open motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> were also responsible for the
vast majority of boat-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> admissions , with cabin
motorboats ranking a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and canoes and kayaks
ranking an even-more distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>; presumably if you get into a serious
accident on a kayak or canoe, it's more difficult to get yourself
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> .)

            A shockingly high proportion of boating accidents-- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
percent-- involve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> , and given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s incentive to lie about
such things and the difficulty of administering breathalyzer tests under such
circumstances, this statistic surely understates the problem. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, a boat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood alcohol</ENAMEX> concentration above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX>
percent is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10</NUMEX> times more likely to be killed in a boating accident as
a boat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood alcohol</ENAMEX> concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Hadley</ENAMEX>, a research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins School of Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Injury, Research</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy</ENAMEX>, an unbelievably high
proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who kill themselves on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> are male--based on his
research in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, it's something like <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>. That should be evident
not only by the high correlation between accidents and alcohol consumption, but
also by the other major factors causing boat accidents--excessive speed,
careless or reckless operation, inattention to what's looming up ahead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inexperience</ENAMEX>. (By comparison, "equipment failure" registers hardly at all.)
These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who get drunk and behave in stupid ways that are
characteristically (though of course not exclusively) male.

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apologia</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> of an earlier version of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> may have been
puzzled by its erroneous assertion that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, as counted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, rose from "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10,000</NUMEX> to about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,0000</NUMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1987 and 1997</TIMEX>. That should have read--and now does
read--"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 12 million</NUMEX>." Sorry for the mistake.]

         
      
   
