
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Laundry</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>'s dismissal of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who
worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> accounts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> stuffs this story,
and fronts an interview with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX> who supports the
conventional wisdom that both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and mobsters illegally
laundered money through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the indictment of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the story). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with talks held among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX>. Northeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are now reluctantly considering
much smaller reductions in nitrogen oxide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> than they had proposed. All
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> front the abandonment of space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mir</ENAMEX>, after 13 years
in orbit. The WP fronts political unrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>, a story the other
papers stuff.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>'s reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Edwards</ENAMEX>'
dismissal: She falsified bank records, refused to cooperate with an internal
investigation, and violated bank policies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> suggest what
these violations might be: She used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s name in dealings unrelated to
her job and she endorsed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s application for several accounts without
mentioning that they were married. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Berlin</ENAMEX>, who used
accounts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> to move <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $4 billion</NUMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benex</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with alleged mob ties. The papers delightedly mention the topic of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">speech Edwards</ENAMEX> gave at a recent conference: money laundering. International
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> continue to deny that funds were skimmed off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
accounts but admit that they've had accountability problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in the past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Banking Committee</ENAMEX> plans to hold hearings on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> money laundering in Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Khodorkovksy</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> pumped billions
of dollars out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> when insider information suggested that currency
devaluation was imminent. He also supports the conventional investigation
wisdom that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semyon Mogilevich</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> crime don, used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benex</ENAMEX> corporation
to launder money through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khodorkovsky</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s largest oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menatep</ENAMEX>, an
insolvent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menatep</ENAMEX>'s business relationship with and personal
connections to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> have brought it under scrutiny. Konstantin
Kagalovsky, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menatep</ENAMEX> and current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chairman</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khodorkovsky</ENAMEX>'s oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, is married to a (currently suspended) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who handled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> accounts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Ruiz Massieu</ENAMEX> is accused of using his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to extract bribes from
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX>. He has laundered over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 million dollars</NUMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and was arrested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> for attempting to smuggle currency out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Alternating</ENAMEX> attempts to indict and extradite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruiz Massieu</ENAMEX> have strained
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> relations for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, but the case for indictment has grown so
strong, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now supports the
proceedings.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> cite the same reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX>'s demise: failed
attempts to privatize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, the apathy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, and
pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and others to devote scarce funds to a proposed
multinational space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> will be sent to knock the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> out of
orbit to burn up in the atmosphere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that
no money has yet been earmarked for this elimination mission.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> helped persuade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">northeastern</ENAMEX> states to consider smaller levels of nitrogen oxide emission
reductions. Nitrogen oxides, a cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>, blow into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, making it especially difficult for northeastern cities
in the region to comply with the air quality standards of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Environmentalists</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> endorsed the shift
in stance to curry favor with other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> in hopes of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> vice
presidential nod.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> describe the conflict between the
constitutional assembly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Chavez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, which consists mainly of an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> of political and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>.
After the assembly passed orders to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from making new laws,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> attempted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to enter the locked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Capitol building</ENAMEX> in
defiance of the order. A scuffle ensued, injuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>-odd
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chavez</ENAMEX> says he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> are merely discarding a corrupt
governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> say he's short-circuiting democracy. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> adds that intervention of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> was helpful in
defusing the situation, which ended with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> retreating. Everyone
notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is "deeply concerned" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>'s efforts
to undermine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            
               High and dry: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reveals an unexpected effect of the
area's recent droughts. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flora</ENAMEX> everywhere withering and browning, carefully
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tended</ENAMEX>, thriving marijuana <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> stick out like sore green thumbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>
law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, using low flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> to detect the devil <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX>,
have seized twice as many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> as they had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at this time last year</TIMEX>.
But the heat has taken its toll on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>'s quality: "This isn't good <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX>,"
bummed-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> report.

         
      
   
