
   
   
      
         
            Take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>
            

            The top issues are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grant of clemency for imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s official announcement of his presidential
candidacy. The death of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s tax cut and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s likely defection
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> also get discussed.

            The commentariat is nearly unanimous in its condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
clemency for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX> associated with a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
released <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo Jimenez</ENAMEX>, appears on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press . He does not make a good impression. He rocks back and forth,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swivels</ENAMEX> in his chair, stutters, and shows little, if any, remorse for FALN
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bombings</ENAMEX>--though he does renounce violence. (See quotations from the interview
below.) Later in the program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> spars with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX> over
the clemency issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX>--who, as usual, looks like a lizard on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amphetamines</ENAMEX>--notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> and many religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Tutu</ENAMEX>, support the clemency. But on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> scoffs at this defense. For a while, he says, 
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wouldn't even take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s phone calls, so it's absurd to think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now takes his advice on domestic policy. And on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> speaks for many when he asks, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can</ENAMEX>
you explain to me how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who wants you to go to jail if you don't have
a trigger lock is going to say that these [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>] should be released, even
though they were collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>?" As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s belated disagreement with
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> over the clemency, even her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>--note that the move has only confirmed the stereotype of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> as tin-eared and imperious.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s speech announcing his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidacy</ENAMEX>, as well as his rising polls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> says
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> are actually worried about peaking too soon. Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opinion-makers</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign is "getting into desperate trouble"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> ) thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> might lose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>'s
endorsement if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> brings <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>. But
despite all this, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is still the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to
beat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will have to win
both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> to have a chance at the nomination, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ) warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> could veer too far left to remain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electable</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, concede that tax cuts is a no-win issue this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )--think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will make taxes a
campaign issue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Tumulty</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) note the oddity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> wanting to spend the
surplus and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> wanting to pay down the debt.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> all but announces his defection to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. "I'm leaning in that direction now--strongly," he says. "I
genuinely believe I could win the presidency of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. I think the
road through the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>] primaries ... [it's] almost closed and rigged. But the
door is really wide open [with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>]." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> promises not to
renounce his pro-life views, but stresses that abortion is the only issue on
which he and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> disagree. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s apparent involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> will
only serve to further alienate the isolationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
mainstream. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) flashes a poll indicating
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> would consume nearly all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">three-way race</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan Bludgeoning Grilling Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> spends most of the interview imputing
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s views on foreign policy are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>. As evidence, he trots
out a quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s new book (buy it here ) arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy is hostage to
ethnic lobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> is the most powerful. Now,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> may in fact be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>--many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> neo-cons think
so--but a pundit as grizzled as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> should know better than to make such a
serious accusation without serious evidence.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repent</ENAMEX>? No. Renounce? Yes.
On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> asks released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> prisoner
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo Jimenez</ENAMEX>, "If you in fact are part of an organ, in support of an organ,
that sets off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> bombs, isn't there a pretty strong possibility that innocent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to be hurt and killed<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No, no.</ENAMEX>"

            "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One hundred thirty</TIMEX> bombs--taverns, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, places where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>
frequent?"

            "No, no. If, if, if, precautions--I think all precautions were taken, you
know, to make sure all human life was preserved."

             Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimenez</ENAMEX> says: "I definitely will not be using any violence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whatsoever</ENAMEX>, or acts of violence, to further any goals of the independence
[movement] of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
