
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX> vs. Having It Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent</ENAMEX>,

            Thanks for your message. First things <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-please call me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamar</ENAMEX>. After all,
we're having breakfast-and, effectively, lunch-together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> long. More
interesting still, on this at least, we don't seem to disagree all that much.
Maybe we should dine together more often? (As you can see, even though I write
about politics, I don't really relish or even like the battle part of it. It's
sappy, I know-and maybe because I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, or a rationalist-but I always want
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to find common ground and settle on some middling, "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-way"
solution.)

            That's why I think of myself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX> (I've also been known to vote
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">liberal Republican</ENAMEX>)-which I gather you do not like. And as you suggest, it's
what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s left-leaning political establishment-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Serrano</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX> and the rest-really don't like about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. Sure, these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are unhappy that she didn't come to them to kiss their rings and inquire
before she took a stand on any issues they claim to care about. But more than
that, what they really can't abide-and you don't like so much either, I
gather?-is that she isn't going to turn out to be the all-or-nothing,
never-compromise, hard-core leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have always expected
she would be.

            So I should be pleased, right? Well, not so fast. Because I don't think
she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX>, either-she's certainly no credit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Democratic</ENAMEX>
movement I'm sometimes drawn to. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX> doesn't just mean political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunist</ENAMEX>. It doesn't mean tacking and trying to have it both ways-as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
is indeed trying to do, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has been doing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now. Unlike
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opportunists</ENAMEX> and others like them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who truly occupy
what's sometimes called "the vital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX>" find a way to go beyond ideology
with practical, problem-solving positions that borrow from both sides and
appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> across the spectrum. When it's done right, it's not about
hedging. It's about real political creativity and the much needed balancing of
conflicting political interests. (And it usually ends up alienating political
regulars on both sides of the aisle.) True enough (I concede in advance), there
aren't many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> out there who actually live up to this standard-but let's not
give the vital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> a bad name by pretending that it's no more than dishonest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tacking</ENAMEX>.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, well, I'm not a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of those lefty ideological positions
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serrano, et al</ENAMEX> hoped she would champion, but in the end I would
have respected her more for that than for the unprincipled hedging that you so
rightly point out is apparently going to be her hallmark. All these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, I
thought she was urging Bill to stick to his left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. But now it turns
out she's the one who's been arguing all along that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> should
trim and hedge and give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> whatever it is they seem to want. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
advice was "Just say no"; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s is apparently "Just say anything-as long as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> wants to hear it." It's going to be a great campaign to watch and
write about, but I agree with you-following her is going to make us all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dizzy</ENAMEX>.

            Whoops! It's almost cocktail hour and I'm going on as if it were still
breakfast. Let's talk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>' appeal for minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>?

            Looking forward to it, whatever it is.

            All best,
Tamar

         
      
   
