
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan Finds Enlightenment</ENAMEX>
            

            As has become usual, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> at the gathering of
the world's central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson Hole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyo.</ENAMEX>, has been ardently
scrutinized by both the financial press and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> anxious to figure out
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> is planning to raise interest rates anytime soon.
What's occasioned the most notice, fittingly enough, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s argument
that central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> needed to pay attention to asset prices--like, oh, the
stock market--in addition to the prices of normal goods and services if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> want to have a handle on what may drive inflation in the future.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> have also remarked that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s speech, far from being
"a stark warning," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> termed it, was a tempered acknowledgement that
even central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> have a hard time figuring out when markets are overvalued.
That, in turn, suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> understands now that his "irrational
exuberance" speech of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> was precisely what it was, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
attempt to outthink a market that it is very difficult to outthink. What's
especially curious about this is that one would have thought this was a
conclusion a supposedly ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotee</ENAMEX> of the free market would have reached a
long time ago.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, of course, has never ascribed to himself (at least not in
public--who knows what he thinks as he sits contentedly in his bathtub) the
level of wisdom and farsightedness that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have come to grant him. His
remarks are typically shrouded and hedged, and though it is of course the job
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> to restrain inflation and promote economic growth, which requires
him to make at least educated guesses about the future, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> generally
does seem well aware of the limits of his own knowledge.

            This is as it should be, since a fundamental principle of a free-market
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> is that the market knows more than any individual within it. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s comments on the stock market--including, but not limited to, the
"irrational exuberance" speech--have been oddly dismissive of that principle,
and oddly certain that something like a bubble was in place. In his speech on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> acknowledged that market prices are determined by
"<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of investors</NUMEX>, many of whom are highly knowledgeable about the
prospects for the specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>" that make up the market indices.

            Even more important, perhaps, he suggested that the unprecedented rise in
stock prices over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> in particular was due to a substantive
change in the way the market discounted the future. Obviously, we don't know
exactly what that change is, but it does seem as if stock-market investors
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> think stocks are less risky than they once did, believe that inflation is
not a long-term threat, and believe that the economic dominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--and the extraordinary recent growth in corporate profits--can be
extended for a long period of time. Put those things together, and you end up
with a strong case for higher stock prices. Any or all of those assumptions may
be wrong, of course, but in pointing to the discounting process in particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> did something important, which was get away from the simple idea of
"irrationality" and move toward a more rigorous analysis of what's been
happening.

            The other thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s speech signaled is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is not
going to jack up interest rates just to prick a stock-market bubble, imagined
or not. In emphasizing that the best, and clearest, use of monetary policy is
to revive an economy in the wake of a deflationary crash by cutting
rates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> seemed to acknowledge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> was ill-equipped to be in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of figuring out what stock prices should be. The point of watching
asset prices for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is to understand whether the wealth effect is helping
rev the economy beyond sustainable growth. It's not to scold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. We may
be heading for a crash (though I don't think so). But if we are, we'll get
there all on our own. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> won't be giving us a push.

         
      
   
