
   
   
      
         
            Never Trust a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel Guide</ENAMEX>
            

            Say what you might about travel guides, I'll always respect a literary form
that can be field tested. For the benefit of eavesdroppers, I've included a
thumbnail sketch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of our little experiment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor's</ENAMEX> is the gold-plated grandam of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> guidebook scene. No
matter how old you are, this is probably the guide your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> use. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets well-to-do</ENAMEX>, graying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>, but aspires to youthful
hipness with the occasional off-the-cuff, misguided pop-culture references:
"Keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> distracted is key [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] to making sure your stay
doesn't turn into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes</ENAMEX> cartoon." If they delight in misusing
outdated slang like "jiggy," this is probably the guide your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> use.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight Guides</ENAMEX> are "softer," emphasizing glossy photos and punchy
captions over facts like prices and opening <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compass America</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor</ENAMEX>'s
associate, is stylistically a synthesis of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> models.

            A backpacker favorite, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX>'s guides advocate a budget-minded,
low-impact approach to travel. They're the only guides we are discussing that
didn't originate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and are still largely targeted at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Isles</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> feel a great
affinity to [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway tokens</ENAMEX>, akin to what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in general
feel about their useless <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one-cent</NUMEX> coin ..."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brainchild</ENAMEX> of information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Saul Wurman</ENAMEX>, the Access
Guides seek to better the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guidebook</ENAMEX>'s always rocky marriage of maps and text.
Though the books are not actually written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wurman</ENAMEX>, his name graces the cover
and the spine, lending credence to the idea that one need be neither much of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traveler</ENAMEX> nor much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to be a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Testing Ground No. 1</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>. All the books agreed that this
was a worthy site, and they all had the same advice on how best to see it: Get
there for the earliest ferry and beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> in the race to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Liberty</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crown</ENAMEX>, where spectacular views of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> await. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guidebooks</ENAMEX> disagreed on
(or simply didn't mention) when the first ferry actually left, but none quoted
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a time</TIMEX> earlier than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:15 a.m.</TIMEX> But when I arrived at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:45</TIMEX>, a sign informed me
that the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30</TIMEX> ferry had already left, and that only those lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> aboard
would be admitted to the crown. Here I learned (or rather, relearned) a
valuable travel lesson: Never trust a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>. If a guidebook fact is
going to make or break your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation day</TIMEX>, you'd better call and double-check it
yourself. The disclaimers in the books tell you as much themselves.

            Which begs the question: Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (myself included) continue to rely on
(and delight in) products that so frequently prove unreliable? And how can so
many guides to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> alone has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> titles) prosper, and inspire
fierce brand loyalty, when they all say approximately the same thing? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> is just the beginning: From Wall Street to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>, there is
almost no disagreement about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s worthiest sights.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Testing Ground No. 2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>. I was intrigued to see how the guides covered
areas perceived as dangerous by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> with whom I spoke. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> warns
that uptown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s sights are best seen by bus tour. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet rails</ENAMEX>
against this ghetto safari mentality, chastising, "If you're too scared to go
on your own, stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midtown</ENAMEX>." While I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LP</ENAMEX>'s assessment (I visited
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, without incident), the haughty tone is a bit troubling.
Have you noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> are always quick to ridicule other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>?
Budget guides can be particularly harsh: Is this a considered reaction to the
economic and environmental damage that higher-end and package tourism can
cause, or just knee-jerk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">irreverence</ENAMEX>?

            Should travel guides educate their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, or simply pander to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">preconceived</ENAMEX> notions? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Polo</ENAMEX> (and even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Frommer</ENAMEX>), travel guides were written by bona fide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, and people
who bought them were unfamiliar with the places they described. But mass media
has made armchair travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> out of all of us, at least in the cases of
such high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>: We know, or at least think we
know, what these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are about, and what we want to see when we're there. In
theory, it's thrilling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can travel farther from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, and that they
know more before they arrive, but is the end result simply longer lines at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hard Rock Cafe</ENAMEX>? Can travel guides still gently
educate their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, or have they merely become handmaidens, shuttling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over-visited landmark to the next?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, how things are going in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>? Are you finding any substantive
differences in the way your guides cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>? Are they at least getting
you to the ferries on time?

         
      
   
