
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Birthday</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>!

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> received an e-mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy McCain</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>). The e-mail,
addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s candidacy, conveyed the following
secret: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s birthday is this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 29th</TIMEX>! To help him celebrate I
have arranged to surprise him with a special gift in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>. Please click on
the following for the details of his surprise."

            Unable to resist the invitation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> clicked the designated link and
was transported to a page on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2000</NUMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> Web site. Under the headline,
"Happy
Birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>!," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX> explained that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has been so busy
campaigning, "I doubt if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> has given any thought to the fact that he will
turn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63 this Sunday</TIMEX>. That's why I'm excited about my plans to surprise him with
a special birthday gift in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 29th</TIMEX>." The gift, she confided,
will be "a specially-designed Birthday Card that carries your personal best
wishes as well as those of so many of his most ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. I
know I can count on you to participate in this project."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX> continued: "And to make sure we can keep the momentum <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s campaign and guarantee that he will have the financial resources needed
to get his positive, conservative, and independent reform message out to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, I'm also hoping you can contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $63</NUMEX>, along with your
birthday greetings. Your contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $1</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>--will be a
special way to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> for all he's done for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. And if we
can meet our goal to present him with a birthday campaign check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63,000</NUMEX> to
accompany our special card, it will give him the added financial boost that's
so necessary to carry his campaign forward. But right now, time is of the
essence. To make sure your e-mail will arrive before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 29th</TIMEX>, and be
included in the special birthday album we will present to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, I must hear
from you soon. That is why I urge you to contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63</NUMEX>--or whatever amount you
can forward at this time."

            Chatterbox, whose passion is to be in on secrets, felt deeply honored to be
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX>'s invitation list. But a sad thought occurred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>: What
about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>, if not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> who
haven't received <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX>'s e-mail? Will they miss out on the surprise? So
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> decided to use this space to get the word out. Pssst! All of you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> out there--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is planning a surprise for him this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Go to his campaign Web site to get the details. And above all-- don't
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>!
            

         
      
   
