
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unequal Distribution of Physical Fitness</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> has a cover story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Why We Take Risks</ENAMEX>," that bears some superficial resemblance to
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> columns on vacations that kill. (See "
Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vacations Kill?</ENAMEX>" and "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Idiots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Their Boats</ENAMEX>.") Essentially it's a story about "extreme sports,"
whose rise in popularity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> links, somewhat unconvincingly, to day
trading and "unprotected sex" and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> use. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports that while
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, touch <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, and aerobics are declining in popularity, riskier
sports like snowboarding and scuba diving are becoming more popular. "By every
statistical measure available," the article says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are participating
in and injuring themselves through adventure sports at an unprecedented
rate."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> piece isn't nearly as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Koerner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News cover story on the same subject <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years back</TIMEX>.
(Chatterbox should probably disclose here that he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
at the time, though he had nothing to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koerner</ENAMEX>'s story.) A more serious
problem, though, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s story is apt to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with the
impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are engaging in more physical activity than they used
to. In fact, overall, they may be engaging in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less</TIMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> report on "Physical Activity and
Health" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Surgeon General</ENAMEX> complains that
"despite common knowledge that exercise is healthful, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 60 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are not regularly active, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of the adult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> are not active at all." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> are particularly sedentary: "Nearly
half of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-21 years of age</TIMEX> are not vigorously active; moreover,
physical activity sharply declines during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">adolescence</TIMEX>." This is typically
characterized as a national decline in physical fitness, attributable to
excessive TV-watching. That may be an exaggeration; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have been
complaining about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' sedentary habits for some time. (According to
another section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General</ENAMEX>'s report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> made a fuss back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX> over a study called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Muscular Fitness and</ENAMEX>
Health" by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> that stated that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56.6 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> "failed to meet even a minimum standard required for
health.")

            But even if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are no lazier in the aggregate than they were 40 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, the rise of "extreme sports" underscores a trend that's a bit different
and more interesting than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is promoting: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Namely</ENAMEX>, that a
small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> is engaging in pathologically daring leisure activities requiring
unprecedented physical fitness, while the rest of us are getting fat on chips
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> while we watch these gladiators on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>. From a social-justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, the danger of extreme sports is an inadvertent equalizer. These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unbelievably</ENAMEX> fit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may be as likely to die young as the physically unfit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> are, if not more so (though not, of course, of the same cardiovascular
causes). A better way to achieve equality would be a redistribution of physical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fitness</ENAMEX> in which everybody engages in sensible, moderate exercise, and
nobody engages in BASE (an acronym for "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, antenna, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX>,
earth"), which, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>, involves hurtling off a cliff or a
bridge on a bicycle with a parachute on your back.

         
      
   
