
   
   
      
         
            Who's Afraid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>?

            You'd think that gossips everywhere--which is to say, everyone
everywhere--would be grateful. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s latest innovation, its "purchase circles," lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in one Zip code or at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
company see what books are selling well among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in other Zip codes or
at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Videos</ENAMEX> and CDs, too, but somehow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> isn't as
interested in them.) So, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, who lives in suburban
Pelham, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, and works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice McDermott</ENAMEX>'s novel Charming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business @ the Speed of Thought</ENAMEX> are the two
top books, respectively--gets not only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>
but also to find out what her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anniston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> at a competing high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, are reading: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Jenkins</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim LaHaye</ENAMEX>'s wacked-out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> sci-fi thriller Apollyon: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Destroyer Is Unleashed</ENAMEX> , and a boring-sounding book called The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zone: How Strategic Business Design Will Lead You to Tomorrow's Profits</ENAMEX> ,
respectively. This strangely satisfying form of literary eavesdropping,
achieved by a simple re-sorting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' e-mail domain names, shipping
addresses, and purchases, is not limited to the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
What's hot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>? A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX>-page scholarly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tome</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bomb</ENAMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esmeralda Santiago</ENAMEX>'s memoir <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Almost a Woman</ENAMEX> . In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Drucker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Management Challenges for the</ENAMEX>
21st <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>.
            

            Purchase circles are a simple but brilliant conceptual coup. Whoever thought
them up understood a fundamental principle of salesmanship, or rather, herd
psychology: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want to know what everyone else in their peer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is
doing, so they can do it too. Statistically speaking, the data are meaningless,
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> doesn't reveal the sample size behind each list. There could
be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from 3,000 to three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pelham making Charming Billy</ENAMEX>
its best seller. But no one's claiming that these lists represent some larger
truth about the book market (such truths are elusive, anyway, since publishers
are notoriously secretive about sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>). They're a hint of the regional
and cultural differences among us, no more, as well as the mildly galling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">similarities</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Harris</ENAMEX> top the book lists in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>). Plus they're fun. Who
could fail to be titillated by the fact that the No. 2 best-selling book in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kosher Sex: A Guide to Passion and Intimacy</ENAMEX> ?

            Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Booksellers Association</ENAMEX> and Internet privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, for
starters. They consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s purchase circles an invasion of privacy, yours
and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s. Certain exaggerations aside--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could deduce a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s secret strategies or level of workplace satisfaction from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' reading lists, for instance--their argument amounts to the old
slippery slope: If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> will do this, what else will it do? The answer, of
course, is as much as it can get away with. If you don't already know that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> is keeping a file on you, you ought to be forbidden to shop on the
Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s business strategy has been widely publicized: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>
believes that if it ever turns a profit, it will do so by exploiting
information gained from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to sell them other products. Since the
integrity of its customer database is of tremendous importance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, we
can probably take its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at their word when they say (in a policy page that appears to have gone up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>) that
they won't give out any information that could identify you personally. For
instance, no purchase circle is being created for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 200</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has no reason to want to piss you off.

            That's why much of the alarm about Internet privacy strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> as
Chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little</ENAMEX>-ish. Consumer rage is disastrous for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> whose profits,
present or future, depend on its ability to compile and deploy information on
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. There are just too many ways for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> to undermine the
data-collection process. At <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, for instance, they can "opt out" of both
purchase circles and general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> profiling by sending in blank e-mails.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> can keep themselves out of purchase circles by faxing in a request.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> get mad enough, they can bail out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> altogether and buy
their books at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble Online</ENAMEX>, which as yet does not have purchase
circles. If enough <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> "opt out," it might be reduced to offering
them discounts or other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX> to "opt in"--which would be fabulous for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> but of dubious economic value to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colleague Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX> has shown.

            Obviously, sometimes the privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are right. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> they're also
upset about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S West</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>-based phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that recently won on
good reason to be. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> had tried to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S West</ENAMEX> (and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> who became party to the suit) from exploiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s personal
information--calls made, services ordered, etc.--to sell that customer more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and products. (The ruling did not give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the right to sell
this data to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that keeping a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> from using
its customer databases to inform its sales pitches infringed on its free
commercial speech. That seems true in general--why shouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> use what
you freely give them?--but wrong in this case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S West</ENAMEX> has a virtual monopoly
on local phone service in its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>, so the usual free-market remedies don't
apply.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would urge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to have faith in the power of corporate
self-interest to protect them, at least in non-monopolistic situations, except
that she's not convinced that that's what's really causing the general public
to wax wroth. She suspects it's more what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s invention reveals about
shopping nowadays: that it takes place inside an endless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of mirrors. After
all, what's better than shopping? Watching ourselves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. Watching ourselves
being watched as we shop. Watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> who watch us as we shop. Ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infinitum</ENAMEX> and nauseum .

         
      
   
