
   
   
      
         
            How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Out-Travel Your Travel Guide</ENAMEX>
            

            My trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> began fantastically, thanks. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, I jumped
out of bed early and headed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell Street Market</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s famous
once-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-week</TIMEX> open-air bazaar. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boomed</ENAMEX>, and the market now hosts a veritable food fair of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> delicacies.
Squeezed amid the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booths</ENAMEX> hawking used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> fenders, lacy underwear, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$15</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bootleg</ENAMEX> copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Windows</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'98</ENAMEX> are makeshift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, constructed
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> out of tarps and folding chairs. I wandered for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>, sampling
a ceviche-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish salad</ENAMEX>, spiked with lime, cilantro, and hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>; tamales
coated in a green mole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tasted</ENAMEX> differently with every second it
lingered on my tongue; and for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>, golden <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">empanadas</ENAMEX> filled with creamy
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice pudding</ENAMEX>. Nothing I ate cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $3</NUMEX>. I want to go back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Sunday</TIMEX>,
so I can try the cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shrimp soup</ENAMEX>, the goat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tacos</ENAMEX>, and the
Bavarian-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>-flavored churros.

            But I didn't find out about the market's delights from any of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guidebooks</ENAMEX>. Its charms are no secret-in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, the market has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saveur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>-but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor's</ENAMEX> (which boasts of its coverage of "off and on the beaten path" sites)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Access</ENAMEX> (the cover of which claims to make "the world your neighborhood")
don't mention the market even once. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight Guide</ENAMEX> describes its past
incarnations-as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> peddlers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1880s</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>'s market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, and a place to watch busking blues
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50s</NUMEX>-but says it's now just a place to buy fake <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolex</ENAMEX>
watches. My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compass Guide</ENAMEX> dismisses the current market a "sanitized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>"
to the old. And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX>, with its orthodox adherence to alternative
travel, has some good historical scraps-a block of the old market once seceded
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and established an anarchist country-but barely mentions
any reasons to go now.

            Oddly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell Street Market</ENAMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> than the others,
mentioning the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>, if not their offerings. Even better, it lists the
market's Web site. The other books contain a smattering of travel sites,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> is alone in listing Web addresses for every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>,
and attraction that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. This is an easy and obvious solution to one of the
biggest weaknesses of guidebooks, which is that they're out of date from the
moment they're printed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, for example, you could have theoretically
logged on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>'s Web site to find the correct departure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for the ferry.

            However, this was pretty much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer</ENAMEX>'s only virtue. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of the
book unironically quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel & Leisure</ENAMEX> review calling the book
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cronkite</ENAMEX> of guidebooks-with all that implies." Clearly, this is not
a guidebook for jetsetters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure travelers</ENAMEX>, or anyone else who might
consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronkite</ENAMEX> a less-than-ideal tour guide. As you say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> is very
much our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX>.

            But even older and tamer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> deserve better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX>. The book
breezes through the architecture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Loop</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s spectacular downtown--in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pages. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are dismissed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three</TIMEX> sentences. Dates and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> for some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are listed, but others are mysteriously omitted.
(In contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight Guide</ENAMEX> gives Loop architecture <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer</ENAMEX>'s devotes an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times more copy to hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">décor</ENAMEX> than to the
design of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. For example, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-sentence review of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampton Inn</ENAMEX> notes that its interior "takes inspiration from the Prairie
architectural style, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">woodsy lobby</ENAMEX> with slipcovered furniture
and a few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> architectural artifacts, feels like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
Guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are residential and warm, with framed collages of vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
postcards on the walls." Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rookery Building</ENAMEX> and its famous Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Wright</ENAMEX> lobby get one line. I also found a historical error-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> says
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recorded settlement was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1781</TIMEX>. Not to
quibble over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> could have checked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library</ENAMEX>'s timeline or the other guidebooks, which list the correct
date as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1779</TIMEX>.

            What fun it was to write that last paragraph. Did I detect a similar note of
triumph in your voice when you caught the guidebooks flubbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty</ENAMEX> schedules? Maybe this is the answer to your (excellent) question about
why we buy and tote around guides we know are flawed, outdated, and out of
style. My trips often become contests between myself and my guidebooks: Can I
do them one better, finding more inside information, local color, novel tastes,
and great prices than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>? When I saw the paltry descriptions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX> Street market, I felt a small rush-I had out-traveled the travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>.

            Or at least I've out-traveled my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. You're right about how
quick these books are to ridicule other voyagers. Rather than showing real
concern for the impact of camera-toting hordes or knee-jerk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">irreverence</ENAMEX>, I
think the books are dispensing garden-variety flattery, making you feel
superior to the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> ticket line. Traveling has become subtly
competitive, with all of us vying for maximum independence, authenticity, and
adventure. Buy me, boast the books, and you won't be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugliest American</ENAMEX>.

            But there's only so much exoticism to be had, especially in well-trodden
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. In fact, hipster travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallpaper</ENAMEX> have recently been taking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> approach
to oft-visited locales, telling their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to embrace their tourist status,
to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle Line</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cruises</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and ride to the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Could this be the backlash to the never-ending search for novelty and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">virgin territory</ENAMEX>? I'm not sure where the backlash would hit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, but
I'll keep my eyes open for fashion models wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> shirts and white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">patent-leather</ENAMEX> shoes.

            Thanks for the thumbnail sketches; I'll try to cover more books <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. In
the meantime, if you had to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> guidebook to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, which would it be?
And which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> have you already chucked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
