
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acquisition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Karmazin</ENAMEX>
            

            If there's anything odd about the just-announced merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, it's that it seems utterly quaint to worry about whether the concentration
of so many cable, radio, network TV, and Internet assets in one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is the
best thing for the free flow of information in a democracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> regulations may
require the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> to sell a few of its TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>--because there's a rule
saying one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can't own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> that serve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 35 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>--and to either spin off or fold in the still-struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX>. But
for all intents and purposes, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 billion</NUMEX> deal is done.

            When you think about whether it should have been done, you end up
confronting again a central paradox of the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: The more
fragmented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> and consumer markets become, the more important scale
appears to be. That's true both because the larger you are, the easier it is
for you to re-purpose content across many different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> (how's that for a
jargon-laden clause) and the easier it is for you to promote that content in
many different places. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the ability to distribute content (and
advertising) is probably as important as the ability to produce content, and
even though in the age of the Internet and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>-channel cable systems you'd think
anyone can get a message out there, successful distribution is still basically
all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about aggregating</NUMEX> lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> could do that just
by broadcasting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All in the Family</ENAMEX> . Today, it has to use its radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>, its billboards, its TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, and its broadcasts. But the fact
that it can use all those different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> is essential.

            Now, you could think of this as synergy. And certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>, likes that idea, as evidenced by things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>'s
selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>'s releasing The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rugrats</ENAMEX> movie, and so on.
But in a way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX>'s "content is king" refrain seems a bit old-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> next
to the "distribution is king" refrain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Karmazin</ENAMEX>, who is head of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> and
will be the operational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX> has done an excellent
job of managing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX>, selling off assets, paying
down debt, and generally focusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> on its core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. But it's
who's really essential to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>'s future, because it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX> who recognizes
that no matter what you make, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't see it or hear it, it doesn't
matter.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX>'s relentless focus on shareholder value and his essential frugality
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> have long distinguished him from the media moguls--like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redstone</ENAMEX>--who spent much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '90s</TIMEX> borrowing huge sums of
money to make questionable acquisitions and engage in hostile takeover battles.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> from radio chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinity Broadcasting</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> still
owns), and brought to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> a measure of economic rigor that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> was
hard to find in the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. When you listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karmazin</ENAMEX>, you get the
feeling you're listening to someone who thinks that media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> should be
judged by the same economic and business standards as other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, as
opposed to someone who thinks that media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> should be valued by the
grandiosity of their dreams. Needless to say, this is a good thing.

            The irony, though, is that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX> is the new-model media exec
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX>" being a word that doesn't fit), one of his greatest strengths is his
ability to recognize the value of the seemingly mundane. Radio and outdoor
advertising, for instance, are incredibly un-glamorous. But they're also
fast-growing markets (unlike, for example, television or even the movies), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX> has ensured that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> has reaped great benefits from them. Local TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> are similarly boring, but while they are not the cash <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> they once
were, they're still very profitable, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX> has agitated (successfully)
for a relaxation of federal regulations to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> to own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
station in a given market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable</ENAMEX> is not a booming business--though it may be in
the future once we all go to digital cable--but it is a profitable one, and
this deal gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX> a host of cable networks to play with. All mergers
should, given the historical record, be greeted with skepticism. But in
acquiring the rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karmazin</ENAMEX>'s services and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s assets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX>
may have made the best decision of his business career.

         
      
   
