
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Massaging the Press; Pressing the Flesh</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tamar</ENAMEX>,

            Take it easy there. I did not intend to cast aspersion. But you seemed to be
upset that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> and tried to feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>'s pain. I agree that these episodes can be awkward-and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, if they are
awkward for you, how do you think they feel for me. But the fawning often stems
from a naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earnestness</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s. Sometimes it stems from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s failure to understand that black and brown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> have pretty much
the same interests as white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. They want: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to work; the jobs to
be plentiful; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> to be safe.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> coming to shake hands at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, perhaps it was
"a throwaway" as you say-but no more so (and quite probably less so)
than shaking hands with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> conference
are opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>, many of them. What they do and say could end up being
crucial as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of this campaign grind forward. In short, when things get
tight, many of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity-goers</ENAMEX> will be rendering opinions in cold, hard
print. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would have been ill-advised to pass them by.

            I remember covering the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'92</TIMEX> and thinking, My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, what a shaker of hands and massager of backs! I asked him way back then
what it would take to win. He said, "Give the same speech everywhere. Shake
hands (meaning 'touch') as many as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible." I thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> is confident of his power to press the flesh." But flesh-pressing is the
stuff that the trade is made of and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> did it better than anybody. The issues
are important, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tamar</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> tend to make powerful, intestinally based
judgments of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s likability. Which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> has a chance against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>-and why his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            I apologize for not having read your book. But there is still time.

            As for the "hard" issues, I take it that you mean affirmative action. We
will in fact get to that in the campaign, but you cannot blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for not
rushing to an issue that has been so heavily contaminated with ill will in the
post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era. In any case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> has worked around the problem in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-Hopwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. They simply invoked the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> rule, accepting the top
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> at ole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longhorn U.</ENAMEX> This is less
than optimal but will have to do until we can summon the political will to
improve the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that serve black and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. I wrote
a column recently about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX> (slayer of affirmative action in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>) embracing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> lawsuit that charges <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> with failing to
provide qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and advanced-placement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>-as required in state law. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connerly</ENAMEX> stared right in the face of a
"hard question" and made an honorable choice, don't you think?

         
      
   
