
   
   
      
         
            Indo-amnesia

            The continuing violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
off-leads the story, choosing instead to go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s selection, to be
announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, of ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Danforth</ENAMEX> to head up an independent executive
branch re-investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> operations at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says that the choice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> is an effort to quell bitter
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>, exemplified by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s call by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> for her resignation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s off-lead, but it's
not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> or USAT fronts. Nobody besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fronts Danforth</ENAMEX>.

            The USAT <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> goes high with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s decision, driven by a fear of
abandoning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> to murdering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>, to buy some time by delaying until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the planned evacuation of its remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The
paper also detects the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> stirrings, however faint: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> steaming to the area, and talks between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militaries</ENAMEX>. But, the coverage notes, despite what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls a
"scorched earth" situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is not ready to send in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is willing to support the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multinational</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> has volunteered to lead but
only if it is invited in by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Timor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front-pager</ENAMEX> focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> tempo,
noting for instance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> is taking the lead there,
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> trying to jawbone <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> into
personally taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> control of the situation. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that
threatening to halt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> isn't much of a stick: this
currently totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$476,000</NUMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also observes (as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> )
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> may serve as a powerful brake on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misbehavior</ENAMEX>, in that
it has promised, but not yet delivered, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of billions</NUMEX> in emergency financial
support. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead leans more toward on-the-ground details.
Like: "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convoy</ENAMEX> that had left the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> to retrieve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> from a
warehouse turned back when it was attacked by militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-16</ENAMEX> assault
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rifles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machetes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> stood by as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> dragged a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX> out of a truck and threatened to kill him."

            It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead that writes the story from the most basic
humanitarian point of view. Its very first sentence throws down the moral
gauntlet: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six months</TIMEX> after leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> into a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78-day</TIMEX> air war campaign to stop
'ethnic cleansing' in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and serving notice that it would not let such
human-rights atrocities go unchallenged again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has
decided to limit its military role." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> comes close to this pitch
at times, referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> "calculation" favoring "mineral-rich" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX> impoverished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. Next to these challenges, the official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
explanations for military inaction seem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>. "Because we bombed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
doesn't mean we should bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Berger</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> national security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honcho</ENAMEX>, "explains" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . An unnamed senior administration official
(=<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>?) tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> because ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is a repeat offender. Democracy doesn't exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> has brought democracy to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs inside, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s telephone
conversation between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said the corruption charges against him are politically inspired.
Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that in response to a direct question from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> flatly denied the charges. But another says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repudiation</ENAMEX> was less than categorical.

            
               Tip <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#6</NUMEX>: Wait Until <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yom Kippur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When They're Weak From Hunger The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptist Church</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> released a
pocket-sized prayer guide for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> that offers tips about how to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">evangelize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> during their <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Holy Days when</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> explains,
"they are sensitized to spiritual matters."

            A recurring feature in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that revisits items from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archives</ENAMEX> today covers an entry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Sept. 9, 1974</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pardoned Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> report contains an unjustly ignored
example of the fine old political art of deceiving without lying: When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> was
asked at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential confirmation hearings if he would ever pardon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> if he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he replied, "I don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would
stand for it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>'s "Business Bulletin" reports that a
new Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> intends to focus on making loans to gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lesbians</ENAMEX>. The item quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>'s assessment: "To succeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G&L Bank</ENAMEX>
will have to be competitive on products and rates and offer more than lip
service."

         
      
   
