
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Ignorant</ENAMEX> Slut

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thought on reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Search of Herself</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Bedell Smith</ENAMEX>'s
deliriously mean-spirited (though boringly written) catalog of all the ways the
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy-tale princess</ENAMEX> turns out to have been troubled, trite, and
exasperating, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> didn't get its money's worth from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. During her marriage, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
cost her subjects <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,287</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>). Much of that paid for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothing</ENAMEX>, cosmetics, hair styling, physical and speech training, health care,
beauty treatments, fancy vacations, and a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>--all legitimate
expenses for a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> whose job it is to be a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>.
(Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> would pay their royals to do such a job is another
question.)

            If you go by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s account, the rest must have gone to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a surprisingly
large number of cell-phone calls--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 20</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--to a surprisingly
large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternative therapists</ENAMEX>--astrologists (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spiritualists</ENAMEX> (including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clairvoyant</ENAMEX> who put her in touch with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandmother</ENAMEX>), a tarot card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, an energy healer, a hypnotherapist, an
"anger-release" therapist, colonic irrigationists, osteopaths, chiropractors,
reflexologists, aromatherapists, shiatsu and tai <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chi chuan experts</ENAMEX>,
acupuncturists, and a "mind-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>" therapist, the last a former tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>
who gave her massages and diet advice; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) more conventional forms of treatment
for sleeplessness, eating disorders, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>, and self-mutilation, including
an episode in which she slashed her arms and smeared the blood all over the
walls of an airplane; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) lunch at fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> to which she secretly
invited tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> so she could drop by their tables and leak whatever
she wanted to appear in their publications <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>.

            When you think about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Item 4</ENAMEX> probably is in the job description
for an official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, which brings us to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reaction to
this book: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> got everything they paid for and more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was an ill-educated, impulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who spent her adult life reeling
from what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> dubiously diagnoses as a borderline personality disorder.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> knows as little about psychiatry as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> does, but she knows wild
analysis when she sees it.) Whatever the cause, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was depressed, secretive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoid</ENAMEX>, dissembling, self-loathing, desperately <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>, and unable to sustain
close relationships.

            Yet she was also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s most popular royal personage, a fact that now
seems not at all unrelated. When you know how unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was, you grasp
that it was her lack of self-control that fueled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s obsession. She got
our attention because she was cute, but she held it because she gave the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paparazzi</ENAMEX> so much to work with--all those unchecked expressions of slyness or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shyness</ENAMEX> or vulnerability or boredom, all that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sturm und Drang</ENAMEX> about
needing her privacy. Tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> put her on the cover day in and day out
because eating disorders and fainting fits made good copy, not out of sympathy
with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>. And since by the ironclad laws of yellow journalism the
famous have to be famous for something, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> became the universal symbol of
individual suffering, the victim of unfeeling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> everywhere. Others
might have found the attention devastating, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> must have been relieved
to find in the public eye the unflagging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, pity, and sense of drama
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> demanded, and failed to get, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> only
ever had one loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitor</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--and she quickly figured out how to win
its favor, cultivating tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> while complaining about their
impertinences, figuring out more often than not what to wear and say and how to
upstage the other royals.

            It was strangely easy for her to outfox the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. No rational being, no
one concerned about shoring up a marriage or maintaining a position in society,
could have predicted what move <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> would make next. She leaked stories that
put her in a questionable light. She collaborated with a tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX>, on a royals-bashing biography that made divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' only
option. She defied everyone she knew, including her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, to go
on television for a notorious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> interview in which she came off as wildly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-pitying</ENAMEX> and un-self-aware. She flaunted her relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi</ENAMEX>, the
no-good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a corrupt and authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> never cared much
about being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>. She cared about being a celebrity, and her public
responded to her devotion by canonizing her: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Diana</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bathos</ENAMEX>. You'd have
to be mad to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> such a fate, but luckily, she was.

         
      
   
