
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slander Patrol: Did Bradley Flip Over Vouchers</ENAMEX>?

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> have been laying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">into Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> for reversing his position on school choice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Allesandro</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backer</ENAMEX>, was quoted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester Union</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> recently changed his
position from pro-voucher to anti-voucher "for political expediency." The
current issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> makes the same claim, charging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> with a
flip-flop on the issue.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> voted for experimental voucher programs in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as 1992</TIMEX> but now says he doesn't think vouchers are the
answer to problems of education. In an appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>--where
a voucher program has been the subject of a heated court battle--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> also
raised an objection to vouchers based on the separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and
state.

            Sounds like an open-and-shut case. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s position isn't really
contradictory. It's perfectly consistent--and reasonable--to support
small-scale experiments with vouchers while expressing skepticism about their
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">efficacy</ENAMEX> and about whether they can pass constitutional muster. The
argument is that since no one knows for certain what kind of education reform
will ultimately be most effective, we should try a lot of different ideas on a
relatively small scale. This was, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s stated position when he
was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Here's what he said about vouchers at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press Club</ENAMEX>
lunch in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>:

            

               I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is out as to whether it actually would lead to
an improvement of education. I think that choice should be considered. I have
some reservations about it, but in the course of an education bill that moves
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> I think we can look at it thoroughly, and it is a
possibility. As I say, I have some reservations about it, and I think that you
have to confront some of the basic questions about who will receive the
vouchers. And if you receive a voucher, are you allowed to go to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>? Are you allowed to go to only certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>? Are you allowed to go
to public or private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>? Are you allowed--there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 or 20</NUMEX> different
questions that are raised by the issue of choice and education vouchers.

            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to vote for Bush-supported
legislation that included funding for voucher experiments. In endorsing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> (which never passed) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> made the same point again: When it comes to
education reform, even imperfect notions are worth trying. "Choice may not be
the panacea for all our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s education ills," he said in a speech on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor, "but we cannot afford not to take an honest look at whether more
options would help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are trapped in the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in our
poorest areas."

            The only thing that would represent a reversal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s view would be a
categorical statement that he no longer supports any experiments with vouchers.
This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s position, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> demanded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>,
who is interested in vying for their endorsements, may cave and contradict his
earlier statements on the subject. But he hasn't done so yet.

         
      
   
