
   
   
      
         
            All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times all lead with the agreement reached by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to resume peace processes outlined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wye River</ENAMEX> accord signed last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and calls on both sides to refrain from taking unilateral action,
which ensures the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> won't declare statehood and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> won't
build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX>. It also lays out an ambitious
plan to achieve permanent settlement between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX> diplomacy: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> is
given credit for salvaging the agreement, which hit a snag on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> refused to release an extra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> as part of the deal. Uncowed by
the posturing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brinkmanship</ENAMEX> attributed to both sides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> quickly
switched gears, from passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to diplomacy maven. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explains
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>, heeding an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> request that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> play a back-seat role
in the negotiations, had been reluctant to interfere but plunged into the fray
with decisive mediation. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>,
positioned in front of a painting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dome of the Rock</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, seemed
anxious to stress that her role was minimal, insisting she was neither a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mediator</ENAMEX> nor a facilitator, but a "handmaiden" (her word). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s starring role has given her a much-needed boost as she travels
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> to try to jump-start negotiations between that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> front stories about independence-election results in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly chose to break away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> focus on the violence expected to follow the
official announcement: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> who have been terrorizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> have said they will reject the results
of the referendum. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or have plans to leave. Only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX>, fearing for their
lives, could flee the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> draws a connection between
the arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, sent to "restore peace," and the
imminent refugee crisis: It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> that trained, paid, and supported the
anti-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> who're leading the killing rampage.

            The top-front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story is basically a recap of the law-enforcement
controversy plaguing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>, who pledged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to find the truth behind
the now-public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> tapes that show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> firing combustible tear gas rounds at
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Waco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does report that a second
videotape, released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s claim that the tear
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas canisters</ENAMEX> did not penetrate the bunker, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Danforth</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, has agreed to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s investigation into a
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> cover-up. Neither of the other papers fronts the story, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries a similar story inside, and reminds us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danforth</ENAMEX>, best
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>' chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>, will need to pass a background check
before being officially appointed. No word on who (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>?) will perform that
background check.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> class-action suit brought by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plant</ENAMEX>. The suit
accuses former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> of misleading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> about the whereabouts of
radioactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> stored at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, thereby exposing them to illegally
high doses of radiation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also reports that its own investigation
into conditions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, which prompted a full-scale <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Richardson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, has spurred other discoveries. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>,
a computer with dangerously high radiation readings was almost donated to a
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-leads with a report on the "soft growth" of jobs in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, which represented the smallest increase since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> but drove
unemployment down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.2 percent</NUMEX>, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> hope that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> won't
raise interest rates at the next policy meeting, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager reports that damages awarded to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> Floridian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> in a class-action suit could not be paid in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> sum, saving the
tobacco industry from a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multibillion dollar</NUMEX> verdict that might have forced some
of the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to fold. It was bad news for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, but
good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> gained <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.25</NUMEX> a share.

            Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s will to live is
influenced most strongly by physical distress and can fluctuate wildly in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> before death. Both right-to-die <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> and right-to-die <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>
have found ways to embrace the study. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> points out that if the desire
to die can be controlled with treatment, it should not be taken at face value;
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> points out that if the desire to die is caused by reasons other
than pain, it should be heeded.

            More flak on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>. After mentioning that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Post Co.</ENAMEX> owns
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kaplan</ENAMEX>, the expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> test-prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dismisses ETS</ENAMEX>'s new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Striver</ENAMEX>" category as "troubling." The idea, explained in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, is that the new system would recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
achievement relative to a test-taker's social and economic background. What
does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> achievement relative to a test-taker's
(undisclosed) access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>? No easy answers here.

         
      
   
