
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Entrepreneur Is the New Madonna</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Joe</ENAMEX>,

            I know what you mean about being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. Almost every assignment is a
challenge in a different way and it never seems to get easier. I often feel as
if I only get half the story sometimes, so I typically do a massive amount of
reporting that is most often much more than I will ever need. I think that is
why I welcomed doing a book--it gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the ability to use so much of what is
left on the cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> floor of daily journalism.

            Think of all the good stuff we all collect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> in our reporting that we
never add to stories. Most often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> recount these tales with each other
and with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> rather than share them with the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. Much of
it, of course, using the standards of top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, cannot be used since it
is largely gossip we are repeating, although it certainly could make for some
very good stories. I often wonder when a really great fictional book will be
written about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> (probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> hence as it is too close).
In any case, there certainly is no lack of information available about the
moguls of technology now as they all become our current pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">icons</ENAMEX>. I would
posit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> have become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madonnas</ENAMEX> of the
current age of stock market mania and celebration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>.

            So the shift in the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> has been an interesting one for me to
watch. The smart-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy technologist</ENAMEX> is now being painted as the whiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>. I
personally always thought it was a risk to pin the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> on just
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, for example, there was a conscious effort to develop other
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>," for lack of a better word. So there, while you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case</ENAMEX>, you
also think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonsis</ENAMEX> and increasingly a range of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>, of course, is now getting a lot more attention at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, but
it still seems to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s show over there.

            While I did not attend the trial--I was lucky to be able to read your highly
amusing and informative dispatches, several of which made me spit up my lunch
laughing--it certainly seemed as if the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> took a beating and
the insular culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> did not look so good. That's ironic, since I
think it was just that insularity that helped them, much in the same way that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> has benefited from being in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> suburbs rather than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> would never have existed if it had been founded here, I am sure,
since its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> would have been mocked into obscurity by the digerati. Out
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> area, they looked positively exciting next to all the
government-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>. I wonder if that means geography is destiny,
and it's still location, location, location.

            From where I am sitting, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial has been the really
obvious turning point between the computer era and the digital age. I think it
almost does not matter what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> does since it's clear that the balance of
power is shifting again, although it not clear where it will land. Will the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX> of the era be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, or one of the big media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>? Or will it be none of them because the Internet allows and
encourages a plethora of strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and a complex interconnection of
businesses where none are allowed to dominate?

            I always use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> simple words when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tell me that one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--whether
it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>--is in charge of all our destinies: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX>
was. That incredible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> dominated the world and I imagine it did not seem
possible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living then that anyone could loosen that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>'s grip on
humanity. But we all know how that story turned out.

            Now I am getting way too philosophical, but this is my final missive, so why
not? Perhaps you could hasten a prediction of where this is all going. As for
me, I'll stick with my philosophy of reporting and, I guess, life--nobody
knows.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Kara

         
      
   
