
   
   
      
         
            Land of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh, Home of the Blaze</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the long-suppressed video evidence of federal pyrotechnic use at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the ethics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>--including the financing of their
mortgage and their public "disagreement" over clemency for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s flirtation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> all agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> investigation has been mishandled, but
they disagree over who mishandled it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberal pundits</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> (both of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> )--tend to blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>
Freeh, charging that he was closest to the suppressed evidence.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX>--blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> took office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>.

            Interestingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> mirror this partisan divide. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has publicly supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX>, and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Conyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, does the same. But on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation Clinton</ENAMEX>-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, supports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>; and on
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Edition Republicans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and former Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Thornburgh</ENAMEX> also back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornburgh</ENAMEX> casts
Freeh as a "fall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> calls him the "single best [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>] I've
seen.")

            But just how important is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX>? Answers range from "in fact, there
isn't any evidence [that the feds started the fire]" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) to "we're talking about an event unparalleled in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newshour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> compares the impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> psyche to that of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> assassination.) Despite this disagreement, everyone seconds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s call
for an independent investigation, and they marvel at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s aura of political
independence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox panelists Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> speculate
that her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincoln</ENAMEX> status" derives from her refusal to participate in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> social scene. (To read 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s independent image, click here. To learn more
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about Waco pyrotechnics</NUMEX>, click 
here.)

            The commentariat splits over the propriety of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAuliffe</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> underwriting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' mortgage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara</ENAMEX>
Liasson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) think it doesn't matter--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX>, and it's not really
a gift. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) think it does matter--giving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX>
dollars in collateral to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, even for private use, amounts to
improper influence.

            The opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> guffaws over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s belated opposition to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
proposed clemency for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. Almost no one believes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s assertion that she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> never discussed the pardon offer. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> speculate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> might pardon <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>
to appease <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newshour</ENAMEX> ) and every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang panelist</ENAMEX>--predict that presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> will bolt
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> are both economic
populists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> explains, and by nominating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan Perot</ENAMEX> can wrest control
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, who opposes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
nomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> dislikes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for its
alleged "dirty tricks" in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'92</NUMEX> presidential campaign. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
caution that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> won't jump <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> can virtually guarantee him
the nomination, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> may lose his pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> if he joins
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>, which eschews social issues. Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> note with
glee that many of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who refused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> the podium at the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'96</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX> are now begging him to stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            
               Portrait of a Humanitarian: Still on vacation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> runs another prerecorded show, this time on immigration. (He tries
to peg the topic to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX>.) Unlike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s entertaining but airy show
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s smart program is grounded in specific policy
issues, like temporary work visas, mail-order brides, and bilingual education.
But what's remarkable about the show is not the topic; it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Stein</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the closed-borders <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAIR</ENAMEX>, who comes off as singularly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obnoxious</ENAMEX> (no mean feat on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> ).

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX>," he warns us, "brings about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazilianization of America</ENAMEX>."
When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> remarks that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are valedictorians, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> sneers,
"You and I should visit some federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> together." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>
talks about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> in her childhood neighborhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stein</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interjects</ENAMEX>, "Why don't you move there if you like it so much?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> also
informs us that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> trumpets immigrant labor as an inflation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weapon</ENAMEX>, "what he's [really] saying is, 'We're redistributing income to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> themselves--take[ing] it out of the pocket of
middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>--to pay for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of marching poor
that we're importing into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.' " In truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s politics aren't
that unreasonable. But one has to think that even the Know-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nothings</ENAMEX> had more
class.

            
               Last Word
               : Defending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> policy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Biden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, says, "We've been
dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> because he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> [in power]. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> behind him
are no box of chocolates. You know, everyone thinks there's a Jeffersonian
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> waiting to pop up. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> reform] is going to take a
generation. The question is, How do we cut the losses, and how do we keep a
process going where we continue to destroy nuclear weapons<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
