
   
   
      
         
            Intimations of the Triple Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s admission of the use of government pyrotechnics at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>. A distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is abortion and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s assertion that the pyrotechnics almost certainly did not
cause the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Waco</ENAMEX> fire, the commentariat thinks her admission hurts the
government's credibility and demonstrates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is honest but clueless,
bordering on incompetent (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gang</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s revelation proves
that continued interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> is not just the occupation of lunatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">right-wingers</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>--argue
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>'s importance is overblown.

            Several shows react to the recent abortion fudges by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX>--in which both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> assert their pro-life bona fides while
downplaying the importance of the issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s balancing acts show that the pro-life
movement is still to be reckoned with. Others, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>,
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> have shifted abortion rhetoric away from the hard-line
stances taken by past <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and still followed by grassroots
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> spends most of its round-table discussing a focus
group it conducted of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Among the
findings: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> approve of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s equivocations on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
question--largely because they resent the perceived arrogance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>;
they cannot agree what the correct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> stance on abortion and gun control
should be; and they now hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elder</ENAMEX>, whom they
regret abandoning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'92</TIMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> agree that the
focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s warm fuzzies for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> underscore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s shift away from
the fiery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>-invoking rhetoric of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Ideological purity among
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is now "as antique as the free coinage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F.</ENAMEX>
Will.

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlson Chronicle</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> told his fellow Late Edition
panelists that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas Board of Education</ENAMEX>'s decision to not mandate the
teaching of evolution was sensible because it allowed for a "diversity of
views" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> enough. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> what
he makes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s refusal to come out in favor of the mandatory teaching of
evolution. You'd think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> would applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s hesitancy to impose his own
views on others. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> answers: "So [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>]'s sort of a cool,
rational techie on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and kind of a snake-handling fundie on the other? I
mean, this is politics. I mean, this is what I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> feels like he has to
do. I mean, it's another sign of the fact that his campaign is thrashing about
a bit."

The Second Coming of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> is
both celebrated and notorious for ignoring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Issues</ENAMEX> and
instead discussing his own idiosyncratic topics. He devoted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s show
entirely to the social, political, and economic direction of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>. (He even assembled a panel of three academic "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>" on
millennial issues.) This is a fine subject to discuss, but it renders his
"Predicting the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future in 10 Words or Less</ENAMEX>" format a bit ridiculous. Typical
queries from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s show: "Over the upcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>, will science and
religion converge, or will they annihilate one another--and if so, which one
will survive? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX>?"; "Will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX> improve life for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>--as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the current millennium</TIMEX> has done--or will it end progress and impose restraints?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin on Post- Fin de Si√</ENAMEX>®cle
Alienation
If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX> tendencies occasionally produce madness, they can also
produce genius (at least as far as chat TV goes). Take this piece of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oratory</ENAMEX>--from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> voice-over--delivered in his trademark stentorian
slur: "When <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX> rolls around, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revelers</ENAMEX> will find that their lives, their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loves</ENAMEX>, are no different--after all this expense--than they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX>.
In fact, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will see all those zeroes behind the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Triple Nothing Burger</ENAMEX> . So, beware the post-partum millennial
blues."

         
      
   
