
   
   
      
         
            Test Patterns

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s announcement <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX>, supports an
outside investigation into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s failure to disclose the use of incendiary
devices at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>, a development nobody else fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with what it claims is alarm among "education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>"
(as opposed to the rest of us?) about continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> disparities between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>
and nonwhites in the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> score data, released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads local (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s
highway and rail expansion plans) and off-leads semi-local, comparing local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> to national trends. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> info, including a discussion of the
new "striver" scoring system written up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , in its top-of-the-page "talker"
position, and leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Summers</ENAMEX>' announcement that
in light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> banking scandal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would not support
further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> credits for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> until there has been an adequate accounting of
the money already lent there. This, notes the paper, puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> at
odds with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> has advocated uninterrupted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> loans.

            The headline over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
lead cites an "ethnic gap" and refers to the worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are failing
to prepare "nonwhites." But the story itself never mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> performance
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, an omission that is stunning given <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>'s
demographics and that lends false credibility to the stark picture the paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX>. False, because as a graphic accompanying the story indicates, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>
have the highest math <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> and the second-highest verbal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story
makes the same elision, mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> only once in passing, and never
mentioning their scores. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> also mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> only once in
passing but does mention their scores.

            Also, the stories fail to establish any sense of context that would justify
concerns over the differences in scores they report. For instance, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that nationally, scores for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> "rose" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point from the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> before, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Americans</ENAMEX> were each down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> points in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">math</ENAMEX>, but there is no discussion of what a standard deviation would be on
samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores. Since test scores are known by college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> and
admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to often vary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of points from one
test-taking to the next by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, surely a few points can't be the
stuff of crisis. Or if it is, at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> need to argue the point.
Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the national verbal score "remained mired at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">505</NUMEX>." But wasn't the idea behind the recentering of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> precisely
to put the median score as close as possible to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> piece
hardly mentions the ethnic angle at all, dwelling much more on differences
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>' scores, and (in the online version at least), sits
under a refreshingly calm headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Board</ENAMEX> Scores <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vary Little From</ENAMEX>
Previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Waco</ENAMEX> lead also mentions that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that's starting its
own investigation is said to be interested in what role the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Force</ENAMEX>
may have played in the operation. It would have been nice if the story had said
something about what the law is on military involvement in domestic law
enforcement. It's not an absolute firewall anymore, is it?

            Once again the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' ban-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africanism</ENAMEX> is in evidence. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who tried to topple the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Congolese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX>, drawing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> into a war in the process, signed a
cease-fire. Only the WP fronts the story, although it runs it below a
piece about a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s offer of support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
bid if she'll lobby her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to release convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-leads <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s introduction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> of its newest family
of computers, called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G4</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , in its coverage of the uncoverage,
says the computer is designed to bolster the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s offerings in high-end
publishing and design. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> breathes harder, noting that company
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> says the machine's new chip will "toast" that of his main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competitor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>. On the development, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> stock rose to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year</TIMEX> high.

            The LAT front reports that while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is concerned about a
downturn in production and the flight of movie business to foreign locations,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> entertainment business is flourishing: porn.
Although feature production in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX> is down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>,
says the paper, "adult" (used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> without the scare-quotes) movie
production is up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, one out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> local shoots was a porn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, which is how the biz will manage to churn out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> new titles this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. The story quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>'s estimate that skinflicks create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> jobs. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> keeps, er, growing: A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of porn profits come
from overseas distribution. And the Internet now accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> sales.

            Given the front-page headlines garnered when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> bombed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, where would you figure to read about
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s word from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that it was paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the raid? Did you guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>'s Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>?

         
      
   
