
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Well, it's as if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> never happened, as all the gains that the stock
market racked up in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s interest-rate hike have evaporated,
and in the space of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six days</TIMEX> we went from being convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>
was done raising rates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> to being almost certain that it would be
back in action <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX>. The truth is, who really knows? But the one thing that
has become clearer and clearer is that any notion that bond-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
are more rigorous and less hysterical than stock-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> is just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wrongheaded</ENAMEX>. Bond prices have been oscillating as wildly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>
as Internet prices, and for reasons that are often even less obvious than those
moving the stock market. Everyone, in other words, is looking forward to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. So take a nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long weekend</TIMEX>, drink heavily (I mean think
heavily), and wonder, as we all will, where the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> went. On to the
Chatter.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> would no longer be covering the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> on a day-to-day basis but would be retaining his title as chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent 'out</ENAMEX> of respect to him and his position.' Has this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> never read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">King Lear ?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juniper Networks</ENAMEX>, which makes routers for the infrastructure of the
Internet, went public in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX> and, at its peak, was up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">700 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s now worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 billion</NUMEX>, despite having <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $32</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in sales. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, it announced that it was already going back to the
market for a follow-on offering, selling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 1.5 million</NUMEX> shares. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, it's
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> said right after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> election, 'Get it all now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>,
because it's not going to get any better than this.' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX> told a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> business
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock market was endangering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy, because
'a strong market crash' was increasingly likely . Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> blamed the global economic meltdown not on panicky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> but on
busybody <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> had better get ready to feel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s wrath."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> finally lifted the capital controls it imposed in the wake of
the drastic devaluation of its currency and the collapse of its economy last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. Surprisingly, massive capital flight from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is not
expected . Massive consternation on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary</ENAMEX>
Fund and neoclassical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> is."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Transit Authority</ENAMEX> is running an ad campaign pushing
courtesy on its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ad, for instance, reads, 'If you don't put
anything on the seat next to you, someone else will be able to sit down.' I can
just hear my fellow subway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> say, 'And your point is? ' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "Long-struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>, which thought it had finally found a true winner
in the high-speed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Acela</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acela</ENAMEX> won't be
launched until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX> at the earliest because the vibration of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trains</ENAMEX> is causing 'excessive wheel wear.' Until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acela</ENAMEX> is launched, existing
trains will be made noisier, so that it seems like they're going faster."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> are concerned that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s employment report will
bring bad news , because school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> in much of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> back onto payrolls, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> has
apparently not made the necessary seasonal adjustment yet. So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> bond traders
have as much reason to dread <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of summer</TIMEX> as little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do."

         
      
   
