
   
   
      
         
            Explaining <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> have requested explanations of some of the terms used in

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers"</ENAMEX> column. Here is a brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glossary</ENAMEX>.

            
               Above-the-fold : On the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the front page (therefore visible
even before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is unfolded). Signifies one of the most important
stories of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, according to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.

            
               Evergreen : An article that could run at any time. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types
of evergreens: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) an article without a direct tie-in to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s news (e.g.,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Traffic on the Rise in Metro Area"</ENAMEX>); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a story that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recurs</ENAMEX> regularly
(e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elderly Threatened by Record Heat"</ENAMEX>).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Front</ENAMEX> (as a verb): To place a story on the front page. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> often reach different decisions on which stories to front
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any given day</TIMEX>. (See also, above-the-fold .)

            
               Jump (verb or noun): For a story that begins on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (usually the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front</ENAMEX>) page, to continue on another page. Or the place in the story where it
breaks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between</NUMEX> pages. Or the entire part of the story after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> page.
Because studies consistently show that few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> follow an article beyond the
jump, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> attempt to lay out the crucial elements of the story before
the jump. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> is the most extreme case, with front page news
stories that almost never jump). Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of facts around the
jump can often reveal a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s slant on a story.

            
               Lead : The news story deemed most important by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. In most
papers, the lead appears on the front page at the top of the right-hand column.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is the strictest about this rule, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> --which often runs a feature story across the top of the front
page--varies the most from this standard. On occasion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> will displace the lead with a feature
story--usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with an eye-grabbing visual. In these cases, the lead will
almost always be the next story down in the right-hand column. The Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> has not adopted these conventions for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX>. Instead, the
paper usually fronts feature stories and an extensive, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-column news
summary.

            (Note: The opening sentence or paragraph of a news story is also known as
the lead, but usually spelled "lede" to avoid confusion.)

            
               Off-lead : The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most important news story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The
off-lead appears either in the top left corner, or directly below the lead on
the right.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Op-Ed</ENAMEX>: The page in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> where opinion pieces not
written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> appear. It originally stood for
"opposite the editorial page." It also refers to the individual articles on the
op-ed page (e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed on the nuclear
test ban treaty"). Some op-ed pieces are written by regularly syndicated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnists</ENAMEX>, and others are submitted to the newspaper unsolicited.

            
               Reefer : A brief front-page synopsis of a story that appears
inside the paper. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newsline</ENAMEX>" and the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's News</ENAMEX>" are essentially multiple reefers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> tend to
integrate reefers into their front-page layouts.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slug</ENAMEX> (as a verb): To run under the headline of (e.g., "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> slugged the story, 'Teen births fall to record low' ").
The term originally referred to the pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> which held the type in place
on printing presses.

            
               Stuff (as a verb): To place a story inside the paper.
Slightly derogatory, usually implying that the story was underplayed. (e.g.,
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> fronted the Waco
controversy, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> stuffed the story").

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
