
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Closing Music</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tamar</ENAMEX>,

            Isn't that just the way. Just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> puts on the hottest tunes, the party
is over. Let me depart with some personal history that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who wish to can
find in my memoir <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Parallel Time: Growing Up in Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> . I was
recruited to college off of a street <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX> in a dying factory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> were traditionally channeled into dead-end vocational jobs. I remember
being startled when a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> visiting our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> told me after an
hour's conversation, mainly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, that I was college material and
would do rather well there--something that guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> at
my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> had never said, despite my appetite for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. I went to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widener University</ENAMEX>, south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, where I found myself in the company
of a great many prep-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> who had blond hair, orthodonture--and every
other conceivable advantage, including prepping for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> that had probably
boosted their scores by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> points or more. I was middling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> in high
school and middling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> but in fact graduated 26th
or so out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400 or so</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widener</ENAMEX>--well ahead of all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> with
the orthodonture and prep-school educations. I was quicker (dare I say "more
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">intelligent?</ENAMEX>") and a far better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. Which amazed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> to no end,
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had been relatively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>-free for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous century</TIMEX>. I
gave the honors commencement speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and what an interesting
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> that was.

            In this vein, I would also point you to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Steele</ENAMEX>'s most illuminating
essay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> just recently about the role of racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stereotyping</ENAMEX>--by white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>--in suppressing academic
performance among even superlative black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steele</ENAMEX> is rather a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genius</ENAMEX>, I think, along the lines of early geniuses such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">psychologist Gordon Allport</ENAMEX>, who seemed to see it all. Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allport</ENAMEX>'s game?
He'd begin a lecture showing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> photographs: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> holding a
knife; the other of a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> empty-handed. At the end of the lecture, he'd
ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> "who had the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">knife?</ENAMEX>" Inevitably, student memory--which is to
say, culturally engrained bigotry--had caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> to migrate to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>'s hand. As a former college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> (in statistics), I have always been
interested in the nexus between the quantitative and the qualitative--and
especially in the role of preconception in human performance.

            The moral of this complicated picture is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> are not the be-all and
end-all. They tell you some things, but not all things. In an adjacent vein,
these stories about genetically enhanced smartness in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> are hilariously
superficial. We do not yet know what intelligence even is. When we find
out, its visual representation will be something like a very complex, perhaps
even three-dimensional molecule, with elements all over the place.
On affirmative action. Am I ambivalent? No. It's the only thing that kept us
from collapsing into racial factionalism and civil war. I really think that.
But I am most determined to speak loudly on equal access to education.

            On politics, I disagree with your assessment of my view. Tactical strategies
do not preclude core values. But as you have said yourself, very few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have anything that even approaches the latter. I am sure that our
paths will cross again, perhaps at luncheon, perhaps in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Central</ENAMEX>, where we
can catch a glimpse of the famous Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lilly Bart</ENAMEX>. But, uh oh, there goes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buzzer</ENAMEX>. Game over, see ya later.

         
      
   
