
   
   
      
         
            Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> Loves Death

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has pioneered in the emerging field of necro-monetary policy (the
study of the impact of economic incentives on the decision to die). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> to
explicate the implicit logic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' push to eliminate all
inheritance taxes (see 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/12/99</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> followed up with empirical evidence in support
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s hypothesis that, consistent with economic theory and the human
distaste for the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>, high estate taxes are positively correlated
with low death rates, and, conversely, low estate taxes, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> seeks,
are correlated with high death rates (see 
Plotz, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/19/99</NUMEX>). Neither of these seminal contributions to the literature,
however, satisfactorily explained (or, indeed, even attempted to explicate) the
motivation behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>'s effort to accelerate the shuffle
off this mortal coil into a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50-yard</NUMEX> dash.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are, of course, in the forefront of public
manifestations of piety. But with regard to the timing of a meeting with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Maker</ENAMEX>, they have been firmly on the side of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> rather than sooner. So
why would a pro-life caucus push so hard to eliminate a policy instrument, the
"death tax," as they routinely denote it, that has such a proven record of
encouraging longevity? The answer may be found in a recent
study emanating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Institute</ENAMEX>. In exploring the ramifications of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s long-range forecasts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence H. Thompson</ENAMEX> points
to a startling fact. Almost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s much deplored
long-term deficit is owing to the expectation that, as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">progresses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will live still longer and, largely in consequence of
their advanced ages, suffer more disability. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> suggests <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> ways to
deal with the projected shortfall: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) cut benefits or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) increase the share of
GDP devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>--i.e., raise taxes. Neither of these
alternatives will recommend itself to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> whose desire to placate
high-voting senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> is exceeded only by its desire to deliver big tax
cuts. Thus the genius of the death tax repeal proposal: Why not cloak a sharp
cut in benefits in the soothing shroud of a tax break? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> must be
jealous.

         
      
   
