
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beauty Contest 2000</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tamar</ENAMEX>,

            First, a little personal history. I grew up in a black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>--just <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>--which was stone-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
and, I think, did not elect a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> until some time in the late
'80s or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '90s</TIMEX>. I do not think I met a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> at all until I was about to
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>. I have often written about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">malfeasance</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feather-bedding</ENAMEX> and such in upper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. I am, frankly, not an ideological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. If you have to call me something, call me, well, libertarian.

            Would I "like" it if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> turned out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hard-core lefty</ENAMEX>? In fact,
no. That time has passed ("way passed,'' as my
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year-old</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">stepson</NUMEX>-to-be-would put it). What distresses me, really, is the
Clintonian inabililty to articulate a central tendency of any kind. That's old
news, I know, and as a battle-hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editorialist</ENAMEX> for the New York
Times , I should be over disappointment. But it disappoints me nonetheless.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX> wrote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> that
"tacking"--back and forth, between left and right--was an honorable way of
getting from the status quo to a new philosophy and a new vision. I admire Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wills</ENAMEX>, but the essay did not convince me. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Gonzalez</ENAMEX> says in todays
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> , the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "actually believing in a cause
must be alien to [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>]."

            But alas, we may have reached a time when believing anything openly
and publically--if indeed you wish to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--consigns you to political
death. What we have now is a beauty contest, I think, in which the candidates
will say as little as possible and wait for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> to crack under
the camera lights. As you say, let's pick this up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

            All best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
