
   
   
      
         
            Just Say No Comment

            Everybody leads with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> to allow an armed external
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> headlines say that it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that's coming. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> headline calls it "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>-led."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s headline notes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> support for the development but also the
absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front gives plenty of space
to a large picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Andre Agassi</ENAMEX> exulting over his win of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX> and
to a story-with-picture about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Jets</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gives a big
chunk of its front to its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> professional sport: show business awards.
This time it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmys</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s acceptance of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> a "stunning
reversal of policy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds that it is "in some ways humiliating"
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX>. Although the majority of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers figure</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say--the
coverage mentions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX> would prefer a predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> mentions that perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> will
even include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> saying that indeed, there is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-white</ENAMEX> sentiment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> which could make things dangerous for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. And, wonders the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , what will happen to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militias</ENAMEX>?

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager reports that an examination of records reveals that
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 eight</TIMEX> federal appeals court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> took part in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 18</NUMEX> cases
in which they, or their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> or trusts they managed held stock in one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> involved. (The story is a follow-up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>
City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> , by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, now with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>,
says the paper, attributed their participation to innocent mistakes or memory
lapses about their finances. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> case cited gives a feel for the amount of
lapse required: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who participated in a ruling favorable
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> held up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> worth of stock in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX>. Some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offending judges</ENAMEX> are quoted saying that they are "chagrined" and promise "to
try to be more careful." The story doesn't call the practice "illegal" (a
related editorial does, though) and doesn't explain to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> aren't looking at criminal charges, civil suits, or at least discipline
from within their profession.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> interview with former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, in which he supports his presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate son</ENAMEX>'s
decision not to answer questions about alleged youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. A suggestion:
If the press is looking for embarrassing questions to ask presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> about their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long-ago</TIMEX> past, how about this one, arguably much more
relevant to presidential performance than ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use: What were your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>
scores? The real issue isn't who used dope; it's who is a dope.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a piece about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">87-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX> revealed by a forthcoming book to
have been an undetected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> operative, active from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '40s</TIMEX> until the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX>. The little old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> fessed up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past Saturday</TIMEX>, saying that she
had been trying to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> keep abreast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
But she added, "In general, I do not agree with spying against one's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press is saying that soon up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Britons</ENAMEX> who spied for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> intelligence will be unmasked, including a
now-dead prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> figure.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Segal</ENAMEX>, makes a sharp observation upon a
visit to the new Web site of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s premier lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, Patton
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boggs</ENAMEX>. The hype text says at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patton Boggs</ENAMEX> was the first national
law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to recognize that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could serve as
forums to achieve client goals." How, wonders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Segal</ENAMEX>, does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> lobby the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> has a wicked version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s recusal from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX> clemency offer: "I want you to
listen to me. I never discussed clemency for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Not a single time; never." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> also asks a properly pointed
question: If federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can't even accept a lunch from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>, what
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s acceptance of a house loan guarantee worth about a grand
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ran an op-ed piece worth looking up. It
recounted a wacky trend in shady political campaign contributions: maximum
donations "by" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> recently received
separate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1K</NUMEX> donations from twin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year-olds</TIMEX>, the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multimillionaire</ENAMEX>. Lest you think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubya</ENAMEX> has cornered the market on this
form of cribbing, the piece reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> included an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a correction saying that an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 24</TIMEX> story about
money added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to appropriations bills favoring specific universities
"referred incompletely to the source of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$797 million</NUMEX> figure" which is this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s total for such funds. Now reading that, wouldn't you think the original
story said something about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>? Well, it didn't. That figure was
calculated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Education</ENAMEX> in its own story on the
topic, but in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 24</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$797 million</NUMEX> appears
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unattributed</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> shows up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fourteenth</ENAMEX>, and without being connected to the figure. Hence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s newspaper
deconstruction: "referred incompletely to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>" means "referred to the
source, without mentioning that it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>." These baroque newspaper
corrections are to a mistake what a comb-over is to baldness.

         
      
   
