
   
   
      
         
            Will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Save Us From Disney</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Witold</ENAMEX>,

            If one measure of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s success is, as I've
been told, its ability to bring like minds together, then I must compliment
Celebration, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, on at least the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> count, of giving us a pretext to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correspond</ENAMEX>. Celebration, of course, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> built by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, and our
concern here is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> recent books about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Celebration Chronicles: Life, Liberty and the Pursuit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX>
Value in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Town</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ross</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration, U.S.A.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living in Disney's Brave New Town</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Collins</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Frantz</ENAMEX>.

            I wonder if you shared my spooky feeling reading both
of these books, a feeling totally unconnected with literary merit or effect.
You and I were both early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration</ENAMEX>, you for
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> and I for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, but that was back when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> had no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
and, at least when I was there, no habitable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. My experience with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, when it was still a vast pasture and palmetto swamp
attached to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> World <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a later</TIMEX> visit, a
veritably complete downtown had sprung up, but it was yet vacant, its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">storefronts</ENAMEX> without signs, its windows without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>, not a solitary pedestrian
along its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. Witnessing that kind of progression, the field giving way to
the skeletal, empty, immaculate ruin, is the common experience of the
archaeologist, but not of the urbanologist. What complete <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was ever all at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time empty? But the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archaeologist</ENAMEX> can only wonder about the lives of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s bones, hard as one might work to get those
bones to speak. And that's the spookiness: We saw the ruins and wondered about
the lives, and now, with these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books, the ruins are speaking and the place
has come miraculously to life.

            Both these books follow a similar trajectory: Their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> moved in early in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX>'s existence--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> into an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz/Collins</ENAMEX> into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Savannah</ENAMEX>" model <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>--and watched the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> unfold during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> of its infancy, seeking, like some anxious
parent, the significance behind every diaper change and wobbly step. They
record many of the same events: The conflicts over school quality, shoddy home
construction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-enforced conduct codes. And they eventually seem to concur
in their wistful conclusion that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX> is a bit of a corporate harlot,
it yet has a heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, or at least of honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>, and does not deserve
the easy contempt of its oh-so-sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX>.

            Now we, who once critiqued the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, are invited to
critique the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, we can surmise from this, has come a
long way. I'd like to volunteer that these books have drawn some perversely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsatisfying</ENAMEX> combination reviews, most notably in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , which devoted the weight of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 column inches</NUMEX> (by my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pica</ENAMEX> rule) to admiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration, U.S.A.</ENAMEX> , except
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> paragraph spent denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Celebration</ENAMEX>
Chronicles on the astonishing grounds that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> is a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in an
apartment without a mortgage or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and thus had no "real stake"
equipping him to comment. This credentials-committee rebuke must have made even
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frantz</ENAMEX> and Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> cringe, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avowed admirers</ENAMEX> of diversity that they are.
But it opens up an interesting question: What is the purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX>? It
isn't a mill <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or a railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, a seaport or fall-line entrepot. The
Times review, in its denunciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' bachelor
insufficiency, implied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s purpose was focused on child rearing and
real estate accumulation. And surely education and innovative housing were big
draws for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. But most of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, it is clear from these
accounts, also were animated by enthusiasm for the larger experiment,
Celebration's self-declared mission of turning around the soul-deadening blight
of suburban sprawl and employing virtuous design and bedrock community
principles to reinvigorate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s civic life. Far from innocent,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX> was a knowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> from the beginning," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> writes. While
Frantz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> admit to a bit of discomfort at their roles as spies
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX>'s knowingness makes them more than just
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>. In an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> pull it up by the roots
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each morning</TIMEX> to see how it is doing, whose central motif is self-inspection,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are the professional self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX>'s original
captains of industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reviewer called
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' tone "oracular," and it is, appropriately. Both of these books are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oracles</ENAMEX>. The issues they raise--Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> more abstractly and wittily, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz</ENAMEX> and Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> more earnestly and intimately, are not side issues to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> experiment. They are as deep and as urgent as the question
Celebration's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> and muse, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney</ENAMEX>, expressed in a memo before his
death: Is democracy the best way to run a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>? These books, and perhaps our
conversation, concern the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> charter in the corporate age.
Does it take a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>? And if it does, is that
because the enemy we are saving it from is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>? Because of these issues, we
all have a stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX>, and I look forward immensely to talking with
you about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, and about these books.

         
      
   
