
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sega Dreamcast</ENAMEX> Ads We'll Never See
            

            Unless you're a hardcore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamer</ENAMEX>, you may not know that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> saw the debut of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreamcast</ENAMEX> video-game console, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">128-bit</NUMEX> system ever (that means
it's really fast) and the last hope for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that has gone from having
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the strongest brands in the world to having the words "laggard" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">also-ran</ENAMEX>" permanently affixed to its name. But even if you haven't noticed
Dreamcast before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, it's a safe bet that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX> the
product is going to become inescapable, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX> is in the process of
spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of dollars</NUMEX> on an elaborate marketing campaign that
includes, among other things, sponsoring <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV Video Music Awards</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreamcast</ENAMEX> is, incidentally, quite dazzling, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> game from Sega
in particular is the most amazing sports video game ever created. But what with
even more high-powered game systems arriving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>,
Sega can't rely on technology alone, although word of mouth should help sell a
lot of the consoles. And so we're getting a sophisticated, pseudo-grassroots ad
campaign, with edgy graphics and oblique slogans. It's a good campaign, but
it's not exactly revolutionary.

            That's not surprising, since at this point in the history of marketing, it
seems impossible that you might actually come across something new. The irony,
though, is that the TV ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreamcast</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX> has run in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>--where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> was launched <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX>--really are like nothing you've ever seen
before. They're self-flagellating, bitter ads that acknowledge not only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX>'s
past blunders--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sega</ENAMEX> was the dominant video game <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, but
it was crushed by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playstation</ENAMEX> and N64
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>--but also the quixotic nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dreamcast</ENAMEX> launch.

            The ads star an actual senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managing director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yukawa Hidekazu</ENAMEX>, who looks much like what you imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salarymen</ENAMEX> look
like. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yukawa</ENAMEX> eavesdrops on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX> video games
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suck</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playstation</ENAMEX> is much better." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melancholy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yukawa</ENAMEX> heads to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, gets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drunk</ENAMEX>, and on his way home scuffles with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>, who beat him up. The
commercial ends with him collapsed in the doorway of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, as an offscreen
voice exhorts, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come on</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yukawa</ENAMEX>, get up!"

            In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ad, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yukawa</ENAMEX> is on a remote mountaintop, dressed in a business
suit, talking to a group of seemingly friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who tell him that Sega
has changed for the better. "Really?" he asks, at which point the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
eyes turn black and they scream, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, it's a joke! We don't need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX>--we want
Playstation!" The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> then opens beneath <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yukawa</ENAMEX> and swallows him, just before
he wakes up on the floor of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to realize that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> has caught
him daydreaming. The ad ends with him reflecting on his nightmare.

            The later ads are slightly more hopeful, but the overriding tone, which one
Sega exec calls "this sort of wacky hara-kiri approach," stays similar. That
tone has made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yukawa</ENAMEX> a cult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. He's recorded a hit single, a love song to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreamcast</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega</ENAMEX> printed up a limited edition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> phone cards with
his image on them. At a games conference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lined up for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
to have their pictures taken with him. Most improbable of all, the Dreamcast
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">box</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> features a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Yukawa-san</ENAMEX> looking somehow anxious and yet
charming.

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yukawa</ENAMEX> ads are startling, they make sense in the context of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> veneration of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Morris</ENAMEX> famously called "the nobility
of failure," as well as what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> calls "their emphasis on culpability and
accountability." As such, they throw into sharp relief the differences between
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> market and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market, and point up a basic problem faced by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sega of America</ENAMEX>: This is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, trying to target a market different from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which its parents
are rooted. In other words, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yukawa</ENAMEX> ads for us.

         
      
   
