
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Championship Wrestling</ENAMEX>
            

            The spat between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s offer to pardon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX> is staged-no more plausible than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those all-star
wrestling matches with fake <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and fake grimaces. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be happy
to use the power of the executive branch to help her bid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> at every opportunity. But as this episode shows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> road show
will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>. First, she will recommend from time to time
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federales</ENAMEX> reopen investigations, or look into this or that
problem-just to remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that she draws legitimacy from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
(She did this recently in the case of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yeshiva</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who was shot to
death on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>.) <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, she will disagree with the
administration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> to show that she is independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and
nobody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but her own. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> will tack left, then right in
an attempt to gather votes from both downstate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and upstate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>-and will have it both ways, pandering to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distancing</ENAMEX> herself the next. This is vintage "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX>" stuff, pioneered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> himself. The message to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, by the way, is:
"Take it or leave it. Its the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrats</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>; take your
choice.''

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX> stories are not well reported and have not yet given us the nitty
gritty. To make a judgment about whether the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> deserve to be pardoned-or just
locked up forever-we need to know who did what to whom and whether the
sentences were fair or ridiculously heavy. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Gonzalez</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> suggests that those being considered in the clemency
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bonanza</ENAMEX> were convicted not of bombings but of "lesser offenses.") In the
absence of the nitty gritty, however, I will take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flier</ENAMEX> and say that the
administration did this for political gain-i.e., to help Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, home of a great many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. If this had been a serious, closely
reasoned plan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> would have some point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> out there, making
the case to the public. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>handed nature of the thing suggests that what
you suspect is true, Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacoby</ENAMEX>.

            This opens onto a broader political question of how the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> can
appeal to minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> without constantly insulting their intellects. My own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hunch</ENAMEX> is that both middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Latinos</ENAMEX> are pure
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX>, waiting to be claimed, if only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> can get into gear and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mount</ENAMEX> a campaign less insulting that what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> dish up. A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> for
your thoughts here.

         
      
   
