
   
   
      
         
            Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chinese Spy Story Fizzled</ENAMEX>?
            

            For months there have been news stories suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> in which the first atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> was developed in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, is still the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> research and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. There have been further suggestions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> case exposes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> as cavalier about national security--or, worse, that it
traded national security for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> campaign contributions. Recently, though,
there have been stories suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> may not have been a spy after all.
What, in brief, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of play?

             

            The investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> espionage has actually been going
on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. It is clearly established that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> somehow obtained design
specifications for many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s nuclear warheads during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '90s</TIMEX>. But these secrets could have leaked from many places, including
other government research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and private defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>.

             

            What is the evidence implicating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>? Mainly, it seems,
his apparent friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. He often attended scientific
conferences in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and hosted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> on visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>.
He was even once seen hugging one of them. But these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> visits and
conferences were all part of his job as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>--and indeed
friendship among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> was part of their purpose. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
also downloaded secret files to an insecure computer--a clear violation of the
rules. But there is no evidence the information ever went any further. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> says
he was just making backup copies. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have done the
same, though on a smaller scale.

             

            The thinness of the evidence against him has led some to
suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, who was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, is being persecuted because of his
ethnic heritage. There is scant evidence for that, too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> now concedes
that it is unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> will ever face charges of spying. At most, he may be
charged with mishandling classified information--the offense for which he lost
his job in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. However, even this charge may never end up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Deutch</ENAMEX> was stripped of his security clearance
for a similar offense, but will not be prosecuted for his actions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
would likely find it difficult to justify a different standard being applied to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>.

             

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is accused of compromising national
security by mishandling the investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. How? Separate investigations
launched by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> were poorly coordinated,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> did not act quickly on recommendations to improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and to revoke <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s access to sensitive information. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were not fully informed of the security issues until late in
the investigation. But there is no evidence of actual damage to national
security due to these lapses. And there is no evidence tying any of this to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign contributions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> agree that the most significant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> losses occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>--well before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> was suspected of any
wrongdoing, and before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

             

            Next question?

         
      
   
