
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Stonewalls, Part II</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Crowley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books about
her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, is annoyed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> for characterizing
her stance toward her plagiarism controversy (see "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Stonewalls About Plagiarism</ENAMEX>!") as "stonewalling." She told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (who finally reached her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by phone): "I did not stonewall you
or the issue." She hadn't returned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s earlier queries because she was
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>, she said; and she'd already explained herself to Felicity
Barringer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

            But careful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s earlier item--about the striking
similarities between a recent Op-Ed piece <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> wrote for the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and an essay written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years earlier</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX> for
Commentary-- will note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had already allowed for the
possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> was on vacation. They will also note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>'s
comment as quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --that "I have not read" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
piece--seemed, under the circumstances, to be less than truthful. It was mainly
in reference to this Times quote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> of
"stonewalling." And guess what? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>--who confirmed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that she's
currently writing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX> profile for Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--is
still stonewalling!

            To review: No <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than five</NUMEX> passages in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Op-Ed</ENAMEX>, a tribute
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> pegged to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">25th</NUMEX> anniversary of his resignation, were worded in ways
that were identical or nearly identical to passages in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> article.
(Scroll down to the bottom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s 
earlier item to assess the extremely damaging evidence.) It isn't
possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> never read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s piece. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
got wind of the similarities, it published an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s note saying it wouldn't
have published <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>'s piece had it been aware of the "striking similarities
in phraseology."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> now says she does not remember making the absolute statement ("I
have not read") that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> attributed to her. Her mantra to
Chatterbox was, "I do not remember reading the [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Johnson</ENAMEX>] piece." Cleverly
pretending the accusation against her was that she stole <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s ideas
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, she said that "the concepts in question are shared by those with a
knowledgeable background of [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s] life and career." Well, sure, it can well
be imagined that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would independently arrive at the (erroneous)
idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> got screwed. What can't be imagined is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> people
would independently arrive at the same words to express this idea.

            "I understand that there are clear similarities in some of the language use,
but I arrived at my conclusions independently and I expressed them that way,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>. "Nor would I ever submit material from a source for
publication without attribution, without citing it properly."

            But surely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> sputtered, you must have read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>. Are you saying you didn't read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s article?

            "I don't remember ever reading the piece," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> answered.

            But that's not possible! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> said. Lengthy passages are repeated
verbatim, or almost verbatim!

            "I acknowledge to you there are similarities in the phraseology," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>
said.

            Oh, come on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> said. Why not come clean and at least admit that you
must have plagiarized inadvertently?

            "I did not plagiarize. Absolutely not."

            What about the giveaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britishism</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> is not) you
repeated--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> emerged from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> "with credit"?

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come on</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>, I've been using that phrase for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> briefly considered dedicating the rest of his life to finding out
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> has ever before used the phrase "with credit," and decided
against it. Clearly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> wasn't going to do even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Shalit</ENAMEX> (i.e., admit
plagiarism but say it was inadvertent and trivial), which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> previously
thought was the minimal amount of self-abnegation such a situation demanded.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> was just going to ... stonewall.

            It's working. Aside from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s rants on the subject, there continues
to be no follow-up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> item (and an earlier one by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ) in any news outlet tracked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX>. This provides
further evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> is wrong when he argues in his new book,
Shadow , that lying and obfuscating by public figures is inevitably
self-destructive. Chatterbox remembers writing this before ("Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> Was
Better <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off Lying"</ENAMEX>), but the archival link doesn't seem to be working just now,
so he'll just plagiarize himself.

             

         
      
   
