
   
   
      
         
            Strange <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Sexual Politics</ENAMEX>

            Do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Justice</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>'s dramatization of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
book about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas-Anita Hill</ENAMEX> episode, have secret <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> envy?
The TV movie (which airs this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>) has already been criticized for
its pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> bias, as the book was. Like the book, the movie sides
substantially with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>. The book marshaled mountains of evidence to show that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> was telling the truth when she said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> sexually harassed her and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> was lying when he denied it. The movie leaves out the evidence but
contrasts their behavior during the confirmation hearings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thoughtful</ENAMEX>, self-searching, dignified, and reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cipher</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who lets himself be used as a pawn until he erupts in an
unconvincing fit of rage before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Confirmation Committee</ENAMEX>.

            A triumph for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> everywhere? Not exactly. Consider the
puzzling way the movie depicts the sexual lives of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. The
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the movie is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Duberstein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy Patinkin</ENAMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavellian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> who shepherded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> through the nomination
process. A charismatic if not particularly sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, he gets most of the
screen time, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delroy Lindo</ENAMEX>). Both he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> spend a lot
of time at their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, where they enjoy the fruits of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-style marriages. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> are sweet, loving, and endlessly
supportive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duberstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> gives him a pep talk in bed when he worries that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> might derail the nomination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> cradles him in her arms
when he collapses in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>; she calls him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX> for God. In
addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duberstein</ENAMEX> has a beautiful blonde <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> who dutifully tracks poll
ratings, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, shakes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s
incomprehensible charges, and beams in delight when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> is confirmed.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> intriguing cracks in this portrait of happy female
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subservience</ENAMEX>. During a visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> make to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vernon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, she is all but sexually harassed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broker</ENAMEX>--he
kisses her as he takes his leave and calls her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX>." She is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blank-faced</ENAMEX>, and no one says a word. Later, during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>'s testimony, Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duberstein</ENAMEX> calls her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to tell him that she can't understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>
would have come forward if she weren't telling the truth. He sighs. Once these
moments pass, it is as if they never happened. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> never mention them
again, nor do they break ranks with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>.

            On the other side of the fence are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, a coven of
female law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and senatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>. All of them seem to be single women
(some of them may have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>, but we never see them); all of them dress in
power suits. None is shown at home. They congregate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hill</ENAMEX>'s hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> or
maneuver behind the scenes of the confirmation hearing. They have neither
cheery helpmeets, nor, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duberstein</ENAMEX> points out, any idea how to win.

            Which would you rather be--a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> with a lovely, caring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> or a lonely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>, a feminist with no life? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Justice</ENAMEX> seem to have made their preferences
unwittingly clear.

         
      
   
