
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indo 180</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX> that an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> might be necessary to control the violence
raging in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with a pact signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> which would allow an expansion of gambling operations on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> reservations; the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is the
agreement between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> command center
that would monitor "missile early-warning data," in case the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> computer bug
causes missile "mishaps" (read "launches").

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> armed forces
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiranto</ENAMEX> has bowed to international pressure to consider accepting
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that it's not clear what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">changed Wiranto</ENAMEX>'s mind but offers as likely possibilities the presence of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> sent to sway the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s warning that
continued violence could lead to charges of crimes against humanity. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, is skeptical that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiranto</ENAMEX> has changed his mind,
reporting he said that outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> would not be welcome before the
army could "calm down the situation" (no word on when or if), and that
widespread anger at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> "will be shown and aimed at the incoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>," should they arrive prematurely. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes on to list the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s "varying explanations"
for the violence, including charges that the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> was "exaggerating
the problem" and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiranto</ENAMEX>'s own suggestion, that the violence is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s
fault for playing a role in the independence elections in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that in addition to the routing of the general
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, the systematic killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergymen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>,
who were seen to have supported independence for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, continues. The
WP fronts a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>'s first-hand account of a massacre of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of such graphic reports to emerge from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead describes the deal granting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> exclusive rights to
operate "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>-style" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>, a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawmakers</ENAMEX>
approved a constitutional amendment that would facilitate the deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are predicted to approve the amendment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> as saying, "For too long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> have been denied the
respect and dignity they deserve. That sad chapter in our history ends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>."
Problem solved?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front a ruling by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> judge
that declares the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mecklenburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> officially desegregated,
thereby ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the thirty-year old</TIMEX> busing program designed to reduce
segregation. The ruling represents the end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX>, and will have countrywide
ramifications. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX>-page ruling outlaws
"assigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or allocating educational opportunities and
benefits through race-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>, preferences, set-asides or other means
that deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> an equal footing based on race." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte-Mecklenburg</ENAMEX> joins the growing list of desegregated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , which provides the better overview, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> is
considering desegregation orders in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, described as a former campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> and
appointed to the bench by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' behest, collected signatures on a
petition against busing back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ordered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX> to desegregate (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown vs. the Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> ).

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front story reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> granted
clemency by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> renounced
terrorism, as part of the clemency agreement. Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports
that the controversy triggered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision continues to
haunt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who admittedly botched her reaction to the issue last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>.

            In a WP front story, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Edwards</ENAMEX>, now
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy School of Government</ENAMEX>, claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is suffering from a typical <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s problem: She feels
compelled to talk. "This is what happens when you can't keep your mouth shut.
... I call it bubble<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-gum</ENAMEX> mouth: You put in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nickel</ENAMEX>, and something comes
out."

            Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> paid a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at a
school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> who had expected to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> failed to show up, because of bad weather, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> took the opportunity
to show him up: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign, better known for playing defense most of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, quickly seized the offensive. Moving with uncharacteristic swiftness,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s campaign wangled an invitation to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
and hastily rearranged [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s] schedule." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> left
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:20 a.m.</TIMEX> to make it to school on time.

            What's the connection between computer hacking and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis Kao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> restaurant
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> played host to a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who pioneered the Internet and
the personal computer industry, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> cooked his last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal</TIMEX>. Reasons given
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kao</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> for the connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
included: convenience (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are open late, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> eat late
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>); intrigue (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-restaurant menus are mysterious and complex, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> are driven to figure them out); and plain old good taste.

         
      
   
