
   
   
      
         
            Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> Report: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Fathers: A Family Memoir</ENAMEX> By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Salter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">349</NUMEX> pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$25</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy the book.)

             Declining to offer
details about his misspent youth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> commented, "When I was young
and irresponsible, I was young and irresponsible." His <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
rival <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> takes a slightly different tack: Let me tell you about
when I was young and irresponsible.
            

            There is, for instance the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, on leave from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Naval</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>, went to visit his latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> in a classy suburb of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>. After knocking back a few too many at the train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, he
collapsed drunk through the screen door of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> house. Or the time
during his pilot training in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX> when he dated a stripper called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flame of Florida</ENAMEX>." Marie shocked the polite society of his married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> by pulling a switchblade out of her purse and cleaning
her nails. Or, in a far more serious vein, the time when, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> attempted to hang himself with his shirt.

            In a culture where most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> scurry to minimize any hint of behavior
that might be deemed scandalous, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> reminds you of the Seinfeld
episode in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> resolves to do "the opposite." He offers up his
youthful indiscretions in detail and without feigned regret. He's proud of the
bashes he threw, the babes he bedded, and the stunts he pulled. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
purpose in sharing all this isn't, or isn't merely, to boast. It's to paint a
truthful portrait of his earlier life, before he was transformed by his
experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. Like many political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, I
have long admired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> for his extraordinary frankness and independence.
After reading his gripping book, I'm more convinced than ever that his abnormal
honesty isn't a calculated strategy for winning over the press. It has that
effect, of course, but it's the authentic expression of a remarkable
personality.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s story has been told well before, namely by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Timberg</ENAMEX> in The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightingale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Song</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> book about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Academy</ENAMEX> graduates. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sections on McCain</ENAMEX> have been culled for a separate paperback, just issued,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entitled John McCain</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Odyssey</ENAMEX> .) But even if you've
read that book, the tale gains something in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s telling, or more precisely
in the ghost-telling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Salter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>'s long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. Where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timberg</ENAMEX> looks at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s career in relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Academy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> era, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> examines his own history in the more personal context of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s military tradition. For that reason, his story ends in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POWs</ENAMEX> returned home.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sidney McCain Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sr.</ENAMEX>, were
distinguished naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who rose to become four-star admirals. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> indicates, they fell far short of sainthood. They drank, gambled
and swore like, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>. But both understood what being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> meant.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were fiercely devoted to an unwritten code of military honor. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> explains, "keeps his word, whatever the cost. He must not shirk
his duties no matter how difficult or dangerous they are. His life is ransomed
to his duty. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> must trust his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, and expect their trust
in return. He must not expect others to bear what he will not."

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Naval Academy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> the youngest followed in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s rascally steps by performing poorly as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and chafing under
the hazing that "plebes" were expected to accept. "I resisted not by refusing
the hazing but by letting my resentment show, and by failing to conform fully
to the convention of the squared-away midshipman," he writes. "… I wanted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> class to know my compliance was grudging and in
no way implied respect for them." Constantly breaking the rules and provoking
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX>, he nearly "bilged out," but managed to hang on, graduating
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> from the bottom of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> got by, barely, is typical of his oddly charmed life. As a pilot
in training, he crashed an A-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skyhawk</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corpus Christi Bay</ENAMEX>, and lost
consciousness on impact. But he came to underwater and surfaced unharmed. He
was at ground zero of a catastrophic explosion and fire aboard the aircraft
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">carrier USS Forrestal</ENAMEX> that claimed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX> lives, but suffered only superficial
injuries. You might say he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky</ENAMEX> to be shot down over the center of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX>--or you might say he was lucky as hell to survive the crash, despite
breaking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> limbs, and to avoid being finished off by an angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> attributes his survival in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison camp</ENAMEX> to the fortuitous discovery by
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sensing McCain</ENAMEX>'s potential propaganda value, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> gave him
enough medical attention to keep him alive.

            The account of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five and half years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> spent in captivity, which
occupies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> of his book, is wonderful: vivid, unsentimental, and
very moving. As a POW, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> kept up his habit of surly resistance, constantly
drawing beatings and time in solitary confinement for communicating with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and taunting his jailers. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resisting</ENAMEX>, being uncooperative and a
general pain in the ass, proved, as it had in the past, to be a morale booster
for me," he writes. His most heroic act of insubordination was declining to be
released from maggot-infested captivity ahead of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">POWs</ENAMEX> who were captured
before he was--an offer others accepted, in violation of military rules. As
extraordinary as his decision to remain a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> seems, it was entirely in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, one begins to understand, has been essentially the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> throughout his life. The unwillingness to bend to hazing as a
midshipman, to the threat of torture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX>, and to the marching orders of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> are all of a piece. He is a subversive
through and through.

            Why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> rebel against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>? The answer that emerges from his
book is that insubordination is a way of establishing moral independence. By
being contrary and difficult, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> demonstrates that no one owns or controls
him. He reached his point of deepest crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> when he discovered that
his actions weren't fully under his own power--he could be, and was, broken by
torture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s rather feeble suicide attempts came after he could no longer
resist and prepared to sign a confession saying he was a "black criminal" and
an "air pirate."

            Before reading this book, I didn't quite understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> so regretted
affixing his name to an absurd-sounding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> confession. No one else would
criticize him for caving to torture--why did he beat himself up about it? In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s version of events, his obsession with his surrender starts to make
sense: It was the moment he realized that he was beyond his own control. "I
felt it blemished my record permanently, and even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I find it hard to
suppress feelings of remorse," he writes. "In truth, I don't even bother to try
to suppress them anymore. My remorse shows me the limits of my zealously
guarded autonomy." He couldn't hold out alone, and wouldn't have held up at all
without the solidarity of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>. Today <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>,
but he's no longer an adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>.

            If there's a criticism to be made of this fine book, it's that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
doesn't grapple with the morality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> in any serious way. In his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concluding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, he casually refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s involvement as a terrible
mistake. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, he describes it as a worthy cause. At another point
he suggests that we were wrong to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
didn't support the war sufficiently. This is perfectly circular reasoning: The
war was immoral because unpopular, and unpopular because immoral. I'm surprised
that he says this. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, who recently stood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly</TIMEX> alone in advocating the
use of ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, obviously doesn't think that public opinion
should determine the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military intervention.

            Pulling down another cliché about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> should have fought the war harder or not at all. This is the approved
wisdom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell Doctrine</ENAMEX>, but doesn't get you very far as a judgment in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hindsight</ENAMEX>. What should we have done in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>--fight harder, or not at all?
Even the outspoken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> seems not to want to answer that question.

         
      
   
