
   
   
      
         
            FDR: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock 'n' Roll</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has never visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock and Roll Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, but he has it on good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> that the place contains no exhibit memorializing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> Delano
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s crucial role in creating a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
art form known as rock 'n' roll. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about rock 'n' roll's
crossover into mainstream white culture, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> they're usually talking
about is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who usually gets the credit is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presley</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock and Roll Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>
exhibit.) But the groundwork for the youth culture that supported rock 'n'
roll's growth was laid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades earlier</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            The important role played by big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in creating teen culture is
explained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> largely owned by, of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the
conservative presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> , and the article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise and</ENAMEX>
Decline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teenager</ENAMEX>," is an excerpt from a new book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hine</ENAMEX>
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise and Fall of the American Teenager</ENAMEX> . Judging
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heritage</ENAMEX> excerpt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hine</ENAMEX> takes the self-serving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby-</ENAMEX>boomer view that teen-age culture started to decline, oh, right around the
time he ceased participating in it. The "decline" portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> is the sketchiest and least convincing part; perhaps he fleshes out his
argument more convincingly in the book. But the "rise" portion is fascinating,
and highly persuasive.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hine</ENAMEX>'s thesis is that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>" didn't really exist as a cohesive social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>. (The word <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared in print in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Science</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.) But

            

               
                  after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX> took office, virtually all young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were thrown out of work, as part of a public policy to reserve jobs for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> trying to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. [Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hine</ENAMEX> might also have pointed out that
a similar impetus to throw old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of work would later lead to
the creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>.] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Businesses</ENAMEX> could actually be fined if they
kept childless young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on their payrolls. Also, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two years</TIMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> essentially ignored the needs of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> it had turned out of work, except in the effort of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civilian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Corps</ENAMEX> (CCC), which was aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and early
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">twenties</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            What did these unwanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> do? They went to high school. Although public
high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> had been around since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1821</TIMEX> (and prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> had been around
before then), secondary education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hine</ENAMEX> writes, had been "very slow to win
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> among working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that counted on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
incomes for survival." It wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> that a majority of high-school-age
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were actually enrolled in high school. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hine</ENAMEX> writes, "an overwhelming majority of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were enrolled, and
perhaps more important, there was a new expectation that nearly everyone would
go, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>." When the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> entered <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II the</ENAMEX>
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> received deferments. "Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seventeen</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>, and younger had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s previous
wars," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hine</ENAMEX> writes. "By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> they had come to seem too young" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> was also
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie</ENAMEX>, the definitive comic-book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, was introduced to the
world by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John L. Goldwater</ENAMEX>, who died
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Montana</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hine</ENAMEX> argues, quite persuasively, that the indulgent mass "teen-age" culture
is largely the result of corralling most of society's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-to-18-year-olds</TIMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom, which began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> after the
war ended, obviously fed that teen-age culture's further expansion. But the
teen culture itself--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jughead</ENAMEX>, bobby-soxer mania for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>--quite obviously predates the teen years of the very oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>,
who didn't enter those golden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>--until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hine</ENAMEX> doesn't get into this, but boomer math contradicts the boomer mythology
that that it was the baby boom that first absorbed rock 'n' roll into the mass
culture. For many pop-culture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, the Year Zero for rock 'n' roll as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX>-cult phenomenon was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>. That's when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> recorded his first No. 1 hit,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heartbreak Hotel</ENAMEX>." You can also make a decent case that the Year Zero was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Haley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comets hit No. 1 with "Rock Around the Clock</ENAMEX>,"
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rock 'n' roll record ever to climb to the top of the charts. Were the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who turned "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rock Around the Clock</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heartbreak Hotel</ENAMEX>" into hit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9 and 10 years old</TIMEX>? Of course they weren't. They were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> who'd
been born during and shortly before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. And they wouldn't have
existed as a social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>--who, tragically, died before he got a chance
to witness the mainstreaming of rock 'n' roll--hadn't invented them.

            [Thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fraygrant</ENAMEX> who pointed out that an earlier version of this
item erroneously stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boom began in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war ended in 1945</TIMEX>. (The returning vets needed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least nine</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to create <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>.)]

         
      
   
