
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passing on the Left</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tamar</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> was known as "Dollar Bill" when he played professional
basketball--not because of how he played but because he squeezed his dollars
until they wept and cried. While his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Frazier</ENAMEX> ran around in mink
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rolls Royces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX> wore the same ratty trench coat and shoes
run down at the heels. Just something I thought you'd like to know. We are back
again at tactics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> has looked at what seems like a lock
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and decided to run to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s left. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorites</ENAMEX> have seen this and
are protecting that flank--but not too flagrantly. They showed this recently
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> proposal to achieve health insurance for more of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Not all "tactics" are evil. This a worthy goal, one that will save us
all those emergency-room dollars--but it is part of a political maneuver as
well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has rightly sensed discontent among traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dems</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s me-tooism with respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> philosophy. The problem is that
the discontent was eclipsed by public anger about the impeachment drama.

            The brilliance of the conservative movement (take a bow, you crafty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristols</ENAMEX>) lies principally in how it changed the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
politics. "Liberal" became a pejorative, synonymous with weakness, taxation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overspending</ENAMEX>--and blind obeisance to welfare cheats and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonplused</ENAMEX> and bit their nails as the conservative ideology machine turned them
into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pulp</ENAMEX>. That machine would still be dominating the debate--had it not been
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> who overplayed the mandate and made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> edgy. Dollar Bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhodes Scholar</ENAMEX> that he is, is smart enough to know
all this and is betting that there will be some daylight to the left of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> is in the same ball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. He saw that frothing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> convention
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'92</TIMEX> that spelled disaster for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. He will not be out-compassioned and
will utter sweet nothings even as he pulls the switch on the electric chair.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> recognize that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the
middle . But as for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX>, he's caught in the passing lane behind the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> express. As that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl group</ENAMEX> used to say in the famous doo-wop song:
It's gonna take a miracle, yes, it's gonna take a miracle."
            

            Speaking of loaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">terminology</ENAMEX>. The big conservative coup was transforming
the phrase "affirmative action" into "preferences"--as you do in your
posting--such that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> use the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> interchangeably. I refer you to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>--just about the only prime-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to really jump on this, this ... linguistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hijacking</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terms are not interchangeable. "Affirmative action"
connotes reaching out to underrepresented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> on the grounds that some
racial mixture is socially desirable. When I go out to find and hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I
do not "prefer" someone nonwhite. But I do in fact "prefer" to have a staff
that reflects something of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that my business is meant to
serve--lest my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> falter and die. Hence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> cops searching
for gay police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. Wise move, in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigstock</ENAMEX>, that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX>
drag ball.

            On the question of how we salvage inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. We as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> must be
willing to ensure at the minimum that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have a qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> at the
front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, a set of books, and a safe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are
particularly bad--as in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, I have advocated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vouchers</ENAMEX>, not penny ante ones proposed by some in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but real
ones that would send at least a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to the very best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> available. We can't do anything about bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--be they white bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or black bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--and simply must treat that issue as such. If it
takes federal subsidies or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> strategy, so be it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> suit in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> may be slow going, but it has highlighted the principle problem. As
a culture, we have tended to believe that good education is wasted on the black
and brown poor--who will soon be the majority. And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX> said the
other day, that sets up a self-fulfilling prophecy that is killing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s future in the bargain. We can either throw up our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX>--or
send in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. It's that simple, I think.

         
      
   
