
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Affirmative Action vs. Preferences</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Brent</ENAMEX>--

            I guess this is it--our last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. In a way, I feel as if the
conversation is only just getting started. Though we turn out to agree about a
surprising number of things, we also disagree--in ways that I'm not sure we've
really gotten to.

            Take preferences, for example. I don't think that's just a trick of the
tongue. There's a real difference between affirmative action as it was
initially defined (an effort to expand the recruitment pool and make sure that
there is no discrimination in the hiring process) and what is generally
practiced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: flagrantly color-coded double standards. I believe college
admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and corporate personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> do literally prefer to
admit and hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of color for certain slots. In fact, it's stronger than
"prefer"--they make sure they do. Otherwise, you wouldn't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>-point gaps
in average black and white <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> at many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. And here, once again, I
go back to the question of means and ends. Of course, as you say, "some racial
mixture is socially desirable." I couldn't be more eager to see a thoroughly
diverse student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and an integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, from top to bottom. But
I don't think preferences are the right way to get there. And I believe it's
very helpful to have terms to distinguish the tools that you find useful from
the ones you feel are counterproductive or downright pernicious.

            (But by the way, I thought from one of your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> messages that you too
were ambivalent about preferences?)

            Be that as it may, we did--I thought--agree on the much more important,
underlying point: that, like them or not in the short term, preferences must
eventually be replaced by better education for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. My problem here: I'm
not sure it's a simple as you think. I agree it's unclear what to do about bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parenting</ENAMEX>. But I think that what happens at home in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is
a critical part of the problem. (So, increasingly, by the way, do a number of
"liberal" social policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Jencks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meredith Phillips</ENAMEX>'
important book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Black-White Test Score Gap</ENAMEX> .) I also agree about
no-holds-barred vouchers, but that too is only a beginning. (Somebody still has
to find ways to reach and interest and discipline the least prepared, least
motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.) As for federal subsidies ... alas, it turns out, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that spend the most money don't necessarily do the best job--often far
from it. I only wish the remedy were so obvious--because if it were, I think
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> would muster the political will. Unlike you, I don't believe that
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> feel that schooling is wasted on black and brown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are mostly focused on getting an education for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, but if they
think about it, they understand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> needs to make the most of all
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>--and I don't think they think that much about color.

            Maybe this is what it comes down to: Even when you and I agree, my take
tends to be earnest and yours--by comparison, anyway--instinctively skeptical.
I see a shift in the national mood; you see tactical maneuvering. I see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--some, anyway--really trying to stake out new middle ground; you see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tacking</ENAMEX> and opportunistic positioning. Maybe my labels are unfair: Maybe I'm
just credulous and you're more worldly-wise. But, whatever it is, there is some
fundamental difference here that I feel has been dogging us even when we seem
to see eye-to-eye.

            So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent</ENAMEX>, that's my stab at closure. Now you have the last word. It's been
a pleasure. Maybe we can do lunch someday?

            All best,
Tamar

         
      
   
