
   
   
      
         
            From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX> to Warfare

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times lead reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have not spent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> of the
money they received from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-99</TIMEX> to fund anti-poverty programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syracuse University</ENAMEX> study showing that federal prosecutions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> cases
have recently dropped by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and that convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are serving less
jail time.  The paper off-leads <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s referendum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> on
independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local
utilities cannot account for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 66 million gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> a day--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a fifth</NUMEX>
of their total supply. The loss, which adds up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, is brought to light as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">area</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are being asked to conserve,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conserve</ENAMEX>, conserve.

            An analysis conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> probes an unforeseen effect of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> welfare law, which freed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to run their own anti-poverty programs: A
combination of fixed federal grants and shrinking welfare rolls have left
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.4 billion</NUMEX> in the black. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> conducted a mammoth survey of state
spending records to figure out where the money is going, and found that "in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>
state budgets reside <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> different stories." The article emphasizes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> results
of the study and profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The federal
government spends <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64 percent</NUMEX> more per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> than before the law took effect,
averaging <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,300</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' allotments and changing
state welfare enrollments may feed new political clashes (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> got about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times more money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Much of the money hasn't been
converted into new benefits and services--state spending has increased only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
percent. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Some of the poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, are the slowest to
tap their anti-poverty funds.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Militias in East Timor</ENAMEX> said they will restrict their armed forces to certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> to prevent interference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s referendum, according to a
LAT front-pager. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cautions that similar agreements between pro-
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>independence forces have dissolved in the past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> will
supervise the vote and announce the results in no less than a week. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> depicts the military struggle as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> one-sided, conducted by
"brutal, rag-tag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> that oppose independence." Both papers explain that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, which has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, would face intense poverty if it gains
independence. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulent Ecevit</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that northwestern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have industrialized and expanded over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few decades</TIMEX>, despite a
string of predictions that an earthquake would hit. The paper points out that
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, a respected (though unnamed) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> singled out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izmit</ENAMEX> as most
vulnerable to a quake. Other details of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s role are emerging: The
state never set up a communications network that would link them to local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> during crises. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, vacationing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX>, could not
call to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> after the quake. A law requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> for free; costs to be met with international
loans. A dramatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday Report</ENAMEX>" looks at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who must rebuild their lives from scratch. 

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syracuse</ENAMEX> study suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>' shorter prison terms indicate
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have been less than successful targeting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
biggest illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of gun control blame federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> for failing to enforce existing laws. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> told the
Times that the survey did not take enough into account, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">understaffing</ENAMEX> or the number of cases referred to state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LAT</ENAMEX> devotes its entire editorial space to a plea for stricter gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> calls on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> to ban assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, require that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
be registered and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> licensed, impose background checks at gun shows, and
ban Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> sales by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. 

            International health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> concerned with preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX> are
trying to soften a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> global ban on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDT</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> wants the treaty to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to spray small amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDT</ENAMEX> on walls
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indoors</ENAMEX> to repel disease-carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told the
Times that such a provision is likely, but not without a fierce struggle
by unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX>: public health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> "capital flight" at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion-150 billion</NUMEX>
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and suggests that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s problems (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
carousel, inflation, and social disintegration) have only encouraged a broad
range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with money to find ways to send it westward. The article
mentions a couple of recent, highly visible financial scandals but does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">allot</ENAMEX> space to the back-stabbing political environment that is thought to have
helped them surface.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" piece takes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Golfer</ENAMEX>'s notorious
habit of hitting "mulligans," or spontaneous "do-overs," after flubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>:
 "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, after all, claimed that he did not inhale, and that he did not
have sexual relations with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.  Why wouldn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> also put the
spin on his golf <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">score?</ENAMEX>"  Dissatisfied with its own <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shot, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
grants itself a mulligan.  Earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, the paper (and others) ran a
glorious photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> following through on a swing, his cheeks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflated Dizzy Gillespie</ENAMEX>-style, eyes intently tracing the ball's path.  The
Times' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> shot turned out much better: It's in full-color and at
least twice the size of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, which had hooked left, straight onto the back
pages.

         
      
   
