
   
   
      
         
            Tough Questions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Throwaway Gestures</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hey Brent</ENAMEX>,

            Now you're confusing things. I'm all for paying respect to minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
I'm all for equal access. I'm committed to the goal of better race relations.
And I resent the insinuation that I might not be. If I've devoted myself to
anything in my life as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, it's to advocating what I call
"integration." (I still use that old-fashioned word because I think it best
captures what I believe in-the still distant ideal of a truly shared,
interracial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.) Check out my book, or just about anything else I've
written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>: It's all about figuring out how to make what you
call "the browning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>" a smoother, happier process. But paying
respect and pandering are not the same thing, and what the presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are doing is pandering, pure and simple.

            The hard questions on all these issues are about means, in my view, not
ends. I know there are still plenty of bigots out there: lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
think the black check-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> won't do as good a job as the white one next to
her, and some-though a much smaller number, I think-who actually wish black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ill and would go out of their way to harm them. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, I'm
convinced, have come around by now to accepting the goal of racial equality.
Just about everybody thinks there should be a healthy share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> at top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> know there must be black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generals</ENAMEX>, and black corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX>. And I don't think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> want to
step in the way of anyone-black, white, or brown-who's qualified. What's hard
is figuring out how best to achieve these ends, and that's where I think the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>-and lots of the rest of us-are ducking the issues.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C'mon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent</ENAMEX>, you can't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s pass at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity</ENAMEX> convention
amounted to anything serious? I'm pretty enthusiastic about his candidacy, and
even I saw that as a throwaway gesture. This is what I mean when I say the
fault's not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> but in ourselves. We've got to ask more of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-on race and all the other issues that we care about.

            I don't think the answers are easy-far from it. But all the more reason why
we need some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that can face up to the tough questions. Surely, you
and I can agree on that?

            All best,
Tamar

         
      
   
