
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Culture</ENAMEX>

            The newest statistics on the spread and lethality of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> lead at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> fronts the story but
goes instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s decision to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>'s recent 5
cents a minute (plus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> fee) plans with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7 cents</NUMEX> a minute (plus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>
fee) option. The phone news is on nobody else's front page.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple AIDS</ENAMEX> stories are prompted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s release of
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> at a national <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s main
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">takeaway</ENAMEX> is the same: The steep decline in new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDs</ENAMEX> cases and in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths
that began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, and which is associated with the emergence of the
multiple-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> anti-AIDS "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX>," has leveled off appreciably. New
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cases declined <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 11 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
deaths, which dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, declined <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 20 percent</NUMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            This means that, in the words of the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>, quoted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , "there is no magic bullet." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention</ENAMEX>, she says, is turning out
to be more important for controlling the spread of the disease than
treatment.

            The papers pass along the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>' consensus for why anti-AIDS success is
flattening out: There is a saturation effect in which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know
they're infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> are already taking the more powerful cocktail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">therapies; HIV</ENAMEX> seems to be gaining some resistance to the therapies; and the
strict regimen that optimizes their effectiveness is hard to stick to. Another
factor that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> emphasizes more than the others and high up to boot
is that excessive confidence in the therapies may be prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
practice more unsafe sex. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and black people
account for higher rates of infection. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, note the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, who represent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX> of
all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> is alone in mentioning the strikingly good news
about infantile <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>--there were only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">242</NUMEX> cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law enforcement officials
now say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> records that would have served as evidence of the
laundering of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> money have been tampered with or
destroyed. An inside story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> television
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> said that he had evidence of bribes paid
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabetex</ENAMEX>, a
Swiss-based construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager reviews the blooming of open "God talk" among
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopefuls</ENAMEX>, seeing in it an efficient way to flash distance from the
squalor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals. The story notes that the new public piety
seems to have unwritten rules: It's apparently a political plus for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX>
only. And just having opinions about religious matters isn't enough--an
atheist, no matter how earnest, would, says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> quoted in the piece,
still get slaughtered.

            A story on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has given an
interview to the gay-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in which he says the
"don't ask, don't tell" rules in the military governing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>
"aren't working the way they were intended to work," and that he would work
with military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to bring about an implementation strategy that's
"fairer." The story notes that the policy was a major headache for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration in its earliest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. And that until now, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> candidates
have largely ignored it. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> has
responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s interview by taking a position "aggressively to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
left," expressing grave doubts about the current policy, and saying that we
ought to move toward a time "when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> can serve openly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> go inside with a new survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>
indicating that low paternal involvement with a teen is a key determinant of
adolescent substance abuse. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> with an excellent relationship with a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, the study says, has a far better chance of avoiding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> abuse than
does one living in a two-parent household including a diffident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports on a new version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT scoring</ENAMEX> being developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. The
idea is to incorporate certain sociological background factors-- such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> isn't his/her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>, he/she went to a crappy high school, is
from a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> etc.--about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, to come up with a likely score
range for him or her, and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s actual score exceeds the likely one
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 200</NUMEX> points, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> is identified by admissions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> as in the valued category of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Striver</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> is preparing
race-blind and race-sensitive versions. The idea is that this would enable the
identification of talented minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in a way that will survive the
recent negative rulings about affirmative action in admissions. But the piece
isn't too clear on why this would work. Doesn't it just transfer the legally
dubious extra-academic evaluations from the admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to the test
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>?

            Sometimes you just know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> are messin' with ya. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Names and Faces"</ENAMEX> column reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> would like to launch her
own lipstick line and recently tested the staying power of various lipsticks.
She says, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "the secret is opening your mouth
'really wide' when eating."

         
      
   
