
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>)ither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel Guide</ENAMEX>?
            

            Careful, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>-reading your evocative description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell Street</ENAMEX>
Market, I could sense your inner travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> clamoring to run free. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guidebook</ENAMEX> might be extinct before you have a chance to bring your gifts to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourist masses</ENAMEX>. Accurate contact information (Web sites, phone numbers), it
seems, is only a stopgap measure in the battle against obsolescence. If you've
got to get online anyway, what's to stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> from eliminating the middle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> by using an online content site? Very little, when you're visiting an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> metropolis.

            Even if the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> is endangered, I have high hopes for the real wonder
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, the regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>. A book that can point you from the bus
station to a reliable place to eat and sleep in a remote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, day
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, is amazing. And the sympathetic voice of a paperback travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">companion</ENAMEX>, even one as chatty as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX>, can be quite a balm on those lonely
train rides when no one else in your compartment speaks your language.

            But which guides do I like specifically? I find myself agreeing with the
Access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> most often. And I love their "celebrity" picks: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> may be
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronkite</ENAMEX> of travel guides, but only Access has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> himself telling you
where to nosh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zabar's</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor</ENAMEX>'s solidity and
unapologetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stodginess</ENAMEX> warm my heart, but its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Compass American</ENAMEX> book can't make
up in literary savvy what it lacks in maps and practical information. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX> earns its keep, particularly with its clear, compact maps. It's
also let me in on some secret, out-of-the-way neighborhoods that other guides
neglect-the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">borough</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, for example.

            But without a large, unwieldy fold-out map, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet</ENAMEX> will likely be
overlooked by the new "tourist chic" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. I love that the drive for
tourist-free fun is coming full circle, pushing hipsters back on the beaten
path. In these retro-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">crazed</NUMEX> times, even the loathed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ugly American</ENAMEX> is getting
another chance to be hot. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solitude</ENAMEX> is all well and good, but no one comes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to get off the beaten path. Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> are fun-even more likely
than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> to say something shocking, enlightening, or both. And you may
as well learn to love them. No matter when you visit, it's impossible to
separate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine Chapel</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> from their attendant
tourist hordes, unless you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> (or on the masthead of
Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>).

            You're spot-on, by the way, about the thrill of putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over on the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>," as I'm sure any of the regular contributors to 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
Fray would
happily tell you. Still, I find your architectural critique unduly harsh. The
question of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 or 14</NUMEX> pages of guidebook coverage is splitting hairs-passing off
either as a comprehensive guide to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Loop</ENAMEX> architecture is sacrilege. Ideally, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guidebook</ENAMEX> should give you just enough information to get you in the door, and
then suggest a good text on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> architecture if you're still
interested.

            But not even recommendations are sacred anymore. Another pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeve</ENAMEX> of mine
is the blatant self- and cross-promotion that plague these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>. Most
guides contain a list of "recommended" films and books, including travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guides</ENAMEX>. Brands like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frommer's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor's</ENAMEX>, who produce multiple New York
titles, invariably recommend several or all of their other guides. Credibility
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> of a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>; why would one sabotage it with such
naked self-interest? It's corporate "synergy" at its ugliest: Only a sap gives
away an honest opinion when there's a buck to be made passing someone on to a
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.

            On a lighter note, do you have any favorite travel writing banalities yet?
Given what little I'd seen and heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> on TV and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, and movies before I came, I expected a bland expanse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
places largely indistinguishable from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other. Imagine my surprise when
Citytripping , a locally produced guide to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> culture,
informed me that I was entering "a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of contrasts." Access refined this to
"a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of dynamic contrasts." Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fodor</ENAMEX>'s floored me with the revelation that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> at all, but a "mosaic of grand contradictions." And you,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>? Are you taking care to "rub elbows with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> alike<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" And
what percentage of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guidebooks</ENAMEX> warn you that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, despite its abundant
contrasts, just might be "your kinda <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>?"

         
      
   
