
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Before we get to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>, I have a correction to make.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s column about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>'s use of symbolic action to guide
interest rates in the right direction, I wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s adoption of a
neutral bias was a shift from its earlier stance. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> had already
adopted a neutral bias at its previous meeting, shifting from a bias toward
tightening. What threw me was that it's relatively unusual for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> to raise
interest rates off a neutral bias, but that is in fact what happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.
The bond market, meanwhile, seemed so concerned about inflation that it felt as
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> was leaning toward tightening. (Which it did do.) So when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>
announced that it was staying neutral, it felt like a change.

            All of the above is true, but I still shouldn't have made the mistake.
Apologies.

            In no small part because of that interest-rate hike, it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a roaring week</TIMEX>
in the stock market. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s minor sell-off, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> had been up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous seven trading days</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> was up an amazing
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>. It used to be that interest-rate hikes were automatic bad news for
stocks, since the idea behind the hike is that it will slow down the economy
and, presumably, profits. But this economy seems so strong that the danger of
having the boom killed by inflation--which would eventually lead to very sharp
interest-rate hikes-- feels more powerful than the danger of having the boom
killed by a slowdown. So as long as the interest-rate hikes remain manageable,
the stock market welcomes them. Who knows how long this will last, but right
now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> seem to feel that if things are stable, the only answer is to
buy. You can't keep a buoyant market down. Which is, I suppose, why you would
call it "buoyant." Anyway, on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatter</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> admitted--well, I say 'admitted' because
it sounds more dramatic than 'said'--that it has no idea whether money it
loaned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> was improperly diverted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>
further down the line, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> leaves the monitoring of disbursements
to central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. Now, we're not asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> to hire someone named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vito</ENAMEX> to
go collect, but considering that it's now loaned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX> with few
discernible results, maybe making one or two phone calls wouldn't be
unreasonable . You know, something like: 'So, how much of that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX>
is still around? Really? Well, a kickback here and a payoff there do add up.
No, I understand.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "As expected, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX> announced that it would miss a scheduled
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$94 million</NUMEX> interest payment on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX> bonds but insisted that it was
not defaulting, just deferring to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later date</TIMEX>. 'Does anybody really know what
time it is? Does anybody really care?' the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finance minister</ENAMEX> reportedly
said."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> headline for an article on Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Records</ENAMEX>'
purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Immortal Film and Music : 'Virgin Picks Up Immortal</ENAMEX>.' So what
kind of line do you have to use to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX> to come home with you,
anyway<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> everywhere is a film based on that great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'children</ENAMEX>'s classic,' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Dog of Flanders</ENAMEX> . I'm sorry, but is there
anyone outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanders</ENAMEX> who considers this a classic? Are there any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who have even heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanders</ENAMEX>, let alone the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that come from
there?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX>'s powerful media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Reif Cohen</ENAMEX> jolted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>'s stock price <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> when she cut her earnings estimates for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, citing a disappointing performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>'s music
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX>. Oddly, though, what the cuts did was bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s estimates in line
with those of most other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> who follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The definition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>: You can agree with an already-existing consensus and still have it
make news."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Belluzzo</ENAMEX> resigned as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
Graphics, after spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 months</TIMEX> trying to turn around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. He then
took a job with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> , heading up all its Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, wait a minute. Let me rephrase my opening sentence: The visionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belluzzo</ENAMEX> resigned as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Graphics</ENAMEX>, after dedicating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">valiant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to turning around that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
