
   
   
      
         
            The Conversation
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Kara</ENAMEX>,

            I think I'll decline your offer to predict the future, and instead head in
another direction for my last <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX> entry. (Or is it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dinner Table</ENAMEX>
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of day</TIMEX>?) Did you see the story buried (alas) in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Circuits</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> today by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Hafner</ENAMEX>? It was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thoughtful</ENAMEX>, beautifully written meditation on the differences between a
real-life community and a virtual community--a meditation provoked by the death
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, right up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from me.

            "The week I spent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX> just after the crash"--her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was
killed when the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> he was piloting crashed--"was a blur," she writes.
"But what did stay in sharp focus were the faces and voices of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
came to the door or stopped me on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> to tell me they had known my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. They knew his comings and goings, his eccentricities. They had been to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for dinner and heard his stories ... They had argued with him at town
meetings and read the letters he sent to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>."

            She goes on to compare this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to the virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, such as
the Well, that have sprung up on the Internet--and about which she herself has
written admiringly. "In the course of writing about the Well," she says, "I saw
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there grieve for their fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> when they died and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX> support
in an emergency. I saw intense commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> ... But my experience in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williamsburg</ENAMEX> was of a different order, and it convinced me that the real and
virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are fundamentally different." Ultimately, she concludes,
the real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is more cohesive. It works better.

            On some level, I feel the same way about the exercise we've just concluded.
It's been a lot of fun; it's been thought-provoking; and I feel as though I've
gotten to know you a little bit. But no more than a little bit--and therefore
it's not completely satisfying. Wouldn't it be more fun, and more
thought-provoking to talk about the things we've been e-mailing each
other about? Wouldn't you prefer to see the face and hear the voice? I
would--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX>. Now that we've had these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>, I want to get rid of the
technology and talk to you in person. So the next time I'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>,
I'll give you a call and maybe we can have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.

            No, I won't e-mail ahead of time. I still prefer the telephone. Old habits
die hard.

         
      
   
