
   
   
      
         
            Homeless Couple Gets Help

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> videotape's revelation that incendiary tear gas canisters were used
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> with the knowledge of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> there and the
political fallout this is generating leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
fronts a story about tension between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> (ditto the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) but leads instead with an evergreen: the failure of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
diplomatic mission (led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>) to produce a peace accord
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, a story that is fronted at the LAT
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The sticking point du jour is how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Israeli</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jails</ENAMEX> should be released. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is willing to spring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 50</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> are saying no to.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>'s lead mainly dwells on the imminent outside investigation of
Waco, saying that its honcho could be named <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as today</TIMEX> and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has this as well.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> focus instead on wringing significance from the
videotape released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says it shows a "hurried
and seemingly casual decision" arrived at by the then-head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s hostage
rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rogers</ENAMEX>, in a discussion with a subordinate to allow one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to use incendiary military tear gas cartridges against an
underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> near the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound building</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that
in a subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Waco</ENAMEX> assault, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX> made no mention of the
incendiary rounds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> adds that when in an appearance before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, then-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Sessions</ENAMEX> testified that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> did not
use any flammable munitions at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX> was sitting behind him. The
Post adds that in court documents, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> stated that no
videotape existed covering the phase of the operation when, it turns out,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>' directive was issued. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reminds, was later removed
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage team</ENAMEX> job, because of his role at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>
standoff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> in which an unarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was killed by a sniper
under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> raises another interesting point: Did senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> listening to "sporadic" radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> from Waco hear the conversation on the videotape? The paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quotes Carl Stern</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, who was at the command center
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, as saying that he does not recall hearing it.

            There is much discussion in the stories about how these revelations have
hurt the credibility of federal law enforcement. But somebody else's
credibility takes a hit too: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s. It's a little hard to believe that if
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of a fringe-left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had died in similar
circumstances, the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> would have left the story to a documentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaker</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> vowed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that if
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he would strip federal funding from failing public schools
and give the money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> for tutors or to help them transfer their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, including private ones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run the
story inside. The coverage notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> never used the word "voucher."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports a new finding in the unraveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> funds scandal: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of corporate and individual bank accounts at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> around the world are now suspected of receiving parts of the
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> that is missing. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX>, some of these accounts,
says the paper, received transfers of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100 million</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes top-front with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have signed a contract to buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 million</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">colonial home</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chappaqua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. They will close in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> runs the
item under a nice headline, WITH SOME HELP, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLINTONS PURCHASE A WHITE HOUSE</ENAMEX>.
The "help" refers to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.35 million</NUMEX> in collateral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McAuliffe</ENAMEX>, put up to secure the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> loan. The paper quotes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> as saying that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> have assets of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just over $1</NUMEX>
million but legal debts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2 million</NUMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> were a little bit wary about
providing such a large mortgage without some extra security." The WP
reports that the angel was supposed to be former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX>, who bowed out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>, to "the consternation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>." Isn't it a little surprising that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't mention the
similarity to the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> got his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a little help from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebay</ENAMEX> was offering for
bidding a "fully functional" human kidney. The opening bid was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> and the
last bid was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,750,100</NUMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ended the auction, no doubt because
trafficking in organs is a felony.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, having reprogrammed its computers to allow
much longer screen-names, has also taken the step of preventing subscribers
from using as their log-ons any of the celebrity names that are now for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time technically available. So, the paper explains, no
Billclinton@aol.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> unless you're Him. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> is reminded of something
it just learned about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> online. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to
register with a screen-name, but doesn't require real names. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> suggested he'd like the screen-name, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IhatetheNYtimes</ENAMEX>." No, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX> told him, that one's already taken. Would you like "IhatetheNYtimes3"?

         
      
   
