
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pyrotechnical Difficulties</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s reactions to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> flip-flop--after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of denials, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> admitted that
"pyrotechnics" were used during the standoff with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has ordered an internal investigation. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> front this story.) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads with further developments in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> money laundering investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> scrutinize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laundering</ENAMEX>, and the WP fronts the scandal's ramifications for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads local with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s surprise flash floods. Between two
and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> fell during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning rush hour</TIMEX>, effectively shutting
down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> and flooding many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, and LAT
all front photos of a triumphant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Johnson</ENAMEX>, who broke an 11-year-old
world record in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 400-meter</TIMEX> dash.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> note <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s call for an investigation, and
stress the still unresolved question of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the
affair. Technically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is barred from participating in domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> work, but the WP details their involvement in the siege,
including the presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s anti-terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Force</ENAMEX> during the
standoff. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> claims they were there as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>. The investigation, to
be conducted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, will attempt to explain why the fact that
incendiary canisters of tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> were used wasn't made public earlier.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s desire to protect her own credibility
will hinder the effectiveness of her investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ruth</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>'s investigation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> assault, warned that keeping the investigation internal renders it useless
and redundant: "If they don't reopen the whole thing now and actually use
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, this will be like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> assassination for the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s dirty laundry thus far: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Billions of dollars</NUMEX>, most intended as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
loans, may have been laundered through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> into accounts held
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Benex</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benex</ENAMEX> is purportedly a front for a top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mafioso</ENAMEX> (currently missing). The man suspected of laundering the money for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benex</ENAMEX> is married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> (currently under suspension).
Another bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> (currently under suspension) who handled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> accounts is married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who once worked as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the deputy chair of a now-defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> (also
targeted by the investigation). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Security Service</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
"equivalent" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>) announced that it would begin its own investigation.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> stated that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> nor any of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have foreign bank
accounts.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> presents an interesting angle to the laundering story below
the fold. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> once touted his dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> (particularly involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>) as evidence of his foreign policy savvy. Now he's forced to
answer allegations that he and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> were too lenient with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> despite evidence of rampant, ongoing corruption.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX> offered to settle lawsuits over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norplant</ENAMEX>, a
contraceptive that could be injected into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to prevent pregnancy for up to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> filed suit with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> throughout the
1990s, claiming that they were not adequately warned about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX>'s side
effects. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> were disappointed by the amount of the
settlement: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, for a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $50 million</NUMEX>. The flaw in
their case was an inability to prove permanent damage-most side effects
disappeared after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> stopped using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s offer of clemency to
imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> was unanimously opposed by a range of
Federal law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Prisons</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX>, who were never convicted of crimes which resulted in death
or injury, have not yet responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conditional offer.

            
               Mine Your Own Business: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> began featuring
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of customized bestseller lists for places like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> protested, claiming that the information the site
made public was actually private. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has now
made it possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to opt out of these "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Purchase</ENAMEX>
Circles," which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> creates by "data mining" its extensive customer
database. This option did not come soon enough to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> from
running a few <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Purchase Circle shockers: The Microsoft File: The Secret Case</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is a bestseller at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, and the Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> list at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Semiconductor</ENAMEX> includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nights of Grrreat Sex</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
