
   
   
      
         
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> scares
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, the "chicken flu" crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600-plus</NUMEX> epileptic
fits caused by the flashing red eyes of a TV cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, caused
most of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to sound the alarm. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> reported that the TV station that broadcast the cartoon
show had apologized in only a guarded way, refusing to accept responsibility,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, it claimed, was resolved to get to the bottom of
the problem. Quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> oozed
smugness, saying that such frenzied eye-flashing was already forbidden on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX> screens.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> gave blanket coverage to the flu virus with which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>
have infected several small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s
practical advice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> seemed excessively relaxed under the
circumstances, saying merely that flu symptoms include fevers and chills and
can take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as much as two weeks</TIMEX> to recover from. "Do not struggle into work," it
begged the industrious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Chinese</ENAMEX>. The infection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> whose
little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> had already caught the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> was being urgently studied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> because it suggested that the virus might also be
transmittable among human beings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> said. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> health
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> said the virus had so far been "relatively inefficient" but might now
mutate into a more virulent form.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the holiday mood was beginning to take control
of the press, though it was generally devoid of any spirit of peace or
goodwill. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported on its front page how a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Yorkshire</ENAMEX>
had been struck across the face by a department-store <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> after
questioning his legitimacy, claiming to have seen another <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> in
another department store only a short time beforehand. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> was crying
his eyes out," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said. "All the innocence has gone and it can
never be replaced."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auberon Waugh</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evelyn</ENAMEX>), writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>, blamed the existence of such fake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
Clauses on the influence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and mentioned that, "according to
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hoot</ENAMEX>, the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> child
is so terrified by the experience that it should be seen as a form of child
abuse." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , incidentally, launched the most perverse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
charity appeal in history with an editorial asking for money to save the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">threatened Ethiopian wolf</ENAMEX>, which it said had fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to "a rabies
epidemic and canine distemper spread by the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oromo</ENAMEX> tribe
for herding their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>." "Beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX>, the ass and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> around the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">manger</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX> is an unusual candidate for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas benevolence</TIMEX>,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> admitted. "But this is the last chance for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX>."

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">patriotic British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX> 
               Mail , there was another
attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, this time over the practice of eating <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. Calling for a return to the older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> tradition of having roast
beef or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>, right-wing political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Heffer</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> was "yet
another unfortunate example of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americanisation</ENAMEX> of our glorious culture."
Anti-Americanism was evident in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> press as well, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> claiming
in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concessions</ENAMEX> at the recent "global warming" summit in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, amounted to a rare <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild West</ENAMEX> victory by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Indians</ENAMEX> over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>. This was, it said, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had accepted any
kind of limit to its economic expansion: "The old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> have lassoed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX>, who have been left
without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> since the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bloc</ENAMEX>."

            
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' side, urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Al</ENAMEX> to choose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> rather than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Airbus</ENAMEX> for its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX>, despite the fact that the
commercial arguments were finely balanced. It recalled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>'
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3-billion</NUMEX>-a-year aid for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>, was always opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy,
"and in ways that directly jeopardise <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s interests."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna Nasser</ENAMEX>, as
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> would not attend the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>" millennium
celebrations unless there was an end to "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">annexation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>," although one of the central purposes of the event is to create a
splash by bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> together with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. This may
give a better chance of success to the much-mocked millennium celebrations in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the former involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eiffel Tower</ENAMEX> laying an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> and huge
plastic fishes poking their heads out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seine</ENAMEX>, and the latter--as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caustically</ENAMEX> emphasized in all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--involving no known
purpose at all apart from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX> at a cost
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 billion</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are
reporting, meanwhile, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> has successfully requested the
withdrawal for further consideration of a CD intended for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> market
in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s singing voice, taken from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> tape recordings, has been
set against a background of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock guitars</ENAMEX>. It is said to be concerned that this
might give the wrong impression.

         
      
   
