
   
   
      
         
            

            There was nothing but gloom
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> over the prospects for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Both the liberal daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> and the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> lamented the
collapse of efforts to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX> during
his visit, but they were far apart in attributing the blame.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , in an editorial, attacked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> for refusing to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> as an official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> and
"rudely" announcing that he would have to buy a ticket like anyone else. It
blamed the incident on powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> government
who, in their hostility to the peace process, "are not prepared to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
... to show homage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> ,
by contrast, accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> of having turned this "well intended gesture
sour." "A way should be found to reverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s refusal to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Memorial Museum</ENAMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> refused to treat him as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head-</ENAMEX>of-state," it said in an editorial, though it did not offer any
suggestions for how this might be achieved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> also published an
op-ed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akiva Eldar</ENAMEX> under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talks Born to Fail</ENAMEX>," in which he
said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> no longer have expectations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>.
They consider failure a certainty."

            Claims by the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Raymond</ENAMEX>
Seitz that the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> "stopped passing sensitive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> because it often seemed to find its way to the
IRA" were the subject of a strongly worded editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>. Under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secrets and Lies: American</ENAMEX> betrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>," the conservative, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seitz</ENAMEX>'s
revelations as "damning and devastating," and said, "They will inevitably cast
a shadow over the present <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> peace process."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
deserves not only an apology from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> but credible assurances that
such episodes will not occur again," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said. "There is one move
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> can make as belated compensation. He must show that there is more
to his stance on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> than pandering to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>. To that
end, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">[Jean</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX> should cease to serve as her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Ireland</ENAMEX>."

            
In more moderate language, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> also described
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seitz</ENAMEX>'s revelations (from his forthcoming memoirs being serialized in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>) as "deeply alarming." And it said it was now
"the duty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> ... to use all its political weight to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuade Sinn FÃ</ENAMEX>©in/IRA to keep talking" in the multiparty talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>.
"Access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the capacity to raise funds from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
are precious commodities for Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">[Gerry</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> should make it clear that both will be
withdrawn--permanently--if the present ceasefire is broken. If he does
otherwise, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will lay himself open to the charge that he puts votes
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> ahead of lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> defended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Independent</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying that the attacks on her had to be seen in the
context of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seitz</ENAMEX>'s problems in trying to counteract her influence with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> believes she has been critical in focusing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> on the peace process and in helping to bring about the IRA
ceasefires," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said. "As the process enters a crucial phase, the
Government believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will keep Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX> on as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> and will not be deflected by the attacks."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> also continued its serialization
of the revelations in verse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX>, about his
much-discussed relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX>, whom he
married in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>. Of their <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloomsbury wedding</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> wrote:

            You said you saw the
heavens openAnd show riches, ready to drop on us.<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Levitated</ENAMEX> beside you, I stood
subjectedTo a strange tense: the spellbound future.

            Since the
Times started publishing these poems over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, there has been
much comment tending to exonerate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> of the blame often attributed him for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plath</ENAMEX>'s suicide.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> commented in an editorial on the news that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> since the
death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, secular funeral music has become the rage. A chart
issued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co-operative Funeral Services</ENAMEX> listed the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> tunes chosen in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> for playing at funerals, of which the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> were: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candle</ENAMEX> in the
Wind (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Simply the Best</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Turner</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Way</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knocking on Heaven's Door</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>). In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> , the top choices were different, the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most popular being <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wind Beneath My Wings</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Midler</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unforgettable</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Cole</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Because You Loved Me</ENAMEX> (Celine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dion</ENAMEX>).

         
      
   
