
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of the Cuppa</ENAMEX>?

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            As newspaper headlines
around the world were dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> op-ed piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Nation</ENAMEX> called the incident "a wake-up call." Set to "throw
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> into a political turmoil, it has turned out to be the unifying factor
that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has so badly needed." After all, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyans</ENAMEX> are appalled by
the damage caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>, it asked, why don't they similarly condemn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> ethnic clashes that, despite having cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of lives, "did not
result in the kind of humanitarian response as has been seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few days</TIMEX>"?

            In the
wake of the bombings, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> counsels against a precipitous response. In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the paper opines, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> that
shouldn't be eaten at all; certainly not by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> have always
pursued it as a policy of deterrence as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> satisfaction. But can
anyone really say <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> terrorism has decreased as a result? The opposite is
probably true."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamil Mahuad</ENAMEX> took over the Ecuadorian
presidency <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fabián Alarcón</ENAMEX> appears to have
created a border crisis by sending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecuadorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> territory
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX> denies the invasion.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País of Spain</ENAMEX> described the apparent foray as "the most serious incident since
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">short</ENAMEX> frontier conflict between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> cost the lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La República</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (who together form the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>
Military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observation Mission</ENAMEX>, designed to guarantee peace between the feuding
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>) will stand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecuadorian</ENAMEX> incursion. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> declared that the "hemisphere's peace and stability cannot be
endangered by a confrontation that can be resolved at the meeting table."

            In addition to resolving the
frontier crisis, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Fujimori</ENAMEX> must also name a new prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Valle Riestra</ENAMEX>, who held the
position for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>, resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. The naming of Valle
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riestra</ENAMEX> had been a surprise, since he was a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fujimori</ENAMEX>'s
military-supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La República</ENAMEX> suggests his short term in office indicates "the opposition,
divided, weak, and confused, doesn't take proper advantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
mistakes."

            In another
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> transition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrés Pastrana</ENAMEX> assumed the presidency of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, as guerrilla <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups FARC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELN</ENAMEX> bade farewell to his predecessor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto Samper</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20</NUMEX> attacks throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Nación</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> was guardedly optimistic that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastrana</ENAMEX>, who is supported by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX>, could bring reconciliation and reform to a nation wracked by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criminality</ENAMEX>, corruption, and inequality. "His success depends on the extent to
which he can assimilate into the political life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> groups that
until now have been opposed to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>," it concluded.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the continued decline in the value
of the "loonie" (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Canadian dollar</NUMEX>), which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> experienced its largest
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> plunge since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1995</TIMEX> referendum on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> separation, is at
the forefront of domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that the "latest slump ... has reawakened calls
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to adopt a fixed exchange rate, pegging the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> currency
at some set rate against its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>." However, the stability of a
pegged rate would come at the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> independence: "By adopting a
fixed exchange rate, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> would essentially cede control over monetary policy
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX>, yielding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more lever of economic
policy to international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>."

            The silly
season is clearly in full swing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the
Independent called for a "campaign for real <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>." Apparently,
consumption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s signature drink is slipping--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of coffee
chic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s tone was more funeral dirge than rallying cry: "One of the
more regrettable consumer fads of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> has been the invasion of ersatz
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">American-style coffee bars</ENAMEX>, all stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> and froth and cool. Their
meretricious charms have proved all too attractive to us, especially for those
who want to live out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleepless</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> fantasy lifestyle in Wapping
or Wolverhampton. It looks all too much like a re-run of the grey squirrel
versus the native red or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> versus the chippie. Now it is the espresso
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">macchiato</ENAMEX> versus the cuppa."

             

         
      
   
