
   
   
      
         
            

            The word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enough</ENAMEX>," splashed
across the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Moudjahid</ENAMEX> ,
referred not, as one might have expected, to the continuing massacres by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>, which are reported to have claimed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 600</NUMEX> dead since
the holy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX> began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30</TIMEX>, but to the agitation the killings have
provoked in western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "Only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> has no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>
plan," ran a headline in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX> over a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s fear of offending its former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.

            Everyone
else was urging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> to agree to an international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> of inquiry, an
offer that it angrily rejected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">El Moudjahid</ENAMEX> suggested that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> trying to meddle in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> affairs "begin by worrying about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> they harbour and protect in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territories</ENAMEX> in the name of the
right of asylum and the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L'Osservatore Romano</ENAMEX> (ignoring the murder of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>-in-waiting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, which was given big play in all other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> because of its apparent homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overtones</ENAMEX>), called for
"a clear and decisive intervention" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> to stop the massacres from
sliding into "genocide." Most of the press in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world remained silent on
the subject, an exception being the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Jazirah</ENAMEX>, which
appealed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algiers</ENAMEX> "to accept the offers of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and to co-operate
with them to study ways of pursuing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of these terrorist crimes."

            On the subject of terrorist
crimes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> carried an op-ed feature by former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX> (whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Unreported Stories</ENAMEX> was reviewed in

                  Slate
               ) under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Oklahoma Bomb:</ENAMEX> has justice been
done?" It claimed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> had deliberately
covered up the fact that the bombing had been a broad conspiracy, involving
several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, in order--for unexplained reasons--to put all the blame
for it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim McVeigh</ENAMEX>.

            In an
editorial opposite this piece, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> noted
that even the meltdown of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial system had failed to stem the
fall in the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and said: "The insatiable demand for dollars, and
for dollar instruments backed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, is a defining vote of confidence
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political economy." "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> economy now rules supreme,
vindicating the chaotic dynamism of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture, so much better suited to
the technologies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> than the dirigiste and over-regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>," it added. "But some of the credit, at least, must go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>,
who has re-asserted the primacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>, which he chairs, by
pursuing a monetary policy of near-perfect calibration for the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>."

            
Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">English Channel</ENAMEX>, the influential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said that
nothing seemed able to stop "the financial torment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>," which was now
poised to claim <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as its next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> unless there was a "rapid and
collective reaction" by the international community. "Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
seems to be sinking inexorably into crisis," its alarmist editorial continued.
"There is a vicious circle from which one can see no way out."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200-million</NUMEX> movie, that is--opened in continental <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
to rave reviews, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> describing it (under the headline "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s most beautiful melodrama between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>") as one of "the
masterpieces of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX> was equally enthusiastic
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commented</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Titanic</ENAMEX> is unsinkable."

            Warm praise was bestowed by
the left-leaning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration on the often derided paintings by Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>, of which the auction house <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> staged an exhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. "The old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> had some paw," it said. "Without going as far as the
Times [of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>], which likened some of his paintings to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monet</ENAMEX> on a bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, the exhibition shows the work of a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lib√©ration</ENAMEX> added.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> had anyway far outstripped Adolf
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> in artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>.

            The most widely published
photograph across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">western Europe</ENAMEX> was of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed al Fayed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> department store <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrods</ENAMEX> (and now-never-to-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>), holding on his head a diamond and platinum coronet that had
been reduced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrods</ENAMEX> sale from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX> to just under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>. He was
standing in at the opening of the sale for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX>, who had
pulled out after the death of her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spin on Bono</ENAMEX>'s fatal skiing accident.)

         
      
   
