
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of History</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            Love for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
is undiminished in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emerald Isle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, over a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, carried the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Most Important Visit Since That</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick</ENAMEX>"--a quotation from
a senior citizen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armagh</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>, in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Trouble Ahead</ENAMEX> for Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," hoped he
will survive his present crisis. "His visit here was exemplary in its political
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> and confirmed the sure touch he continues to demonstrate on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace process," it said. The paper quoted his golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">caddie</ENAMEX> in
Ballybunion as saying, "This has been the greatest day of my life."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belfast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Irish News</ENAMEX> said that "although his trip helped strengthen
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> peace process, it will be remembered for one thing: his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever
apology over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> read his
statement on receiving the freedom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limerick</ENAMEX>--that he was pleased
to know he could go there when he stopped being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--as a reference to
the possibility that he might not stay in office for long.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s warning last week
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> cannot remain indefinitely untouched by the troubles in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> aroused anxious comment around the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> said in its main
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, "With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> savings so low, and consumption sustained in good
part by stock market gains, a continuing slump on Wall Street will slow growth
as well as inflation. If this proves to be a correction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s task will
become easier. But Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s speech shows he is thinking of darker
possibilities that would require prompt and decisive action."

            The rest
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was largely taken up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with fresh argument about the
future of the monarchy after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demos</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX> close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>
government, published a report proposing the removal of the queen's last
remaining powers and a referendum to decide if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> should be allowed
to succeed her. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>, in its main editorial, called this a
demand for a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> by another name." The conservative tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> said that "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s pictures of embattled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinging</ENAMEX> to one another like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">drunks</ENAMEX> trying to stay upright do not
exactly lend weight to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX>'s call for an elected monarchy."

            
Dominating the news pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$840 million</NUMEX> bid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester United</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX>--in particular the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>--generally demanding it be resisted. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> must stop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> taking over our national sport," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> . The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
which belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, made no comment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
military threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> was the subject of a front-page editorial in the
conservative Le Figaro
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"American Ambiguities</ENAMEX>," it pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> demands that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> respect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s frontiers come from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that violated them
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just last month</TIMEX> with its airstrikes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aweek</ENAMEX> after the anniversary of the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> reported on the low-key ceremonies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX> to mark the
anniversary of the death of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>, Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teresa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> predicted
that it will be a long time before she is canonized, but quoted her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nirmala</ENAMEX>, as saying, "We know she is a saint, so it's not important
whether that is declared now or later."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, under the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Highway to NAFTA?</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> lamented the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road system</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Praising</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his federal transportation law to upgrade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that "without a similar effort on our part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
superhighway traffic will come grinding to a halt at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> border."

            Interviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journalism Review</ENAMEX> about the extent of his personal interference in the
editorial policies of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, which include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony O'Reilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heinz</ENAMEX> food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, said he gives his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
"absolutely free rein" provided they abide by "some general rules." These, he
explained, were a "constructive" editorial policy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in which the
paper is located and an appreciation of history: "We are all moving towards
what is in a sense the end of history, the fin de siècle , and I believe
this is the right time to be alive. The rules are very clear."

             

         
      
   
