
   
   
      
         
            Stumped by Stumpage

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> goes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ballistic</ENAMEX>, running an immense "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>" package. Adding to reams of
news coverage, an analysis piece reports on the careful press manipulation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s tour. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> are relieved that a controversial ceremony
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> will take place only after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> newscasts in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, relegating it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less</NUMEX>-watched weekend programs. The article
wonders if this was the result of dumb luck or devious engineering. A separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> story illustrates the rampant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Americanization Clinton</ENAMEX> will
encounter in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. In addition to obvious infiltrators (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> ), the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> "way of thinking" has invaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> (both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>); the central
banking system is being modeled after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>; the judicial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is moving toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> style; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is taking its cues
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Point</ENAMEX> protocol. Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have warned against adopting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
values--the "sugar-coated bullets of capitalism."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Online</ENAMEX>
posts the complete text of an article from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Daily</ENAMEX> , the official
newspaper of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. The essay, written on the occasion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit, generally trumpets this summit as a positive step in warming
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino-U.S.</ENAMEX> relations. A few passages stand out, however:

            As far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> issue
is concerned, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have time and again reiterated their
promise: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> persists in its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy ... does not
support the view of 'one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>,' or 'two <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinas</ENAMEX>'; does not support
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> independence; and does not support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>.

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino-U.S.</ENAMEX> friendly ties.
However, a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, who have a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> mentality, will spread rumors
and create trouble to obstruct and undermine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino-U.S.</ENAMEX> relations once
opportunity arises. This definitely does not enjoy popular support.

            Apair of essays in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different papers demonstrates
conflict over the visit. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX>, an editorial laughs at the notion that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> could build a "strategic partnership" with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, which is
crumbling from within and is a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> no
longer has the support of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We need not fear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> without compromise on human rights and political reform.
Meanwhile, an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free China Journal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> holds the
upper hand in negotiations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s agreement to
appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> marks a huge victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>, and the entire trip
has been played according to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> terms. The piece quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> who predicts "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s going to kowtow all over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buenos Aires</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> is
all abuzz over a daring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man invasion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malvinas Islands</ENAMEX> (known in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falklands</ENAMEX>, site of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 week</TIMEX> war that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personnel</ENAMEX>). An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> flew his twin-engine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> toward the islands in a
"surprise" mission of peace. When he was picked up on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> radar, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tornado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jet</ENAMEX> intercepted him and forced him to land in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malvinas</ENAMEX>. "Apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who were killed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> war,
[the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>] was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> to step onto the islands since the
conflict." He was arrested as an illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> and immediately
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deported</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vancouver Sun</ENAMEX> reports in
its lead story that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> logging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> will vigorously
fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> over stumpage rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> want lower stumpage so
they can compete. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loggers</ENAMEX> think lower stumpage will give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> an unfair advantage. What's stumpage? "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stumpage</ENAMEX> is the fee per cubic
metre that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> charges forest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for the right to harvest timber
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX> land." And now you know.

             

         
      
   
