
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heartbreak Hotel</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> anniversary of the
death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> dominated headlines worldwide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press
credited her untimely demise with the greatly increased popularity of the
monarchy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The dramatically diminished shows of public mourning
compared with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> were generally interpreted--though without any
evidence--as a sign that grief for her had not declined but had become
"private." Turning mystical, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial that "she restored to royal life the quasi-religious ideal of the
exalted coming down among the meek. ... Without knowing it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> revived and
modified the medieval tradition of the 'royal touch,' bringing hope if not
healing to the suffering and the dying."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biggest-selling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday tabloid News of the World</ENAMEX> , said
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> who would not go quietly has humbled an arrogant, remote dynasty.
... Now the time for mourning is at an end, but those in high places should
never forget--the time for learning goes on." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
rejoiced that "the hounding of the Queen" has ended and that "instead of
demanding that the Queen be made to dance to the tune of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, the country
appears to be taking its lead from her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> noted "a growing
impatience with the attempts to turn her [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>] into a secular saint" and
pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>' "popularity rating is now equal to that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> who so adeptly expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s grief a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year ago</TIMEX>."

            The anniversary was the subject of massive press comment
around the world, with even an austere <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> devoting three
whole pages to it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. On the cause of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>'s death in a car crash
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> rejected all conspiracy theories and said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magistrate</ENAMEX> has already concluded it was fundamentally a banal
road accident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> published full page profiles of the two chief
custodians of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> cult--her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, Lord
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed al-Fayed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi</ENAMEX>. Both
were portrayed as thorns in the side of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>,
a front-page editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere Della Sera</ENAMEX> titled "The Memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Diana</ENAMEX> in
Ashes" sought to explain why "the river of tears has slowed down and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX> from the myth have become bolder and more numerous." Unlike other
still powerful icons such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita Perón</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Diana</ENAMEX> has
left nothing behind ... not a word, not a phrase that might give nourishment to
her worshippers, that might render her myth lasting, or at least a little more
lasting," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "Through his songs, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> has left
behind an infinite number of memorable words, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> after his death, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are battling strenuously to save from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bulldozers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> in which
he last performed." In contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> are
"groping about in silence" and losing "the faith which seemed so solid only a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year ago</TIMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overlooking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer of India</ENAMEX> ran an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> about his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">homecoming</ENAMEX>" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> after his vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>, saying he is sure to be comforted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frost</ENAMEX>'s lines "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> is
the place where, when you have to go there,/ They have to take you in." The
daily drew a parallel "between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> standoff on the one hand, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair on the other," suggesting that "both are adventures
of convenience activated by unprecedented power that makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unmindful of
consequences." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is useful "as a palliative for personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boredom</ENAMEX>," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is useful "as the excuse for the continued
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Asia</ENAMEX> and as a regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> to checkmate
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">fundamentalist Iran</ENAMEX>'s geopolitical ambitions" (which had been why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> "deliberately stopped short of unseating Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein" in 1991).</ENAMEX> The
editorial concluded by saying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> might refuse to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair
behind them, "especially if they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> who could be interns in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for that matter."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kong</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s determination to crush <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on sexual envy. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, it seems by all accounts, unlike Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, was never any great shakes
with the ladies," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> said. "Unlike Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is not
exactly what one would describe as charismatic. He is not the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who
would light up a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when he walked inside."

            In an
editorial headed "A sorry summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s Financial Times
said that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin "</ENAMEX>is in any
position to help the other" and that the best to be hoped from them is that
they will arrange the closest possible cooperation on security issues because
of the danger in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> "that political weakness at home might lead to
adventurism abroad."

             

         
      
   
