
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stairway</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            As is always the case in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> about to receive a visit from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> press was obsessed with the preparations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s arrival
there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tercera</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a scoop--the text of a "secret memo" from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Hyatt</ENAMEX> about security arrangements. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>
were in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, the elevator would
go no higher than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> floor, the memo said. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 11</NUMEX> people
would be authorized to proceed beyond this point up the emergency staircase to
the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>. They were listed as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> working
round-the-clock shifts, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sr. Leins</ENAMEX>, Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX>, Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flegal, Srta</ENAMEX>.
Sanguinetti, Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piña</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sr. Wallace</ENAMEX>."

            The
newspaper did not attempt to explain who these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were or why they would be
tripping up and down the stairs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>. Those curious about
the alluringly named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Señorita Sanguinetti</ENAMEX> were also left unsatisfied. Anyone
wanting to speak to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should dial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50060002</NUMEX>, the memo added. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> would be sleeping in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">265</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">310</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, with the
remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> being converted into temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. There would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> bars
open during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s stay. "Paradoxical though it may seem," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
Tercera , a list of instructions to hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> included one printed in bold
capitals that it was "forbidden to give any kind of information to
anybody."

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mercurio</ENAMEX> predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would make a point of
praising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> for choosing to move toward democracy. It also predicted he
would put heavy pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eduardo Frei Ruiz-Tagle</ENAMEX> to
purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-18</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air force</ENAMEX>. Interviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Mercurio</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile Gabriel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerra Mondragón</ENAMEX> faced persistent questioning about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s attitude to
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s continued membership of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> said it was entirely
up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> to attend or not; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will make his speech in any
event. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Mercurio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Tercera</ENAMEX> published
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enthusiastic</ENAMEX> editorials on the significance of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summit</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americas</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will convene immediately following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this two-day</TIMEX> state
visit.

            Reports,
which have since been confirmed, of the death from a heart attack of ousted
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> dominated many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> led
its front page with the news that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> had been shown to Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s border with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>. But
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> carried a report from its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangkok</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> saying there was still no
conclusive proof that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> was really <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s. It also ran a feature
describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>, "with its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few hundred</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> on the run,"
as "a mere shadow of the fearsome army which once subjected the entire country
to unbridled terror."

            
The Straits Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> led on a
prediction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wolfensohn</ENAMEX>, made in an interview with the
International 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> , that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 20 million</NUMEX>
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX> may be forced into poverty by their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis
and remain desperately poor for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a
report claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "shares <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s concern over cross-border terrorism
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX> reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> was considering new
sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> after its recent test-firing of a homemade
surface-to-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s principal English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, led from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with a claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> had "discounted" any "fresh
sanctions." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn</ENAMEX> also ran a feature deploring the escalating arms race
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> ran one
front-page story--titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sex Rehabilitated"</ENAMEX>--about former Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Packwood</ENAMEX>'s plans for a political comeback; another about an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">irate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
Yeltsin threatening to exile from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> his close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berezovski</ENAMEX> "if he did not immediately stop his intrigues"; and yet another
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> . The
front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> reported a campaign by the unreformed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportsmen</ENAMEX> from wearing clothes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> logo on
them.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El País</ENAMEX> gave front-page prominence to an order by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukrainian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for a nuclear reactor at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX> to be reopened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> led with the news that gay sex at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> was likely to be made
legal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> led on
an opinion poll jointly sponsored by it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> showing
overwhelming support in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, north and south, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> peace deal,
despite its rejection by large sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX>.

            Asked how they would vote in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s referenda, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electors</ENAMEX> said they would support the negotiated settlement and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> said the same. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
said it came as a "surprise" that support for the deal is smaller
in the south than in the north. It said this possibly reflected concerns about
a planned amendment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> that would make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
reunification contingent on majority consent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulster</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
