
   
   
      
         
            Counting the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hours</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            The pocket cartoon on the
front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London's Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> showed a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s knee
learning about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monicagate</ENAMEX>. "And if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy bee</ENAMEX> is caught with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady bee</ENAMEX> who
isn't the mummy bee, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy bee</ENAMEX> might have to resign as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>. The resignation or impeachment of the president
now seems taken for granted in much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press.

            The scandal story got more
attention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> than in other parts of the world, and much more in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
than in other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
(circulation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 million</NUMEX>), carried a massive front-page headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Hours</TIMEX>," and an editorial saying about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> "soap opera," "The
world knows how the plot will end, and there are few episodes left." But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> added that "for all the personal shame of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> can hold
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> high. The land of the free has upheld the finest democratic
traditions."

            The
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> showed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American eagle</ENAMEX> stealing the arrows off
the presidential seal and defecating on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> as it flew away. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> ran an
editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Indignity of It All</ENAMEX>," blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> fully for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misfortunes</ENAMEX>. "His words are weasel ones, his actions based forever on political
expediency," it said. "He still appears to think that the affair is a
right-wing conspiracy, and he cannot see what he did wrong."

            The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> ran a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> page
scandal chronology compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, who, as its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, began investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> and, according to the paper,
was "vilified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>" as a result. "Once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> have examined the text [of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report], in all its
shocking and prurient detail," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX> wrote, "they will acknowledge
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> is a borderline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociopath</ENAMEX> who must be removed at once." In
an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> described the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as
sitting "in a political wheelchair." "He may beat his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>. He may blacken
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. His charm and theatrical abilities may see him through for a bit
longer, but it is, sadly, to no purpose. He cannot save himself; he can only
degrade his office further."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> restricted its
editorializing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to publishing on its front page, under the rubric
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point of View</ENAMEX>," the full text of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX>'s speech to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 3</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't make the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Figaro</ENAMEX>, the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, but led the foreign news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Paralyzed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demoralized</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also ran a short and unoriginal comment
on the dilemmas facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> as he comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> closer to fulfilling his
presidential ambitions.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
the story of the delivery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report was touched upon only briefly on
the front pages but was covered extensively on the foreign pages. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> ran a comment
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriele Romagnoli</ENAMEX>, who asked why nobody has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the most
important question: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, who the devil ordered the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>
and why<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, which is preoccupied with its own
problems, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, which has its mind on elections, the fate of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> did not dominate the news, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> ran a
report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lame</ENAMEX>
duck looks like a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>," from its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewett</ENAMEX>. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is in for the fight of his life just to remain in a
much-diminished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>," she wrote. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its front
page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> not with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s troubles but with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
special <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Ross</ENAMEX>, currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, is hoping
to draft a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> pullback package before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this week</TIMEX>.

            Earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> ran an editorial about reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poppy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX>
are planning to recultivate opium on a bigger scale because they haven't
received promised compensation for switching to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
must take the challenge of crop substitution seriously," it said.

             

         
      
   
