
   
   
      
         
            

            At this moment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> of the English-speaking world become obsessed with roundups, news
quizzes, retrospectives, and predictions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind or another. For example,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, has published a very long feature called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Another Year Down the</ENAMEX>
Drain." This is largely devoted to the failures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> in all walks of
life, but it also mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>'s new, hugely publicized
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brolin</ENAMEX>, as discussed on television with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX>. "Pass the sick bag," suggests the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> . Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the
newspaper include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, "what a bounder and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cad</ENAMEX>"; click here for 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX>.

            No
country takes astrology more seriously than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> has moved on to tarot
cards. By <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> standards, the predictions are very precise. For example, in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next Month</TIMEX>" (i.e., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX> 
               Age predicts
"colds and coughs" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aries</ENAMEX>, a "skin problem" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX>, "a urinary problem"
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gemini</ENAMEX>, "circulatory or liver problems" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer</ENAMEX>, "weight problems" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX>, "a wheezing problem" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libra</ENAMEX>, "chilblains" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scorpio</ENAMEX>, hormonal
problems for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sagittarius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, a "crick in the neck" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capricorn</ENAMEX>, "personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> and work-related stress" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquarius</ENAMEX>, and "a sore throat or a loose
tooth" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pisces</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX>, in an editorial, takes issue with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>
university that has compiled a vast world database of happiness "to judge the
happiness of each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLE</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Life Expectancy</ENAMEX>] is calculated by
multiplying a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s life expectancy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>-10 scale of average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happiness</ENAMEX>," the newspaper explains. "But for all the complications in arriving
at the final figures, they become simple enough when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and it
is not good news or glad tidings in tune with the season of good will. For, the
list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> industrialised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> lumps <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> almost at the bottom--among the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> unhappiest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--only ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latvia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX>."

            The list,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, "has annoyed almost as many as it has pleased, for it has
arbitrarily included almost the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> seaboard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, regardless of the extent of societal heartache caused by broken
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> and dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>." "More paradoxical still is the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> has got in fairly near the top, despite all its troubles."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>'s troubles increased over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with the murder in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Maze prison</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Rat</ENAMEX>," the jailed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Wright</ENAMEX>, and the subsequent retaliatory shooting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Tyrone</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic, Seamus Dillon</ENAMEX>. While the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> newspaper the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> demanded the resignation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Mowlam</ENAMEX>, on the grounds that she was "responsible for both these
things," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> generally backed her up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>, in fact,
sounded like a loyalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> when it demanded greater security at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maze</ENAMEX> ("if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--loses control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, it
has lost everything") and insisted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-generated peace process
"may have to adjust to the wind, but ... is unlikely to be sunk by the latest
atrocities."

            The great massacre of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> took place after an improvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> sales from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX> of normal since the "avian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX>" crisis began,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was identified as having eaten
chicken for the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> solstice" celebration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 25</TIMEX>, but
many other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> were reported to have been bought, though not eaten, as
"traditional offerings to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gods</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> crisis caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathay Pacific</ENAMEX>
airline to stop serving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> on its flights to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, where panic was high,
though it continued to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> on other flights. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kong</ENAMEX> itself, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> , fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> had switched to
serving frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            According
to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicates</ENAMEX> have been ripping off
chicken-deprived <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> gourmets by passing off cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> as the highly
prized red arowana. Found only in certain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> rivers, red arowana
retails for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $5,000</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. Common forms of yellow, green, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver arowana</ENAMEX> were made to appear like red arowana by being treated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> were then smuggled into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. Another food crisis was reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, where
reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 800</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30,000 flocks</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New South Wales</ENAMEX>
were infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OJD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Ovine Johnes disease</ENAMEX>), a wasting disorder similar to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leprosy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. The crisis had been made worse by a dispute over
compensation payments that had caused most <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSW</ENAMEX> to refuse to
allow their flocks to be tested for the disease.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, which recently banned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reported that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had been "trampled and kicked" to death by an ostrich at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX> while her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, already badly injured by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>, lay helplessly
by "for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>" on a dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported the "disappointment and grave concern" expressed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> over the detention without charges on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zambian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder-president</ENAMEX> and independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaunda</ENAMEX>, by the current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zambian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Chiluba</ENAMEX>, who claimed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaunda</ENAMEX> had been implicated in an attempted coup <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d'état</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last October</TIMEX>.

            The opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zambian</ENAMEX>
newspaper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>, which bills itself as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zambia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Independent</ENAMEX>
Newspaper," published a long and lively editorial condemning the arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaunda</ENAMEX> as "a national and
international disgrace" and "a lasting shame which renders the entire
Government of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic of Zambia</ENAMEX> utterly ludicrous." It claimed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaunda</ENAMEX>'s innocence of involvement in the coup had been confirmed previously to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mugabe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiluba</ENAMEX>, whom it called a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> and
crook" and described as "primitive and uncultured--not even fit to be a village
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headsman</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported exclusively that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire philanthropist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Getty II</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>, had "sealed his love affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> by taking out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizenship</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to what was
once the world's largest private oil fortune received his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> passport in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week before Christmas</TIMEX> and immediately revoked his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> nationality," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> is, by contrast, thought to be very
disappointed by the development."

         
      
   
