
   
   
      
         
            Their Way

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu of India</ENAMEX> caught up
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>, devoting an editorial to the subject. "He combined distinctive phrasing,
punctuated pauses and delicate emotional overtones to create songs that were at
once mechanical in their precision and dream-like in their effect," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unruffled</ENAMEX> and self-assured in its confidence, his was a voice
that seemed to comprehend the rhapsody of romance, the obscure logic of love."
The only negative thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> had to say about the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> was
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Way</ENAMEX>" was "one of his less memorable songs."

            This
tribute to a great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> was especially welcome in a week in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were not feeling well-disposed toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> said
in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the "world's
self-professed conscience <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keeper</ENAMEX> which claims to be committed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-proliferation</ENAMEX> of nuclear and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> technology," has turned a blind eye to
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has long been arming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> with conventional weapons
as well as "nuclear and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> technology while issuing public denials and
pledging itself to improving relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>." Despite this,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> actually approved the first export of advanced nuclear reactor
technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> after obtaining assurances that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> would limit its
arms exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teheran</ENAMEX> (but not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>)," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> is in a dilemma: to
test or not to test," because (contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s claims) it "definitely
does not have the capacity" to make a hydrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> tests without
matching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX> will face the brunt
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>'s disillusionment and wrath," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial.
"If it does not test, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might find it difficult to survive against
the strong public reaction." On the other hand, if it does test, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
will probably take it as a personal affront" and impose sanctions that would
"certainly" cause the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to collapse. "The way out for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> at the
moment lies in a dignified exit from the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s main
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English-language</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, devoted an editorial Monday
not to the mounting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX> to drop its plans but to an
attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. "There seems to be no end to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' theatre of the absurd over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process," the
editorial said. It accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of indifference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>' plight
and of weakness toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> needs more than mere
arm-twisting from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," it said. "It must put Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> on notice to
come round to the negotiating table by a fixed deadline. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> certainly
has the clout to be able to do that." Claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
were becoming exasperated with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> suggested that "the big, bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX>, of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> appears to be mortally afraid while dealing
with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, exists, perhaps, only in his mind."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> devoted its main editorial to an
attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> for its handling of the economic
crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> reopen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>, it said, "then at least
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> will be physically able to hand over the next
tranche of its bailout package." While admitting "the problem is primarily
political and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> can hardly be blamed for Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s mismanagement,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said that "it will now be difficult to rebut the increasing
perception that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> has failed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>." Although the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> continued to
loyally defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, it is probably only a matter of time before
other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, break ranks and push for alternative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remedies</ENAMEX>," it added. "In any event, even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> can hardly describe as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> a program that is partly responsible for such bloodshed and one which
cannot even now be implemented."

            In a front-page news
analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group of Eight</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Friedman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> wrote
that the meeting served merely to "highlight the limits of power in an
increasingly complex world." On issues such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear testing, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s carrying out its own tests, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s descent into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anarchy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were "either divided or unable to offer much beyond
rhetoric," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> wrote. "Moreover, both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> remained
oblivious to it."

            The news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government was launching a legal battle against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and
was on the front pages of most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
