
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Laundry</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stylish New Yorkers</ENAMEX> have for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> mocked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> for its indifference to fashion. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> is our revenge: a
city obsessed with a dress. (A fashion question: Why would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> wear a
cocktail dress to work ? Is that what was meant when they said she
dressed inappropriately? She confused <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> out with a busy day at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>?)

            When I
turned on the television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> I saw, in huge white letters on a black
background, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The DRESS</ENAMEX>." Sadly, it turned out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tylenol</ENAMEX> ad about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>
and her wedding dress.

            Of all the salacious, disgusting, far-fetched notions I
have heard about the dress, my 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colleague Emily Yoffe</ENAMEX> has
the most absurd: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinematic Dress</ENAMEX>. This is a three-stage excuse for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
based on the plot of recent movies.

            Stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>: Primary
Colors . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> denies that the stain is his semen. Then, as the Clintonian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> did in Primary Colors , he switches the blood sample. A loyal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> would take a bullet for him. Surely he would take a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinprick</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Stage 2:</ENAMEX>
If that fails, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumed Innocent</ENAMEX> , a movie in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> is accused
of murder when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> saves his semen and spreads it on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> she murders.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> surreptitiously collected his semen and
smeared it on the dress.

            
When that fails, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Stage 3</ENAMEX>: There's Something
About <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> . This I can't bear to explain.

            A final note. The
circumlocution about the semen-stained dress has been incredible. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> has managed to work up the courage to use "semen," and I
heard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Isikoff</ENAMEX> say the word on television (though not
without a noticeable gulp). Most other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have resorted to "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-stained" or
"stained with genetic material"--phrases that are magnificently vague.

         
      
   
