
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funny Money</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            "The euro is born. Long live
the euro!" declared Le
Monde <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, celebrating the birth in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> of the
single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> led its front page with the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>: outrage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>," referring to the "violent
attacks" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> press against the compromise agreed between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> over the presidency of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Central Bank</ENAMEX>, which will manage
the euro. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wim Duisenberg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> supported by all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX> except <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, will "voluntarily" serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> of his
statutory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year</TIMEX> term and will then be replaced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Trichet</ENAMEX>.

            This
compromise, held by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to be in contravention of the terms in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Maastricht Treaty</ENAMEX> for establishing the single currency, was described in the
Frankfurter Allgemeine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitung</ENAMEX> as "a shadow over monetary union" and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper Handelsblatt</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-trading that would encourage the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euroskeptics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. The popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bild Zeitung</ENAMEX> called the birth of the euro in these circumstances
"a forceps delivery."

            But like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX>, which titled its editorial "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Historic Day</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said the compromise shouldn't overshadow history. "Never mind
that it has humiliated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> without whom the euro wouldn't have seen the
light of day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>." "Never mind that it has shaken one of
the last great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> ... that it has given arguments to his social
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> elections. ... That's
everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The most important, the essential, the historic thing is the
creation of the euro."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> press was seized with euro excitement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> with news of a stock-exchange boom across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, under the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Euphoria</ENAMEX> in the markets," and reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> that the new currency had
already been given a market value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.124</NUMEX>. It also carried an article from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> predicting--despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>'s statements
to the contrary--that the euro would threaten the primacy of "the king dollar."
Reporting lack of enthusiasm from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> said church
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> feared it would necessitate modifications to the concordat governing
relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy See</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s leading newspaper, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, pointed out in a front-page comment that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> was the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to organize a municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> to celebrate the birth of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euro</ENAMEX>.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, which has excluded itself from the
single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency for the time being, the main headlines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> were
about the unsuccessful <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, though the liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>'s main
editorial was an attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for its insistence that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frenchman</ENAMEX> should run the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Central Bank</ENAMEX>. "No one comes out of it
well, least of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> who, like a bullyboy in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>, picked up the ball and refused to play on until everyone agreed
to his terms," it said.

            The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said
in an editorial that the pressure was not on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
to reach an accommodation but on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> that "he
would be a dependable neighbour" and guarantee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s safety. As the talks
move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
was in a position to mediate a final deal. "[I]ts subsidies throughout the
region give it a clout that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> lacks and, unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>, it is regarded as
tough on terrorism, the issue on which the process will ultimately stand or
fall," the editorial concluded.

             

         
      
   
