
   
   
      
         
            

            Reflecting mounting alarm in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> might respond to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> don't have
functioning gas masks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait Times</ENAMEX> led with reassurances by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that the chances
of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> chemical attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> were "remote," but went on to publicize
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s advice on how to deal with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. There being a shortage of gas
masks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> as well as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> announced that gas
masks were "not very effective" anyway. An alternative: Break up pieces of
coal, tie them in a wet towel around one's face, and use that for breathing. An
opinion poll carried out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX> daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Anba</ENAMEX> found that
all those questioned were very optimistic and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unanimously</ENAMEX> ruled out any doubt
regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s preparedness to face any eventuality." Although the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> might be thought to have less cause for alarm, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> led Monday
with a story headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> alert over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> terror strike" about
contingency plans to counteract biological or chemical attacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.

            In an
interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosni Mubarak</ENAMEX> predicted a furious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arab</ENAMEX>
backlash if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. "We have to deal with public
opinion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world, and we are going to face a hell of a
problem," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mubarak</ENAMEX> said. "This is very dangerous--I cannot stand against the
whole weight of popular opinion." While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its
front page with a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> had decided not
to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Yatom</ENAMEX> for his role in the bungled attempt to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assassinate Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khaled Meshal</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>
published an interview with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> and spiritual guide" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheik</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Yassin</ENAMEX>, who said he wouldn't be happy if an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> missile fell on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel Aviv</ENAMEX>, because "I don't like massacres." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sheik</ENAMEX> refused to rule out
further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> attacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, saying that "if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> attacks us,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> have the right to defend themselves."

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> meeting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led with the news
that disagreements about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> were seriously dividing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> threatening to pull out if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> put its
military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> at the disposal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> comment also
continued to link <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s gung-ho policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewsinky</ENAMEX> problem. In a front-page opinion piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Spectre</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio Zucconi</ENAMEX> wrote that despite the
instinctive patriotic solidarity that would accompany the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battle</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> isn't marching into war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>; it is being
dragged."

            Although
it was a coincidence that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very day</TIMEX> the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-52s</ENAMEX> arrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to "launch her bombs against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> knew the risks involved. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of this great power are ready
to die at any time for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iwo Jima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seoul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>," Zucconi
wrote. "But no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> and no stock exchange index could ever save a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> suspected of having sent his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to die for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>." A new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russian</ENAMEX> book of verses titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hail Saddam</ENAMEX>! was the subject of a report
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX>, which quoted from several of the poems
extolling the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tyrant</ENAMEX>. The "pearl of the book," it said, was a poem by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evgene Nefedov</ENAMEX> finding the proof of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s virtue in his physical resemblance
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> led with a report by its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
correspondent that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is understood to want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> back in
the multi-party negotiations on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>'s future before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>'s Day celebrations at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> was suspended from
the talks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> after the IRA was implicated in sectarian murders <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
The suspension was generally condoned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> press, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> dwelt in an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on a new report showing that mortality
rates among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> "exceed those of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX> by some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 per cent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 per cent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>" and
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there have the highest rates of mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hospitalisation</ENAMEX> and
were more than twice as likely as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX>-born to be hospitalised for ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, neuroses, and personality disorders."

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> being reported in every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> as condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> memorabilia industry as "inappropriate and tacky," and in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> as warning "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Fayed</ENAMEX> to stop talking about [her
death] and her relationship with his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi</ENAMEX>" for the sake of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of the new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Princess</ENAMEX> ,
denied being part of the tackiness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Sancton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> chief of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , "What is tacky is the
amplification given to this book on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX>, particularly by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>." Sancton, who admitted to having relied heavily on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayed</ENAMEX> and members
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> for his material, said he had made no attempt to contact the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">princess</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because he believed they would not respond. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">princess</ENAMEX>'s close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Monckton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany and Co.</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dominic Lawson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> , wrote in her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayed</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> were to marry was
quite untrue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> had said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> before her death: "The last thing I need
is a new marriage. I need it like [I need] a bad rash in my face."

         
      
   
