
   
   
      
         
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangkok Post</ENAMEX>
leads with good news from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuan Leekpai</ENAMEX>'s
recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> official visit resulted in a
promise from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 billion</NUMEX> in aid. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also pledged to
"support <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> exports, provide technical assistance to some state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and
ease the financial woes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> caused by the baht
depreciation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leekpai "</ENAMEX>won big applause" from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and "made his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> envious."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Sun</ENAMEX>
identifies a growing rift between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labatt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewery</ENAMEX>, a major mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, and a major biotech
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>) are investing heavily in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, which
enjoy inexpensive labor and warm relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> employ, who earn comparatively huge salaries and get paid in
much-treasured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dollars; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, who take cheap
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vacations</ENAMEX> in a newly cordial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Losers: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, handcuffed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton Act</ENAMEX>'s outlawing of trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government
harshly condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> investments, and several large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ties have stayed out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> for fear of reprisals from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buenos Aires</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> reports on the retirement speech of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, who had continued to head <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.
Under the headline "Don't
cry for me, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> shed tears during
his farewell address. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s speech "tried to justify his decision to seize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>." Explaining away the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> deaths and disappearances during
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 year</TIMEX> reign, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">82-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> said: "The possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>'s
self-destruction was evident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armed Forces</ENAMEX> had to act given these
circumstances." Before he left the podium, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> announced, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mission</ENAMEX>
accomplished." Soon after his speech, a violent protest broke out, during which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Berliner</ENAMEX>
Morgenpost reports on recent ground-shaking elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Saxony</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Democratic Party</ENAMEX> dominated voting, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX>
emerged as a powerful contender for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> chancellorship. Current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> showed grave concern, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenpost</ENAMEX> notes
that "a lot can happen before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>," the date of the general election. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenpost</ENAMEX> also runs an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul/billionaire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bloomberg</ENAMEX>, who is launching a business-TV program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. When
asked how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> can solve its current economic slump, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloomberg</ENAMEX> tells
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>, "I don't know anyone who is successful and doesn't work at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours a day</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six days a week</TIMEX>. ... You have to be more
competitive--only then will you be able to celebrate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. ... If
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> still wants to be the strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> will have to
work harder."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astory</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg Star</ENAMEX>
proves that political upheaval makes for strange bedfellows: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, both faced with rampant crime after political transformation, have
pooled their resources and knowledge in a bid to enhance their crime-fighting
abilities." The liaison will involve joint training sessions, the sharing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> dossiers, and cooperative investigations centering on money laundering
and the trafficking of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">firearms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX>.

            Top stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prague Post</ENAMEX> cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>'s impending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> inclusion. An article credits
grass-roots movements with selling the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion. Approval
had lingered <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 35 percent and 45 percent</NUMEX>, with little help from
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. A frustrated collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> then began a major media campaign explaining the benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inclusion</ENAMEX>, boosting public support to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 60 percent</NUMEX>. An editorial warns
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> admission is "not a panacea." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will have a rough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> "making new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> out of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>," and sharing government information with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Czechs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Poles</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hungarians</ENAMEX> will prove "a prickly issue for some time to
come, no matter how trustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warsaw</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Budapest</ENAMEX> appear to be." (A

                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion pits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East Times</ENAMEX> often arrives at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> with blank spaces where articles should be. Why? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s government
censors have been at work. On its Web site, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> posts an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archive</ENAMEX> of censored articles. A sidebar explains, "We are generally not allowed to do the
following things: Report on human rights abuses. Criticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or his
family. Criticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. Point out the ill-treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'friendly</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. Discuss modern,
unorthodox interpretations of Islam. Report on discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coptic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Antarctic</ENAMEX> Sentinal
reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falkland Islands</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> will soon be using Antarctic
outposts to train potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>, because the region offers isolated,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freezing</ENAMEX>, rocky conditions, replicating a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> mission, on which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> could be sequestered with a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for long periods in a harsh
environment.

         
      
   
