
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newts</ENAMEX> and Parrots

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s most influential
newspaper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX>,
launched a ferocious attack <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> for sabotaging the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process in defiance of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy.
During his recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> had made it crystal clear that he
sought to align the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> unconditionally with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>--"not that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> but that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> far right," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial. His
only message had been that "whatever he does, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> will always have the backing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress of the United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>."

            Thanks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> "is himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s power games,
participating in the definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Middle East</ENAMEX> policy," Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> said. It described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s exploitation of his domestic political
power to make his own foreign policy as "an unprecedented, unhealthy and
dangerous situation," and added that by fighting against his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diplomacy</ENAMEX>, he had "forfeited the right to be considered a statesman." "If he
should <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> take his chance in a presidential election, it should be
remembered that he tried--and, alas, with partial success--to align <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> policy with the positions of an ultranationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
party."

            There was another attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> in the liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>,
which linked him with the recalcitrant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern Irish Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rev. Ian Paisley</ENAMEX>, because both are "distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the international
loony tendency." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few days</TIMEX> they have "tightened the noose of
ridicule around themselves completely unaided"--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paisley</ENAMEX> by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX>" for welcoming the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>
settlement, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace negotiations. But at least, said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> has refrained from taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX>'s name in vain.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parrots</ENAMEX> might repeat what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say, it explained, but "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paisley</ENAMEX>, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, and other mega-bores of the ultra-right merely repeat themselves,
again and again and again."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gingrich</ENAMEX>
was favorably mentioned, however, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> as a supporter of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s right to conduct
its own nuclear tests. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s intimacy
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s biggest problem today
is that he cannot keep his private connections private--whether these be of the
more personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> variety or the scandals breaking out on the
foreign affairs front." It said that his "soft policy" toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was
continuing "despite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s repeated violations of international treaties on
transfer of nuclear and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>." That was probably why "the initial rush of condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
recent nuclear tests has been followed by a chorus of voices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in
support of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>'s actions." (The editorial was written before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
news of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s nuclear tests.)

            
An op-ed article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> said that
"Chinagate" could turn into "the most serious domestic scandal to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, so far" and could seriously damage the forthcoming
summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> "that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> believes is vital to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US-China</ENAMEX>
relations." The FT 's main editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> was about the financial
crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, saying that a devaluation of the ruble should be avoided if
at all possible and that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> could use this crisis as an opportunity to
impose stricter conditionality on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and to demand greater involvement in
its attempts to reform its public finances."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is begging for money" and
quoted a source in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> might
visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 8</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> and ask for a loan of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several billion</NUMEX> German
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>
credits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was seeking were not obtained, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have no
other option but to devalue the ruble and set the new rate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">somewhere between 7</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8 rubles</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar. It added that the best scenario for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
would be to get credits and conduct a devaluation at the same time.

            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> had almost ignored the protests
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akihito</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of his state visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX>, expressed understanding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of the grievances
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>-of-war who turned their backs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> during
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> appearances. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for the ill
feeling it continued to generate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> it fought in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
II.

            "For many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after the war, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> made no real effort to
understand the wrenching experience of war and the anguish of those in other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>," it said. "That is the main reason the problems linger." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> added that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> had tried to resolve these problems a little at
a time, "those who felt themselves victimized by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> might have felt at least
somewhat mollified"; but that "with the passing of time while we do nothing,
however, discontent and ill will can coalesce into bitter enmity."

            
Areport from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phnom Penh</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> quoted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cambodian Ministry of Health</ENAMEX> as saying that traffic accidents now outstripped
land mine and other war-related injuries as a major cause of death in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>.
Injuries in traffic accidents had doubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1996 and 1997</TIMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
main problems is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodians</ENAMEX> do not know how to drive," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transport</ENAMEX>

             

         
      
   
