
   
   
      
         
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
with the "revelation" that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> had supplied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
with strains of the anthrax <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacillus</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, just when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
was starting the production of biological weapons. It said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Type Culture Collection</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasteur Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
had responded favorably to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> requests for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacillus</ENAMEX> for research
purposes. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, which was also approached, had refused to help, it said.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX>, an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Marie Colombani</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
had squandered its "immense prestige and capacity for action" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX> and would not recover it "until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">such time</TIMEX> as it forces the hand of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>." He also accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> of "seeking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> privileged
[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> in the east, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in the west" with, as its goal,
"the gradual undoing of the assertive policies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, and
rejection of a political <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, in favor of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> control."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Romano</ENAMEX> said the war against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> was as unwinnable as the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and therefore proposed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "shuffle the diplomatic cards" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>--as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> once did in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. "If he does with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> did with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and adopts a less blatantly pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> position, he will find that he has
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and has also isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> with much greater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of embargo have achieved."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabloid London Evening Standard</ENAMEX> devoted most of its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to the
sudden resignation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> publishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> allegedly had demanded changes in the
forthcoming memoirs (to be titled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> ) of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Patten</ENAMEX>. Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">China Kow-Tow</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>--who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> had prevented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> (considered "unfriendly" by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>)
from using his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>--feared his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> broadcasting interests
might be damaged if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> published a book containing strong criticisms
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> had called "a perfidious whore" and "a drooling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idiot</ENAMEX>." Patten was reported to have switched to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macmillan</ENAMEX>. He
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> he was "adamant that my book will be read as I intended it to be
read."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> led
with an "exclusive" report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> are helping fund a march
through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday</ENAMEX>, in which an expected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will protest
government interference in their traditional way of life, and especially its
threat to ban <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX> hunting. More than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160,000</NUMEX> was raised by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> auction
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> of hunting and shooting holidays in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Foster</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> Master of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foxhounds Association</ENAMEX>, recently came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and presented a check for an
unspecified sum to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> of the march.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX>, in an
editorial, calls on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to abolish the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "certification"
process by which it sits in judgment on other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' efforts against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> described the procedure as "inconsistent" and "politicised," with
"little connection with what is happening in the market for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX>," and
noted that it "also has the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--the world's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX> of
illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX>--setting itself up as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of the poorer countries
that have the misfortune to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> reported
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> was about to challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> proposals on the
administration of Internet addresses, because it feared they would "consolidate
permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> jurisdiction over the Internet."

            The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> ran a story about
"penguin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> Antarctic
Program had found that male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adelie</ENAMEX> penguins on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross Island</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">800 miles</NUMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Pole</ENAMEX>, "pay for sexual favours with rocks and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>, a limited resource
that can prove crucial for the survival of broods." This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever
recorded example of bird prostitution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. Other stories in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> included a revolt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> country
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> against his plan to create a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> parking lot outside the walls of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> for use by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> visiting the grave of his late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, and
a front-page piece reporting "major cracks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> peace deal" that
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s peace deal "might not have
lifted the threat of military confrontation."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electricity</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jassem Al-Oun</ENAMEX> was reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait Times</ENAMEX> as predicting that "a military confrontation [with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>] will
ultimately take place which will have devastating effects in the region and
tragic consequences for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." He was opening a new telephone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> that he called a big step in repairing the damage caused to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in the last such confrontation. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> ran an editorial headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Triumph for Annan</ENAMEX>," which concluded that
"Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> is entitled now to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> pay up its accumulated arrears to the
world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on the crisis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> after the arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and the resignation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Yatom</ENAMEX>. In an
editorial, it called for a root-and-branch restructuring of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> intelligence services--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shin Bet</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>--and the appointment of a prime-ministerial intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>
to coordinate their work. The conservative English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> also called for
such an appointment and said it was "imperative" to get Mossad "back on track"
as quickly as possible.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>
newspaper, devoted both a report and an editorial to the news that a surge in
demand for exorcisms has led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> to revise its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">400-year-old</TIMEX> formula for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deliverance</ENAMEX>. Changes to be announced shortly "are not expected to alter the key
part, where the demon is ordered to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, but to shorten the
accompanying prayers and invocations." The editorial said it was "encouraging
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> considers exorcism worthy of modernisation," adding, "It is
reassuring to discover that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> has not dropped its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
