
   
   
      
         
            

            In an op-ed article in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandeis University</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of labor in
the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, warned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the world could be
facing a rerun of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. "We are entering a similar era," he wrote. "But we
have become so accustomed to the danger of excessive demand that we no longer
appreciate the danger of its opposite--inadequate demand. Nor do we feel the
urgency of taking pre-emptive action." "A large, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">unco-ordinated</ENAMEX> global
contraction is under way," he added. "We are experiencing only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beginnings</ENAMEX>."

            "Consider
the big picture," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> wrote. "[A]n <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east Asia</ENAMEX> of toppling currencies and bank
insolvency; rising unemployment in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>'s largest economy [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>] and
falling real wages throughout the region; stagnation and unemployment in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>; a rapidly approaching limit to the capacity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to take on
more debt. As the global economy slows, social unrest threatens." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> called
on central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> in advanced economies to consider whether it was time to
loosen the reins on the money supply. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, he recommended
that pending budget surpluses be used for tax cuts and additional spending.

            On the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, the famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> and former presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Attali</ENAMEX> said the world
was on the edge of an abyss and could plunge into "a planetary
recession of which democracy, in several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, could be the principal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>." The reason, he said, was that society was "ruled by the laws of
panic"--"the sheep-like movement in which everybody imitates the madness of
everybody else." "In economics, as in psychoanalysis, understanding is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step towards a cure. ... We must therefore learn to live with panic; that
is to say--to use a fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> metaphor--learn to 'surf on an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">avalanche</ENAMEX>,' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attali</ENAMEX> wrote.

            He listed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> other steps for averting disaster: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) equipping international institutions
with the research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> to stop lying and to tell the truth about the real
state of the world economy; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) taking the worst-affected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> into
international trusteeship before financing them; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) multiplying the fire breaks
by sealing off the world's most volatile foreign-exchange markets; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) taxing
international speculation to increase the financial resources of international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) taking counter-panic measures by, for example, getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> around the world to make public international investments to show
the global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s confidence in its own long-term future; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) encouraging
in the markets a taste for being different, for "finding it fashionable to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unfashionable</ENAMEX>," for going against the grain.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernardo Valli</ENAMEX> discussed the prevailing skepticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
and media opinion toward the single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency, the euro, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s prediction that it would fail and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Feldstein</ENAMEX>'s (in Foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> ) that it could lead to bitter conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Valli dwelt, in
particular, on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> disbelief that a currency managed by a lot of feuding
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> could ever compete, as it was intended to, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
dollar.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>
perplexity over how a politically impotent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> [the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>]
could govern such an ambitious currency is well founded," he wrote. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> certainly won't be able to manage relations with
the other side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. That task would be far beyond his role. But
despite its importance, this subject remains taboo in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX>, where
nobody dares to utter the most relevant but most forbidden word of the
moment--the word 'federation.' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> wouldn't risk saying it in an
election year overshadowed by the imminent abandonment of the beloved deutsche
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX>. Nor would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX> or Jospin dream of doing so for fear of provoking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost</NUMEX>) right not to
understand."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> reported what it claimed were
exclusive background details to the execution of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, which soured relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' official crime had been smuggling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> parts into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, but "their
death had nothing to do with their crime," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Cockburn</ENAMEX>, wrote. "It was retaliation for what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> believed was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> involvement in a conspiracy against him.
It followed interception by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> security of a letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maj.-</ENAMEX>Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talib al-Sadoun</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX>, giving details of a plot."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cockburn</ENAMEX>
quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wafiq al-Sammara'i</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> military intelligence now
in exile, as saying: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> knew about
the plot. Therefore he killed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> a
message." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of the letter, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sadoun</ENAMEX>, who worked in the headquarters
of the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baath</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, was executed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammara</ENAMEX>'i
added.

            
Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s biggest-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid newspaper</ENAMEX>, covered its front page with the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Japan Says Sorry</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>." Inside, it published what it claimed
was "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> article for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryutaro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>. After extolling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> friendship and recalling his own
childhood membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> ("I still cherish the memory of
a simple meal shared with scouts on a cold <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Welsh</ENAMEX> shore"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> reiterated
his recent public apology for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s brutal treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and promised new reconciliation initiatives.

            "This will not bring back
the dead," he added. "But I hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will see it in the spirit
in which it is intended--one of reconciliation and peace and hopes for the
future." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , which claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, explained that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> had written the article to warm up the welcome for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akihito</ENAMEX>
when he visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. And the ploy seems to be working. The
notoriously jingoistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , which has never before shown even a hint of
friendship toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, published an editorial promising "a new era of better
relations between our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
