
   
   
      
         
            

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> hadn't been
made the victim of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> campaign to destroy her credibility, she would
have abandoned her lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> and "nobody
would ever have heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>," her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jones</ENAMEX>, told the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. In an interview published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> had been under such pressure that she had come "within a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whisker</ENAMEX>" of abandoning the lawsuit. Pressed to accept a financial settlement
that would have let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> off without so much as an apology, she is now
adamant that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> be made to atone for calling her a "pathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>."

            "The only
settlement we're going to accept from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is: 'I was wrong. I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apologise</ENAMEX>. I admit that I was in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula</ENAMEX>,' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> said. "We gave
him wiggle room before. We were willing to let him say 'I may have.' But now
we've collected a lot more evidence and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of wiggle room are over. The
word 'may' has been stricken. He is going to have to confess to everything on
our terms now, or face <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>."

            The interview was conducted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, who, as a former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , used to work with
right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political campaigners--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>
would call them--to expose financial and sexual sleaze involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
(See 
                  Slate
               's review of his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: The
Unreported <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories</ENAMEX> .) Banned from giving interviews by a judicial gag order,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> was doing "her best to prevent their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> running
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amok</ENAMEX> and raiding the fridge," while her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> spoke on her behalf,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX> wrote.

            "These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> just don't seem to understand that being called a whore
means something, something we can't live with," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jones</ENAMEX> told him, singling
out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> mainly responsible for bringing
disaster on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "If it had not been for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX> coming out on TV
and saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula</ENAMEX>'s story was 'tabloid trash for cash' ... this whole thing
could have been settled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> with a quiet apology," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jones</ENAMEX>
said. "He chose the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to pick a fight with, didn't he? And now he's
brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to the brink of impeachment. If I could give one piece of
advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, it's get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX>. Fast." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is not alone
in his opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>. See this dispatch
by 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jake Weisberg</ENAMEX>.)

            
Coverage of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monicagate</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexgate</ENAMEX>,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexygate</ENAMEX>," and (increasingly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fornigate</ENAMEX>" continued to be enormous
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, but much less extensive in the rest of the world. Editorial opinion
almost everywhere continued to be dominated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hopes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, whatever his mistakes, should complete his term of office and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
that the crisis should be rapidly resolved. As the headline over an article by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Guardian</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief pundit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Young</ENAMEX>, put it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>: "Let's hope the lecher
survives."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, an editorial in the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Express</ENAMEX> deplored
the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was willing to put its business with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
on hold in order to "explore such inanities as that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>]
who is claiming <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> just because, as she claims, she has
intimate knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s genitalia." This claim is as "wild as
any," the editorial continued, pointing out that a recent survey in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
showed that even long-married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> were unable to properly identify their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>' genitalia "under experimental conditions." Incredulous that the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system" would make "a monumental event" out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
contradictory claims, it concludes, "So far, all the ballyhoo over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged involvement with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> could serve only one purpose.
That of reminding us that after winning the cold war, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has lost control.
Perhaps the cold war was a symbolic reminder to the world that the preservation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> can best come about through the natural conflict of dialectical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. In the present circumstances, we may have to start thinking in terms of
reinventing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. If only to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> get their act
together."

            Quoted in his own newspaper, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianni Agnelli</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plight reminded him of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> had said
when he was criticized for having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>: "What do they want? A eunuch in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agnelli</ENAMEX> spoke warmly, too, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, saying: "I
know her well. She is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rank. Of great quality. I wouldn't
want her against me as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>." In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> seems especially popular in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corriere</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennio Caretto</ENAMEX> wrote: "The facts have
proved that, among many wrong personal choices made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was the
right one.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Macbeth</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>, as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> call her because of her toughness and her imperiousness,
has been and still is his inspiration, his ace in the sleeve." Referring to her
TV appearances <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caretto</ENAMEX> concluded, "It is certain, in any case, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, with her dignity and her firmness, under the able <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dressers</ENAMEX>--her make-up, her haircut, her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, her imperial eagle pin [?] were
all new--enchanted a good part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> isn't among the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> of history, she, on the other hand, is among the best first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ladies</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
