
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Celebrating the release in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midnight in the Garden of Good and Evil</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> devoted no less
than its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pages to him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, while Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX> ran an article and an
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Free Man</ENAMEX>." Both papers
portrayed him as a rare independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. Libération
filled its front page with a scowling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX> under the headline "The Eastwood
Case."

            Amid the deepening <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
crisis, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldona Elezi</ENAMEX> was crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Albania</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tirana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s first national beauty contest since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The runner-up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johana Gega</ENAMEX>, recently celebrated her
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> birthday. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Albania</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteachers</ENAMEX> typically earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 to $70</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>) and said she
wants to become an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>.

            Amid
general condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> over the repression
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, the conservative Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> struck a discordant note with a column
defending his right to "maintain order" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> and attacking the
economic sanctions decided upon by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact Group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Commentator Patrick Besson</ENAMEX> wrote that the new sanctions were the
equivalent of "pushing under water the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of someone who is already
drowning," and asked, "This international community, is it you? Is it me? If
not, who is it?"

            In an op-ed article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortimer</ENAMEX> said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>,
are the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the new world order": "It is largely in reaction to
them that, by a series of improvisations, the vaunted 'international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'
has defined itself." They have obliged the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--which, after winning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, would have happily left the rest of the world to its own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devices</ENAMEX>--to continue with "the tiresome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of threatening and using
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>, deploying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in faraway places, and cobbling together coalitions."
And they had presented the rest of the world with constant dilemmas: "to demand
more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> or less, to tag along behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> or to risk
being labelled accomplices of evil."

            The legend
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s triumph in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> underwent further
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embellishment</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> devoted a whole page to a detailed
account of the negotiations, attributing a crucial role to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanceros de</ENAMEX>
Cohiba cigars. It said that after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a sticky first half-hour</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cigars from his pocket and offered him one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
looked him straight in the eye, hesitated for "long" <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>, and then said, "I
only smoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in whom I have confidence." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A moment</TIMEX> later, he accepted
the cigar.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> published a front-page
photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Paul Getty Jr.</ENAMEX> in top hat and tails outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX>,
where he had been invested with a knighthood by the queen. The newly created
Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>, recently became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizen</ENAMEX>, and he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that he felt "very proud to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>" when
he heard "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God Save the Queen</ENAMEX>" being played. "It's my national anthem now," he
said. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said that after giving away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $320</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> cultural and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 15 years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Getty</ENAMEX> had "imperceptibly become an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> himself." It concluded,
"This eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knight</ENAMEX> is a model <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also
announced that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent National Directors</ENAMEX>, a body established when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> bought the paper to ensure he didn't interfere in its editorial
policies, had rejected allegations that he had suppressed criticism of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> came under attack from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX>, who told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> in an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> didn't
need to kowtow to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to protect his business interests there. "He has at his
disposal a wide-ranging publicity and propaganda organ," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX> said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> should be afraid of him, and not the other way round." The next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day Wei</ENAMEX> was reported as having called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX>
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-faced" and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coward</ENAMEX>" for failing to join him in a photo call and
allegedly keeping him away from the press. Despite foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> denials, the
Daily 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> "showed every
sign of being browbeaten by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and dazzled by the potential
of its market. So much for an ethical foreign policy."

            Leading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with the
news of its acquisition by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony O'Reilly</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.J. Heinz Co.</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Independent Newspapers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
said it was adopting, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, an
American-style editorial system, with an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>" in charge of news and an
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor-in-chief</ENAMEX>" in charge of comment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a new
parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent Newspapers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bradlee</ENAMEX>, former executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Patten</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Murdoch nemesis</ENAMEX>, is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX> said he believed the system would
work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. "The principle is well established in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and I believe it
makes for very healthy journalism," he said.

         
      
   
