
   
   
      
         
            

            The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> led its
front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the alarming headline "Neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> tide sweeps through
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX>." The story, by its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Traynor</ENAMEX>, said that
"large parts of formerly communist east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> are becoming virtual no-go
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> 'outsiders' as support for racist, neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX>, backed by violence, intimidation and clandestine propaganda, grows
rapidly across the region, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in the worst-affected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brandenburg</ENAMEX>, which forms the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hinterland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, had listed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> as neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> reported.

            "Nationally there was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX> increase in extreme rightwing offences <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, with the proportion
considerably higher in the east. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> put the number of active
neo-Nazis at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47,000</NUMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.5 per cent</NUMEX> increase on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX> and the first
rise in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. But that figure represents only the hard core of those
prepared to organise and engage in violence. In the east ... much of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, young and old, is receptive to neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> ideas, sympathetic to such
views, and often tacitly endorsing violence against the heterodox."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said in an editorial: "Worse than neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazism</ENAMEX> proper and the dribble of
neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> incidents in the west is the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Germans</ENAMEX> who would not
consciously embrace racist or far right ideas, seem ready to work themselves up
into a hysterical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>, as the recent uproar
over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> shows. What is happening in both <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">halves</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in an election
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is that the mainstream political agenda is being affected by racist and
extremist ideas." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that sees itself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> "surely
has a duty to curb the growth of racist attitudes whether in the crude protest
form they take in the east or the more subtle variants seen in the west," the
editorial concluded.

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> "deeply offended" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> by publishing a front-page cartoon of him in
the uniform and helmet of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> concentration-camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> to mark his arrival
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> for a summit meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine</ENAMEX> later reported on the summit under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Rome Kohl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calms Anti-German Waves</ENAMEX>," but it also quoted at length from an article in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
suggesting that sharp differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> about the single
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency--the euro--might become "permanent." The article complained
that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s "war of nerves" over the euro, from which many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Europeans</ENAMEX>
would like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> excluded, had split the continent into three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blocs</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South European</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> made the front-page lead in several
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> under dramatic headlines but was reported more calmly on
inside pages across most of the rest of the world. It didn't, for example, make
the front page of either Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankfurter Allgemeine</ENAMEX> , which led instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> peace talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, with much emphasis on the dispute about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s proposed visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported a
furor
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> when this subject came up. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset Shmuel Halpert</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Torah Judaism</ENAMEX>) described the invitation to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> as "a desecration of the memory of the murdered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, the
trampling of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> honor and the abuse of the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>," Saleh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saleem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadash</ENAMEX>) yelled back, "If you had been alive during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, you
would have been on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rechavam Ze'evi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moledet</ENAMEX>) said that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> who had expressed a
willingness to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> were "stoop-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who were groveling to
this scoundrel." But Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shevach Weiss</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>), himself a
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>, said he welcomed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>,
because it would be "a slap in the face of all <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deniers</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> 's editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> was titled "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX>," and it blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> embargo for the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> was still <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>. "The embargo is one
of the mainstays of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>," it said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> knows
that perfectly well, but till now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> hasn't had the courage to face
up to the anti-Castro dogmatists in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. It is a sign of the times
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban-American</ENAMEX> opposition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> is beginning to evolve. If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>, in his turn, increases the pressure against the embargo, he will
participate once again in collapse of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>."

            In the
Far East and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> region, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> gave prominence to the failure of
the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> rescue package to restore faith in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, where the national currency, the rupiah, had just fallen
in value by another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> reported that, according to an "internal document prepared by a
major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, which was circulating in the financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>," the rupiah is now a " 'gaping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black hole</ENAMEX>, there is no alternative
other than the probably violent overthrow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> [of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>].' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mugabe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>, where another
collapsing currency and hyperinflation provoked food riots <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in the
capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harare</ENAMEX>, was accused in neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> of being the sole
cause of his own misfortunes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg Star</ENAMEX> said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mugabe</ENAMEX>'s arrogant disregard for the health of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> was astonishing," adding that he had failed to consider any of the
economic consequences of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> politically motivated decisions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) ordering his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to "find" the money to pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> unbudgeted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gratuities</ENAMEX> and pensions and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) ordering the seizure of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
privately owned farmland, most of which was owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.

            While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimbabwe's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chen Chimutengwende</ENAMEX> justified the
land-seizure plan by saying that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was only protecting white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> from black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> who, otherwise, would rise up and kill [them],"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mugabe</ENAMEX> had defiantly stated that he intended to go ahead with the seizures, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reported. "Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zimbabweans</ENAMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, hope
he will pause and rethink his positions on the land issue, the economy and
democracy," it concluded.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX>
reported that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81-year-old</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">violinist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yehudi Menuhin</ENAMEX> (now an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English lord</ENAMEX>) had been outraged by hints that his health was responsible for
the last-minute cancellation of a concert to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 24</TIMEX>. He
was to have conducted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuanian Symphony Orchestra</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Fort</ENAMEX> as part
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> -anniversary celebrations, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>
announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that the concert was being canceled for "unforeseen
reasons," while privately hinting that this was because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menuhin</ENAMEX> was unwell. The
real reason, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX> , was that they had failed to arrange for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> to come. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menuhin</ENAMEX> had written an angry letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX>
saying that he was in perfect health and would still be happy to come if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orchestra</ENAMEX> did. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> were now trying to persuade him to come without
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> added, "but the chances of that seem rather
remote."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX>
reported
on its front page the murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Anglican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergyman</ENAMEX>, found
stabbed to death in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with a collection of gay pornographic
magazines at his feet. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> said they "could not exclude" the possibility
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Beyhedt</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vicar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All Saints</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican Episcopal Church</ENAMEX>, was the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> in a series of murders that
have shocked the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> gay community. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrico Suni Lizi</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s household and a known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>, was found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>
with his head smashed in by a candelabrum.

         
      
   
