
   
   
      
         
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netherlander</ENAMEX> reports
that former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> central bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and monetary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Szasz</ENAMEX> is
gravely concerned about the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic and Monetary Union</ENAMEX>. Szasz
worries that standards for entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> will soon be diluted and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s admission could cause "major problems": "If that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is permitted
to join, it will be on the basis of what they say they are going to do, not on
what has been achieved."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimbabwe Standard</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">700 Zimbabweans</ENAMEX> die of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the sexually active
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> positive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of health and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> welfare
also notes two sad trends: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS sufferers</ENAMEX> has
overtaken discrimination on the basis of race and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most people</ENAMEX>
want to pretend [<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>] is a black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, but the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is equally
affected, they just have more money to keep it hidden for a longer time than
their black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>."

            An editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vancouver Sun</ENAMEX> supports the immigration curbs recently
suggested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the piece notes, that is often accused
of racism and extremism). Among the proposals: Tie immigration levels to the
unemployment rate--when more jobs are open, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> can be let in; give
higher priority to the "independent" class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> (those with necessary
job skills); crack down on family sponsorship of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, limiting it to
immediate family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>; and cut down on fraudulent claims of refugee
status.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Petersburg Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> identifies a bizarre <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> forming in reaction to burial
plans for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas II</ENAMEX>, the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>. The remains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX> and his family
are set to be formally buried, with an official ceremony, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petersburg</ENAMEX>. Vehemently protesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX> are, on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side, monarchists (who
severely doubt the authenticity of the remains) and, on the other side, radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Communists</ENAMEX> (who claim the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> is "reviving the ghost of tsarism--because
those in power have nothing to rely on"). Another theory: The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX> is a "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'dress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rehearsal</ENAMEX>' for the eventual burial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> himself." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, a
"pragmatist," wants to plan ahead for his final sendoff, argues an anonymous
source.

            
The Guyana
Chronicle announces that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electoral Assistance Bureau</ENAMEX> has determined
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guyanese</ENAMEX> elections fair and valid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAB</ENAMEX> found that "no polling
place was considered to have had a poll that was unacceptable or invalid."
Controversy had engulfed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX> election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Jagan</ENAMEX>, with
repeated attempts to declare her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> illegitimate. Jagan greeted the
good news by declaring, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAB</ENAMEX> report proves what we always had known."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX> reports on a
downside to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar es Salaam</ENAMEX>'s exploding night life: "decaying social values." The
entertainment and gambling industries, successful and still expanding, have
spawned prostitution as a growing field in this economically shaky <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
Smart, educated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gainfully</ENAMEX> employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have taken to becoming casual sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--the profits of a single <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> can equal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>'s paycheck from a
legitimate job.

         
      
   
