
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hiccups in Iraq</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> presaged the latest
Iraqi brouhaha with a brief account of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s objections to the current weapons
monitoring program. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> had asked for an accelerated schedule of inspections so that
sanctions could be lifted immediately. They recoiled at the specifics of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>'s plan, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tariq Aziz</ENAMEX> reportedly saying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> were up to their "old games and tricks." The conservative
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> saw the widening clash--in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> announced it
would no longer cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>--as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">face-off</ENAMEX>, prompted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> maintains that the inspection
regime is being abused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to maintain the embargo
indefinitely." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also voiced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>' reaction to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> calling it a "hiccup." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hiccup</ENAMEX> could lead to "another stand-off with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of the sort that
almost led to war in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, and before that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX>," the paper
speculated.

            By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> had united with its conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to accuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> of prompting another confrontation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> continue to attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
program for "serving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> interests," rather than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world's</ENAMEX>.

            The appointment of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of finance in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiichi Miyazawa</ENAMEX>, who also served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finance minister</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>--will
do little to pull that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> out of its economic mudslide, wrote the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s is "an economy from which confidence is being
drained by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX>." The gravity of the crisis is underlined continually,
and the growing concerns are (appropriately) illustrated on a global scale,
since any injury felt by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> would also be felt internationally. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Times</ENAMEX> reported that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Chamber of Commerce and Industry</ENAMEX> had called on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for a
bailout "for small- and medium-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, which have been hit especially
hard by the prolonged economic slump." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keizo Obuchi</ENAMEX> that he "may be one of the most globally criticised prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s history." As the crisis escalates, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> pile on
further.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Vision</ENAMEX>
("For a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Uganda</ENAMEX>") scored a scoop of sorts in its coverage of the
rebellion against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Congolese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in the eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">regions of Congo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Vision</ENAMEX> reported that rebel front <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>
Z'Ahidi <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ngoma</ENAMEX> had announced on the radio that the uprising was a nationwide
movement, even though the rebellion is led by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> that is
closely allied with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX>-dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ngoma</ENAMEX> insisted that the fighting
was not an incipient attempt by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwandans</ENAMEX> to colonize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>. No paper
appeared to have collected any comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kabila</ENAMEX> himself on the uprising.

             

         
      
   
