
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ups and Downs</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rejoicing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>; despair
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. "They are world champions, and they brought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and a half</NUMEX> million
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champs-Elysées</ENAMEX>, the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> in the world and the
mythological <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>," said the normally restrained Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s most serious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, which won an unexpected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> in the
World <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cup</ENAMEX> final in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX> said on its front
page that "in the euphoria which has overcome the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> there is a dominating
idea that something has changed, or may change, in the collective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consciousness</ENAMEX>, in our vision of our own identity." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> would become less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racist</ENAMEX>, it said (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> were of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>,
nonimmigrant backgrounds). And it pointed out that the far-right, racist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Front Party</ENAMEX> had "found itself, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages</TIMEX>, unheard, in
fact totally irrelevant."

            The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX>, in a
front-page comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alain Peyrefitte</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> victory showed
there was "still a future for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> confidence, for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> ambition, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> unity." Referring to the multiracial nature of the winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> said, "They spoke to us of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. They made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> sing in our hearts.
They gave us a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> pride, they offered a model to the universe."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening Standard</ENAMEX> commented:

            We have
often remarked before upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> tendency towards emotionalism and
triumphalism on the slenderest of grounds--they can become dangerously
stimulated over a game of boules. ... This may be an appropriate moment at
which to draw the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> to the shortcomings of their
nationalized industries, fiscal honesty, road safety, hygiene, and performance
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waterloo</ENAMEX>. Otherwise, it would all really be unbearable.

            The burning of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ballymoney</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, by suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> dominated most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> devoted its
front
page to a poem--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Songs on the Death of Children</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich Ruckert</ENAMEX>--and
its main editorial space to a psalm of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lord Is My</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX>." In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> has stalked our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
and it has touched us each on the shoulder." It further suggested "[i]t would
be a powerful focus for healing if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were to nominate a day
when we could each reassert the commitment to basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> principles we
made at baptism."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
called
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first minister</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, to show "an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unequivocal</ENAMEX> commitment to the law, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> and equality" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. It
concluded, "We in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> have so often asked: need it ever be thus? The wider
world will ask the same question, and get the same answer. There need not, and
must not, be any more sacrifices of the innocent."

            
Following the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryutaro Hashimoto</ENAMEX> after a drubbing in elections for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upper House</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that "the change is cataclysmic" and
called on the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> to dissolve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower House</ENAMEX> to permit a
general election. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainichi Shimbun</ENAMEX>, pointing out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> failed to win a single seat in metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX>,
blamed the election defeat on "rising unemployment and bankruptcies."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Times</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
that the election had "injected greater uncertainty into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s political
future, but at the same time the outcome has raised hopes for the realization
of greater justice and fairness in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s parliamentary democracy." It
said, "[t]here will be no respite allowed for the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that vacillation over tax cuts had cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>
his job. "His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> will have to set a firm course and stick to it," it
said. "Unless the will is there to restructure and introduce transparency, the
system could collapse, with the prospect of dragging down the rest of the
global economy."

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainichi Shimbun</ENAMEX> devoted its main editorial to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s new defense cuts, pointing out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> expects to save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion yen</NUMEX> on its defense bill over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three years</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> expenditure continues to rise. "Why has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> been unable to reap a
peace dividend like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>?" it asked. "No convincing explanation
has as yet been found. The pace of deregulation and financial-market
liberalization are not the only areas in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> lags behind Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>; it appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s defense, too, is due for a thoroughgoing
review."

             

         
      
   
