
   
   
      
         
            Odd <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Out</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>"
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> came under
worldwide fire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for refusing to support a permanent international war
crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' "unfortunately
petulant" opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, which was established by an accord signed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. Describing the agreement as "a landmark in the quest for a
more decent world," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said "there would be more reason to celebrate
... if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had been a signatory" instead of joining "China, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> as one of the handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> voting against it." The
"superpower that sees itself as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX> of the world's conscience should think
again," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> added. "Otherwise, it could jeopardise its claim to the
moral high ground in international affairs."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in
an editorial page article signed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katja Ridderbusch</ENAMEX> that "if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
wants to be consistent with its own pretensions, it has no choice but to
approve the idea of a world system of justice." And whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> "love each other," it predicted they will have to "work
together in both their interests."

            Passionately welcoming the agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> lamented
that the "intransigence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [flawed]
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s mandate ... in several crucial respects." Its main complaint was
that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> proposal to rule the use of nuclear weapons a war crime was
rejected "by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> officially-recognised nuclear<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-weapon</ENAMEX> states." The
opposition was "completely irrational," said the paper, "[b]ut since the
nuclear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> did not want their right to commit mass murder to be compromised
in any way, they ultimately had their way."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>,
under the headline "Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> obscenity," an editorial in the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stridently</ENAMEX> condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> agreement's inclusion, on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> initiative, of
a paragraph that defined as a war crime an occupying power's transfer of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> to territory it has occupied. "This attempt to place the relocation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Judea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Samaria</ENAMEX> on the same moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> as genocide and ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleansing</ENAMEX> is obscene," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. It described the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> failure to exempt its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s jurisdiction
as "a stinging diplomatic rebuff."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
Star published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of many extravagant eulogies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>
as he celebrated both his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 th</NUMEX> birthday and his marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gra√</ENAMEX>ßa
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machel</ENAMEX>. Calling him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> "who came to be revered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vagabonds</ENAMEX>
alike," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> said: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madiba</ENAMEX>, we wish you health, wealth, happiness
and, most of all, we wish you love. When we look at you, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, we see
all that is and can be good about our beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Johannesburg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> said in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> editorial marking <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Population Day</ENAMEX> that the projected
increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">758 million to 1,454 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between now</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2025</TIMEX> (compared with an expected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28 million</NUMEX> decline in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> over the same period to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 700 million</NUMEX>) "need not spell only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">doom</ENAMEX> and gloom." It said that if the widely used term "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> renaissance"
signifies "a deliberate developmental revival" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, the future of the
continent might still provide hope for all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. But if "political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chicanery</ENAMEX> and corruption" continue, the term might be "soon enough consigned to
the already substantial scrap heap of meaningless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> catch phrases."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the queen of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> may be restored as a
kind of sovereign to her former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Fiji</ENAMEX>. Though committed
to keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a presidential republic, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Council of Chiefs</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suva</ENAMEX> might approve, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two day</TIMEX> meeting starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the queen's symbolic
return as "paramount <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuvalu</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of atolls in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, reincorporated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Jack</ENAMEX> into its own flag after people
criticized its removal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> gave major coverage to a recent photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherie Blair</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, showing her wearing a "bioelectric" pendant
round her neck to protect her from harmful energy rays. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pendant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX>, chiropractor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Brown</ENAMEX>, as saying
that it "contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'magical</ENAMEX> configuration' of quartz and other crystals which
deflect electromagnetic radiation from modern office equipment--and counter
'negative vibes.' " The secret formula for the pendant was closely guarded by
its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bioelectrical Shield Co.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said,
quoting its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> as saying "he believed that Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> had
decided to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after a recommendation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
