
   
   
      
         
            Mash Notes and the Masher

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The throwing out of Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' harassment case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> led the last editions of all
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadsheet newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, but the tabloids preferred the
theft of love letters from the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, to her ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hewitt</ENAMEX>. These reportedly intimate letters, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1989 and 1991</TIMEX>,
were offered for sale for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$240,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Daily</ENAMEX> 
               Mirror by
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt's</ENAMEX> spurned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fiancée</ENAMEX>," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> refused the offer and
handed the letters to the executors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>'s estate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Standard</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt</ENAMEX> was expected to take legal
steps for their return.

            The Jones
decision came too late for the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and for
editorial comment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> ones, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX>, in an inside page feature, said that the
affair had "damaged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency, perhaps irretrievably." "Even if
the sex scandal subsides, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has been tainted," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "He
will not be remembered for his economic triumphs, his political agility, his
visionary trade policies, his well-meant dialogue on race, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
other smaller initiatives. Already he is the subject of countless jokes, and he
will be remembered as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who could not keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">zipper zipped</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the press was dominated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> by the
conclusion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s longest trial, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Papon</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">87</TIMEX>, accused
of (and sentenced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> for) crimes against humanity:
deporting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vichy France</ENAMEX>. The trial gave rise
to a flood of soul-searching comment. It had served, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX>, "to open our
eyes."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> loves to dwell on her
past," it said in a front page editorial. "She even lives in it, fascinated by
her navel. But until now, she has cared above all for her moments of glory,
when she thought she could give orders to the universe. She preferred to skip
the black pages in her history. But not for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> may call it
masochism, or self-denigration, or self-hatred, but it's a good thing all the
same that she dares, at last, to look herself in the face. With stains on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forehead</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX>
published an article titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Universal Victim?</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascal</ENAMEX>
Bruckner, who said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> displayed "a unique combination of arrogance and
self-hatred," and added, "We combine an unequalled vanity with a lack of
self-confidence that is the symptom of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> in decline."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> devoted a front page article to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> investigation of supposed breaches in the
traditional wall between advertising and editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. Relying
heavily on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> , it included among its examples the censorship
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> of a reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neiman Marcus</ENAMEX> in an article about the death of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> had not bought any advertising space in the
paper.

            
Other leading topics in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> were
the political uncertainty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the crisis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace
talks, exacerbated by the death <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramallah</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohiyedine Sharif</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that the consequences of this could be "as
severe as those which have almost destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process since
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> killed the No.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist organisation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening</ENAMEX> 
making "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." It urged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> community
abroad to "ask themselves what future there is for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> under a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> who seems determined to lead it into impasse and isolation." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>, in an
editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Peace at Risk</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>'s death might deliver the coup
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX> grâce to the peace process. "The fear is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>, the feast of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resurrection</ENAMEX>, may be transformed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of peace," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> said. "A new blood bath would play the game of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>
on both sides who have always been opposed to peace." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> supported
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s call for direct <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>
talks on the withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> territory.

            Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous Games</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> 's editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> questioned the staying power of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. "The 'Russian miracle,' that of always avoiding catastrophes at
the last moment, remains, however, fragile--more and more fragile," it said.
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX>, soon perhaps, the public will have to stop gaping at the ability of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin 'to</ENAMEX> be good at times of crisis.' " In a report from its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, Le 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> said presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>
Lebed was involved in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> scandal in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> had read a lesson at a memorial
service for one of his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodrow Wyatt</ENAMEX>. He
read the parable of the talents from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gospel</ENAMEX>, with its praise for
those who get a good return on their investments. "Take, therefore, the talent
from him [who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>] and give it unto him which hath <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> talents,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hath</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
