
   
   
      
         
            Flytrap on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>

            The dirty little secret of
my journalistic career is that, despite having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for 23 years
and having been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, I have never seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the
flesh. (Well, I watched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> speck through binoculars during his first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inauguration</ENAMEX>, and I once saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> running, but he was still vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> is my chance to remedy that.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> for a private session with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.
Everyone knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won't say anything to the press assembled outside, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horde</ENAMEX> has gathered anyway. We are hoping that he'll tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> something about the scandal in private, and they will pass it on
to us.

            By the time I arrive at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:15 a.m.</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is already
inside the conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. (He ducked the press and entered through a side
door.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are swarming outside, and a dozen cameras are
trained on the microphone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> security is
treating the press with all the respect we have come to expect: We are penned
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tensators</ENAMEX>, and anyone who dares step past the guide ropes is yelled at<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
then moved back by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schieffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
news, is herded like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX>.)

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> gather, rumors
follow. Among the utterly unsubstantiated rumors circulating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> on the dress; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> are quietly calling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and asking how they would respond to a mea
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">culpa</ENAMEX> .

            Cameramen
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> buttonhole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> as they begin trickling out around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, and it
is immediately and disappointingly obvious that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said nothing
about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Topic A</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> didn't ask him about it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> by one
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> file past, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by one they are drilled with the same question by
the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-mouthed</NUMEX> monster: "Was there any discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s, ah,
legal troubles?"

            
And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by one they answer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Green</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: "No
discussion at all. ... No one brought it up. ... NOTHING was brought up. ... AT
ALL."
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Klink</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>:
"No one did. ... No one talked about it. ... No one did. ... NO
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ONE</TIMEX>."
            

            Is it possible, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>,
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--who are congenitally incapable of
silence on any subject--can spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> in private with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and not
talk about the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">800 pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>? It is.

            After a
few of these futile interviews, I begin to discern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct genres of
nonanswer:

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High-Minded</ENAMEX>
Dismissal. This is the favorite of the savvier <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dems</ENAMEX>, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vic Fazio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>. How does
the high-minded dismissal work? Put on a tight, sour smile when Flytrap
question is asked, sigh deeply, then say exactly this sentence: "The
meeting was very, very positive. [Always "very, very." Never just "very."] We
discussed issues . Issues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> care
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s bill of rights ..." It never fails: As
soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horde</ENAMEX> hears the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>," a silence falls. Pens stop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scratching</ENAMEX>, cameramen turn off their high beams. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> turn away and
start talking to each other.

            
               The Logorrheic
Dismissal. The choice of more awkward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX>, this requires dismissing talk
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, then talking endlessly about why you're not talking about her.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Kanjorski</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, lecturing reporters on why he
would not talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> should not ask him about it, and
why they should be ashamed for even mentioning the subject. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> spent on
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Flytrap: 15 minutes</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> spent on the "issues <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in my district care
about": <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 minutes</TIMEX>.

            
               Dismissal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interruptus</ENAMEX>. Practiced by a few, perhaps more squeamish, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. This
involves a disjuncture between mouth and brain. The mouth becomes literally
incapable of talking about the scandal: "He has already addressed this once. He
announced that he did not have a relationship with, a ... a ...," <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> off
one well-coiffed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. "There was no discussion. We did not get into any of
the diff ...," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Dicks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, swallowing his words. (If that
were my name, I might not want to talk about the scandal either.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Istill</ENAMEX> don't get to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
are mouthing these sweet nothings by the front door, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president heads</ENAMEX> out a
side door and leaves through a blocked-off corridor. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> used to
complain about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> avoiding the press. How long has it been since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
answered a question?)

            Since I
was in the neighborhood, I thought I should drop by another scandal landmark on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>. Any presidential impeachment will go
through this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. This is a prospect all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> should anticipate with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> offers as fine a display of intellect and
surliness as can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. If impeachment comes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> may or may not be judicious, but it will certainly be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intemperate</ENAMEX>.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s business is a class action lawsuit
reform bill that everyone seems to agree with. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>,
bless its heart, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that can disagree to agree. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>
of collegial discussion, presided over with mountainous dignity by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>'s genial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> reverts to type.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>,
who has never found a subject he doesn't like arguing about (and has never
started an argument he didn't win), introduces an amendment. It would, and I'm
hazy on this, make it either harder or easier to dismiss class action suits.
Whichever it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Goodlatte</ENAMEX> vehemently disagrees. Goodlatte,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the new breed of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who looks like a choirboy and acts like
Savanarola, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> at high volume.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> responds by yelling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' parliamentary mantra: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> the gentleman yield his time?" Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) talks incredibly fast; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) has a thick accent (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bayonne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) seems to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton wool</ENAMEX> lodged in his cheeks, this sounds
more like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wildegenmenyeelistime?</ENAMEX>" Goodlatte ignores <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> and raises his own
voice further. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> counters by yelling the phrase again and again and again.
By the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> iteration, all that remains is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wigenyeel?</ENAMEX>" Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> is
being goaded on by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerrold Nadler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Berman (a Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> lookalike, incidentally). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Chabot</ENAMEX> has buried his head in his hands and is yanking his cheeks in
frustration. Impeachment-crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, who looks explosive even
in repose, has turned an even beetier shade of red than usual. (Whenever I see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, I think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosemite Sam</ENAMEX>, steam pouring out of his ears.) In the corner,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Buyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, seems to be flirting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>, who's trying desperately to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, is fingering his gavel like he
wants to heave it at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>. And this is what happens when they agree!

         
      
   
