
   
   
      
         
            

turbulence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> may cut nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> off the output of industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> around the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> made headlines in many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, which were happy to note, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> growth should slow
down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.8 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.7 percent</NUMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s should creep up from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.8 percent</NUMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OECD</ENAMEX> pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s
better performance was predicted only because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> was expected to do well,
with its GDP rising <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, and warned that, in any event, all
forecasts will have to be revised as the turmoil continues.

            The worst
economic damage was predicted, of course, for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> itself, and especially for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> reported a major fall in business confidence, with the Tankan
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> survey showing that the index of confidence among major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
had fallen from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">+3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-11 percent</NUMEX> now. The newspaper
blamed the publication of the survey for a fall by the yen against the dollar
to its lowest level since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1992</TIMEX>.

            But the news from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> seemed to be getting a little
better. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
Post of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> said, in contrast to reports elsewhere that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> had already rejected the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s request for an early
release of some of its expected international bailout funds, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Young Sam</ENAMEX> that he personally supported the
request because he believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> was abiding by the demands for
government-spending cuts and other financial reforms made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> government news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> also said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
had now agreed to consider the matter.

            But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX>
reported that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> summit meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lumpur</ENAMEX> had been dominated by growing dissatisfaction--most strongly expressed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--with the conditions imposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
supplicants, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Badawi</ENAMEX>, was quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> as saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
should show flexibility rather than simply impose on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the same
type of conditions it demanded of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. You shouldn't automatically
give the same kind of painkiller to everybody, he said. Meanwhile, reported
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London's Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of protest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seoul</ENAMEX>
were demanding imprisonment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> and renegotiation of the rescue
deal imposed by the "colonial" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>.

            
Another deeply discontented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>,
which, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34 years</TIMEX> of struggle to be accepted as a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, was told by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> that
it still isn't considered a suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> said it
was freezing political relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> and indicated that it wouldn't
attend a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pan-European</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next March</TIMEX> because of the "biased,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prejudiced</ENAMEX> and exaggerated assessments" of its record on human rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> as bizarrely describing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">communiqu√</ENAMEX>© on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> as "[a] way for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> not to turn its back, but
its face to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>," and an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> as saying, even more
bizarrely: "If this was a fair world, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> would have been rejoicing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankara</ENAMEX>." But an opinion column by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirma Evcan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> 
               Daily

               News said that "[e]ven the strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> cannot
swallow the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Luxembourg Summit communique</ENAMEX> which says nothing new, gives no hope.
It is just a new version of telling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>: You are not one of us, but you may
go on trying your best to become so in the unforeseeable future."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s court decision on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was the
subject on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> of an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX> 
               Times and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thunderous</ENAMEX> opinion column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>. The FT said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s ruling
might "mark a watershed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s history--the point at which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s effective monopoly of personal computer operating systems moves
firmly into the ambit of the law." "Increasingly," it predicted, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> will
be a product shaped as much by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> as by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imaginations</ENAMEX>."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rees-Mogg</ENAMEX> wrote: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last January</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> was still generally
seen as a benefactor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>, who had developed new and efficient software
to spread the advance of electronic communications. Now, this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is widely seen as a systematic monopolist of communication software who
is exploiting the information age. ... His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, as their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> attacked the old monopolists, as a 'malefactor of great wealth.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>
Rees-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mogg</ENAMEX> said that "[t]he precedents under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law are that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
will not be allowed to expand, or even retain, its present degree of monopoly,"
and he suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> take a leaf out of the book of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
who, in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>, consulted a public-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and "took to giving
out dimes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in order to soften his image as a
hard-hearted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>." The column concluded: "The best advice one can offer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is to start handing out money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; I know he will need to
offer them dollar bills rather than dimes."

         
      
   
