
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L'Affaire Clinton Makes Prudes</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> devoted several
pages to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s possible influence on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> questioned by the
newspaper urged that the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> boundary between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private
morality be maintained. Many of them also "wondered if this may not be the
start of an evolution affecting all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> because of the distrust that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surrounds</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, the latitude permitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, and the pressure
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>," it reported in its main front-page story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> quoted
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UDF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran√ßois Bayrou</ENAMEX>, as saying,
"At the root of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s destabilization is, above all, a meshing between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> is immune from that."

            Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> used <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> as a pretext to protest a
proposed increase in the independence of public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> pointed out that, until now, episodes involving the mingling of
private and public life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> have been extremely rare. The most recent was
the revelation, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, in the magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Paris Match</ENAMEX> that the late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fran√ßois Mitterrand</ENAMEX> had had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>--a report that
had provoked many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> about the intrusion into his privacy. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s appearance beside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> generated nothing
but emotional sympathy, "demonstrating once again that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> don't confuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bourgeois</ENAMEX> morality with public morality."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX>'s front-page cartoon showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in bed with a
naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, blindfolded and holding the scales of justice as he ate little
figures of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> out of a heart-shaped chocolate box and sighed, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ah</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La France</ENAMEX>!" In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> carried a front-page cartoon of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> sitting in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s chair in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> and reading with dismay the newspaper
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> Report: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Stole Biscuits</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Separate Occasions</ENAMEX>."

            An op-ed
piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">U.S. Democrats</ENAMEX> to "unite around an unequivocal policy of
opposing impeachment, on the grounds that the 'crimes' alleged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
report fall far short of the constitutional requirements for reversing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s electoral choice." This, it said, is in their own interests. "They can
go on condemning Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> morally. They can vote for public censure. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> must insist that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has hurt nobody, except perhaps his
family, and has done nothing to warrant impeachment." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> carried a
correspondence on its letters page about whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual
behavior can be explained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>'s theory of evolution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowan Hooper</ENAMEX> of
"if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can't help it because it's in the genes, then why did he use a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cigar?</ENAMEX>"

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX>, in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, deplored <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>'s apparent decision "to revert to a programme of
money-printing" and said "it is now hard to see anything but chaos in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
future." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX> can't justify giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> any more funds, it said,
because such money "would undoubtedly be wasted." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> said
that, since its financial crisis and the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> as prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> "is returning to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'G7</NUMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>' with regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
relations with the world powers." It added, "No-one speaks about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'G8</NUMEX>' any
more." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX>,
commenting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX>'s latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> appointments, said that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
now includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> of various colors--red, white, and pink." It concluded
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> had no choice, because no single political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is
willing to accept responsibility for the crisis.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> reported
prominently that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, having recently acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s most famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester United</ENAMEX>, for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, is now
attempting to acquire the TV rights for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s top football matches. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> led on the decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Basque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> organization <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETA</ENAMEX> to
declare an "indefinite truce" on the lines of the IRA in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration
announced on its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>
pill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> has lifted the taboo on discussion of sexual dysfunction. It
published figures showing that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> suffer more frequently than was
thought from sexual failure."

             

         
      
   
