
   
   
      
         
            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ol' Boys</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Venice Film Festival</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have been clamoring for the opinions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>
about the crisis engulfing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. Will they continue to
stand by him now that he is down? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> will, at any rate. He told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
Repubblica <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that he regards the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as just another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of
"this wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarthyite</ENAMEX> persecution of powerful and successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> said, is a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> an "intriguing bitch"
(this last phrase being printed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>). "And we mustn't forget the role of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who instructed her and who is certainly much more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> than she is
at things of this kind."

            But in an
interview with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, ex-philanderer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> took a different
view. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are "a moralistic and sexophobic race," he said, but a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has to understand this and make the necessary sacrifices. "To
renounce his manhood for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> is a fair price to pay," he
said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like him--and on another level, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me--cannot expect a
right to privacy." They should recognize that new technology "lays bare
throughout the world our most intimate and secret acts--sins which would be
quickly forgotten if, for example, the internet didn't render them shameful,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obscene</ENAMEX> and irremovable." The only real difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>
is that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> believed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s right to privacy, and the second
didn't.

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> drama topped the news in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> around
the world, the bulk of editorial comment came from western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, where
opinion was weighted overall in favor of his survival. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, under the
striking headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hell Is American</ENAMEX>," was particularly strong in its
condemnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report, which it likened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Inquisition</ENAMEX>.
It accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> of treating "the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pitiful</ENAMEX> lie of a seducer" as a state crime
that could, in theory, lead to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s imprisonment. It also criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
for accepting, unchallenged, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s version of events. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s main
offense, it said, is that he used family values as part of his re-election
mandate.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnist Matt Ridley</ENAMEX> of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> departed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s fiercely
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> line by saying that "compared with ancient emperors, modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>--even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--are models of monogamy." The
ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fei-ti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ridley</ENAMEX> explained, had a harem of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgins</ENAMEX>
and "was expected to make love to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>, and was trained in special
techniques to make sure that he could manage this." "Even at this rate it would
take him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> to get back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thought of," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ridley</ENAMEX> added.
"It is not surprising that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperors</ENAMEX> complained of their onerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amorous</ENAMEX> duties."

            
Among a batch of letters to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> affair, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> wrote: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
hypocrisy! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, is deified despite her misdemeanours (a
robust sex life outside marriage) while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is castigated for
displaying natural human foibles while being excellent at his work." The
paper's editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> said it was difficult to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now having
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> had wielded when he persuaded a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>: "His presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is
damaging not only to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but to all those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> which share its
values."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, which is also anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, complained that impeachment "should be a
legal, not an electoral device." "In a parliamentary system, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could
be forced to submit his resignation because he has lost the confidence of key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>," it said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. "The American founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
presumed that honour would provide that alternative to impeachment. Without it,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has been placed in political limbo." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has behaved "weakly and dishonestly over sex" but agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that "these are not grounds for impeachment: they are
grounds for divorce." "She is right. Let's hope <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> agrees," it
concluded.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> broad sheet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>, said that "by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overreaching</ENAMEX> himself, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has thrown him [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>] a lifeline. If
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> survives, it will be because Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> published, and was damned."
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Independent</ENAMEX> (owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Independent</ENAMEX> ) said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should resign if he cannot maintain his authority. In the world's
current parlous condition, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and prudent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> policies are vital,"
it said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, under the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>?" (meaning, luckily, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Duma</ENAMEX>), the daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> published a front-page lead story about the expected
confirmation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>.
Commenting on his decision to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> into his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, Segodnya
said, "The most important thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> is to get control of money
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> exports. This money will become a source of financing in the next

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX>, the government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newspaper Granma</ENAMEX> celebrated the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the
invention of the cha-cha with the unlikely boast "that it was danced by no less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
