
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian Anxieties</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX> came under strong attack both at home and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> for his failure
to curb the political momentum of the racist, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian One Nation Party</ENAMEX>,
which won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a quarter</NUMEX> of the votes in elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queensland</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that "[t]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hese</ENAMEX> are dangerous times for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
democracy" and that the danger "will not recede" until the mainstream parties
meet the challenge posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Hanson</ENAMEX>, the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist leader</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>. "The essence of that challenge is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One Nation</ENAMEX> peddles
simplistic certainties in times that are anything but simple and certain," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> has, through timidity and ineptness,
helped to make this monster. He must lead the way in ensuring that it does not
grow any larger."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> ran its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation</ENAMEX>, observing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queensland</ENAMEX> election result "says very worrying things" about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>,
with "deep implications" for its relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. "It would be deplorable
if other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> tried to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> card in the run-up to the next
general election," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "Rather, their job is to work out ways of
showing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queensland</ENAMEX> how mistaken they were."

            Amid the continuing economic crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Kuan Yew</ENAMEX> (now senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>)
said in an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s main economic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nihon Keizai Shimbun</ENAMEX> (or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikkei</ENAMEX> ), that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must help the economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, because the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> does not "have the
strength to solve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s trade problems." He also told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> will need to review its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> aid program,
which had been drawn up on the assumption of an exchange rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
dollar to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> rupiahs; the rupiah has since fallen to a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
dollar to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,800</NUMEX> rupiahs.

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, in
an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dragon</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s first foreign
policy task is to deal with "the challenge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and the possibility of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino-U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>." It said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> "must alert <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and the rest of
the world to the danger posed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino-U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>." "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
others who have advocated a multipolar world should be made to realise that
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is trying to establish is neo-bipolarism," it said, adding that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> should embark on talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> as soon as possible, even over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, because "the defusing of tension is in the interest of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>." It concluded, "When the alternative is the unthinkable, it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">churlish</ENAMEX> to quibble over dates, venues and terms of reference."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s biggest circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Komsomolskaya Pravda</ENAMEX>,
led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> has fallen in
love with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-born model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alyssa Sourovova</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s
female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> around the world are in despair," it claimed. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also
quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Svetlana</ENAMEX>, as saying she does not believe the story,
because, if anything serious were going on, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> would have told her
about it. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Svetlana</ENAMEX> admitted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa</ENAMEX> was much impressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s
performance in the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> and had met him in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> night
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX>.

            The daily
paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Segodnya</ENAMEX> (circulation <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>) claimed in its lead story that
proceedings to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> look set to become a permanent
feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Duma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>). Proceedings begun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Independence</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day holiday</TIMEX>, would fill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">working hours</TIMEX> until
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July summer</TIMEX> recess, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. They intend to set up a special
commission to investigate all the accusations against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and there
will be no time limit on its operations, it added.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> , a small circulation daily
controlled by financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>, made fun of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day holiday</TIMEX>, saying its absurdity has been obvious
from the start, because nobody knew whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> was supposed to have gained its
independence from. In the meantime, everyone who wanted to be independent from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> had already become so, it noted sarcastically, pointing out that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> regions had become independent of even their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, by issuing
their own bonds and heading toward bankruptcy.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> reported
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> on the ambivalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s attitude toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, pointing out that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> after accusing it of promoting
violence and having direct responsibility for massacres in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, he
had gone to dinner in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> with film industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who had poured
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of dollars into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> coffers. "This contradiction of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> summed up the inability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to come
properly to terms with the interweaving of show business and death, of dollars
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
