
   
   
      
         
            

            A wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX>
feeling swept through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, fueled by a mixture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Faye Tucker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, and the cable-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> disaster
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavalese</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> Dolomites. Anti-Americanism was exceptionally strong
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, where a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. Prowler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> on a low-flying exercise from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air
base at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviano</ENAMEX> cut through the wire of a cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
skiers plunging to their deaths. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers were packed for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> running with negative comment about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, taking their
lead from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Luigi Scalfaro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX>, both
of whom, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s apology, had used harsh, undiplomatic
language to condemn the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> role in the tragedy.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>,
the respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giorgio Bocca</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aviano</ENAMEX> of "manifest and
inexcusable arrogance." For months on end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bocca</ENAMEX> said, they had ignored
repeated civilian warnings and protests about the low-flying exercises. "There
is a fundamental contradiction in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy," he wrote. "On the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has realized that the world cannot be entrusted
solely to the pursuit of profit and to the indiscriminate use of the global
capital market, and it has breathed new life into supranational institutions
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
military continue to regard their host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as subject to their military
needs or to their war games while they live in superb isolation in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncontrollable</ENAMEX>, inaccessible bases. Perhaps imperial powers have always behaved
like that, but it's not pleasant and it's not dignified for those who have to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> the consequences--in this case tragically."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, front-page commentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brought Tucker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aviano</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> together under the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sad Face of America</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Author Gianni Riotta</ENAMEX> said: "The old and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tired Yeltsin</ENAMEX> raises his voice against his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> in tones
that haven't been heard in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. An astute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
recognizes the sad face of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and seizes the opportunity to appear as a
wise elder statesman." There was now a risk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riotta</ENAMEX> added, that the Europeans
would see only this "sad face" and forget the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of "respectable
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>" more interested in debating issues than in oral sex.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rambos</ENAMEX>" in a headline and published a front-page
column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> titled (in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee Go</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX>." This was not a call for action, however, but a nostalgic evocation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anti-Americanism</ENAMEX> of the past. All <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> prominently
reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>'s new demand for the closure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> soil and the remarks made by the parish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavalese</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, whom he called variously a "womanizer," a "warmonger," and
"a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> without moral or political principles."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, the execution of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, was the subject of much adverse comment. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>,
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> and
Libération featured it
in their front-page lead stories and their main editorials. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libération</ENAMEX> , a smiling photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> filled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the
front beneath the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Frightening America</ENAMEX>." The editorial inside described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> as "a manifestly sincere
penitent," and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> couldn't imagine a better argument against the death
penalty than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Tucker</ENAMEX>, or a better demonstration of the absurdity of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> vengeance that is taken after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> not against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the
crime, but against this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> the criminal has become in the meantime."
The editorial said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush Jr.</ENAMEX> had made the right decision, from
his own point of view, to show no mercy--after all, he might wish to run for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> presidency, which is probably how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> thought when he was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and didn't once exercise his power of clemency.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> 's front-page cartoon showed the traditional figure of death, with a
syringe in one hand and a scythe sporting the stars and stripes in the other,
facing a sea of television cameras and announcing, somewhat obscurely, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX>,
I've had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s main
headline was "The execution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Tucker</ENAMEX> underlines the
banalization of the death penalty in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," while its editorial,
headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Justice That Kills</ENAMEX>," said this was a kind of justice that could
never be justified. The paper quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX> statistics showing
that, out of a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">193</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> had abolished the death
penalty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> finds itself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, it said, adding, "The social and racial logic that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
has never radically questioned deepens the barbarism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
exception." It is common knowledge among criminologists that "the death penalty
strikes <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost at the underprivileged. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> awaiting
execution in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 1998</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> were white and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>
percent black, [even though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>] represent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 12 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>."

            As he departed for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> on an official visit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> published an op-ed article in the conservative
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> reaffirming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s readiness to take part in military action against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. He wrote that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> had recently asked him if he had
"considered cancelling the visit in the light of the media frenzy that has
surrounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of weeks</TIMEX>." "The thought had
not even crossed my mind," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> wrote. "The idea that we should distance
ourselves from an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> because of short-term media turbulence is
absurd." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days earlier</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Young</ENAMEX>, chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> and normally very
sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, had written: "What is unfolding between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> shows the same submissive respect by the lesser for the stronger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> as prevailed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, highlighted now by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solitary</ENAMEX>, potentially catastrophic, part in a joint venture against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that "air strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> will
start in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 days</TIMEX> time on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 February</TIMEX>, if current diplomatic moves to defuse the
crisis fail." Quoting "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Cockburn</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> considered this the
optimum date for attack, because by then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would have three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> would be able to say
they had given ample time for diplomatic moves by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to bear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keegan</ENAMEX> wrote that a new air campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> "would probably have to be
nastier than it was before, directed at civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, which the coalition
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX> deliberately spared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>." He proposed the targeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
electricity grid, but acknowledged that a lengthy interruption of service would
inflict much misery on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal was still alive and kicking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Express</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>
said in an editorial that it would like to "commend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for their watchful insistence on probity and moral rectitude for public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office holders</ENAMEX>," but proposed caution in pursuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because "it will be
foolhardy for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to cut its nose to spite its face." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> said it was appalled not by the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> having an
affair but by "the world's refusal to be shocked by it." It blamed "this
non-judgmental stand" on the expression "It's my life"--"the magic mantra of
our times which spells instant immunity from all wrong."

         
      
   
