
   
   
      
         
            

            
               This is a new feature,
which, beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, will appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s speech to the world summit on climate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, received an
almost universal thumbs-down, especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> disappoints the
world" was the headline in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX>, and almost the same headline was used by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> spoke of "great
disappointment" and "a wave of frustration" and said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> might even have
caused the summit to fail. In its host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX>
was more polite, but still referred to his speech as "ambiguous." The worldwide
consensus was that the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>-lagged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX>, whose arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> had been
awaited with such excitement, had signally failed to deliver a breakthrough in
the stalled negotiations because of political pressures at home.

            But the world summit
commanded relatively little attention in the press outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
Age didn't mention it at all, being more interested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s prowess
in beauty contests. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Hayden</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> on a
"tour of glory," was "not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to stun planet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>," it said, for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> had also provided <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners-up</ENAMEX> at the Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX> and Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia-Pacific</ENAMEX> contests. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> was quietly
pleased, as were other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, about a special gas-emissions
deal being offered to its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX>, but paid more attention to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canberra Senate</ENAMEX> ruling that transsexuals should be allowed to compete in sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competitions</ENAMEX>, raising the question of whether they should do so as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or be
put in a category of their own.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> the Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> reported on a visit by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, Armando
Cossuta, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, where he had "fallen in love" with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> when he
met her by accident in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry Cipriani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX>. She was,
he said, "in the dreams of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>" and "even more beautiful than on the
screen." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, was "a world made to measure for
the rich" and not a model that other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> should imitate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> was
preoccupied with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s difficulty in finding a new commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX>, it being the view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX>
that the deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alois Estermann</ENAMEX>, wasn't "aristocratic"
enough for the job.

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
carried a report of a confession on television by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Fujimori</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> that he slips secretly out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to indulge in "romantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">escapades</ENAMEX>": "I run out through the back door and drive past the gates in a
small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, which is not so obvious." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fujimori</ENAMEX> also said he had been "a late
starter" at romance, having experienced his first kiss at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 32</TIMEX> "with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> I had, at the end of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the lessons." He may be trying to
protect himself against posthumous revelations by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
