
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Linen</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            A leaked report in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> had secretly agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to accept a consignment of highly radioactive weapons-grade material
from the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> for reprocessing at the Dounreay
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> created heavy fallout in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>, who was forced to confirm the deal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, denied accusations of
secretiveness, but editorials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> were predominantly critical of him.
While most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> accepted the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to play its part in taking
in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s dirty nuclear washing, they argued that this particular
matter had been badly handled.

            The
conservative tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX> said that "the fact that the New York
Times broke the story, rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, is a public
relations disaster for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX>" and "an uncovenanted gift for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nationalists</ENAMEX>," who seek independence for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. While there was "a
respectable case for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> doing its bit to stop surplus nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> kits
being sold off by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> from the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> said, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> would have done better to trust the people
with the truth in good time before this controversial assignment was due to
arrive."

            The same view was expressed in the left-leaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent</ENAMEX> in an editorial headed "But they should have told us." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said
that while it was "obviously right" that radioactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
should end up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dounreay</ENAMEX> rather than be "made into nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> "should have allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to consider the
issues involved before, rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">after</TIMEX>, the event." Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> was
totally supportive of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, saying that he had nothing to be ashamed of and
that even the charge of excessive secrecy had about it "an aura of manufactured
outrage."

            After the
rows in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' alleged failure to report stories
that might in any way distress its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> gave full coverage
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to the separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of
marriage. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>, claimed in a front-page headline that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> marriage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">break-up</ENAMEX> shakes media industry," because of its possible future effects on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mystery</ENAMEX> over where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX> really died," following reports
that she had died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, and not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, as the
family had originally stated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> over the
ticketing arrangements for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>. When a telephone hot
line was set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> were employed to receive
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of calls--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> alone.

            
As articles to mark the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> proliferated around the world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its
front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with the news that the event would be celebrated by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent reduction of the jail terms of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> who had already served
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 60 percent</NUMEX> of their sentences. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> Foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Downer</ENAMEX>, appealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> for the establishment of a
humanity. He said that the diplomatic conference to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July this year</TIMEX> offered "an unprecedented opportunity to establish a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> with
real teeth" and that "the ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> should be a reminder [to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delegations</ENAMEX>] of the importance of their work."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French-language</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Watan</ENAMEX> recently splashed on its front page the news that "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX> desert their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>. Panic in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oujda</ENAMEX>." The
paper said an armed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moroccan</ENAMEX> border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oujda</ENAMEX> had
murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, and commented that "the appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
terrorism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX> constitutes a grave danger for the stability of the
Maghreb region." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moroccan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had not commented officially on
these reports, though a source in the interior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> had described them as
"fantasies." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with an agreement that would lead to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Caledonia</ENAMEX>'s complete independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 to 20 years</TIMEX>.

            In an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Opening</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> praised
what it dubbed "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prodi</ENAMEX> doctrine"--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX>'s call
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> for intense dialogue with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world, including "rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>"
like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, to avert the threat of a conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> and the
West in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX>. In this he was profoundly at odds with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. On its front page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> reported a
warning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> that it was futile to try to predict the
timing of the end of the world. It would end, he said, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> had not
indicated when.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> had taken in about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.5 million</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> box office over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three months</TIMEX>, making it by
far the biggest-earning film in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history. The previous record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Collins</ENAMEX> , took in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $5 million</NUMEX> less.

             

         
      
   
