
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soccer Madness</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soccer</ENAMEX> tournament in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> dominated much of the world's press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The
elaborate opening ceremony in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, featuring giant plastic racial stereotypes
parading at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 mile per hour</NUMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champs Elysees</ENAMEX> with forklift <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> as
feet, was not greatly admired abroad. "Violence and boredom at the opening
festival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX> in a front-page headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was
also sniffy about what it saw as tedious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> artistic pretentiousness. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> from every conceivable angle, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX> in an editorial
on the glory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> as "the only truly universal sport." A special
supplement reported on everything from the exploitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> symbols by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> fashion industry to the difficulties experienced by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> censors
in cutting images of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>'s scantily clad female <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> from TV
coverage. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> ran a long philosophical essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">academic Jean d'Ormesson</ENAMEX> suggesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, having supplanted religion and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patriotism</ENAMEX>, is the new "opium of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> provided especially full coverage of the war between its former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies Ethiopia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eritrea</ENAMEX>. In a comment titled "The Brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illusion of the Afro-Optimists</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domenico Quirico</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turin</ENAMEX> paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hopes for the continent have been "felled like a tornado" by the war.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eritrean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaias Afewerki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meles Zenawi</ENAMEX>
were regarded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> "young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>," rejecting violence, promoting democracy, respecting human rights, and
encouraging economic reform. But now they seem "bent upon repeating the cruel
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monotonous</ENAMEX> rites of the religion of totalitarianism." "Offering themselves
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as bulwarks against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, they filled their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arsenals</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old Pentagon</ENAMEX> stock, which they are now discharging copiously on each other,"
the article said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoweri Museveni</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> visited
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, is hardly better, it added. He was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of the
"no-party system"--"a more sophisticated version of the old one-party system
that led <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> to shipwreck and plunder."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> Gen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sani Abacha</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>,
the independent, pro-democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Express</ENAMEX> called on the new military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> to release political
re-establishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> democracy. "Its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job would be to restore
civility to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "There has been so much violence, so
much corruption, so much arbitrariness and so much criminality in this land."
Another recommended priority: to "restore confidence in the spirit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalism</ENAMEX>," because "the rate at which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigerians</ENAMEX> flee their fatherland or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vandalise</ENAMEX> public property should worry any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anywhere."
Finally, it should organize a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Conference</ENAMEX> to discuss the sore problems
that make us a disunited and grossly discontented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg Star</ENAMEX>,
commenting in an editorial on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>'s appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to rid their continent of tyranny, was just as pessimistic:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A man-made famine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, the current border conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eritrea</ENAMEX>, and ongoing difficulties in bringing peace to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> are among
outrages that suggest the end of tyranny in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> is a long way off." The
Star also criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his handling of the nuclear weapons
crisis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">subcontinent</ENAMEX>: He should replace "sanctions,
disapprobation, and isolation" with the promotion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations Security Council</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group of Eight</ENAMEX> in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> holding a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plebiscite</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants to avoid a nuclear catastrophe for the
world and the dustbin of history for himself, he has no other choice," the
paper said. "His reward would be just as tangible. He'll be remembered as the
greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>."

            In a front-page comment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> took a serious and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condemnatory</ENAMEX> line on the marketing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s deathbed sandals
as "the new youth symbol of revolutionary anti-Western romanticism." It
lamented "the speed with which, through a banal pair of sandals, there is
happening in record time the iconic beatification of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most savage
mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> of our time." "It's a shame for those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of skeletons to
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> massacre have been reduced. They can't
even wear sandals."

             

         
      
   
