
   
   
      
         
            Open Skies

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> devoted its main
front page story and its principal editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to the European
Commission's approval of the planned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX> and the partnership between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lufthansa</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandinavian Airlines System</ENAMEX>. The editorial said, however, that this is "far
from the end of the story." Once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BA-</ENAMEX>AA deal is also approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> should proceed to negotiate an "open skies" policy
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has used 'open skies' agreements as a
divide-and-rule tactic, to secure privileged access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> market for
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said. "Now that most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have signed up,
they should have a strong incentive to support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>' efforts to negotiate
on their behalf a broader and more balanced deal, which would liberalise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transatlantic</ENAMEX> aviation." Meanwhile, air transport needs to be brought within
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> rules, the editorial added. The long-term aim should
be "to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> out of the airline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, other than to the extent
required to ensure safety, essential infrastructure, and free competition."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s resignation from The 
               New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> to manage a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> was the subject of a short editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in the
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>, which described her as one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s "most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exuberant</ENAMEX> exports." She "put life back into a dreary over-intellectual magazine
that was little read and even less talked about," it said. "She axed the
interminable essays on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> land reform, commissioned glitz, and went
determinedly down-market in search of circulation--most successfully. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
knew how to inflame debate. She will be missed--by some, at least."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> on a warrant issued by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>
for the arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> for screening "vulgar" films on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Movies TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. The warrant was issued on the initiative of an obscure,
self-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX> of family values, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anil Goel</ENAMEX>, who had
objected to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> films-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jigsaw Murders , Dance of the Damned</ENAMEX> ,
Stripped to Kill , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad Mama</ENAMEX> --that were broadcast in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said. The case is due to be heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22</TIMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> the "honeymoon" has ended between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> because of serious
disagreements over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian Sea</ENAMEX>. This is bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, which has long regarded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> as its key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the
region and gone so far as to "risk its standing in the eyes of the
international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by continuing to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and building
nuclear power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> on its territory," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. But it concluded that
a cooling of relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> isn't a bad thing in the long
run, because cooperation with one of the world's most hateful regimes is
"unnatural."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>' small-circulation
Nezavisimaya 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazeta</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> might soon be "on
the brink of total instability." A "wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s wrath" is already
spreading across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, it said, despite forecasts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> that mass
civil unrest will not break out until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>. Referring to protests by
defense industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and energy sector <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Ministry</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> paid no attention to attempts by government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and trade union
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to appease them but continued to shout slogans such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Send Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> to trial." Underestimating the present threat could be fatal not only for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but also for the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> of the northeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yobe</ENAMEX> has appealed to the state government
to help meet the cost of burying armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX>, lunatics, and unclaimed bodies.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s sanitation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malam Adamu Bajob</ENAMEX>, said he has
sometimes had to pay for such burials out of his own pocket. The cost is often
high: Delayed release by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> means the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are decomposed and
require "extra burial materials." Since the state stepped up its campaign
against banditry, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has been burying an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> such bodies a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said. In an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Starr Should Not Tarry</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Express</ENAMEX> cautioned
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> not to "lose sight of the broader picture": It said his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was created not only "to assure the unfettered investigation of charges
against the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>" but also to ensure "that a
prosecutorial judgement be rendered in a timely manner." And in the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, "that time is rapidly approaching."

             

         
      
   
