
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plump Sheep</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            What the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers call
"sexygate" or "sexgate" was back on most of the world's front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
offering a promising lifeline for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> during the dog <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of August</TIMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> seemed to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would get away with it, though at
some personal cost. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has changed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> customs for ever," said
Corriere della
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>. "He has won the right to privacy for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>. But the
price he has paid has been a spider's web of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-truths and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-silence which
is wearing him away." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public opinion has already forgiven <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
for a sin he won't admit to having committed."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said that if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tried "to fend off the questioning with dodges similar to the one about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fellatio</ENAMEX> and penetration, he will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> in ridicule. If he admits to having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lied</ENAMEX>, he will be found guilty of perjury." But it was still unlikely that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would find enough evidence to bring a charge of impeachment to trial,
it said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
said it was now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s word against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX>, and the paper doubted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> could make his case against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> stick.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should
not be toppled by the affair. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would be wrong to commit perjury
about his relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, "but not perhaps so incredibly and
shockingly wrong." It said there was also some irony "in expecting a president
to be absolutely truthful on personal matters when he heads a government which
often varnishes the truth--or worse--on matters of much graver importance." The
paper concluded, "This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> now seems likely to be remembered for the climax
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> saga, but it is not so earth-shaking that it should bring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> down." In an op-ed article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, Anatole
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaletsky</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s decision to testify before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was the best possible news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>'s
congressional elections. ... In a straight contest between the word of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the testimony of a self-confessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fantasist</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
it is inconceivable that any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, or even a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
would unseat a hugely popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>." And "in the extremely unlikely event
of a move to impeach Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> now goading
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> would suddenly turn on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
of trying to reverse the will of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by abusing the legal system,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaletsky</ENAMEX> added.

            Under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Presidency Holed by Starr</ENAMEX>," the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> tabloid
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> said in its main editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that "even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidency</ENAMEX> is able to run its course, it already resembles a drifting hulk,
gutted by the tawdry activities of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skipper</ENAMEX>, bereft of the moral authority
and energising spirit that should emanate from his great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>." In an op-ed
piece in the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>, Ambrose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, turned his fire on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
calling him "a trimming, limp-wristed procrastinator with the zeal of a plump
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> who works part-time on the job, craves approval and bears the imprint of
the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who sat on him." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX> concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might
survive--"He may skate yet, as they say in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> grew up, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> analyzing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> divorce said it was "very unlikely that this
divorce will ever go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s demand for full disclosure of
his business interests was "a ruse to wring a settlement out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--known
for his personal parsimony--by hitting him where it hurts most." The Murdochs
were a family where business came <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the article said, and that meant two
things: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, that the price for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> of seeing that business survive in
something like its current shape will be one of the most expensive divorce
settlements ever recorded. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, that the settlement will be reached out
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
