
   
   
      
         
            Apocalypse Now

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> across the
world led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with apocalyptic headlines about the collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
none were more apocalyptic than those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> warned that the
addition of a political crisis to the existing economic crisis might result in
"a revolutionary situation." The possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> might be left
without legislative power for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three months</TIMEX> is "fraught with the most
dangerous consequences--including the disintegration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," it
said.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> reported
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX> is on the edge of civil war and that the halting of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ruble-dollar</NUMEX>
trading on the financial markets means that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is facing the threat of a
return to a fixed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ruble-dollar</NUMEX> exchange rate, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> times.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> could be facing hyperinflation, as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
general situation is rapidly approaching the critical point: It faces
simultaneous financial, industrial, social, and political meltdowns; it must
also deal with the fighting already taking place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Caucasus</ENAMEX>, and
with the danger of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> military action on its southern border.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> papers concentrated on the
reappointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> said
that, with this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has effectively given up power and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novye Izvestiya</ENAMEX> that his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> coming is attributable not to any
failings by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s predecessor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Kiriyenko</ENAMEX>, but to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
decision not to seek re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> said in
a front-page comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandro Viola</ENAMEX> that "seldom in history has a country
received from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> so many reasons for hope and then so many
afflictions as ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>."

            
Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stop This Bloody</ENAMEX>
Terrorism," the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cape Times of Cape Town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, condemned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s bomb blast at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> as "cold-blooded,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mindless</ENAMEX>, unjustifiable terrorism" going to "the heart of the tensions in our
troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>." Making no reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or to the
possibility that the attack might have been a reprisal for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> missile attacks
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, it blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> who "want our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> to
remain divided." It urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to "use this opportunity to recommit ourselves
to a united <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and isolate all those who have different and sinister
intentions."

            In an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis will reach "a point
of no return" by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-September</TIMEX> failing a miracle. It proposed stopping
negotiations for a bailout package with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Development Bank</ENAMEX>--with
which "it is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> fraternal feeling, as some of us would like naively to
believe, but pure profit motive which seems to have weighed." Instead, it
advocated a closer look at a prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> package,
even though "[o]f course, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> programme would bring massive hardships for
the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Star</ENAMEX>
accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish Republic of</ENAMEX> riding roughshod over civil liberties
in the new laws they are drafting to make it easier for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and courts
to convict suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. Referring in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to the "firestorm of anger and revulsion" that
had followed the recent bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omagh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that
this "new crackdown, so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late in the day</TIMEX>, smacks of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-reaction." It
concluded, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil liberties</ENAMEX>, once eroded, are not easily regained." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>
led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will meet more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> assembly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday</TIMEX>. He will
also visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omagh</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
