
   
   
      
         
            

            Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine</ENAMEX>--faced up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could be in real trouble, and allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal onto their austere, photograph-free front pages. Under the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in Need," printed in small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> script, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> paper said in an
editorial that the scandal had the makings of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nightmare that could
do as much damage as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>.

            In Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Georges</ENAMEX> said, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallic</ENAMEX> hauteur, that it was
"extraordinary" that the greatest democracy in the world should permit itself
the luxury (via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>) of "a universal media course on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anatomy</ENAMEX>." He added: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> can't altogether rule out that these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> may
be showing off or lying. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, too, can sometimes lie."

            An editorial in the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> said that, "as
usual, lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will guffaw over all this fuss about a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscretions</ENAMEX>." But it said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> should understand that the scandal was
not about sex, but about truth. "We can trust <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> freedom of
expression--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> which supports it--to ensure that we are
not spared any detail, whether spicy or not, of the relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>," it added. "Let's laugh, if we want to, or let's wax indignant; but let
us not forget to understand."

            In a
front-page comment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caretto</ENAMEX> spoke up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidential record, saying he had corrected
the capitalist excesses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX> and that, although he stood accused of
betraying the liberal traditions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, he had at least--by moving
to the center--kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> at bay. "His suspected relationship
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> may generate sarcasm and evoke comparisons with that
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lolita</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humbert</ENAMEX>, but nothing can take away from his success,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caretto</ENAMEX> added.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , which
is normally hostile to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should
not step down until his guilt of either obstructing justice or suborning
perjury "has been demonstrated beyond a shadow of doubt." "As was illustrated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> can certainly survive such traumas," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said, "but at a tremendous cost, especially to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
foreign relations. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> fell largely as a result of the paralysis of
the presidency.) The stakes are scarcely lower <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
Hussein continuing to menace the international order."

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to follow the examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, who had tried to
restore their reputations during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> scandals by
throwing themselves into foreign affairs. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has to prove to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and to the world that there is a purpose to his presidency. Foreign
policy is the proper forum for him to do so," it added. Whatever the impact on
his reputation of the present scandal, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should seek to mitigate it
with international accomplishments. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> argued, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is what
he has achieved, not what others think of him."

            The Financial
Times said that "what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> needs above all, and what it is probably not
going to get, is a rapid resolution to this unhappy affair." It said that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> under siege couldn't give the world the leadership it needed. "The
whole build-up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Tuesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">State of the Union</ENAMEX> speech has already been
thrown off course, and this may be just the beginning," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said.
"The media frenzy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has been extraordinary to behold: there can be
no rational discussion about the great policy issues so long as this
lasts."

            The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said the talk of impeachment was premature. "Impeachment is a
deadly serious matter, best reserved for deadly serious offences," it said.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That 'droit de seigneur</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tradition of serial infidelity, as
established by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>, may be as gross as it is
foolish. But it is not yet the stuff of impeachment."

         
      
   
