
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifty-First State</ENAMEX>?

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>"
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            Taking up a cause recently
promoted by its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Black</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> (circulation <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 million</NUMEX>) argued <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> should apply for membership--or associate
membership--in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Free Trade Agreement</ENAMEX>. It said in an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>'s proposal was supported not only by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>,
several leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
largest circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ) but also by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.

            The
notion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to remain part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> bloc
is "becoming out of date," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> are waking up to
the fact that the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>] contains an important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX>
component. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, perhaps the most influential of post-war foreign
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinkers</ENAMEX>, recently warned against further <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> integration." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> said the case for "associating with the New World" doesn't
rest simply on an affinity of culture, language, or political values but is
based on hard economic calculation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>, congratulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on the fact
that the longevity of his rule--46 years <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>--"has been achieved mainly
through consensual rule rather than despotism." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s editorial recalled
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Lippmann</ENAMEX> on the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX>--"the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is to leave behind him a situation which common sense,
without the grace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, can deal with successfully"--and suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>
has achieved this.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> plans to
cash in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> craze by exporting its essential chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> not yet covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s patent. In a report from Chennai
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madras</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchid Chemicals and Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> plans to start
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">exporting sildenafil citrate</ENAMEX>, the active ingredient in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of August</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchid</ENAMEX> has had trade
inquiries from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>; it has the necessary
licenses from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to manufacture and export the chemical and
has already started importing the raw materials.

            
In an editorial about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision to
suspend all scientific collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and to send several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> home, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX> said "few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from the erstwhile
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> faced such treatment as has been meted out to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
now, even at the height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>." If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> continues to
behave like an international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, "the result will certainly not be greater
peace and cohesion in the world: that much is for sure."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s main English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>, focused <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on the crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Accusing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and other Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of "inexplicable delay" in checking
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s relentless offensive" against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar Muslims</ENAMEX>, it warned that if the
world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> continues "to waver and dither over what is happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
for long," it will find a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-like conflict in [its] lap."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> , commenting on Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, vacationing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karelia</ENAMEX>, had deliberately distanced himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> because he didn't want
to look as if he was begging for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> money. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> said this "must
have left an unfavorable impression."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainichi Shimbun</ENAMEX>
criticized the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keizo Obuchi</ENAMEX>
for being "devoid of fresh ideas" for reviving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy. "Obuchi
should remember that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> has an intense desire to see an
economic upturn, it is not waiting for easy-to-swallow solutions," the paper
said in an editorial. "Even if the measures implemented require painful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sacrifices</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to bear them if they promise a secure and
healthy future."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Times</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX> "may be obliged to reconsider his pledge
to hold steady the value of the currency. That in turn could--most likely
would--trigger another round of devaluations in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and set back the region's
recovery." It concluded, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> cannot afford to stand idly by: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
difficulties make ours look small in comparison."

             

         
      
   
