
   
   
      
         
            Birthday Greetings

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            Celebrating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
lauded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s enormous achievements but said they have been "darkened by
clouds of failure and hardship." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, it said in an editorial, is "at the top of the ladder of inequality among
developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>" and has limited its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' freedom of choice in important
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> because of "a political covenant with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> and ultra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">streams</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> also condemned the "skeptical and negligent approach
of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> toward peace agreements with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will need "spiritual strength" if it is to transform itself
"from a national movement to a civilized and developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>," it added.
"Improving democracy, firmly establishing the rights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>,
granting equal expression to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, supporting the weak, encouraging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX> and maintaining a non-patronizing relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Diaspora</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
are the necessary conditions for this to happen."

            The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that "[s]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">omehow</ENAMEX>, even during our
birthday celebration, speaking of achievements is not quite in fashion." Even
so, it added, "The resurrection of an ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in its own land, following
the destruction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of its number in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, is unique in history
and represents ample cause for celebration." Quoting an opinion poll in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> that showed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> expect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will live to
celebrate its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 th</NUMEX> anniversary, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said it wasn't the
"confidence of the overwhelming majority" that was striking but the question
itself: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]hat other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> celebrating its jubilee would even ask such a
question?" In a jubilee interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> "the greatest success story of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, and in many ways the greatest triumph of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all the nations
of history."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> anniversary was the subject of front-page
stories and editorials throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, many of them emphasizing
current tensions within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> at least as much as the reasons for rejoicing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
carried an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Rabin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of assassinated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>, in which she said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yigal Amir</ENAMEX>, was "the product of a
climate orchestrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX>." She added, "I absolutely blame 'Bibi' for the
hate campaign he carried on against my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>." If "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> society is
desperate" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and "the young want to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," it's because of
him, she said: "This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must be overthrown by any means."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">liberal French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> devoted its whole front page and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> inside pages
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jubilee</ENAMEX>, including a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-page joint interview that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shimon Peres</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. "We are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, we were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX>, we will remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>. "For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to remain a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, we have to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
state," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peres</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> 's editorial said that deep rivalries
between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of different regional origins explained "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> of the sinking of a peace process the success of which was the
essential condition for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s entry into adulthood."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> headlined its main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> jubilee story
"The fifty joyless years of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> headlined its "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, fifty years of joy and
mourning." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mundo</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in an editorial
to end its present "stubbornness" and to ensure the peace process resumed, "so
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2048</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will be carrying on as strongly as now ... and that a
viable and peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> will be keeping it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the
Times said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX>
would remain "a restless, innovative society" and continue to make sacrifices
to support its own. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> is not facing a midlife crisis, but a
succession of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> childhoods," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said. "It is unlikely that
'normality,' whatever that is, will prove a blessing or burden for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in
the near future." The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> wished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> "all the best on its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
birthday, but urge[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>] it yet again--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--to try harder still
to achieve the just and lasting peace they and their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbours</ENAMEX> so badly
need."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX>'s editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> was
devoted to the recent advance of the right-wing, racist, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Party</ENAMEX>, which won <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in regional elections in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saxony-Anhalt</ENAMEX> in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. It said the result was "very worrying" and
reflected not only specific grievances in the east but also more general German
fears: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and globalisation are nourishing deep identity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anxieties</ENAMEX>," it observed. Slogans such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> first" are becoming more and
more fashionable, and they are even being used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Social Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX> to increase his chances of becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, Le

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> said. On another note: A survey in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> revealed
the principal cause of popular discontent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is noise.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
papers mainly led their front pages with congratulatory remarks on the imminent
launch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> single currency, which both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have qualified to
join. Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> carried a front-page commentary by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ennio Caretto</ENAMEX> titled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The American Euro-Fear</ENAMEX>" on the reportedly growing anxiety in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
about the effect the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX> may have on the dollar.

             

         
      
   
