
   
   
      
         
            So <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Want to Immigrate</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, a nation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, has a love-hate relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX>. Despite its
reputation as an international melting pot, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 7.9 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> was born overseas, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.7 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">percent of Switzerland's</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.1 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s.

            Not
surprisingly, the immigration system is set up to benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--only a small percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would like to come here are
allowed in, and only a tiny fraction of the ones who make that cut are allowed
to stay indefinitely. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996 fiscal year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 23 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>
entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on tourist visas, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">418,117</NUMEX> on student visas, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227,440</NUMEX> as temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with extremely restricted temporary work visas
(most are seasonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 65,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are allowed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in a specialty occupation"). In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">915,900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> received an
immigrant visa (a "green card"--it's actually pink), which makes them eligible
for permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> and most of the benefits of citizenship, with the
important exception of the right to vote.

            
               Who Gets
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Card</ENAMEX>?
            

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">596,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>
percent of all green-card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>--were "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>." About
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> were immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX>), and the rest were "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-sponsored
preference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> (and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>) of naturalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult sons</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">daughters</ENAMEX> (and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>) of naturalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homosexuality</ENAMEX> ceased to be
grounds for exclusion from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, but since gay and lesbian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> cannot legally marry in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, there is currently no legal way
for them to benefit from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-preference laws.

            
Employment-based preferences account for an annual minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX>
of whom a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> may be unskilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. There are basically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
categories of work-related "preferences": skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, priority workers
(including "multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>" and "outstanding professors
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>"), "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> with advanced degrees," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> or
employment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>, and unskilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, there has been an annual lottery
for "diversity" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, designed to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with low
levels of emigration to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to jump the queue. (Such countries
are currently defined as those with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 50,000</NUMEX> emigrants to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous five years</TIMEX>.) The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> lottery, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55,000</NUMEX> green cards
up for grabs, closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 24, 1997</TIMEX>. (This page provides
more details.) The dates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s diversity-visa lottery haven't yet
been determined.

            Within
these complex categories, there are national quotas to ensure that no country
can take up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 7 percent</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> green-card allocation (though
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-reunification categories are exempted from this limit).

            
               What's
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Difference Between a Resident Alien and a U.S. Citizen</ENAMEX>?
            

            Until
recently, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of green-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card holders</ENAMEX> were content to live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident aliens</ENAMEX>. But of late, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> have indicated a change of
attitude toward legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, and this has affected the number of
applications for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> federal welfare law separated rights from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entitlements</ENAMEX>, denying legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> access to government housing and welfare
while still requiring them to pay taxes. This loss of benefits has almost
certainly precipitated the jump from the long-standing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> average of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> citizenship applications to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.6 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> estimates show that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.8 million</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.5 million</NUMEX>
green-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card holders resident</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> were eligible to apply
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>.)

            
               I Won the
Lottery. How Do I Become a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citizen</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> for citizenship
must <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 or older</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) have resided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> continuously for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>--or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> if married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>--(short absences are
OK); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) demonstrate the ability to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and a basic knowledge of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history and government (click here to see if you pass the test); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) be of "good moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> must submit a set of fingerprints for review by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>.

            The
increase in citizenship applications has led to longer processing periods and,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> being wrongly naturalized. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> audit of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were granted citizenship
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between September 1995 and September 1996</TIMEX> revealed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,946</NUMEX> cases "in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> arrest should have disqualified an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> or in which an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>
lied about his or her criminal history." A more recent press release from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has made a
"dramatic turnaround" as a result of new policies initiated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>.

            
               Evading
the System
            

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> estimates,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, and there were
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 million</NUMEX> illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 2.1 million</NUMEX>
of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> are "nonimmigrant overstays," that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who entered the
country legally on a temporary basis and didn't go home. Most illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immigrants</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated 2.7 million</NUMEX>, come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 16 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are overstays, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> of those
from other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91 percent</NUMEX> from all other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> deported <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111,794</NUMEX> "criminal and other illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, and
recent changes in the law, summarized here, establish new grounds for denying admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. For example, nonimmigrant overstays can now be denied readmission for
up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>.

            Access to
jobs attracts illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> negotiated its largest
work-site settlement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant chain</ENAMEX> agreed to pay a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7-million</NUMEX> fine for hiring and employing illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> doesn't do enough to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who make extensive
use of illegal labor. Unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> as more
manageable and less likely to complain. Despite regulations that punish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who knowingly employ them, pressure from business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> scuttled an attempt to include computer verification of employee
eligibility in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> immigration bill.

            
               What
About <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Refugees</ENAMEX>?
            

            A fact sheet prepared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population, Refugees</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migration</ENAMEX> outlines the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> refugee policy. Around
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> are allowed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> if they flee their
country "due to persecution or a well-founded fear of persecution because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, religion, nationality, political opinion, or membership in a particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>." Recent changes in the law prohibit asylum applications from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who have been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> are also offered refuge--unless they can get a better deal in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, of course.

         
      
   
