
   
   
      
         
            

            The war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch by Conrad Black</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telegraph Group</ENAMEX> continued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> after the
confirmation of rumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have been trying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> the organs of executed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> for livers,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> for lungs of nonsmokers, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> for kidneys, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> for pairs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corneas</ENAMEX>). In a scoop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> revealed the
circumstances under which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX> subsidiary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>, had canceled publication of the memoirs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Patten</ENAMEX>, for which it had already paid an advance
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>
had personally intervened to get the book stopped, because he feared that its
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slant</ENAMEX> might threaten his TV interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. After one
ferocious editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another Monday</TIMEX>
saying that "behind the machinations within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> is Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
determination to suppress condemnations of a vicious and brutal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>,"
which "allows its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to be shot, dismembered and sold in pieces." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Murdoch</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> have long been locked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> newspaper price war.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
provoked much comment by failing to publish anything about the affair until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>, when it carried a small story on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp</ENAMEX>
Puts Its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Side in Row Over Patten Book</ENAMEX>." But it grew more evenhanded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> when
it said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> was now "fighting a rearguard action to stop a
threatened revolt by some of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of this story, the
Times ' media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Snoddy</ENAMEX>, was widely reported as having said
in a radio interview that the lack of coverage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> had damaged
his own reputation and probably that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> as well. "I agree
entirely what has happened is unacceptable," he is supposed to have said.

            The Financial
Times reflected in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patten-Murdoch</ENAMEX> affair had
"brought forth a torrent of abuse from his newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, of a kind that
might make a lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> feel faint." But it said that this scandal was "not
nearly as shocking as his decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> to drop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> news from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> satellite service to appease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>," and concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
didn't need legislation to curb <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s media power but needed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
with the guts to snap their fingers at bullies."

            In an
op-ed piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Stephens</ENAMEX> wrote that those who fear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch "</ENAMEX>should stop for a moment to savour the delicious irony of his latest
obeisance before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> gerontocracy." He concluded, "The frenzy with
which he seeks to expand his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> betrays a realisation that it will not
outlive him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday</ENAMEX> 
               Times ,
said his ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> had "shown neither integrity nor morality in his handling of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patten</ENAMEX>'s book. It is a sorry tale from which he emerges a diminished, tarnished
figure."

            
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anointing of Gerhard Schr√∂der</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Social Democrat opponent</ENAMEX> in the
fall election for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> chancellorship, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> made more
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s "countryside march," which brought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 250,000</NUMEX> country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to demonstrate against proposed legislation to abolish <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX> hunting and
other assaults on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> way of life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> described the march
as "a public relations triumph" and attributed much of its success to one of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Bettelheim</ENAMEX>, "a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barrister</ENAMEX> who works
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>," who was credited with supplying "much of
the ideological drive and marketing expertise." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
claimed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> had helped finance the march.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> led on
Schr√∂der but devoted its main
editorial to the "miracle" by which all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with the
exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> had met the economic criteria for taking part in a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency, which will now be launched on schedule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> carried much comment on the visit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> Foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamberto Dini</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX>, generally praising him for his highly
conciliatory posture, which included denying the existence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
sponsorship of terrorism and refusing to criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s application of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koranic</ENAMEX> law. Quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dini</ENAMEX> said the still-extant death sentence on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">writer Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX> "will not be an obstacle to relations between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> is willing to discuss the whole question."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London's Daily</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Human Rights Commissioner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Robinson</ENAMEX> as saying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> had assured her that the
death sentence on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX> would not be carried out, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayatollah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khomeini</ENAMEX>'s "fatwa" against him "cannot be revoked."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> had overtaken the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX>
to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> world's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest share <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.
It also criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> for trying to
"have his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> cake, and eat it," saying that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> doesn't want more
Western advice--what it demands is more financial help."

            Commenting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
elections, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that it was "virtually
certain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will again face a hung <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> of uncertain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duration</ENAMEX>, cobbled together by the flimsiest of uneasy regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX>." It
blamed this outcome on the intervention of onetime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rajiv</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia</ENAMEX>, in the campaign. An editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> said that "the polling, it is true, has not in all cases been as peaceful
or free and fair as it should be in an ideal situation, but then nobody has
ever suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> politics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> even remotely approximated the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that Labor</TIMEX> opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> plan
to resume the peace talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> would be well received by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> if put forward "without exaggerated pressure." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
devoted an editorial to the report, denied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
might be willing to admit that he kissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> without engaging with
her in an "improper relationship." "It cannot be long now before the tissue of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-truths and leaks is stripped away and something resembling the truth is
told," it said, accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of "a pattern of slipperiness." The
editorial concluded, "He smoked but didn't inhale. They had 'a physical
relationship' but it wasn't sexual. He spoke but we couldn't hear. He is in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, but not in power."

         
      
   
