
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farewell</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here. And
if you missed the most recent installments of this column, here they are:
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 25</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX>.
            

            The toppling of old king
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>, the longest-serving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in any democracy, was received with great
excitement across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, though less so in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> than anywhere else.
Everyone agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>'s departure marks "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of an era</TIMEX>," and
this was even the headline on a front-page editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX>. The
paper noted that this was the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> election in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>,
was the focus of attention. It also noted that foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> would have
preferred that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> win, because they fear that, with the move of its capital
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhine</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spree</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> will become "more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and less
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> would have been the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to dispel these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>," it
said. "Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lafontaine</ENAMEX> [the victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Social Democrat leaders</ENAMEX>]
have to prove that they are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> too, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Europeans</ENAMEX>." The Frankfurter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgemeine</ENAMEX> also pointed out that "never before has an election been fought
in such an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> style, with so much theatricality."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Süddeutche Zeitung</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> said it hopes this will be the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> election in which millions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> aren't allowed to vote because of their immigrant status:
"Democracy doesn't function when certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are excluded." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> challenged the comparisons
being made between the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> reformed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schröder</ENAMEX> didn't," it said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX> has
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leftist, Lafontaine</ENAMEX>, behind him; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't." Nor was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schröder</ENAMEX> preceded
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> who imposed strict economic discipline.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schröder</ENAMEX> has to do the unpopular things himself," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX> said.

            In other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, most of the editorial
comment concentrated on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>'s place in history. The conservative Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schröder</ENAMEX>
has overthrown "a historic monument," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Mann</ENAMEX>'s
formula, worked "so that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> would become <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> in order to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX> will automatically assume the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the social democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> (which include those
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>) because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s "dominant weight." "With a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wobbly America</ENAMEX>, a prostrate capitalist <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> facing
the risk of retreat into poverty, there has never been so much need of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> model as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," it said.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> was praised as a figure of major historical importance, but his
departure was welcomed by papers opposing greater integration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mail</ENAMEX> said that "high on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herr Schröder</ENAMEX>'s list
is likely to be a forging of a closer alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, not as a
substitute for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> influence but at least as a counterweight to it." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> said: "The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leitmotivs of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> in office were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> integration and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> unification. It was his commitment to the former which ensured that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> achieved the latter, without arousing the suspicion and hostility of
its former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wartime adversaries</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> said the important thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> emerge
from the economic paralysis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, "because we all know that
what happens to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> happens to some extent to all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great statesman</ENAMEX> to whom <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> is grateful for his support of its entry into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has now receded from the
front pages across most of the world, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press of Christchurch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zealand</ENAMEX>, carried an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> advocating his removal. "What now can be said in
favour of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>?" it began. "Not much." And it concluded, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has no one to blame for his fate but himself. He has tarnished his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. His actions have earned him at best ridicule and at worst ignominy.
Whenever he departs, he will leave a sad legacy."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> for his views on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> scandal. It is "a rather sad spectacle"
from which nobody will emerge victorious, he replied. Asked if he felt
sympathetic toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he said, "I feel a great sense of solidarity
with everyone who finds himself under the scrutiny of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, which in this
case have behaved really badly."

             

         
      
   
