
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Whispers

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            In a special section on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> that
"the trip has left <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> feeling sore and [has] caused friction
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s diplomatic relations." It quoted an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> as saying
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was "unhappy with the reception China
accorded Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, believing it was bigger than the welcome Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
received when he visited in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>, similarly, were
"put out" by the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> refused to brief them on the visit
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and chose instead to send a standard press
release to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> in its then capacity as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>. "The decision
meant that the only official account of the visit to be transmitted from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> was based on talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Times</ENAMEX> editorial
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has rightly "elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to a far more central place
in its foreign policy than it occupied in the past," given that "China is
poised to become a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st -century</TIMEX> superpower and is already playing a
major role in stabilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> economically." But it rejected the idea that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> might be planning to substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> as its key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> remains "an oppressive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>," it said, and this
stands in the way of a "genuine" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> in any field besides trade and
business."

            An editorial in the Monday
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> said
that the main conclusion to be drawn from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is "that the
limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX> have already been reached." It's all downhill from here.
Though the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> made his trip seem "like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> journey of a mediaeval potentate, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> language was that of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">travelling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>," it said. "There is no sense in relying on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>"

            The
emotion aroused by the closure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kai Tak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> (to
be replaced by the "modernistic marvel" of the huge new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chek Lap</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kok</ENAMEX>) came "close to rivalling the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>," when the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> was restored to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> . Referring
to the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>'s hair-raising, rooftop-scraping approach and its
environmental deficiencies, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said that "the sheer audacity and
improbability of the place so perfectly captured the spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> will seem lost without it."

            The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> strongly
criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for its failure to get tough with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s unwillingness to demand that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> uphold the commitments it undertook in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX> accords is
now threatening to undermine the most vital system of checks and balances in
the diplomatic arena." The "initiative" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s "most important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>" could
be "superseded by inter-Arab or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> initiatives that will be far
tougher," it said, adding that it will now be almost impossible to
"rehabilitate the ruins of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>" the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> once
had in the peace process."

            The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> led its front page with the warning by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mubarak</ENAMEX>, following his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> summit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, that the negotiations deadlock and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s plan to
expand <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> could ignite violence that might prove unstoppable. In an
editorial, it
put the blame for the present impasse in the negotiations firmly on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>,
who, it said, makes "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s delaying skills seem almost amateur."
Demanding urgent fulfillment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s 6-year-old promise to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX>
Covenant to erase calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s destruction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also called
for "an end to the long boycott by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> of direct negotiations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to support an Arab-sponsored move at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> "for its blatant attempts at judaizing" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Quds</ENAMEX>
area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were to veto the resolution, as it is
reportedly proposing to do, "it would detract from its credentials as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal promoter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process," it said.
"For once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should put all diplomatic niceties aside and make
it plain to Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obduracy</ENAMEX> must come to an end. For him, there
is simply no option but to return to the path of peace and stability in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>."

            The front pages of most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were dominated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the standoff in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange Order</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which used
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orangemen</ENAMEX> from marching through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drumcree</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>, the Ulster
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ulster</ENAMEX> assembly, had
threatened to resign if the march wasn't allowed through. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> called
for an improbable compromise by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drumcree</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garvaghy Road</ENAMEX> would lift their objections to the parade going down it, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange Order</ENAMEX> would voluntarily decide to return <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> by another route.

            The main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
focused on the enforced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arabization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, where, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, classical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arabic</ENAMEX> became the sole official language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, with the use of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Berber Arabic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> being prohibited. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libération</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would rejoice over this are
"those struggling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and terrorism to transform <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>
state."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> also reported on its
front page that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, marriages within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> are calmer and more
stable than civilian ones.

             

         
      
   
