
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that he knew he was close to an
agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> asked him if he
could leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few moments</TIMEX> to pray ("I knew that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> was also
praying for peace, and with such support, how could I fail?"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX> said he
believes the agreement will hold because--as has never happened before--it was
negotiated in person by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>; he also said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> had shown "a great
capacity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis by uniting diplomacy with a show
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led on the protest march in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with white sheets over their heads demanding access to a new cancer
treatment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has been trying to suppress pending the
outcome of clinical trials. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> barracked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX>, who refused to come out because he was with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, who reportedly was ticking him off for not being
tough enough on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> issue (see 
                  Slate
               's
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>"
for more on the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>). The cocktail of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">untested cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
prescribed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luigi di Bella</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modena</ENAMEX> has aroused huge popular
enthusiasm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>--a fact attributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugenio Scalfari</ENAMEX>, founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>,
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s unique faith in miracles.

            One miracle in which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> don't believe, however, is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> will change their ways. An opinion poll published over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> support the legalization of brothels.
In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> called for open discussion of the
prostitution problem and did its bit for the cause the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> by devoting two
richly illustrated pages to the subject. Also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> ran
an editorial supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s anti-smoking crusade, which it said
had replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> as the chief diversion from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal. The
paper expressed surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s attacks on smoking were treated as
remote and irrelevant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>--especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>--when tobacco was in fact
the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> in most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the world. "We import from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States</ENAMEX>
so many useless fashions, horrible films, and suspect religions," it said. "So
why can't we pay more attention to a war that, in this instance, actually is
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'just'?</ENAMEX>"

            The other
big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> news story over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> was the life sentences imposed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of appeals on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84-year-old</TIMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Priebke</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">henchman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Hass</ENAMEX> for the massacre of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">335</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> at the Fosse
Ardeatine caves outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1944</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> welcomed the
sentences for "conciliating the law of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with that of memory and conscience"
but reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that they had divided <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, the largest and oldest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, formally dissociated
themselves from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Israelitic Communities</ENAMEX>," Tullia
Zevi, who had called for clemency saying that "nobody wants an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80-year-old</TIMEX> to
end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>."

            
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> led with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>, recently accused of suppressing a report showing that cannabis
isn't as dangerous as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, had now suppressed "a study which
shows ... not only [that] there might be no link between passive smoking and
lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> but that it could even have a protective effect." The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX>
claimed in its front page lead story that this was nonsense put out by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British American Tobacco Co.</ENAMEX> It said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BAT</ENAMEX> had deliberately drawn the wrong
conclusions from the study, which had not been held up by WHO but had been
submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cancer Institute</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.

            The
Times and the
Daily 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> both led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with stories about
plans for the downgrading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in response to pressure
for constitutional reform--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX> would
lose his seat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> that minor royals
would lose their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> escorts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> had already been reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> as preparing to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) end bowing and curtsying and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) cut down on the
number of "royal highnesses" in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> led mainly on the
implication of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roland Dumas</ENAMEX> (now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional Council</ENAMEX>) in an alleged corruption scandal that has to do with
the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">frigates</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> press focused on the German
Green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>, whose radicalization might make a political alliance with moderate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> that much harder. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX> is challenging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> for the chancellorship in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>'s election.) This was seen as
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> a better chance of victory.

            The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said in a
gloomy editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that there was "a chilling sense these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of sights and sounds from the period of impervious apathy which preceded
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> war." It accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> of achieving
nothing during his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-nation <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tour. "The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-point plan which he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hurriedly</ENAMEX> submitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> only recycles
his futile proposals," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> led on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s request for a halt in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>
settlement activity. In an editorial,
it urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s proposal for a summit with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, who, it claimed, was now responsible for the stalemate in the
peace process.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq Al-Awsat</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were facing a very grave
crisis with unforeseeable consequences because of the fall in the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>.
This would be "a very difficult year for the economies of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,"
it said, adding, "The risk is a repeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> of the second half of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX>, which, in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, resulted in a bloody and unstoppable
civil war."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> reported plans by left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to disrupt the planned summer
burial of the remains--of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Czar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas II</ENAMEX>; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandra</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of their
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>--discovered near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yekaterinburg</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. Despite continuing argument about the authenticity of the remains, the
government had made "a final decision" to have a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> (complete with a
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> saluting the cortege along its route) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX>.
While the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will foot most of the bill for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>, "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> will have to cover costs for paving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and painting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> said.

         
      
   
