
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> vied for stardom in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. On what is a
make-or-break day for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> peace talks, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadsheets</ENAMEX> led
with stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> government optimism for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last minute</TIMEX> settlement,
despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionists</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> rejection of the draft agreement submitted
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> who is mediating the talks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>, however, gave top priority to the arrest of pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Michael</ENAMEX>
for "engaging in a lewd act" in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will Rogers Memorial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s best-selling
newspaper, dedicated its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> pages to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s misfortune, with a
front page headline that read, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zip Me Up Before You Go Go</ENAMEX>."

            In its main editorial, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> (which, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s instructions, supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>) praised the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s peace efforts but condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s draft as "an
appeasement of IRA terrorism" that would "sign away the sovereignty of a part
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>. It is like letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX> help run the
Falklands, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> share control of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gibraltar</ENAMEX>." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> was at odds
with most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> sea. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Protestant Belfast Telegraph</ENAMEX> declared in an editorial that the
creation of cross-border, north-south <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> was "asking too much" of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulster Unionists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionists</ENAMEX> to accept them as "a
logical development." Its front page headline on the talks was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So Near</ENAMEX> and Yet
So <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Independent</ENAMEX>,
reporting optimism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial
that "the prize is within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX>' grasp": "If they fail to seize it,
they will surrender to the sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lurking in the wings. At the moment of
truth, they must not flinch." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> carried no editorial on the talks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, but its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Holland</ENAMEX> wrote on the op-ed page that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>
had "failed, dramatically, to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionist leader</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX>] of
the need for radical change." She added, "Perhaps, even at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this 11 th</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> will be able to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionists</ENAMEX> that embracing change is
the best way to safeguard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. But the damage that has been done in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few days</TIMEX> is enormous."

            An op-ed comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Beck</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
expressed alarm that recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> rulings against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> could encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> protectionism and lead to a loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> confidence
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the rulings mentioned condemned a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ban on
imports of shrimp caught in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> nets that could also kill rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX>;
another rejected a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> complaint that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was obstructing imports of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Kodak</ENAMEX> film. "A few more headlines proclaiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is letting
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> die at the hands of ruthless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>, or allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to cheat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> out of jobs, will not create the climate for a
clear-headed debate on the future of world trade," the article concluded.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
accession to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> was one of the issues on which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zemin</ENAMEX> hopes to make "substantial progress" when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> visits
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> reported, quoting diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Others
were <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and the resumption of high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> had indicated they hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will promise to put pressure
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taipei</ENAMEX> to enter negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> also hopes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit will bolster his own prestige as a statesman, "upstaged" by new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX>'s successful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tour.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX>, who died with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> in a car crash in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London's Daily</ENAMEX>

               Mail that he is sick of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed al Fayed</ENAMEX>, who
owns the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duchess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windsor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> (which he had
hoped to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s home), recently sold its contents at an auction
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Now he says he plans to redecorate it. "I want to get rid of all
the royal spirits," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX> 
               Mail . "They haven't done me
any good. To hell with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsors</ENAMEX> and the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> does not
deserve to be preserved historically." Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported fury
among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">POWs</ENAMEX> once held by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> that the queen is to invest the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Order of the Garter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s highest order of
chivalry, when he visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Wynette</ENAMEX>, the subject
of many large obituaries in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press, was remembered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX>'s op-ed page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
for her advice to "rester près de <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> homme, quoiqu<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'il</ENAMEX> arrive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, après tout,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ce n'est qu'un homme</ENAMEX>." And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>, profiled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera, was described as "a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX>," who, "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> as a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>,
and then as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, has spent his career trying to understand the point of
view of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
