
   
   
      
         
            

            The world's press is still
far from agreeing on a name for it. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monicagate</ENAMEX>" seems to be quite popular,
having been used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as far apart as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Age</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√©ration</ENAMEX>). But the Paris
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>-Soir calls it "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexgate</ENAMEX>," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have generally plumped for the even more ludicrous "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexygate</ENAMEX>."
"Zippergate" was taken up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Sunday Independent</ENAMEX> . The serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, which tend to avoid catch lines anyway, are calling it
nothing at all, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> ones have so far sensibly resisted "gates" of
any kind, using straightforward catch lines like "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Scandal" or
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Scandal</ENAMEX>." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> excelled themselves by
managing to demean even a sleazy sex scandal with revolting front-page
headlines of which perhaps the worst was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday People</ENAMEX> --"I'll
Give <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You My Baby Gravy</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was a day on which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> who hadn't yet managed to get their hands on the story
rushed to have their belated say, many of them posing as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old World</ENAMEX>
sophisticates bewildered by the simple-minded puritanism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, its main female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalia Aspesi</ENAMEX>, wrote: "Seen from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the drama which is imprisoning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, which is endangering not only his presidency but
even the economy and politics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, if not of the entire
planet, appears an amusing, absurd and incomprehensible triviality. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX> have never had such problems, partly because
they are almost always <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Democrats</ENAMEX>, or at any rate very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, at
least in words, and partly because they are almost always ugly and old and
shadowed by energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> who do not permit them any distractions, or they
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widowers</ENAMEX> pledged to chastity." But if they did commit such indiscretions,
she added, they would be much more popular.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriele Romagnoli</ENAMEX> wrote that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Houdini</ENAMEX> couldn't have got himself out
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s mess, because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> could not have tolerated the commonplace
nature of his offence. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> based on hypocrisy can forgive the sins which
don't belong to it, those which it dreams of committing, but not those which it
commits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>," he explained.

            In the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Amiel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> who is married to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Black</ENAMEX>,
wrote in an op-ed article headlined "Stop this madness" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of political correctness. "It has come to this: the natural desire of a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for an aggressive, handsome and powerful middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and the
reciprocal pleasure that such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has in the flattering attention of a pretty
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>--these totally mutual and consensual instincts that are built into
the human psyche, whether one likes it or not--have created a tempest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> that could lead to a constitutional crisis. Indeed, this natural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libidinous</ENAMEX> reaction could well have a major impact on the lives of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iraqis</ENAMEX>, not to mention the world economy."

            After
saying that "the one great contribution that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could make" would be to
"expose the sexual political correctness that distorts our law and our lives,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amiel</ENAMEX> concluded, "One wonders what Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is really feeling through all
this as she manages <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX> defence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. My own view is that, like Lorena
Bobbitt, she is sharpening the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> to remove the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major impediment that
stands between her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> presidency."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> featured as a subject in numerous
tasteless cartoons. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> on the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> showed Bill lying disconsolately in a double bed beside
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, who is saying, "So it's the dollar that's dropped, then?" The liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
had a cartoon on its editorial page showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> dragging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by
his penis off his presidential pedestal into a throng of hysterical,
knife-waving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. Beside it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s editorial--titled "Tell
the truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>"--said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> "needs to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> why she
is still standing by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--why the peace and prosperity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> are an
achievement for which he deserves credit. She persuaded her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was fit to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> once before. She needs to do so again. And she
cannot afford to fail."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandal might trigger a wave of
anti-Semitism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It quoted an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the
Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League of B'nai B'rith</ENAMEX> as saying that the fact that the fate of
the administration hung on the word of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had already
produced accusations of a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> conspiracy" against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> operated by radical right-wing and white supremacist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharonot</ENAMEX> , commented, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
used to think, in all good faith, that the fate of the peace process was in the
hands of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> calling herself <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>. Apparently
it's in the hands of another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
published an op-ed article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Rubinstein</ENAMEX>, saying, "In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world and
among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe that because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is
Jewish the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> sex scandal is nothing but another stunt by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
Mossad, intended to distract the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> away from the peace process. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> you could hear perfectly serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying the timing of the new
scandal could not possibly be a coincidence. According to that version, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> were alarmed by the possibility the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> might take a
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> stance, and quickly cooked up the new sex scandal."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> devoted a whole
column to the unpromising scandal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domingogate</ENAMEX>--a story from its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> about how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Lewis</ENAMEX>, had included in the original manuscript of her
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Private Lives of the Three Tenors a passage</ENAMEX> "imagining" a love
affair between her and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pl√°cido Domingo</ENAMEX>. The tenor had issued a statement
admitting to having seen her around the place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Opera</ENAMEX> but
denying she had even interviewed him for her book--let alone participated with
him in an "imagined" romance. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> had a scoop over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had applied for asylum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, but was
likely to be denied it.

         
      
   
