
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diversionary Action</ENAMEX>?

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> airstrikes
against targets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> were met by strong protest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistan Press International</ENAMEX>, "large
anti-American demonstrations are underway in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> ... condemning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawn</ENAMEX> reported that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> received the news of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> attacks ... with a complete sense of shock."
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> daily the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX> contacted one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> "on satellite phone at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX>
pm on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to convey his statement through another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>." Bin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> denied responsibility for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX> bombings but called for the
continuation of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jehad</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airstrikes</ENAMEX> received qualified approval from most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
described the attacks as the "beginning of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s fightback against
terrorism." In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said, "This was a legitimate
and necessary response which should not be understood as blind retaliation for
the appalling crimes committed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>. It was far from blind;
and there is good reason to credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s claim that this was a
pre-emptive assault on operational terrorist bases preparing to carry out
further attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> targets which would have cost, as they did in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>, the lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as well."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> reported that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> welcomed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> action. 'The atrocities
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar es Salaam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omagh</ENAMEX> have shown the pain and
suffering terrorism can bring to innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,' he said. 'I strongly support
this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> action against international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.' " The story concluded
with a dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> correspondent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Burke</ENAMEX>, one of few
Westerners in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> when the airstrikes occurred: "Our hope is that the
Taliban may have struck a deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, perhaps giving them the
details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s whereabouts in return for recognition by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as
the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. If so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> might be expected to
protect us against the anger of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> which everyone expects to materialise
any minute."

            By
contrast, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> signaled its attitude to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> actions with the
headline of its editorial: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diversionary</ENAMEX> action." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> clearly laid out its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the</ENAMEX>
Dog theory: "After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> of sexual revelations and lies, which have
taken a severe toll on his reputation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> with the help of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>, has found a means of rallying the country
behind the presidency and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stars and Stripes</ENAMEX>." It concluded, "[F]or Mr
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> action against those who have taken <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and other lives
is [a] clear way of demonstrating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> presidency is
about much more than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> test taken at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, the right-wing daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> took
a similar tack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s pictorial
cover juxtaposed a shot of a statesmanlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> arriving for her deposition accompanied by the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> Testified Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Jury</ENAMEX>."
Inside, an opinion piece suggested that on hearing news of the bombardment,
"no impartial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> could avoid the immediate suspicion that it was a desperate
maneuver to distract world public opinion." The more liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> was more
supportive, though it counseled fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> surprise attacks and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
involvement.

            According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> welcomed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> airstrikes despite concerns
that they could lead to retaliation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> aide
observed, "If we allow our fear of retaliation to dictate our action or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inaction</ENAMEX>, we will have handed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> the ultimate victory." An analysis said,
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> invoked the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> method in the war on
terrorism, which tries to deter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and make them pay a price for their
actions. Although the results of the strikes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> could not
be immediately confirmed, the critical factor here is not the damage that was
caused but the signal that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> sent in response to surging international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> fundamentalist terrorism."

            Elsewhere
in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zvi Bar'el</ENAMEX> sounded a more
negative note: "In the absence of precise intelligence, the administration
has ... adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> general methods of operation: bombing targets of some kind
... and imposing sanctions. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, the states
that have given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, imposing sanctions would be
ineffective. Apart from the export of opium, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> has no commercial ties
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>; and partial sanctions have already been imposed on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>--sanctions that do not interfere with the business interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
petroleum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Because of those interests, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> was removed from the
sanctions law <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, even though it is included on the list of countries
that support terrorism."

             

         
      
   
