
   
   
      
         
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis continued
to deepen divisions within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, generating growing antipathy toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s unconditional support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, described
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as "simply traditional" but said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s "stentorian position" was more irksome to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
From the start, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> has taken a stance in favor of
military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> without consulting his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, while at
the same time proposing himself as a candidate for the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Biancheri</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of "giving world public opinion the
impression that the showdown with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> reflected not so much respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
resolutions as a wish to end a match with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> that had been left
unfinished by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert Storm</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, he said, were behaving "as if the rules of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> foreign and security policy did not exist," and seem to love wars.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Falklands War</ENAMEX> boosted the popularity of Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
turned out to be fruitful for both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s military and economic prestige,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biancheri</ENAMEX> added. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> seem to be saying to themselves, 'We have an
experienced and excellent professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, so let's keep it busy.' "

            The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX>, under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Britain Goes to War</ENAMEX>," reported
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX> opinion polls showing a majority of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> in favor of bombing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. This, it suggested, was because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> were "inundated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'revelations</ENAMEX>' about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s arsenal"--a comment not without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> should be denied use of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, it condemned "an operation that will end up
by hurting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> much more than it will hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>."
Nevertheless, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> led
with an offer of support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">José Maria Aznar</ENAMEX>, which
included giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> access to the bases.

            
Within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, press opinion was generally
divided between rejection of military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and support for it on
condition that it resulted in the elimination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>, in a
front-page editorial, said that "profound errors of judgement are about to be
made." It said that "the purposes of the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> remain
fatally unspecific," and added that one reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> had not dared to use his
biological and chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> was the weight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
power ranged against him.

            "Without
the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> created during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, gung-ho <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militarism</ENAMEX> is especially offensive. Worse still, it will be ineffective," the
Independent concluded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> also published an interview with former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros</ENAMEX>
Boutros-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghali</ENAMEX>, condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and saying he was "astonished" that
nobody considered the sufferings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--"[a]nd the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>, remember,
was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> created to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>, another liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> refusal to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> due to inspect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> chemical-weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> was
justified by "precisely the same argument used by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> about the
preponderance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> now in dispute." The
impression of double standards being applied was particularly strong where it
did most damage--in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> concluded. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amr Moussa</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Monde</ENAMEX> in an interview
that "nothing can justify the military option."

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
which led its front page with a story about an astonishing secret alliance
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> to oppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> was neither "an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poodle</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s lapdog," and that he
couldn't be the toast of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and continental <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
foreign and security policy, it said, would be insular and isolationist and
would invariably prefer appeasement to intervention. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> should note
that the special relationship cannot be reconciled with the creation of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that includes this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," it said. In the conservative
tabloid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX> wrote
an article supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>.

            
The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> published
an article by former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Perle</ENAMEX>
proposing that the West recognize and arm a provisional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
overthrow the Ba'ath <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, and ran an editorial supporting him under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Target Saddam</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> carried a front-page
report by its resident conservative conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>, Ambrose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, that former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Projects</ENAMEX> and
Special Needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robyn Dickey</ENAMEX> had been "transferred abruptly to a job at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defence Department</ENAMEX> after she was named as a long-standing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>'s sexual harassment lawsuit."

            In an editorial, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> blasted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of The

               New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , for her sycophantic treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>.
Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina-bopping</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> quoted from an article she had
written for her own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> dinner for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, accusing her of "sheer gush" and "babbling soppiness" toward both him
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "Come back and help our 'clever, young and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsullied</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> in his desperate struggle to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX> trendy after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> in power," it said. "Come back and bathe him in the balm of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjectives</ENAMEX>."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
press, many column inches were devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>'s interrogation as a
witness by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magistrate</ENAMEX> in connection with an international call-girl
scandal, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press much space was given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Al Fayed</ENAMEX>'s
interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Mirror</ENAMEX> saying he believed that the deaths of his son
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> had been the result of a "conspiracy."

         
      
   
