
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Lame Ducks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etc.</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            Under the main front-page
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clinton Bombed Civilians on Purpose</ENAMEX>," the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> knew he was bombing a civilian target
when he authorized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. Tests
he had ordered showed there was no nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> on the site, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claimed. An
editorial described the missile attacks as a disaster: "The hasty resort to
violence shows that yet again the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is failing to grasp the political reasons
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">anti-Americanism</ENAMEX>. ... Until it addresses its failure to pressure
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> into making concessions to legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> claims, and recognises
that the continuing presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mecca</ENAMEX>,
creates deep offence, ... the cycle of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attack</ENAMEX> and retaliation will continue."
The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> papers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> and the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> supported the missile strikes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>
published an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheik Omar Bakri</ENAMEX>, described as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bakri</ENAMEX> has pledged global war against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> "until every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> has been withdrawn from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> and until the embargo which is starving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has been lifted." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he predicts, will never be able to
lay his hands on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s fortune--which he estimates at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX>--because it is held in secret by various financial and commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world and managed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surrogates</ENAMEX> who don't even
know who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> is.

            Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s new purge of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, his forthcoming meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
being discussed in western <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> as a summit of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lame ducks</ENAMEX>.
Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Blind Man and the Paralytic</ENAMEX>," an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> old before his time,
diminished by sickness and by his obsession with power, who fails in everything
he does and who is leading his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to ruin." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, it said, is hardly
less handicapped. "In contrast to the dollar, but just like the ruble, he is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devalued</ENAMEX>, ridiculed and lacking credibility," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libération</ENAMEX> said. "It is a
far from ideal position from which to negotiate with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> who has nothing
more to lose and who cunningly exerts an effective blackmail by threatening
even greater chaos." In a front-page editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crisis of the Lame Ducks</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugenio Scalfari</ENAMEX> attributed the world's financial crisis to the absence
everywhere of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said it is "a disgrace" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s war against
terrorism is not getting the full backing "of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX>, and all its so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> world." It said, "A 'Lewinsky motivation' can be dismissed as tabloid
trash--for except in the world of movies and conspiracy theories, that is not
how the vast machinery of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> intelligence, military, and diplomatic
services operate. In any case, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidential approval rating
remains barely dented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> investigation, it is nonsense to
suggest he needed a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> to enhance
it."

            By
contrast, the liberal daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s military initiative is "doomed to
failure" unless it is accompanied by diplomatic efforts to promote
reconciliation between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. "That," it said, "is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
challenge."

            
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawn</ENAMEX> announced a
"new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> doctrine of unilateral brinkmanship" by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
claimed to be sole "international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and hangman, all at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
the same time." It asked: "If the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is to replicate the judicial standards of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild West</ENAMEX> across the global <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>, what need for the flummery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> and all the talk that goes with it of international law and morality?
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> thus, in the best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> tradition, is to shoot from the hip, why
not push the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> edifice into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX>?" In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>, the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> called
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> missile attacks "utterly injudicious and irresponsible" and "a wanton
display of vengeance by the world's only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>power."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s biggest-circulation
newspaper, Komsomolskaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pravda</ENAMEX>, gave a horrific account of the experiments inflicted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cosmonauts</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. Their training, kept secret from even their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>,
involved making them lie motionless for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> with their heads lower than
their legs, keeping them for long periods in isolation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> in total
darkness and silence, making them give samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone marrow</ENAMEX> and muscle and
bone tissue without anesthesia, and starving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 days</TIMEX> while showing
him pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Only now are the stories leaking out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
biggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX>, published an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, who, asked to sum up the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> in a single word,
replied, "Disappointing." He told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiroki Fukuda</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>,
more than any other, has been steeped in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and controlled by the power of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX>. Its pre-eminent symbol is the concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, or perhaps the
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, he added, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> cannot look forward to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> st
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> with any optimism.

             

         
      
   
