
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cruel Britannia</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> reports on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s public declaration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> policy. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> strongly pressured him to state the policy in clear terms, something he
had avoided doing. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, he was unwavering: "We don't support
don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> should be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in any organisation for which statehood
is a requirement." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> asserted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> have no right to determine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s future without input from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taipei</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers delve deep
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> soccer loss to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> headline: "It's
Just <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Cruel to Take</ENAMEX>." General conclusions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beckham</ENAMEX> was
an idiot to have committed the foul that got him kicked out of the game ("an
astonishing display of petulance," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckham</ENAMEX>'s
infraction was harmless and did not warrant an ejection; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) 18-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phenom Michael Owen</ENAMEX> is a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> interviews coach
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Hoddle</ENAMEX>, who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckham</ENAMEX>'s retaliatory strike "wasn't violent conduct.
...Why do we always need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX> in a case like this?"

            The
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> salutes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> for playing "brilliant and brave
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>," noting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s fortitude in playing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> down for almost the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">entire second half</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also nabs a quote from the queen: When
asked if she'd been rooting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Highness</ENAMEX> responded, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>,
I think one should." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> wonders why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is bad at
penalty shots (the match was decided in a penalty shootout). Dismissing the
possibility of inferior talent, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> decides it has something to do with
the national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>: "Is there some cancerous part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> psyche
which produces serial chokers. ... Might not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s performance be seen
as the classic example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on the dither?"

            Oddly, one must go all the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for the
unattractive griping one might expect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX>
quotes several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> declaring they were "robbed" by a missed call
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentines</ENAMEX>. Other whines: "They don't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> to win. ...
It appears that there is some bias against us. ... I haven't seen such rubbish
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. ... We've been cheated." The paper downplays any leftover
bitterness from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Falklands War</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1986 World Cup</ENAMEX> match in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> on an illegal play: "Maybe during the war we were angry.
But it's a game," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>. Offering a less cavalier attitude
toward the sport, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> has this to say in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O Estado</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo</ENAMEX>:

            Here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every-four-year</TIMEX> event shows a much more positive and spontaneous Brazilian
patriotism than that of all national <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> and elections together. ... I
wonder what would happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilians</ENAMEX> were allowed to choose between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types
of election: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. I
have a feeling that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilians</ENAMEX> would perceive more reasons to pick the
second choice.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White North celebrate Canada Day</ENAMEX> with pride and patriotism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ottawa Sun</ENAMEX> reports that,
despite their hatred of the very nation being celebrated, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> Day even
touches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
