
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>'s successful
diplomacy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> failed to convince many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> abroad that the threat
of war had been lifted, and pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to back down
continued across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> itself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s presence
did nothing to inhibit the anti-U.S. rhetoric of the government-controlled
press. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> is not an international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> directed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> but an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence services whose
orders it executes," said the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Thawra</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Babel</ENAMEX> , which is published by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uday</ENAMEX>,
said there was no difference between "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American imperialism</ENAMEX>" and "German
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX>." It also accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of hijacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and
"taking for itself rights that the international community has not accorded
it."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, anti-U.S. opinion remained strongest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, where the conservative
daily Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> said in
a front-page editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> double standard in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>--merciless toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for breaking international commitments but supine
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> when it does the same thing--"was bound to scandalize their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>." At the same time, failure to strike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of warlike
rhetoric could have cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> its credibility, Le Figaro
said, adding that "by saving himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> has also saved Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." An opinion poll commissioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to remain neutral in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>,
but the same percentage thought that the prime objective of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> strike
should be "to eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the liberal daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> attacked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for supplying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> with gas masks, antibiotics against
germ warfare, and various kinds of self-protection advice while at the same
time insisting that the risk of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> attack was remote. In choosing the
maximum level of preparedness, it said in an editorial, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has dulled the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
deterrent capability, has made the possibility of nuclear warfare more
tangible, has frightened away <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, has generated huge expenditures, and
has increased doubts as to whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> can provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
real security."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Standard</ENAMEX>, was outraged by the photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>
shaking hands with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>. Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Repulsive Handshake</ENAMEX>," it said
in an editorial: "It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> to conduct evenhanded
diplomacy. But to exchange public greetings with a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> accords him a
legitimacy which should repel most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
considered putting into operation a secret plan to murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> that was
drawn up, then shelved, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Der Spiegel</ENAMEX> carried a story to
the same effect, while Le
Monde of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> on its front page about another plan to murder a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictator</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>)--one for which a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Bavaud</ENAMEX>
was decapitated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1941</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bavaud</ENAMEX>'s martyrdom had been shrouded in
silence by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> during the war, but it was now to be
commemorated with a plaque on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neuchâtel</ENAMEX> where he was born.

            
The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>, owned by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman Catholic Canadian</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Black</ENAMEX>, published an opinion piece
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Killing Season</ENAMEX>," which turned out--only at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>--to be
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Wasserstein</ENAMEX>,
fiercely attacked the "mischievous and irresponsible role" of a certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s "diaspora" who, "[k]nowing little of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> of the conflict,
... project their insecurities, obsessions, and unfulfilled dreams on to the
distant national hearth." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-sympathizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>
led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> "may spurn chance to re-enter peace talks,"
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX> as saying he was still
"totally wedded" to the peace process.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>'s main
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Japan in the Dock</ENAMEX>," congratulated the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group of Seven</ENAMEX> finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>' meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> on the "acrimonious" dressing-down they gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>. If new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hikaru Matsunaga</ENAMEX> "was shocked by the
hostility he encountered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, that shock should be salutary and has come
not a moment too soon," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> added. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press
speculated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on the reason why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had intervened to
stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>'s being awarded a knighthood by the queen: Was it his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> nationalism, or was it his attitude on violence toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>? The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s memorial fund
is to open an office in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> because of "the strength of interest from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> described the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> election as "comparatively peaceful," because there
were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 11</NUMEX> dead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bihar</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Andhra Pradesh</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Bengal</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orissa</ENAMEX>. But in an editorial it deplored the fact that "whether it is
enlisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of goons ... or terrorising innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>,
all methods are deemed to be good as long as, in the perception of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, they lead to his victory."

         
      
   
