
   
   
      
         
            Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Is About Sex</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s news to chew on:
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s impeachment report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
will address only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. It will ignore not only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate, Filegate</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>, topics he has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> studying, but also
Whitewater, the scandal he was appointed to investigate lo these many years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> hasn't totally abandoned the B-list scandals: He will still present
evidence from them to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge panel</ENAMEX> he reports to, and that will
certainly lead to indictments against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>. But the implication is
that the only impeachable offenses he is pursuing relate to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.

            I can't decide whether this
is surprising or unsurprising news. Should reaction be gape-mouthed shock or a
blasé shrug?

            In favor of gape-mouthed
shock: There is something incredible in the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> could spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> and all he can come up with to nail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a sex
scandal.

            In favor
of a blasé shrug: Anyone who has tried to follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation has long
known that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater, Filegate</ENAMEX>, etc., are forests of confusion. Even if there
were compelling evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> committed a high crime, the
scandals themselves are too incomprehensible to make any charge stick. (Or,
even if they're not incomprehensible, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have never succeeded in
portraying them in a way that interests the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.) Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
dropped the B-listers: Now he has distilled his case to the essence, focusing
on the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> understand, and the only one where
he might find a clear, explicable high crime.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap Only</ENAMEX> decision
may disrupt the scandal. In theory, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> Only report should make it much
easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to mea culpa . An apology would clear the
decks: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> would disappear, and the other investigations would not remain
to threaten him. He'd be humiliated but safe. But although a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> Only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> makes it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to mea culpa , it also makes it much
less likely. The sad, persistent fact about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is that he tells only as
much truth as he needs to. The more you press him, the more likely he is to be
honest. Anything that eases pressure makes him more likely to lie. So if he
knows that he's safe from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX>, etc., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may be more inclined to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brazen</ENAMEX> out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. After all, he only has to beat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> scandal, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>.

            The other, more frivolous
consequence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> Only report will be to sow confusion among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. The B-list scandals have always been fig leaves for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. They repeated the names of the scandals like a mantra: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>,
Travelgate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate, Foster</ENAMEX>. Whitewater, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate, Filegate, Foster</ENAMEX>. No
matter what these scandals involved, they served primarily to justify <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX>,
a way to sanitize the sex scandal. See, it's not just about sex. It's about
a pattern of obstruction of justice and perjury dating back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, etc. ... But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s most dogged persecutor, says
there's no pattern, what on earth will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say? That it really
is just about sex? I am looking forward to a week of creative new
answers.

            
               Killing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
            

            How can you tell if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
is going to do a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX> ? My guess: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watch Monica</ENAMEX>'s image.

            In the beginning, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was, you may recall, a "pathological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>" who forged a letter of
recommendation and said she never told the truth. She was a shameless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hussy</ENAMEX> who
seduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, took pride in her "presidential kneepads," and bragged about
her large breasts; a creepy, beret-wearing stalker who tracked the president
from event to event in search of a hug.

            But for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past month</TIMEX>, and especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, there has been a kinder, gentler
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, an innocent trapped in a scandal not of her own making. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
sounded sweetly sympathetic: She told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> "it breaks my heart" to testify
and said all she wanted for her <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> birthday was "my life back." A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> piece bathed her in golden light: She hopes to go to
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in sociology, she's scrimping because she doesn't want to
burden her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> financially, she is so much a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that she
couldn't attend her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s wedding, and--the icing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>--she has
taken up knitting. The coverage of her day in court was uniformly kind, rarely
mentioning that she has lied before and changed her story now.

            Why the "strange new respect"? First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Rule</ENAMEX> of
Conventional Wisdom, which is that it must change. Troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is an old
story: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> needed a new angle for this round of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. Result: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knitting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is reaping the reward for having dumped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>. His
wild, self-aggrandizing public statements made both of them a laughingstock,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> photo shoot he arranged sullied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s image
almost as much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> spread would have. She is also enjoying
the imprimatur of the law. Whenever someone testifies, gravitas follows. The
mere fact of giving sworn testimony to a court imbues a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> with
credibility and weight: She is participating in the measured and solemn
business of justice.

            But the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> reason why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> has seemed like a sweetheart is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has been silent. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s image goes, so goes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were going to apologize,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s new image would be safe. It would do no good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to
savage her if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is going to admit an affair.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> campaign
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is beginning, and that's the best indicator so far that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
is not going to apologize. For him to survive a denial, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> must be ruined.
Having showered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> with security clearances and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> jobs and gifts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> visits, it's a little hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to make the claim that she's
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nut cake</ENAMEX>, but the effort will be made. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> story,
probably based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> leak, quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is
"dangerous" and that she "hallucinates." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> is gathering dirt about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s mendacity and
presidential obsession. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are tallying and comparing all
the different stories <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has told about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, in
her affidavit, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, etc.) and are gleefully looking forward to
exposing the inconsistencies. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> must be killed to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
she will be killed (metaphorically speaking, of course).

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
