
   
   
      
         
            Hell in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacific</ENAMEX> press is rife
with headlines of economic foreboding. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>'s Straits Times
reports the "slowdown in growth for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second quarter</TIMEX> was across
all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>--and is the lowest growth rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> pledges
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s competitiveness will not erode. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
Courier announces that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PNG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which depends on
substantial foreign aid from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, is asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aussies</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> month
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dole</ENAMEX> advance. Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Skate</ENAMEX> assures the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> that
this is not a sign of "dire economic strife." The data dump from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>
Times predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economy will shrink by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Korea</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Seong-tae</ENAMEX> opines that the
"economic outlook is getting worse than was anticipated."

            The
economic news in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> highlights a surprising budget surplus. The national
papers are varying in their response to this good news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX> is aware that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> surplus does
not mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> is now immune to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> sees the new figures as denoting "bigger-than-expected tax cuts"
in the future, a sentiment that dueled with a quotation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Herald</ENAMEX> : "This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> is not in the business
of looking for cuts." The proposed tax package, described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> as the
biggest tax change in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, includes a fixed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>
goods and service tax, which would "clean up the indirect tax system" and
create jobs in the process. The package will also reduce taxes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
extend various personal tax cuts, make changes in the social security tax, and
make way for an "overhaul" of business taxes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aunified</ENAMEX> press criticizes the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National parties</ENAMEX>) for using the tax plan as an election trump card, and an
Age editorial blasts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, noting that there has been
"little headway against unemployment, manufacturing export growth has slowed,
and the innovation culture was receding."

            Covering
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> abroad, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Somalian</ENAMEX> arrested in connection with the embassy
bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> was carrying an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> passport. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
are tightening their security as a result of the bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> has warned that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> (along with those in
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>) is under threat. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> responded in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lumpur</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>, saying the announcement was misleading, as it would
displace attention from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where the threat is very real, whereas
"there are no terrorist activities" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> also
reports increased security precautions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesia's Daily Express</ENAMEX>
also reports rumors propagated on the Internet predicting
disturbances between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian Muslims</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> in a popular shopping
district. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>'s Straits Times discount
the rumors as utterly false, citing the deplorable readiness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
believe everything they read on the Internet.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, has
discovered a solution to its ubiquitous drug problem. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> high government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were reported as discussing the matter, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> condoning extreme
measures when it came to treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>. "Does that measure mean
shooting them?" asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The response: "You can do whatever with them. We
have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">61 million</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 million</NUMEX> should be sufficient. Do a
vasectomy!"

             

         
      
   
