
   
   
      
         
            Trouble in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>"
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> prepared for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s controversial, low-key burial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Czar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas II</ENAMEX>'s remains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petersburg</ENAMEX>, the English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported that "as
in life, so in death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas II</ENAMEX> has served only to divide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>." It quoted
a new opinion poll showing that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 47 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> believe that the
remains, which a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> has found to be those of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>,
are in fact authentic. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that "[b]etween rampant organizational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chaos</ENAMEX>, a stingy funeral budget, sound and fury from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
and a growing list of prominent no-shows, this proposed 'act of national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repentance</ENAMEX> and reconciliation' is shaping up as one lousy historical event."
Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> were to have a last-minute change of heart and decide to
attend, despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s refusal to accept the authenticity of the remains,
the damage has already been done, the editorial said, and "[a] historical
occasion which at the very least deserved both gravity and grace has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irrevocably</ENAMEX> reduced to pure spectacle."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> 's lead story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
playing down the crippling effects of drought on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> harvest
because it knows it cannot afford to provide compensation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>. The paper
rejected a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> claim that the drought's cost to agriculture is around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion rubles</NUMEX>, saying that the drought has hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> regions and has caused a
loss in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Volgograd region</ENAMEX> alone of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 1.2 billion rubles</NUMEX>. The daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egodnya</ENAMEX> predicted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> would seek to attach strict
conditions to the disbursement of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multibillion dollar</NUMEX> credit recently
agreed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>. Among the demands it
expected the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to make were pledges by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> not
to place S-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX>, not to conduct trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, not to
interfere with the blockade of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> gas supplies to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,
and to give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> greater access to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> markets.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with an announcement by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manfred Kanther</ENAMEX> that he wants to get tough with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hooligans</ENAMEX> now to prevent further violence at the next international
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> tournament--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> championship--which is to take place in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>' time. He proposed to place a travel ban on
known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troublemakers</ENAMEX>, but to back this up with fiercer measures such as
immobilizing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> or, as a last resort, locking them up. The conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> backed the proposals
in a front-page editorial that urged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> to accept them in the
interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a whole.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were also preoccupied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with a sports problem--that of drug
abuse by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tour de France</ENAMEX>. Following the arrest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Festina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruno Roussel</ENAMEX>, accused of possessing large quantities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">forbidden substances</ENAMEX>, there were several editorials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> about the
potentially disastrous effects of this scandal on the world's greatest cycling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marathon</ENAMEX>. Libération
praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Sport</ENAMEX> for having apparently decided "to burst the boil"
of drug abuse, which has overshadowed the tour since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, when competitors
went on strike rather than submit to drug tests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said that the tour had
been "poisoned" by the scandal.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> also gave heavy coverage to
the visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez el Assad</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> who, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said, was seeking to
advance the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process at the
expense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might not be wrong to want to integrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> president
into the process rather than exclude him, but asked, "All the same, can one
tolerate the imprisonment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> of conscience in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which one is seeking to make one's 'strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
paper the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>
published an opinion piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daud Kuttab</ENAMEX>
attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for demanding new direct <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> peace
talks. "This is a cop-out," he wrote. "If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, which has
been described by many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> as the most pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Israel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> ever, is
unable to press <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, how will the weak <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>" fare.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening Standard</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> were
"coming forward in droves" to claim fatherhood of the impotence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug Viagra</ENAMEX>
after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s British research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> had been recognized as its
inventors by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Patent Office</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
