
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tycoon Conrad Black</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> expanded its campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> by accusing him of censoring coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
newspaper (and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph</ENAMEX> rival) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>. In a front-page lead
story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Mirsky</ENAMEX>, as saying that the
Times "has simply decided, because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s interests, not to cover
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in a serious way." His comments were taken from the transcript of a forum
on press freedom that took place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> after
the hand over of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
"would have thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> had been airlifted up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pluto</ENAMEX>, that it had
simply vanished," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mirsky</ENAMEX> said. "We have here what is arguably the traditionally
most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in the world, and it has just decided--it has taken not
an executive decision, but an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s position--to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
alone," he added. The beleaguered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Stothard</ENAMEX>,
replied in a statement that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is wholly
and solely in the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>," adding: "I have never taken an
editorial decision to suit Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s interests. Nor have I ever been asked
to." The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, in a signed op-ed piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stothard</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
"to accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s word" that none of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirsky</ENAMEX>'s accusations against him
were true.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --already under attack for
failing to cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s cancellation of a book contract with the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Chris Patten</ENAMEX> --had tracked down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, in a car
on his way to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> airport. The interview ran on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s front page
under the headline "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> screwed up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patten</ENAMEX> row, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Murdoch</ENAMEX>
lashed out in the interview at senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>,
HarperCollins, saying they had "chickened out" and left him "in a completely
inexcusable position." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> admitted he had asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> to drop the
book but said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> should have been forthright about it, instead of
inventing nonsensical reasons. (They claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patten</ENAMEX>'s manuscript wasn't up
to the mark, when its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Proffitt</ENAMEX>, was already on
record as finding it the most lucid and intelligent book he had ever received
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> returned to the fray, reporting on its front page that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Bell</ENAMEX> was "very low" and contemplating resignation
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s attack; and on an inside page that "outrage is bubbling to the
surface in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>" over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s dumping of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patten</ENAMEX> memoirs. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Pelosi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, as saying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s "willing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accomplice</ENAMEX>" in suppressing the truth about human
rights: "His action to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Patten</ENAMEX>'s book is not isolated and is
part of a pattern."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX>'s editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is our
affair," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> should tell <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> forcefully that it would not be
reintegrated into the international community unless there was a negotiated
solution "taking into account the legitimate aspirations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>." Its main op-ed feature was about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s new yearning for
international respectability. On its front page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> ran a piece about the "the most important homosexual event in the
world"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sydney Gay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesbian Mardi Gras</ENAMEX>. Recalling that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such
event <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> had ended with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> arrests, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> pointed out that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> there had been only one arrest--of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> possessing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two grams</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cannabis</ENAMEX>--and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> uniformed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> had crossed the security barriers to
join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. It also boasted on its front page that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was "in a good
position" in the international cloning war and would be putting on show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6</TIMEX>, a cloned heifer called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marguerite</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> carried an
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Talal bin Abdel-Aziz al-Saud</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, in which he said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had got its
policies wrong throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. "Their position is bad because it
doesn't rest on justice," he said. Asked if he also opposed sanctions against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Talal</ENAMEX> said that sanctions didn't work: "Look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>--there are sanctions against their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>, but their regimes survive." In
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> understood nothing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. "Our problem with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is that you all have a colonial past and believe that the hills of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> ... are like those which were occupied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>," he said. "Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> understands
us, and not, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think, because there is a big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> community
there, but because they see us as the new promised land, like their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."

            Having been caught
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worshiping</ENAMEX> alone (with bodyguards) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Westminster Cathedral</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> as denying that he was about to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of England</ENAMEX>
and become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony O'Reilly</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.J. Heinz Co. Inc.</ENAMEX>, was about
to achieve sole proprietorship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> by buying out
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror Group</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">46-percent</NUMEX> stake.

         
      
   
