
   
   
      
         
            Give It Away, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soul-searching</ENAMEX> is always a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> story (as long as it's someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>). So those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> who
assume he did it--that is, all of us--agree that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between now and Aug. 17</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had better do some. He must, as the phrase goes, test his own
character: Am I going to be a sleazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> forever? Or will I finally tell
the truth even if it hurts?
            

            But I am
beginning to think the real character test in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX> is not for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>: What kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> am I? This
question can be asked in a more direct, more pragmatic way: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Starr</ENAMEX> tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the results of the DNA tests before he testifies?

            You can get a headache trying to game all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s possible
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-test tactics. Consider a few:

            Initial test shows <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for blood sample, doesn't reveal results.

            Initial test shows <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
doesn't ask for blood sample, hopes to trick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> into thinking he's in the
clear.

            Initial test shows no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> doesn't say anything, hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will assume he's pursuing Option B,
etc.

            But for
the sake of argument, let's assume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> tests show there is DNA on the dress:
Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> this before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>?

            
Prosecutorial wisdom shouts: Of course not!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has been working this case for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and he has the chance to hook the
biggest fish in the biggest pond. Why on earth would he give away precious
information that might help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wriggle free? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, needless to say, has
no obligation to show the evidence to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> may reveal
sensitive evidence to a witness they are trying to protect (i.e., if a witness
who is helping you might perjure himself in front of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, you tell him
information so he won't lie). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> do not reveal sensitive evidence to
those they are trying to prosecute. Why treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> differently?

            (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, of course, is not a regular target of investigation, because a
regular target would never testify in front of a grand jury if he had something
to hide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, because it's politically impossible, can't take the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX>. It seems unfair to trap him in a lie that he would never have had to
tell if he were a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s setup may be a perjury trap, but that does not
necessarily mean it's unfair. Imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> doesn't tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> about a
positive test result. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, of course, ought to tell the truth, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he might not. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> so far is adamant that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is sticking to his denial.) He might brazen it out by lying to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. The dress and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s story would nail him, an open-and-shut
perjury case. By the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s code, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has hanged himself.

            But what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> can do as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> and what he ought to do as a public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">servant</ENAMEX> differ.

            
What will happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> reveals a positive
result to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? He probably destroys his own case. No matter how much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might want to brazen it out, advance warning from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> would compel
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to admit and apologize. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wouldn't perjure himself and,
as I argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, an apology is likely to kill the appetite for any
impeachment hearings (over obstruction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater, Filegate</ENAMEX>, etc.). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal case</ENAMEX> goes up in smoke.

            Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> gives it away
depends on what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> he is. If he wants to expose criminal
behavior by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and punish it no matter what--if, in short, he is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vindictive avenger Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> say he is--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will sacrifice no
advantage. He will blindside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with test results if that will build
a stronger case. But if he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who wants to turn up the truth as
much as to get his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will give it away.

            "The decent and sensitive
thing to do is tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. There is no advantage whatsoever to getting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to lie before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>," says former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Attorney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Heymann</ENAMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> should] not put himself in the position of
having called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and inviting him to lie unnecessarily."

            Or, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Luskin</ENAMEX> puts it, "You just don't play a
game of chicken like that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>."

            There are strong public policy reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to give
the results away. Do we really want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s career to rise or fall
based on prosecutorial cleverness in a secret grand jury proceeding? Telling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the results makes it more likely he'll go public, and that makes it
more likely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> will be played out in the open rather than in private legal
proceedings. And the public political realm is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> belongs.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s obligations as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is to protect the honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and one of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> is (believe it or not) the dignity of the presidency. That
dignity has been much squandered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but this is a chance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to
protect what remains. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> protects the presidency by exposing criminal
behavior by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. But he can also protect the presidency by preventing
more criminal behavior. Not telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of a positive DNA result may
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">induce Clinton</ENAMEX>--admittedly because of his own hubris--to lie, to trap himself,
to damage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the presidency even more. Telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> lets
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> avoid committing a new crime.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who would benefit
most of all by telling is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> himself. He has been demonized as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who is destroying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> over sex. He can become the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> save himself.

         
      
   
