
   
   
      
         
            Give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>?

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) and "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click here.
            

            The initial euphoria over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace agreement rapidly gave way in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
press to fears that it might fail. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>, recently
purchased by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.J. Heinz Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony O'Reilly</ENAMEX>, appeared to
discount the possibility of failure from the start. A front-page headline last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> read, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peace</ENAMEX> at last for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX>," and an editorial gushed, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t is
not naive to be optimistic about its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX>" and "we must all resist the
temptation to see future violence described as a failure of the peace process,"
although that temptation would surely be strong.

            The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , always deeply suspicious of any dealings between
criticized several aspects of the settlement and emphasized that it "does not
in itself mean peace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulster</ENAMEX>'s time." It added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionist voters</ENAMEX>
"should not, at least as yet, feel that they are against peace by rejecting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s agreement--or be stampeded into voting 'Yes' in a referendum."
"Please make it work," begged the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> in its front-page headline, saying in its
editorial that while failure was a possibility, so also was success. "It is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for gratitude, and even the odd private prayer," it went on. "For this was
a blessed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Friday</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]hat has been achieved is a great new
opportunity, but it is only that. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, north and south, must
make up their minds to take it."

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter Sunday</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> was leading
with the news that peace was already threatened by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>'s refusal to press
the IRA to hand over its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> immediately. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Times , on the other hand, described divisions among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unionists</ENAMEX> as the main threat to peace. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX> to campaign together for a "Yes" vote in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s referendum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulster</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Mirror</ENAMEX> published an "exclusive" front-page report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> was going to ask the queen to confer a
knighthood on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the peace talks, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>.

            
Surprisingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's editorial was hostile to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who had elsewhere been garnering plaudits for his contribution to the
peace settlement. It described his intervention as "merely opportunistic" and
added: "In his intrusions into the peace process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
took no risks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>--has tried to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> as if it were a
colonial power, slowly withdrawing from a Third World 'statelet.' It is worth
reminding him that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> is, and remains, part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> and, as
such, is part of a developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>."

            
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> broadsheet was
stressing the difficulties facing the peace settlement because of divisions
within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> and among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionists</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> led its
front page with a warning by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> of increased terrorist violence at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of the referendum. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, too, emphasized the problems.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> peace remains to be built," said the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> over its main
front-page story. In an adjoining comment, it described the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> settlement
as "typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>" in its pragmatism. "What continental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurist</ENAMEX> could have
thought up a statute which reaffirms <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX>'s dependence on the crown without
excluding its eventual reattachment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Ireland</ENAMEX>?" it asked. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> carried
an article by its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> correspondent about intense <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> interest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> settlement as a possible key to solving the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Basque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> problem in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, spending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">C√≥rdoba</ENAMEX>, as saying
there were no comparisons to be made between the two situations.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> agreement was
greeted with even greater euphoria in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> press than in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cork Examiner</ENAMEX> hailed it as the achievement of "lasting peace," and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> compared
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hume</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Social Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who played the key role in
launching the peace negotiations, to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> entering the Promised
Land"--though, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conor Cruise O'Brien</ENAMEX>
pointed out in an op-ed article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> never actually entered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promised Land</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX>, who has always
been opposed to making deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, noted that there was now less open
emphasis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> on peace than on a breakthrough for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> nationalism, and
he added that an article in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Post</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> most
sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>--had rather given the game away with an article that
said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he IRA, which is likely to maintain its ceasefire for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>,
will almost certainly resist any attempt to accede to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionist</ENAMEX> demands for
actual decommissioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early summer</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX> predicted that Sinn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fein</ENAMEX> and the IRA would continue to operate the "peace process" as "a fertile
and rewarding field for further blackmail" and that the peace proposals "may
well be defeated" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionist voters</ENAMEX> in the referendum.

         
      
   
