
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dreadful Crime Against Humanity</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were
dominated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> explosion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omagh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. The blast killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--and injured more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> in the worst atrocity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Troubles</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was crowded with back-to-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> attending a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carnival</ENAMEX> and parade. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> decried the misleading warning--police
cleared the area named in a phone call to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, only to have the explosion
occur at the evacuation point. As the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constable</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX> Ulster
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constabulary</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>]en, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were
led to their slaughter."

            The
British <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were filled with grotesque eyewitness accounts of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carnage</ENAMEX> and unusually unanimous condemnations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> of all stripes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Maginnis</ENAMEX> of the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Ulster Unionist Party</ENAMEX> declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> "a
dreadful crime against humanity." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin McGuinness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, the political
wing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>, blamed "those opposed to the peace process."
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX> was moved to his first "unequivocal
condemnation of a republican paramilitary action," reported <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>.

            The fragile peace settlement is another potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of
the blast. The renewal of terrorist activity has rekindled demands that Sinn
Fein comply with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Friday</ENAMEX> peace deal by turning in its cache of
paramilitary <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. Reflecting suspicions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> was set by the "Real
IRA," a breakaway <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the IRA (the initial telephone warning was made by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> using one of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s code words, though official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> denied
responsibility <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Unionist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> First
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday Times</ENAMEX> that "this bomb
would not have been made or detonated if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> had handed over its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Robinson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unionist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>, echoed
this sentiment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> : "We shouldn't be sitting down
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> at all until [there is] substantial decommissioning."

            While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> urged that the bombing not be allowed to disrupt the peace process,
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> called for the return of
internment--imprisonment without trial for suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>--which was
recently removed from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> law. An opinion piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Internment</ENAMEX>
will not merely put the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> [of the IRA] behind bars; it will also serve
to strengthen the conciliatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>/McGuinness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> in their arguments with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> inside the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sinn Féin/</ENAMEX>IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."

            Financial panic struck <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
Times reports,
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX> called, in a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s Financial
Times , for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to set up a currency board and proposed a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> ruble devaluation. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> paper, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>
experienced a "liquidity crisis," some restricted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar withdrawals, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Bank</ENAMEX> "stepped in with emergency credits ... to prop up several of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, which were in danger of default." There was a
slight rebound in the market <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
pledged to defend the ruble. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> claims: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devaluation</ENAMEX> would
threaten the banking system with collapse. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zadornov</ENAMEX> said that a fall in the ruble's exchange rate would leave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> still standing." Nevertheless, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Bank</ENAMEX> gave up its efforts to defend the ruble--a de facto devaluation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and
Mail suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that the deepening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> financial
crisis could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s undoing. It reported poll results that show that "his
popularity has slumped to an all-time low" and that "[i]f an election were held
today, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 4 per cent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> would vote for him."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX> renewed tensions are building around
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn</ENAMEX> repeated a foreign
office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s claim that the allegations of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> complicity in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> military campaigns are "propaganda." Meanwhile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, an opinion piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> "the breeding ground for religious
extremism, terrorism, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> trafficking and money laundering." It
concluded, "One can only hope that in the wake of the brutal bombing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Africa</ENAMEX> and the victory of a mediaevalist force in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, the international community will recognise that the war against
terrorism cannot be selective."

            With the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31 one year</TIMEX>
anniversary of her death approaching, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are drowning in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>,
though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-monarchists</ENAMEX> are expected to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">march</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. Among the protest's promised attractions
are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> look-alike stripper and a homemade guillotine. On a more
sober note, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> offered an exclusive report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s legacy ignored in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> landmine scandal" said that
political and bureaucratic blunders have left equipment "desperately needed to
clear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>'s minefields ... unused for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>." According to the story, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> "set aside

         
      
   
