
   
   
      
         
            Stitching Things Up

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            In an interview with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> she had run out of metaphors to describe the
state of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process. But this did not prevent her from
saying of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1993 Oslo accords</ENAMEX>, "Instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX>, it's been sandpaper." She
seemed to be siding with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> when she said
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> had done his best to improve security for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> terrorism ("We have stated over and over again
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> effort [by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>] may not always bring <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>
effect") and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, despite admitted political difficulties at home, was
"in a pretty strong position in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>." But when asked if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> was finally putting pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> replied, "It's not our
policy."

            The
merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> led the front page of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> and all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. In an editorial page analysis, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said that "without a successful merger of minds, the transaction
could rapidly turn sour." "Or as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janis Joplin</ENAMEX> put it in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'One Night Stand':</ENAMEX>
'Just because we loved <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, please don't think it's gonna stay that way,' "
the FT concluded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, home of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX>, lauded the marriage as a "union
without conquest" and attributed this to the launch of the euro. "The single
currency is bringing the two shores of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> closer together," it said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said
the negotiations reflected the increased power of the German automobile
industry.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> all led on the fatal mudslides in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern Italy</ENAMEX>, with the predictable comment that political incompetence was
partly responsible. But they also gave big play to the meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romano Prodi</ENAMEX>, who
described their encounter as "a magic moment" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> relations. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennio Caretto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, noted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had inserted "a premeditated and cunning
note" into his condolences about the mudslides. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prodi</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> would come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aviano</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> out of which an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plane</ENAMEX> recently sliced a ski-lift cable, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and starting a wave
of anti-Americanism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cancer: a Hope From America</ENAMEX>." The
subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judah Folkman</ENAMEX>'s encouraging experiments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. This was a
huge story around the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soir</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> evening
newspaper, led by contrast with a story of a revolt by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury fillings</ENAMEX>, which they claim to be dangerous. They are
asking all their fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> to sign an appeal against such fillings (even
though, unfortunately, they are already in the teeth of around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>).

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening</ENAMEX>
Standard led with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Abbey</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> was
under attack for giving money from TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Fund</ENAMEX> when it should have been given to "the choristers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbey Choir</ENAMEX> as a result of their participating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX>'s funeral
service." The choirboys and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't receive any money in expenses,
even though "a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of pounds</NUMEX> cutting short
holidays to return their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> to sing at the service, which was broadcast live
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> across the world," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said.

            Amid growing hopes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> peace agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>
said in an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Peace</ENAMEX> in their grasp" that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> made an
excellent move when he invited his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX>, to campaign with
him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> for a Yes vote in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX> referendum." "A united
front of the present and former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX> must have a powerful
impact," it said. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led with a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Basque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> murder,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El País</ENAMEX> reporting this
side by side with a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> about the IRA agreeing that its
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, might participate in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> parliamentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
