
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>'s promise to give military support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in any conflict
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less</NUMEX>-than-wholehearted support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX> led
its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a story about growing unrest within the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>'s policy. Left-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winger Tony Benn</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, told the
newspaper, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> has just taken over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidency</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>.
We have had a lot of speeches about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is going to speak for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> doesn't support this. Why should a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and do everything he's told by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>?"

            In its
main editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX> in calling for more time to resolve the crisis
with diplomacy, not force. Surprisingly, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>-owned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> took
a similar view. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bombing Saddam</ENAMEX> is a policy without a goal," it said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>
knows bombs will not lead to his overthrow, but feels it has to do something.
In this it has lost sight of its true objective: to oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> in the pursuit
of a peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and a semblance of human rights in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The
strategy is a desperate one: it might encourage someone inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to kill
him. But it is a hope, not a policy."

            Another conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX>, backed
military action, although it said: "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> orders cruise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to be fired and bombs to be dropped, it will not be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> who
suffers. It will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--and almost certainly the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> among them." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, committed to an
"ethical" foreign policy, had been desperately seeking a high-minded moral
justification for bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, it said. "They have failed to find one, because
there isn't one. The only justification for bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is the crude
utilitarian calculus: violence now by the West should help to prevent future
violence, on a far greater scale, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>."

            Its sister
newspaper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> (in an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Be</ENAMEX>
Ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>") that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> "must face the knowledge
that an air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> alone cannot guarantee <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> compliance." Absent unlimited
access for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, ground-troop deployment was the only way to find
and destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s cache of chemical and biological weapons. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> could be at the start of a long and escalating campaign," the editorial
concluded. Even the ultraconservative tabloid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX> 
               Mail
urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> to be wary about using force against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>. "Will strafing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
military installations <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time make the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> a safer place--or
will it only serve to perpetuate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s malign influence by perversely giving
him added kudos with his long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?" it asked.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> carried an interview with former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baker</ENAMEX>, in which he urged a much heavier bombardment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> than the "pin
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pricks</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. "We will have to strike his [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s] 'palaces,'
military installations, and also civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">infrastructures</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> to
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>," he was quoted as saying. "I am sorry that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> people
will have to suffer, but the fault is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s, not ours." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> said that
although the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> could not be resurrected,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was not isolated. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has become closer to us, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that appear to be keeping their distance are in reality supporting us,"
he said. He added that this time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> should respond if attacked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. "The situation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is quite different from the situation seven
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>," he said. "Then there were several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, and
it was important that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> stay out of a prolonged conflict. Now, a brief
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reprisal</ENAMEX> would seem justified to everyone."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>
announced in an editorial the end of the New International Order. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>--above all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>--presented a front in total
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disintegration</ENAMEX>, it said. "Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX> is unconditionally on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
side." "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> are in discussions with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
but are closer to the position of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, that are
firmly opposed to military intervention. It is a heterogeneous front that
includes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>), and radical ones (like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>), as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>." This is the beginning of a "revolution in the world
political order," and its outcome will be determined by that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
battle with the Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, which are equipping themselves with
weapons of mass destruction. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> wins, the eclipse of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> hegemony
will begin. We are in an era of great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Davos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Economic Forum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masumeh Ebtekar</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> would be "on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" in the event of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack.
This was primarily for humanitarian reasons, she said, "but we also have other
fears." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> has one of the greatest concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in the world,
she said--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5 million</NUMEX>, of whom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5 million</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX>. "You can imagine how we
might view the prospect of a new conflict." Asked if she thought it was
possible to negotiate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, she replied, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Personally</ENAMEX>, I have my
doubts."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">liberal Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported
that both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> had no interest in
involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in any military confrontation with the West, but that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> had agreed to supply more defense equipment to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> "if the
conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> becomes more acute." It also reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had been queuing up for gas masks. In an account
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
said she was frustrated by the lack of progress in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, "I am sick and tired of hearing you giving me a pile of
complaints about the other side."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zippergate</ENAMEX> coverage has dwindled in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> evening paper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soir</ENAMEX> had a front-page
comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's Eyes</ENAMEX>," claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s "passionate
look" in photographs left no room for doubt about her relationship with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. There was no need for her to confess to anything, for those eyes
were the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>" in the case and gave "irrefutable proof" of
her passion, it said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outstripping Zippergate</ENAMEX> in column inches <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was the
imminent execution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Faye Tucker</ENAMEX>, which was the subject of the editorial
in the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. Welcoming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>'s
espousal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX>'s cause, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said,
"Let us hope that more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will come to realise that, if it is
wrong to execute her because she is a God-fearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, then it is wrong to
execute anybody." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> all prominently reported a letter to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> asking for "a gesture of
clemency that would contribute to the creation of a culture more favorable to
respect for life."

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> arrived
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX> for an official visit marking the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary of its independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, he was reported to be considering
canceling a plan to confer a knighthood there on the expatriate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur C. Clarke</ENAMEX> ( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Odyssey</ENAMEX> ) following a front-page story in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> reporting claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> had paid for sex with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. In
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> was quoted as saying, "There is no truth whatsoever in
the allegations that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirror</ENAMEX> are making against me, and
they are very hurtful." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> were
seeking a formal, categorical denial of the allegation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investiture</ENAMEX> ceremony was to go ahead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British High Commission</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombo</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
