
   
   
      
         
            Plagiarism

            An indignant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase-Riboud</ENAMEX> filed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> copyright-infringement suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amistad</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, claiming that the movie
contained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and scenes unique to her historical novel about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>
rebellion. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, she brought a similar suit against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> and won.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riboud</ENAMEX> herself of pinching
several paragraphs from a nonfiction work for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valide</ENAMEX>: A Novel
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harem</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riboud</ENAMEX> acknowledged her debt to the previously
published work, but claimed that she had done nothing wrong because the book
was a "reference" and her novel was intended to be a "seamless narrative using
both documents and fiction."

            
               When Did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borrowing Become Theft</ENAMEX>?
            

            Prior to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> borrowed freely from each other without shame or punishment.
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> word plagaria referred only to the act of physical
kidnapping.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> borrowed passages from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plutarch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>.
Books were copied by hand prior to the rise of the printing press, and
amanuenses were given liberty to rework texts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> passed the first
copyright laws in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1709</TIMEX>, as mechanical reproduction of works and new ideas about
individuality became widespread. These laws provided legal remedies for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> mainly--who believed their works had been
unfairly lifted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">U.S. Constitution</ENAMEX> required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to pass similar
copyright laws.

            Copyright laws prohibit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plagiarism</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have ruled that a work cannot be legally copied if it is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) an original, creative product--not merely a fact or something found in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>, like the sound of the wind, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) written or recorded--not just an
idea. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fifty years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> die, their works enter the "public domain" and
are no longer protected by law.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plagiarized</ENAMEX>? Prove It!
            

            Proving plagiarism in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX> to show that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> had access
to the earlier work and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>'s work bears a "substantial
similarity" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>'s original. It sounds like a legal blur because it
similarity." For example, jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard "Pretty" Purdie</ENAMEX> filed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">copyright-infringement</ENAMEX> suit against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapper</ENAMEX> who lifted a lone cymbal crash
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdie</ENAMEX>'s recordings. He claims that his cymbal crash--a single
beat--is so recognizably his that any use of it violates his copyright.

            
               When Is
Borrowing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Borrowing</ENAMEX>?
            

            Parody--as long as it is
immediately recognizable as parody--is largely exempt from charges of copyright
infringement. Also, the doctrine of "fair use" allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to quote limited
sections of a work, as long as it is germane, properly attributed, and doesn't
undercut sales of the original. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX>
exceeded its fair-use rights in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> when it excerpted key sections of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s memoir in an article that was published slightly before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s book
reached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> can be as fuzzy about what constitutes fair use as
they are about what constitutes substantial similarity.

            
               I Think
I've <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Been Plagiarized and I Wanna Sue</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are My Chances of Winning</ENAMEX>?
            

            Slim. In practice, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> find infringement only in instances where language, images, or music
were lifted wholesale. They rarely consider cases in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> was
copied or a plot was stolen. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> bring suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> claiming
their copyright has been violated, but almost none win satisfaction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> strictly police the unlicensed "sampling" of music (the
insertion of a passage into another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s musical collage). Book and
software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> are prosecuted under the copyright laws, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> are not
really plagiarists.

            
               Who's
Minding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Store</ENAMEX>?
            

            Most professional and
academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Guild of America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Association</ENAMEX>, etc.) investigate formal charges of plagiarism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reprimands</ENAMEX> can come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> or from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>
themselves. Accusations of plagiarism seem to be the greatest deterrent.

            Some say accusations of
plagiarism fly too freely. In a celebrated case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> biographer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Oates</ENAMEX> was said to have ripped off a widely read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> biography
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Thomas</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Historical Association</ENAMEX> criticized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX> for not adequately footnoting his use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' book. No legal charges
were brought. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a comparison of passages that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>
considered most damning.)

            

               Plagiarism on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Screen</ENAMEX>
            

            Most copyright suits in the
entertainment industry are nuisances, but not all. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph Hearst</ENAMEX> claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane screenwriters Orson Wells</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Mankiewicz</ENAMEX> plagiarized him. The author of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> nonfiction book about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swindlers</ENAMEX> filed copyright-infringement charges against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sting</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. Look <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's Talking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>
Heckerling was accused of stealing whole passages of dialogue from a screenplay
shown to her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> before her film's release. These cases, like most
credible suits brought against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, were settled out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            To ward off lawsuits,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> avoid signing rejection letters, making it difficult to
prove that they had prior access to the material, a legal prerequisite to prove
copyright infringement. (As a gesture of kindness, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landon</ENAMEX> signed rejection letters, some of which became the basis for expensive
litigation against him.) Still, examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s sloppiness and
disrespect for intellectual-property rights abound, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film Comment</ENAMEX>
magazine proved with this prank in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>: It shipped the screenplay of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casablanca</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 33</NUMEX> of them recognized it as the basis for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX> film; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> offered to represent it.

            

               Psychoplagiarism
            

            Many alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of
plagiarism are later accused of having plagiarized. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lodge</ENAMEX>
accused a romance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of stealing the plot from his novel <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nice Work</ENAMEX> .
Later he admitted that he had borrowed it himself from a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> novel.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Mallon</ENAMEX> argues
that plagiarism is pathology, akin to kleptomania. Accused plagiarists are
often repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Oates</ENAMEX> faced accusations of plagiarism in
his biographies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr. Poet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Bowers</ENAMEX> was plagiarized by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who submitted a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen</NUMEX> of his poems
to different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Plagiarists</ENAMEX> want to get caught . Most steal
from obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> (from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> or authoritative works). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Academics</ENAMEX>
plagiarize more regularly than nonacademics, prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallon</ENAMEX>'s theory that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> are let off the hook to plagiarize again because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
are too embarrassed to punish them.

            

               Meanwhile, Back at the Amistad Case
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase-Riboud</ENAMEX>'s suit claims
that the film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> read her historical novel about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rebellion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo of Lions</ENAMEX> , and appropriated its fictionalized characters
and plot twists. In a legal brief, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> claim that:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Credited screenwriter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Franzoni</ENAMEX> received a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo of Lions</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franzoni</ENAMEX> worked with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punch Productions</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six to eight months</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Lions</ENAMEX> Project" while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punch</ENAMEX> was licensed to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase-Riboud</ENAMEX>'s book and
helped pitch this project to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franzoni</ENAMEX>'s screenplay for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Amistad</ENAMEX> contains historical "errors" also contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions</ENAMEX>, including:

            a) a letter from Queen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Van Buren</ENAMEX>;

            b) the portrayal of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interpreter</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that speaks near-perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>; and

            c) the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinque</ENAMEX> had.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amistad</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo of Lions</ENAMEX> contain the same fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--a wealthy, erudite
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> involved with the printing of abolitionist literature.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) An early Amistad
shooting script was titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Other Lion</ENAMEX>."

            A motion to block the
opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amistad</ENAMEX> was shot down by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who
found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the similarities between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> works were not substantial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> cannot be copyrighted, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amistad</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> rendered the similarities irrelevant.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that the
suit has virtually no likelihood of success.

         
      
   
