
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap Fatigue</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here. And
if you missed the most recent installments of this column, here they are:
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 29</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept.</TIMEX>
25.
            

            Flytrap fatigue has been
spreading like wildfire across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamburger Morgenpost</ENAMEX> lighted the
flame <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of its pages blank under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Porn Interrogation: We Have Had Enough</ENAMEX>." Since then, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> newsmagazine--have signed a statement saying, "It is our profound
conviction that the intimate life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>, even if he is the president
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, does not justify this obscene official inquiry. We
therefore declare that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for which we are responsible will not, as from
today, continue to focus on aspects of the intimate life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> that
are not of obvious interest to the public."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the press has
generally failed to catch up with the idea that impeachment is becoming
increasingly unlikely. The satirical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private</ENAMEX>
Eye, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s edition, says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, like beauty, is
in the eye of the beholder." It takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Kettle</ENAMEX> and the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>'s
"resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>-baiter"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose Evans</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pritchard</ENAMEX>--and points out that "what both
papers have in common is that their reporting simply reflects their
prejudices--thus leaving the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> hopelessly confused and surprised by
every new turn of events." It takes quotations from both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' articles
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> to show, convincingly, the repeated inaccuracy of their
predictions.

            After its
final quotation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, who wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX> that "those who say
that this scandal does not rise to the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> may have to eat their
words," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Eye</ENAMEX> says, "Perhaps they could be joined on this verbal
banquet by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>." And to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kettle</ENAMEX>'s warning, issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency may be seen by future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> "as a huge historic
disappointment consisting mainly of strategic retreats in a right-wing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> and
as a catastrophic personal let-down for a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>," the
magazine adds, "And for a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> liberal hack, too?"

            The crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> figures prominently in most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nato Ready for</ENAMEX>
Strikes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>." But an editorial seemed skeptical about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will
actually do anything. It recalled that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, in his
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> warning," said that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> used force against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX>
majority, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would intervene: "Then Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> listened. But
now, although he is politically weaker, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nato</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has given
him cause to believe that the West means business."

            The visit
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> was also
the subject of much comment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Süddeutche Zeitung</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> ran an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> pointing
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schröder</ENAMEX> presented the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> with "a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Catholic Rhinelander Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> has been replaced by a northern
Protestant less likely to be sympathetic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX> was reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> press to be reassured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurances</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> will continue to pursue the same <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> policies
while extending the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> relationship to take more account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
