
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seeds of Disaster</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX>
published an op-ed article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> attacking the
proposed introduction into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> by multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> of genetically
engineered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crops</ENAMEX>. His article follows the launch of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> advertising
campaign by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based biotechnology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, arguing that such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> will help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and the environment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> said he will not eat
food made from such produce; nor will he give it to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>:
Genetic engineering "takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> into realms that belong to God and to God
alone."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> also ran an editorial warning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> against
sending ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> into action against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, saying it should
consider air power instead. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> still refuses to cede
meaningful autonomy to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, that power should be used to inflict heavy
destruction on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX>," it said.

            An editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi Shimbun</ENAMEX>
called on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to "clear up doubts" on his land mine policy. The
provocation: a statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National Security Adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Berger</ENAMEX>, in a
letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Leahy</ENAMEX>, to the effect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
intends to sign the international treaty banning land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>. "It is
significant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, one of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, has
shown--if belatedly--a willingness to join a comprehensive framework for
eliminating land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>," said the paper, wondering why such a major policy
shift should have been "made public in such an unusual form." It asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to "show a more specific course of action leading to an early
signing." Considering that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 100 million</NUMEX> anti-personnel land mines
are deposited around the world and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are being "killed or injured at a
rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>," it said, "the world cannot wait until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>."

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> ran an editorial, headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mission Fusion</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s recently revealed, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> love affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margarita Konenkova</ENAMEX>. Referring to affairs she reputedly had with other famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said, "Apparently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> with love
was a firm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in relativity in her relationships." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein "</ENAMEX>must have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pined</ENAMEX> when the affair ended and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Konenkova</ENAMEX> returned to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>, her mission
over. The parallel lines did not meet, a unified <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> could not be found."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cape Times</ENAMEX> warned
that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Africans</ENAMEX> could find themselves effectively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disenfranchised</ENAMEX> barely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> became a democracy" if the
government continues insisting that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> possess a new identity
document if they are to register as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s general election.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> Star mocked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of sport's promise to "intervene decisively" to democratize sport and
put an end to its being "a predominantly white affair in a predominantly black
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." What about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> asked in an editorial. What about the
disabled<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "They, too, should be allowed to play in the national rugby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. One
is not referring here to the mentally disabled, who are already well
represented. ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> is talking about the physically disabled. They, too, have
rights." There is also the question of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Third Sex</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> went on. "It
is disgraceful that we do not know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> are represented in
statistically correct proportions on the sportsfield."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX>, taking up
the cry of several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> papers, attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> for failing to marginalize the resurgent, racist One <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Hanson</ENAMEX>, rejects <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aboriginal</ENAMEX> rights and warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> is
being "swamped" by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>. "A return to institutionalised [immigration]
restraints and bigotry is an ever-present danger, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One Nation</ENAMEX>'s minority
support, because the larger established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> see Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanson</ENAMEX> grabbing a chunk
of their own vote," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> said. It is vital that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> "hit
back and distance his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> from her divisive and hate-mongering politics."

            Reporting on crime in
Chechnya, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s biggest-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Komsomolskaya Pravda</ENAMEX> , said
that at the central market in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>, handguns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">grenade</ENAMEX>
launchers are openly on sale. But <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shariat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>
religious law) police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>, are not. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are also waging war on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and sex, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of "love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>" sometimes hire a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mullah</ENAMEX> to sit at the entrance to pronounce every entering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>"
so as not to infringe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shariat</ENAMEX> law.

             

         
      
   
