
   
   
      
         
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghana</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stopped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at the start of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nation African</ENAMEX> tour, the
Daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graphic</ENAMEX> called this maiden visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "a
victory for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ghanaians</ENAMEX>, irrespective of political belief and social status
or other criteria." Urging "all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to take active and positive part in
welcoming our august <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>," it boasted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had
acknowledged the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s "remarkable achievements" in embracing democracy and
free market economics.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, shunned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because of its military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX> and human
rights record, the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Express</ENAMEX>, which opposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>, reported an
attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to head of state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sani</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacha</ENAMEX>. In his statement titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"No to Coercive Democracy</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alhaji Wada Nas</ENAMEX>
for saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would not accept the emergence of any military
official as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in forthcoming elections. He said that if Abacha
were to contest the elections, "he would not be violating any known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX>
law or international norm." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, he said, "needs no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to rewrite its
laws or disenfranchise its military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>." In an
editorial welcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX> urged the pontiff "to plead the cause of political and other
detainees," which he duly did.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX>, the daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Vision</ENAMEX> reported
on a government news conference before the visit, at which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Affairs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amama Mbabazi</ENAMEX> was asked if opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meet Clinton</ENAMEX>. "Not likely," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> replied. "They did not contact us." In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg Star</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that he would be
confronted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> with "a bizarre no-party system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that outlaws
political activities and stifles human rights." It added, "Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> was
the first Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to criticise the system, warning of far-reaching
regional and international consequences, the warmth demonstrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> shows considerable tolerance."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> ran an
editorial urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to offer "greater <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>-led
initiative to reduce the debt of the poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and backing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>' plans to put the money into health and education." But it also
urged him to do "some frank talking" to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> about reducing
bureaucracy, curbing corruption, and expanding privatization. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> devoted a full
page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to background on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> tour, with an article from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abidjan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory Coast</ENAMEX>, on weak <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> investment--compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> investment--in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX>. It said the limited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
presence "is explained above all by ignorance" (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>
assume--wrongly--that all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the region are as uninhabitable as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> tour <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> paragraph on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> under
the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> to forget <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sexygate</ENAMEX>."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> press was dominated by the political
pact between part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s respectable political right and the racist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Front</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Marie Le Pen</ENAMEX>, which could make <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Pen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern France</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Provence-Alpes-C√¥te d'Azur</ENAMEX>. This was deplored
in Le 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration but even more strongly in the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Observer</ENAMEX> called it "a pact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>" and a "grave danger to
democracy." In similar vein, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said,
"It is a decision of great moment not just for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> but for the whole of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> because whatever they decide, the situation is a warning of the sinister
forces which stand ready to exploit arrogant, bureaucratic and remote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> in bad economic times."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Independent published
a full-page farewell profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX>, who has
announced she will retire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 70</TIMEX>. Under the headline "A very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said that, despite her hotline to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
and her friendship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, she had not been central to
the launching of the peace process in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> but had been used "to
take the flak," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Soderberg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hume</ENAMEX> "worked away quietly" behind the scenes. "She was
always something of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loose cannon</ENAMEX>, not much given to bureaucratic niceties or
diplomatic protocols," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> added.

            On their front pages, the
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> reported respectively that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nightingale</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the swallow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> are heading toward extinction.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>,
called for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-style international intervention in natural disasters such as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> forest fires. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
Figaro of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> highlighted the world's growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> crisis, saying the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to drink will rise from the current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion to 2 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2050</TIMEX>. It reported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX>'s proposal at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> for the establishment of an
international water <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
