
   
   
      
         
            

            The suicide of the famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juzo Itami</ENAMEX>, who leapt to his death from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX>-floor
window <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, has been compared in newspapers around the world to the
death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>--to the extent that both have been seen as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> press. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s biggest-selling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, a weekly gossip magazine
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flash</ENAMEX> had been about to publish a photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itami</ENAMEX> in a
restaurant in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with whom, it said, he had been
having an affair for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itami</ENAMEX> had denied this and stated in one of
several suicide notes that "only through my death can I prove my
innocence."

            By
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coincidence</ENAMEX>, the publication of such a photograph, taken inside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on
a private occasion, would have been specifically forbidden in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> under a
tough new code of conduct agreed upon by all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in
the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>'s death. At the same time, the charge made most
memorably by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>, at her funeral in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Abbey</ENAMEX>,
that paparazzi were responsible for her death, has been implicitly
rejected by her executors, who, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of London</ENAMEX>
(quoting "senior royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>"), are preparing to sue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed al-Fayed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX>
Hotel in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $13 million</NUMEX> for allowing the hotel security man
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Paul</ENAMEX> to drive her when he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the legally permitted amount of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> in his blood.

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> news includes reports in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> that,
according to an opinion poll, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>'s annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day</TIMEX> broadcast
is expected to have its largest-ever audience <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, despite years of
declining interest; and that the names <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, those of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">princess</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, "rocketed in popularity" among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> naming
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> immediately after her death, while the popularity of the name
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> "dipped dramatically."

            Also on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> published another "princess scoop," which
reverberated around the world to almost the same extent as the one about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executors</ENAMEX>' lawsuit. This scoop was about the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monaco</ENAMEX>, who, it claimed, had been initiated into the sinister Order of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solar Temple</ENAMEX>--which was engulfed by mass murder and suicide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>--shortly before her own death in a car crash in
the south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years earlier</TIMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cult</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, a con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph di Mambro</ENAMEX>, had made her a "high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">priestess</ENAMEX>" in a ghoulish quasireligious ceremony with strong sexual undertones,
and got her to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $10 million</NUMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. "There is no mercy for
the dead," commented the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> about this story.

            
The "chicken flu" epidemic, from which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, continued to dominate the pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX>, which by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of light relief reported on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> had "reclaimed part of
its heritage" by setting the record for "the world's largest dancing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragon</ENAMEX>."
It had lost this record to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> but had got it back again by
getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,760</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> inside a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,696-meter</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragon</ENAMEX> to dance for the minimum two
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> required for inclusion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guinness Book of World Records</ENAMEX> .
The event was inaugurated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tung Chee-hwa</ENAMEX>,
who "dotted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragon</ENAMEX>'s eyes."

            Meanwhile, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Johannesburg</ENAMEX>
Star, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> banned imports of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> to keep out chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX>,
but was threatened with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> ban on its ostrich-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> exports unless it could wipe out a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">poultry disease</ENAMEX> of its own within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s
ostrich-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> imports are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leeds</ENAMEX> had sent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards to
convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> warning them they were being kept under surveillance but said
this couldn't happen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> because "the overwhelming number of those
qualified to receive such cards would make the cost prohibitive."

            The
Star published another editorial about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Congress</ENAMEX> convention, at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> attacked the
foot-dragging of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in a speech. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said this speech
would be taken by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> as evidence that he was "hungry for power,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-serving</ENAMEX> and determined that the interests of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> should prevail."
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX> had supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
responsible economic policy; rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie Mandela</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>;
reaffirmed the principle of "non-racialism"; and, "unusually for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>,"
presided over a smooth transfer of power from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thabo Mbeki</ENAMEX>. These, it
said, were all "real advances."

            An investigation carried out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> newspaper
Corriere della
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sera</ENAMEX> revealed that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jalandhar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Punjab</ENAMEX>, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 10 to 12</TIMEX> were
engaged in what is virtually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor, sewing leather footballs printed with
the legend "Guaranteed produced without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor" for export to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> published an attack on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of emigrants," for its reluctance to assimilate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> into its own territory. New <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary McAleese</ENAMEX>, it
reported, had told her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> that they had a duty to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>
the same welcome that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">emigrants</ENAMEX> had always received abroad, but despite
this, their hostility to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> was increasing. The problem wasn't large,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said, for in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 4,000</NUMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> entered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of them from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX>. But the number was still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> times
higher than that of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only five years ago</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
