
   
   
      
         
            Crime <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Punishment</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
urged a "yes" vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> referendums, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republic</ENAMEX>, on the political settlement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulster</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>, reporting a resurgence in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ulster Protestant</ENAMEX> support for the
agreement, said in an editorial: "Yes gives a chance--a good chance--for peace and
stability. No leads back to despair and violence." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Independent</ENAMEX> carried an
editorial page article by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertie Ahern</ENAMEX>
appealing strongly for a yea vote. "The good reputation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> will be
immeasurably enhanced, if we can cast off the negative impression of conflict,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has pointed out," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahern</ENAMEX> said.

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said
in an editorial that, although "there are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand devils</NUMEX> in the details" of
the agreement, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> should accept the convenient rather than insist on
the perfect: they should vote 'yes.' " The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also warned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> that "he must stand by his pledge that there will be
no fudge between democracy and terror." If he fails to insist on the
decommissioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> before paramilitaries could hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> assembly, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> will "be entitled to walk away from an
agreement which Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> had dishonoured." The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , which is
strongly supportive of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulster Unionists</ENAMEX>, highlighted the agreement's
weaknesses and, while not recommending a "no" vote, said in an editorial that
if a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Unionists</ENAMEX> were to vote negative, their decision should be
respected. "Let no one outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulster</ENAMEX> dare accuse them of bigotry or
belligerence," it said. "In voting No, they too will be expressing their desire
for peace, and their sorrowful belief that it is not, in reality, on
offer."

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> resigned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, a commentary
written just beforehand by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Beck</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> response to
the crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> had been "so low-key some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> believe it to be
almost non-existent." The main reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s great caution, he
explained, was that following the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> threat, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' present "biggest headache is that the collapse of a major trading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> will cause a domino effect across the world's economies."

            As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
prepared to hold talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> with that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, the paper <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> reported that a
Pakistani parliamentary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> is also going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> but that "no one
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> side has any idea of what they are going to do or
say to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>." Predicting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>
would be subjected to continuous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cross-examination about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s
nuclear intentions, an unidentified "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> there that they should have chosen a better time to
come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "on a junket."

            "Why to
spoil the fun they want to have at this time when every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> wants to know
what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> is doing," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> said. "And if they want to know what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are doing, sadly the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do not know it themselves." In an
op-ed piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> Finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahbubul Haq</ENAMEX> said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, which for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 10 years</TIMEX> has "suffered the wrath of the
global community on the nuclear issue," should now "make the international
community ashamed of itself through its nuclear restraint and ensure that it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> that is treated as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">pariah nation</ENAMEX>."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan Chronicle of India</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has overreacted
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear tests with a punishment that is not merely heavy but also
"rather vengeful." In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, it said there was "an element of
contradiction" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s current policy of unleashing all
permissible sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> while offering "every gift in its
possession" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to stop it carrying out nuclear tests in retaliation.
If his aim was to prevent a nuclear confrontation between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
then "the same purpose would obviously be achieved by allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to
conduct the tests so that the principle of mutual nuclear deterrence would
automatically come into force and nuclear confrontation can be ruled out for
ever." "However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> obviously wants to establish the point that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the global disarmanent movement," it said.

            In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of the Philippines</ENAMEX> said that "the imagery of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom cloud</ENAMEX>, the ticking clock--has suddenly re-entered the public
consciousness once more as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, in full view of the world, conducted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
nuclear tests and then proceeded to declare itself a nuclear weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."
The editorial described <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> as "an overpopulated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a fractious,
hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, an unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> hatred with its
neighbours" and said "the world has good reason to be nervous" about that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s new nuclear capabilities. "It looks like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the bad old days</TIMEX> are back
again," it concluded.

             

         
      
   
