
   
   
      
         

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arlington National</ENAMEX>
Cemetery, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most hallowed</TIMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial ground</ENAMEX> ," was born
in an act of theft: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> confiscated it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX> from Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Lee</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Custis Lee</ENAMEX>, after he took command of the army
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Virginia</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> dead buried there was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pvt. William</ENAMEX>
Christman, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regiment</ENAMEX> who saw as much combat as did
now-disgraced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Larry Lawrence</ENAMEX>-- none .

            Of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX> national cemeteries , only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> is administered
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Army</ENAMEX>. All the rest fall under the jurisdiction of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> contains the remains of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240,000</NUMEX>
dead . It also contains several monuments, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tomb of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unknowns and the Tomb of the Unknown Dead</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, the latter a
granite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX> that holds the remains of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,111</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. There are also
monuments honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the failed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> rescue
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX>, the slain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the space shuttle
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> mission, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rough Riders</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> (its mast was salvaged from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> and brought to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>).

            
"The event that thrust us into the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spotlight</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>," says cemetery
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superintendent John C. Metzler Jr.</ENAMEX> Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> was assassinated, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six months</TIMEX> following the assassination, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 million</NUMEX> came, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> was attracting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            "Requests for burials rose
by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">400 percent</NUMEX>" following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s televised burial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> continues. As
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late as 1967</TIMEX>, any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> with an honorable discharge was eligible for
burial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> had only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s worth of plots in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reserve</ENAMEX>. To conserve space, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> adopted new eligibility rules that
made the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> a more exclusive --and therefore more
attractive --address for the dead.

            Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> remains the prestigious address , any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> with an honorable
discharge automatically qualifies for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial</ENAMEX>--with military honors--in one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> cemeteries.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> reported the
arcane rules currently in effect for who can be buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>:

            
               Military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who
died on active duty;
            

            
               The heavily decorated,
including those who won the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Medal of Honor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distinguished Service Cross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Cross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Distinguished Service Medal, Silver Star, or Purple</ENAMEX>
Heart;
            

            
               Long timers with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of active duty or active reserve service who qualify for retired pay upon
retirement at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 60</TIMEX>;
            

            
               Those retired for
disability reasons;
            

            

               Those honorably discharged before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 1949</TIMEX>, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 30</NUMEX>-percent
disability.
            

            
The other rules read like the fine print on an
insurance policy:

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> or unmarried
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> or younger) of those listed above or those already buried in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unmarried</ENAMEX> dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> qualifies before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 23</TIMEX>, as does any
adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who acquired a physical or mental disability before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21</TIMEX>;
            

            
               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of an eligible person
already interred. Interment must be in the same grave as the primary eligible,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> must waive his or her eligibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> can have no dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at the time of death.
            

            Those not
eligible include:

            
               The remarried
widower/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of an eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, unless he/she is no longer married at
death;
            

            
               Those
whose last discharge was less than honorable.
            

            
After adopting the new eligibility rules, the
government established a waiver system for exceptions granted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, or by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> or high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Togo West</ENAMEX> has granted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> exceptions since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1993</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High-ranking Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have granted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> during that time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has granted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> granted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> exceptions
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> exceptions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> exceptions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. West explains that the
increased demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> plots helps account for the record number of
waivers he has approved.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
apparently lied about having served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merchant Marine</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> II. (Besides, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merchant Marine</ENAMEX> is not a part of the armed forces.) Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> who did not serve in the military but are buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>
anyway: Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations John A. Scali</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold L. Raphel</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>; he died in an air crash while serving as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoys</ENAMEX> who received burial waivers but did serve
in the military: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William R. Rivkin</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleo A. Noel Jr.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip K.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowe</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolph A. Dubs</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> waivers: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurgood Marshall</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvera Burger</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Burger</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Enforcement</ENAMEX>
Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.W. Seale</ENAMEX>, killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> while on a mission; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry J. Daly</ENAMEX>, killed in a
shootout.

            
While not a secret, the waiver program is
not publicized , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">West</ENAMEX> has acknowledged. He outlined the waiver
rules in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> press conference. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassadors</ENAMEX> who die in office merit
consideration for a space in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>. Cemetery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metzler</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that he would have recommended a waiver for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> , "given the fact he died in office" and was "serving actively in a
post at the time of his death." Also qualifying under waivers are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are "killed in the course of their service to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," those who have performed "unique service" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reservists</ENAMEX> who die while on active duty for training. "Humanitarian
concerns " for the family requesting an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> burial are also
acknowledged, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">West</ENAMEX>, citing a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who didn't automatically
qualify under the rules but whom he would have waived in, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuskegee</ENAMEX> airman
who had flown <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> combat flights.

            Waiver requests often are
forwarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> and the secretary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> from members
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> , although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> can make the requests directly. Because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> have a short shelf life, the decisions are made quickly.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> issued an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>
waiver-in-advance for former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Everett Koop</ENAMEX> , who is
still alive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to have been so honored.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">612 acres</NUMEX> will be filled with
corpses by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX> if the rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> burials a day continues. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> gravesite can hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> caskets. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> burials
approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> were in existing graves.

            There is plenty of room for
cremains: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> added a columbarium in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>; it accepts the cremated
remains of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who received an honorable discharge.

            The
cemetery overlooks the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Potomac River</ENAMEX> and has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 14,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> . Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graves</ENAMEX> are marked with simple tombstones. The major exception:
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> Section, which is crowded with lavish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX> . These stone angels, huge crosses, marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cannonballs</ENAMEX>--and even a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cannon</ENAMEX>--were paid for by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> had buried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 7,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> estate by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX>, deliberately planting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tombstones</ENAMEX> in Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s rose
garden right up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>'s back door. After the war, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">freedmen</ENAMEX>'s
village was established on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX>, and included a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, a
school, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 3,800</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> are buried at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> under headstones that say either "civilian" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX>
expansion , which pushed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">freedmen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> out, may also claim a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24-acre</NUMEX> plot of woods around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The parcel would add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>'
worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">burial space</ENAMEX>. Also eyed for annexation is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Myer</ENAMEX>, adjacent
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, and a parcel owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>,
sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX> for the return of the family estate. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> upheld his claim, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> paid him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX> for
it. The general never returned to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX>. He is buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lee Chapel</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
