
   
   
      
         
            

            Here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX>, and indeed
in the whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, and it normally
consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> thin pages, except when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> makes a speech, at which
time the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s paper shortage is momentarily overlooked. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granma</ENAMEX> , the official organ of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>, named for that overcrowded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> crossed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> it is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebelde</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Rebel Youth"</ENAMEX>)
and run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union of Young</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> it is called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trabajadores</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX>") and run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> trade union movement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebelde</ENAMEX> is said to have a rather lighter touch than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granma</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trabajadores</ENAMEX> to be even grimmer, but the editorial lines of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
are identical, handed down by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> himself. For a brief period, these papers
were printed on recycled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX>, but this gave them the texture and color
of a stiff brown paper bag and was abandoned in favor of recycled paper. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granma</ENAMEX> announced on its front page that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Festival for the Recycling of Primary Materials</ENAMEX>" would be shown live on
television from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</TIMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granma</ENAMEX> is one of the few traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> left in
the world, imbued with irrepressible optimism about the prospects for the sugar
harvest and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> economy in general as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> limps along in the
economic misery that it calls, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s insistence, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Period</ENAMEX> in
Peacetime." Among several cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> stories in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few days</TIMEX> was one
accentuating the positive aspect of recent flooding in the countryside. While
this would set back the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> harvest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granma</ENAMEX> said, it would also make
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX> easier to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>.

            Favorite topics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> are, of course, the
shortcomings of capitalism in general and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in particular, with
much attention paid to racism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, violence and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX>
stories included a full-pager <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Once Again Cuba Doesn't</ENAMEX>
Lie," about a belated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> admission in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Willard Ray</ENAMEX>, shot down over
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter bomber</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>, was on a covert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> mission. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kept Ray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> deep-frozen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years before</TIMEX> allowing it to be sent home for
burial. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's the CIA Again</ENAMEX>," Granma
reprinted from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ecuadorian</ENAMEX> newspaper an article accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> of murder,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torture</ENAMEX>, state terrorism, and other crimes.

            Since the
airing on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> television of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> documentary on the threat to the
world of a wandering asteroid, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granma</ENAMEX> has been obsessed with the
asteroid danger, which it accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of understating. This week
it supported <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>' predictions of "apocalyptic collisions" in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 2004, 2006</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s reassuring one that the world should
survive until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 2028</TIMEX>.

            
Granma regularly makes favorable comparisons
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s human rights record and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>'. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy has been
determined by wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ideas about political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>, it maintains.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Saturday</TIMEX>, its main front page headline read: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The First Human Right Is the</ENAMEX>
Right to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live as a Human Being</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> Will <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Continue Fighting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resisting</ENAMEX>, and
Winning for as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long as Necessary</ENAMEX>." (Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granma</ENAMEX> 's front page has
led, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days in a row</TIMEX>, with the activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> of the visiting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Kitts, Denzil Douglas</ENAMEX>.)

            An
ancient alleged example of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> contempt for human rights was the dispersal in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> identical <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, triplets to see how they would
grow up separately. This story was published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Granma</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> under
the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monstrous Experiment</ENAMEX>." The lifting by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of some
of its anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> restrictions was reported briefly by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granma</ENAMEX> on an
inside page and was the subject of no editorial comment either then or
subsequently.

            Granma boasted on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>'s front page that the
Web site of its international
edition--this is published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX>--has been visited by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX>, a surge of
interest it attributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and the return of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guevara</ENAMEX>'s bones from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolivia</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also deplored the "cultural
domination" of the Internet by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Granma</ENAMEX> specializes in historical anniversaries, finding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to celebrate
almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, even if sometimes on a date that is fairly distant from the
real <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few days</TIMEX>, it has published long articles on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the death
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> underground; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a speech made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 years ago</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Maceo</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angola</ENAMEX>; and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">95 th</NUMEX> birthday of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julio Mella</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>.

            
It has a weekly medical advice column, of which
the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> have been pancreatitis and optical neuritis, and an
occasional books column that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, discussed a book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immortal Body</ENAMEX> , an anthology of erotic letters, in a review that began,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexuality</ENAMEX>, sensuality, passion, and pleasure have always been the main
preoccupation of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> publishes just
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> letter a week from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, always with an editorial riposte at the
bottom. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s was from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and had to do with the desperate attempts
that she and her fiance made to find somewhere to eat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX>. They tried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a half-dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and pizza
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parlors</ENAMEX> and found them variously full, out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, closed for lack of water
for washing up, and charging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-eighth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>'s salary for a single <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>.
But they persevered, she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and optimistic" in their search, until
they were finally allowed by a packed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> to eat their dinner off the
floor. They were lucky enough, she said, to find a bus quickly and be back home
in time to watch the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> movie.

            The comment at the bottom of
this letter said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> had decided to omit the names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
concerned, "because they wouldn't be known by respectable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside the
neighborhood," and made no comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> they lacked. Instead it
congratulated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> on the courage and optimism that had enabled them in
the end to triumph: "You got home in time to see the film, so it really wasn't
such <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad day</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
