
   
   
      
         
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press was
dominated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by the divisions within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, especially the
breach between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. "It is embarrassing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to note that
it is closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in this crisis than to its principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. "A common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> foreign and security policy will have to wait. After
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> has now publicly
given his support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> strategy on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, spectacularly separating
himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> mentioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> opposed to military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s leading newspaper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, said in an editorial that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s position was not yet
clear. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> paying his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, it said, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should make up its mind. "What should it tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>," it asked, "bearing in mind on the one hand its alliance with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but on the other hand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s declared position against bombing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, the widespread appeals for peace by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, and
furthermore the still strong resentment over the tragedy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavalese</ENAMEX> [the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> disaster in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolomites</ENAMEX>]?" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s conclusion: It should come
down unequivocally on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side or the other.

            In an
interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere</ENAMEX> , on the eve of his visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> said he rejected the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> world hegemony. "I must say that
any attempt by any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to impose a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, let alone its own rule, on
the world is unrealistic and even dangerous," he said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> led with a
story
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> "seemed to back down ... from
his earlier appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> not to retaliate in the event of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> attack"
by saying that " 'Israel obviously has the right of self-defense and will
exercise that right as they see fit.' " In an editorial,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> expressed alarm over popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> support for the idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, even if this was not endorsed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. This suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> were not interested in
negotiating peace on any terms. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> need to be convinced that the peace
process is not just about land for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, but also peace for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> concluded.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>, the newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Qabas</ENAMEX> said that
the only worthwhile objective for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> from power. "A resolution to this crisis, whether diplomatic or
military, will only push the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> toward more tension, and will only increase
the suffering of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if it does not take into consideration the
need to topple the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Qabas</ENAMEX> said. "It is not possible to change
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>'s attitude. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deceit</ENAMEX> and the evil intentions are too deeply rooted in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahrain Tribune</ENAMEX>
led on a statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulent Ecevit</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> objective in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was to set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and
to control the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> said this statement reflected "a drastic change in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
official policy towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis." Having started out neutral, Ecevit
had subsequently decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s best interests in dealing with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> threat from northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> would be better served by closer
collaboration with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>. "That is why they [the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>] do not want either the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
to further weaken <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>'s grip on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said. It also
stated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> were now reconciled with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> and opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
air strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and that there was therefore little danger of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> flooding into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> continued to be the subject of widespread
discussion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press, which showed particular interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s
proposal--supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--for a worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> of center-left
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> led by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Labor Party</ENAMEX>. But it took
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Deedes</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84-year-old</TIMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> and
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, to notice what he called "a sartorial curiosity" at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> banquet for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blairs</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wore a wing
collar with his black tie, which used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> style," he wrote in his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> column. "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>, less formally, wore an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX> shirt with a turned down collar, a style introduced to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>."

            A one-sentence letter to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> from an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Hooper</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nottingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>: "Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> speaks on
behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, should it not be a fully paid-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>?"

         
      
   
