
   
   
      
         
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irish Eyes Are Smiling</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> gave an
unqualified welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. Editorials dwelt not on his
personal troubles but on his contribution to peace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulster</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
Independent called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "an invaluable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>" and said that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foolishness</ENAMEX> in his personal life "does not justify the persecution to which he
has been subjected," nor take away from his achievements as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "Among
these, his role in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> affairs ranks high," it said. "His interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
is not sentimental, or designed merely to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> votes and the
friendship of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. It is intelligent, well-informed--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fruitful</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, who was described in the main front-page headline as
"radiant," received high praise from conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kenny</ENAMEX>, who said that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "would probably fully agree that in terms of strength of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is the better of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX>, republican
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Holland</ENAMEX> wrote that even before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ulster</ENAMEX>, his
"visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> has had a dramatic effect." Saying she shared "the sense of
disappointment and bewilderment" over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair and the bombings in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX> said she also believed "there are very many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> alive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, and further afield, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> who would be dead were it
not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s commitment to the search for peace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>."

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belfast Telegraph</ENAMEX> said that "the mere fact of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">presence</ENAMEX> ...
has achieved more progress in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two days</TIMEX> than in the previous two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> election." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic Ulster</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> said in its main
front-page headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> flies in with a brave message of hope."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> summit received less enthusiastic press around
the world, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novye Isvestiya</ENAMEX> said that although "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
did not have much space for maneuvering between support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and
instructing potential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>," everything that he did
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> was "correct." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> controlled by
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>, reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Institute of</ENAMEX>
Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> would show, in research to be published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
faces inevitable bankruptcy and that, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> at the latest, it
will have to admit it can't make payments on its foreign debts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> strongly criticized the
summit because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s request that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> sever its defense links with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> need not take this too seriously, because it
is "just one of several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> skins the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> dropped and stepped on in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>
said, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is not known for his adherence to commonly accepted norms of
behaviour, either in his personal conduct or in terms of international policy,"
noting that "nothing was right about the summit, least of all its timing."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>,
Corriere della
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sera</ENAMEX> ran an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX>,
who, asked if the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> had made mistakes in its behavior toward post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, said it had made several: regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> as the sole guarantor of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> democracy, trying to impose economic policies that were completely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsuited</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and closing both eyes to the corruption of the system. "I
sometimes think that the West prefers a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> that is weak and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-wrecked--not actually in pieces but nevertheless not in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to raise
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> said.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainichi Shimbun</ENAMEX>
predicted "significant repercussions" for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s firing of
a long-range ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Monday</TIMEX>. It criticized the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for its slow response and its delayed release of
information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. "In cooperation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> and other concerned parties, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must adopt a
resolute posture toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> while demanding that it terminate its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ballistic</ENAMEX> missile program," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> concluded.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX>, published an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tetsuo Maeda</ENAMEX>, an arms control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo International University</ENAMEX>, saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> missile
attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist targets</ENAMEX> have expanded the definition of war. They
will "be remembered as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case in which a permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX>, which has special responsibilities for the maintenance of
'international peace and security,' has openly applied the 'state's right of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>' to irregular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maeda</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terrorists</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and
should be treated as such. However, they should not be punished without due
process in the name of 'national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">security</ENAMEX>' or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'protection</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' lives.'
In light of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history, such punishment is virtually a return to the lynching
that was practised during the frontier development period."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> also reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese National Personnel Authority</ENAMEX> is
drawing up regulations to try to stamp out sexual harassment based on a new
report defining what kind of behavior is "inappropriate." It said, "Such
behavior ranges from demanding sex from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> to forcing female office
staff to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> or to clean the workplace." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ogling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> or forcing
female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to sit beside their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> at social events is also
unacceptable. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]omen mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> by calling into question their masculinity
is also classified as sexual harassment," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added.

             

         
      
   
