
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forgive</ENAMEX> and Forget?

            The dress, the dress. Hold
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> for the dress. I'll get to it later.

            First, the new Flytrap
motto, brought to you by kindly inquisitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>: "We are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forgiving people</ENAMEX>."

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap II</ENAMEX> enters <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Week II</ENAMEX>, it is segueing gracefully into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage of
scandal: The initial glee of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> has matured into thoughtful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magnanimity</ENAMEX>. The sound of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> baying for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> has subsided. If
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s theme was high dudgeon, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s will be high-mindedness. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' new strategy seems to be: (Possibly) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forgive</ENAMEX> and (Maybe)
Forget.

            The strategy, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> hinted at over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, seems to go like this:

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is trapped, and everyone else is embarrassed. The only remedy is a
presidential mea culpa (or rather, since the ones pushing the
culpa are not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who would actually apologize, a tua
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">culpa</ENAMEX> ). If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admits his affair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
public, explains that he lied to protect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and apologizes
with sufficient breadth and--this is important--abjectness, then, well, we'll
probably forgive him and call off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatch</ENAMEX>
said that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> (who would supervise
impeachment proceedings) are inclined to be forgiving (unless, of course, there
is evidence of other high crimes). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, he implied, could also be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">big-hearted</ENAMEX>.

            
Any time I find myself agreeing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatch</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> I grab my wallet, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX> in me says this magnanimity
may have been arrived at only after much jujitsu with public opinion polls. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forgive</ENAMEX> and Forget strategy has this virtue for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>: It is the only way
they're going to win a clean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> victory. The polls are impossible for them.
Surveys have been jiggered and rejiggered to find some way, any way, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would back impeachment. No luck. The best effort so far was a
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> poll that found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--up
from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>!--would favor holding impeachment hearings if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had an affair and perjured himself. This is a number made absurd by the
fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> rise is hardly a tidal wave; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) in no universe is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
percent a majority; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) impeachment hearings are not impeachment; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) similar
polls registered impeachment support at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>. This does not
a winning issue make.

            The only
poll that I've heard about that makes any sense, which may be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
is reading, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> survey (I think) saying that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would clear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> if he makes a clean breast of it.

            Whether they've reached their conclusion for cynical or
idealistic reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Co.</ENAMEX> do seem to have hit on the only solution to
this mess, the only outcome that will punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> adequately, satisfy his
persecutors enough to quiet them, and save us from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two more years</TIMEX> of this
horror. (All this assumes the allegations are true. Insert usual caveats here:
"till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>," "DNA testing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>," "unreliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>," etc.)

            Why would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> agree to
apologize?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) It would shock no one and
disappoint few to find out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> did have an affair despite
his earlier claims.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has the rhetorical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX> to pull off such an apology in a way that doesn't seem phony (he'll blame
it on his own big heart, his fierce desire not to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>).

            And most
important: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) An apology cuts off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigations at the knees. Without
an apology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is doomed to enervating, fratricidal, interminable
impeachment hearings. An apology would prevent them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> investigation
is the only part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s work that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> a) understands and b) actually
cares about. Would an admission of lying about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica weaken Clinton</ENAMEX>'s claims
in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> matters? I doubt it. After a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mea culpa</ENAMEX> , the public or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are unlikely to muster much enthusiasm for chasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dull</ENAMEX>, impenetrable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thickets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater, Travelgate</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX>. Even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> decide later that they don't actually forgive and forget, it may be
too late. An apology could wipe away all the scandals but campaign finance.

            
There is no sign yet that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tempted by mea culpa/ Forgive</ENAMEX> and Forget. All leaks out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is sticking to his denial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX>, the
closest thing to an official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> who is talking, deflected the idea of an
apology when quizzed about it. But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> isn't buying, its
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are matching <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> big heart for big heart. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, has suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
should 'fess up if he had an affair, as has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> all but implored his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> to cut his losses and
apologize.

            Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> come
around? If I were a betting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, I would wager that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, other
prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>--as they did when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hesitated over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
subpoena--will make increasingly obvious pleas for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to apologize. And,
unless the dress is a red (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX> blue) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>, I would wager that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will
listen. Surely he's willing to tarnish the legacy he cares so much about in
order to save his presidency.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>: more on the
dress.

         
      
   
