
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Exclusive</ENAMEX>

            The grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> are not the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. I present
a scoop--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, audible statement: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can</ENAMEX> I put a phone in
here? Is that OK<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
            

            More
later on how I collected this tidbit. First, an exegesis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> asked these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX> manning the X-ray machine at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> door.
They are not, admittedly, gripping remarks. They are not, sadly, a muttered
"I'm going to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Schmucko</ENAMEX>!" Still, let's milk these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> words for
all they're worth.

            First, a critical question of interpretation: From my sense
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> language and tone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> was clearly checking to make sure the
phone would not disturb the X-ray machine. She was not asking whether
the X-ray would damage the phone. She was not, in short, making a selfish,
materialistic inquiry.

            That
settled, what do we glean from her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sentences? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is the kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has a cell phone; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is deferential to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is not feeling too confident. She didn't need to ask "Is that OK<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question sufficed, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> felt so unsure that she asked the second
question.

            
The more revealing aspect of her comments: her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>, which has remained a tantalizing mystery. From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> paces down a corridor,
it sounded like the voice of a typical educated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, with none of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> stupidity or helium-squeakiness it has been rumored to
have.

            This
analysis is, of course, an absurd exercise, but no more absurd than anything
else about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s testimony, this is the biggest day in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> since the scandal broke. But it is also a pointless day--or at least a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">pointless morning</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have called a press conference for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>, after my deadline.) Every camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, and newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gathered on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pennsylvania Avenue</ENAMEX> knows, to a nearly perfect certainly,
that we will report nothing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> has assembled to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> get out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, open a courthouse door, walk <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 feet</NUMEX> down a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corridor</ENAMEX>, and disappear. Something momentous may be happening in the grand jury
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX> but, as far as news goes, it is a complete vacuum. No matter<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Her</ENAMEX>
presence makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> the undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of the media
world.

            Ifigure that if I'm going to be part of a pointless media
frenzy, I might as well do it right. So I have arrived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m.</TIMEX> to scope the scene. I am not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. A gaggle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists camps</ENAMEX> by
the side door. Why? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> words: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The List</ENAMEX>." The List, which holds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> names,
filled as soon as it was opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and other outlets
have pulled all-nighters to protect their spots. (A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newsday reporter</ENAMEX>
arrives at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30</TIMEX> in hope of getting Listed. As he tries vainly to cajole the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marshal</ENAMEX>, another newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gloats, "He's totally screwed.")

            In fact,
the List is a dubious honor, an excellent example of the pathetic running
battle between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flytrap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flytrap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The Flytrap
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are winning: The List entitles you to stand in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> outside the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury room</ENAMEX> (everyone else must wait on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>).
Listees may not eat, drink, or sit down. They may not speak to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. They cannot even see anyone enter or leave the grand jury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Holloway Johnson</ENAMEX> has installed partitions to block the
view. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Listees</ENAMEX> have been reduced to staring at the shiny marble walls in
hopes of seeing the reflection of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>.

            
By <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, the rabble has arrived. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel 11</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX> I count <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> TV trucks
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> TV cameras. Because no one knows where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> will arrive, the cameras
cover every line of sight to every courthouse door. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> has even mounted a
camera on a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">picker</ENAMEX> to get a better shot of the most likely entrance. A
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse plaza</ENAMEX> lights up like a fairyland: All the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> are bathed in TV light as they begin delivering their
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning spiels.</TIMEX>

            As I
watch this, I am waylaid by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two wispy</NUMEX>-bearded, chin-pierced college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jimi</ENAMEX>. They are interns from the local alternative rock radio station, sent
to make trouble. They hand me a phone, where I find myself live on the air. I
sputter through an interview with the disc jockey. They start chanting into a
megaphone behind me: "If you can't find the sperm, let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worm</ENAMEX> finish his
term!" and other, less printable, rhymes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jimi</ENAMEX> are the only street
theater going, but the cameras ignore them.

            By <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, a few of us have adjourned to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> in anticipation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s arrival. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> spreads the
latest unsubstantiated rumor: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> had a breakdown <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and won't be
testifying. False: A couple of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later, cell phone reports say she has
left the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 15</NUMEX> of us are waiting inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>. The TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have stayed outside, because cameras are banned, and others haven't
arrived yet, because they don't expect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9</TIMEX>. Too bad for them.

            A guard
shoos us well back from the door where she will enter, and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:25</TIMEX> a black
sport utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> pulls up outside the glass door. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> gets out first
and opens the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> door. She is wearing a blue suit--not quite navy blue,
but a bit closer to that notorious color than I would have chosen--and white
pumps and is carrying a white purse. She looks neither relaxed nor nervous.

            
It is weird, inexplicably weird, to see her in
the flesh. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> of us, who had been talking loudly, fall into a spooky
silence when she opens the door. (It is during this quiet that I hear her two
questions.) The silence continues for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX> till she walks around the
corner and disappears into a closed back corridor, followed by her legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.
At that point the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> break ranks, some sprinting up the stairs, some
(like me) clambering into an elevator in hopes of seeing her enter the grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury room</ENAMEX>. No such luck. She's inside and hidden, and there's nothing more to
see.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courthouse</ENAMEX> is not the only political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> this morning. After
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica vanishes</ENAMEX>, I stroll to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> spectacle.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>, who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Government Reform</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversight</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, the force behind the campaign finance investigation, and an
all-around nutter, wants his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> for
contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> claims, is breaking the law by refusing a
subpoena for confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> reports about the campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> investigation. The contempt measure is expected to pass but,
appropriately for this theatrical day, it is a theatrical gesture: The full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is highly unlikely to approve such an inflammatory action.

            The contempt scheme is such a stupid, vicious, wrongheaded
idea that it is a joy to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Waxman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandstand</ENAMEX> against it. "For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> we have seen this committee
systematically demean and abuse almost every tool of congressional
investigations. ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, you are demeaning perhaps the most
serious power we have--the power of contempt," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waxman</ENAMEX> announces to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, our actions
will be added to the growing list of travesties that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has
inflicted on the oversight and congressional process. We have made a shambles
of any pretense of seriousness and dignity.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> seems to relish
every fight and go out of his way to provoke every imaginable showdown. What
does it accomplish? Nothing. Any fight, of course, attracts some media
attention. But are we doing anything of consequence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? No."

            And that, I suppose, is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s moral.

         
      
   
