
   
   
      
         
            End of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>?

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> press was
indecently jubilant in its response to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s rebuff to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> negotiations.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu Humiliates Clinton</ENAMEX>," shrieked the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration on its front page,
picking out the word "humiliates" in red. The headline on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Offense Done</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>" and on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America Struck</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powerlessness</ENAMEX>." An editorial said that "the long premeditated snub inflicted on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is particularly revealing of the inability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to get itself listened to, even by its closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lib√©ration</ENAMEX> said "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> imperialism" is no longer what it used to be: "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s last Superpower" is "forced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>" to recognize "the relativity" of
its power. "This phenomenon of insubordination" is exacerbated by "the relative
isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," which enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to
"play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> openly against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>," the editorial went on. "Only a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with a clear vision of the world--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> both convinced and
convincing--would have had any chance of imposing himself."

            In
similar vein, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> paper Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu Defies Clinton</ENAMEX>." Next to that story was an editorial titled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Powerlessness</ENAMEX>." This declared that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> ran no
risks when he refused to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to talk peace, because "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is incapable of punishing his insolence as, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> before the midterm
congressional elections, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is disarmed." His <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> know that to appear to be campaigning against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is the surest way
to lose the elections, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said. "Politically weakened by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interminable</ENAMEX> inquiry into his escapades, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> cannot permit himself to
open a new front," it added.

            There was a striking contrast between the attention paid in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> problem and the lack of interest in it in the rest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, which has its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basque</ENAMEX> separatist problem, was far more
interested in the vote by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> and the IRA to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ulster</ENAMEX> peace
agreement, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> devoted a front-page story and its main editorial--titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"An End to All</ENAMEX>
or Nothing"--to the subject <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√≠s</ENAMEX> did, however,
carry a piece from its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">regards Israel</ENAMEX>'s "intransigence" as a threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were still
dominated by the political fallout from the mudslide tragedy in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were buried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> only on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> for a story about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
friendship in crisis." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>'s angle on the story was fear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> that
the peace negotiations are effectively at an end. "For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> it has
been customary to say that the peace talks are blocked, paralyzed, in grave
danger, moribund," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. "Since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> there has been a strong temptation to say that they are dead and not
worth talking about any more."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> also discussed a new report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> situation by
the veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arrigo Levi</ENAMEX>, who, after conducting
high-level interviews throughout the region, concluded that the loss of all
hope by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> could lead to a new "catastrophic" war in
which biological and chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> might be used. In one of the interviews,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Israel Martin Indyk</ENAMEX> said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of extremism are
destroying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> partnership." He was quoted as saying that
the window of opportunity created by the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and the
results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> is now closing. "To the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Left</ENAMEX>, which asks us to
intervene to save <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> from itself, we answer that it is not for us to
intervene," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indyk</ENAMEX> reportedly added. "If something is close to your heart, then
it is for you to do it, not us."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the front-page
lead in the conservative English-language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> said a "yet-to-be-detailed compromise"
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Ross</ENAMEX> makes a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> summit this
month among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a "near certainty." But the leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>, in an op-ed piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akiva Eldar</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> administration
is debating only "when to set zero hour" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>: after his address in
convention; or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>--by summoning him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>,
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is attending the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G7</NUMEX> economic summit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press has been
dominated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> by the crisis threatening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> over claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Foreign Office</ENAMEX> secretly encouraged a private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to help overthrow the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">junta</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>, in
contravention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions against that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">west African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s job
on the line in arms row," said the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. In an
editorial, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> complained about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s reluctance
to celebrate "the West's greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> victory: the breaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blockade</ENAMEX>," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is marking with a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
The airlift, it said, had been "conceived, directed and largely carried out by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Air Force</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> reported on
its front page that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s anti-riot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have been ordered "to shoot to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cripple</ENAMEX> rather than kill" in clashes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX>. Quoting a military manual
leaked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon leaders</ENAMEX> have been
authorized to use live ammunition "in self-defense to cripple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX> who are
clearly threatening to kill others [or to] cause heavy material damage." If
this doesn't work, it added, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon commander</ENAMEX> has the authority "to proceed
with actions he deems appropriate."

             

         
      
   
