
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Carpet</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Il Gazzettino</ENAMEX> reported
on its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 4-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who had seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
cartoon film of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aladdin</ENAMEX> many times on television had thrown herself out
of her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> window on a blanket believing she would be able to
fly. She was miraculously unhurt when she landed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">legged</NUMEX> sitting position. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, who lived with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in a
village on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Como</ENAMEX>, was of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> origin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX>
said in its main editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>
"may survive in office far longer than anyone initially expected." While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> would not be deterred from trying to bring down another unpopular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> even by threats of military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, "there is no longer the strong
national consensus that existed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> immediately prior to Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s
downfall." "Having originally been written off as a stop-gap solution, the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> seems to have acquired a surprisingly firm grip on the reins of
power," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> observed. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
in an editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> should speed up his timetable for free
elections to "possibly prevent a descent into anarchy."

            The Straits Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> expressed concern in an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, former movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrada</ENAMEX>, would fail in his promises "to press ahead with economic reforms,
establish law and order, stamp out corruption, and above all help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> who
form the bulk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." It said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrada</ENAMEX>, "whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>,
could change the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Philippine</ENAMEX> political landscape over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six years</TIMEX> if he
carries out what he promises to do: abolish pork barrel politics." "That,
indeed, would be his greatest performance," it added.

            The
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
sought to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> capability is
a source of stability for the wider region." "A knee-jerk response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
legitimate strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> will only reinforce the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> nuclear
axis, with fearful consequences for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Asia</ENAMEX>," the newspaper
said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> devoted its main editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s nuclear tests. It said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, despite its
opposition in principle to nuclear proliferation, had "left no doubt that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teheran</ENAMEX> regarded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s nuclear capability not only as essential for
maintaining a correct strategic balance in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>, but also as a source of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurance</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> generally."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with
an exclusive report saying that the latest draft of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> peace initiative
required that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> stop expanding its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> settlements and "refrain from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">demolishing 1800</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> currently slated for demolition."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> said it would be "hard to imagine a more humbling
scene for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Solzhenitsyn</ENAMEX>" than the print run of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> copies given to
his latest "vitriolic indictment of post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> society"--his book <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abyss</ENAMEX> . "Former presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Korzhakov</ENAMEX>'s memoirs of
his time as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coterie</ENAMEX> came out in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> copies," the paper
said. "Even a biography of English <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX> to be published in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> has a print run of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> copies."

             

         
      
   
