
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Interview</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here. And
if you missed the most recent installments of this column, here they are:
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 22 and Friday, Sept.</TIMEX>
18.
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> paper claims to
have talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> on the telephone. According to a report from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nedjeljni Telegraf</ENAMEX> got in touch with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Lewis</ENAMEX>, through an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX> of hers, Bozdimir
Bulent, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> called from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> continually for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> finally allowed it to talk to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. The clinching factor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> said, was the mention of a
mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dusko</ENAMEX> with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> had allegedly fallen
in love <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Softened by thoughts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dusko</ENAMEX>, she gave in
and arranged for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nedjeljni Telegraf</ENAMEX> to call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> direct.

            This is how the interview
reportedly went. Answering the phone "in a rather hoarse and velvety voice,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> said: "I was expecting your call. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> mentioned it. I sincerely
hope you won't make bad use of it." Asked if she had ever imagined she might be
the talk of the whole world, she replied, "Not even in my dreams, and I'm not
at all happy about it." Did she love the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? "Perhaps, but now it's of
no importance." Did she feel exploited<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "In a certain sense, yes; I never
expected all this." Would money and fame change her life? "I don't think about
such things. Money has never been important to me."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
said she now spends most of her time on the telephone and almost never watches
television. Asked if she had a message for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the Nedjeljni
Telegraf , she said, "They shouldn't believe everything they read in the
papers." But when the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> asked if, during her meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he had ever mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> decided she had had enough and
put down the phone. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> failed to vouch for the authenticity of
this interview.)

            In the continuing flood of international press comment on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> scandal, there is very little favorable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Express</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, "The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, a
mere intern, could be protected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> against such a mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> as
the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in the world, reveals the beauty and the
costliness of democracy. It is significant to note that even at the possible
cost of the presidency, the right to fair hearing and enabling unconcealed
information to the citizenry [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] have been remarkably upheld in this
case. It is best imagined what would have happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
any enthusiastic reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> of this scandalous episode in any undemocratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>!"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that it is time for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prognosticators</ENAMEX>" to take a vacation, because "[i]f <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
tired of hearing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual life, they are
doubtlessly doubly weary of hearing 'experts' tell them how they feel about the
whole thing." The theme of the editorial was the distinction that should be
made between feelings and deeds. The endless "mood monitoring" of the people
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has revealed a "swirl of conflicting feelings," but the end
product is the "[s]ame as it was when the whole thing started: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> remain guardedly content to keep him
there."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
may be experiencing all kinds of feelings about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, but they are
remarkably consistent when they are asked what they want to do about those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emotions</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> went on. "Impeachment? No, a majority of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> has answered, from the start to the finish of this story." It is
the ability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to distinguish between feelings and deeds
that will save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, it said. "They show no interest in punishing him for
his private feelings but a clear desire to see him pay a limited price for his
deeds. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have clearly stated that feelings aren't the issue here.
Sooner or later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> will understand that too."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johannesburg Star</ENAMEX> ran
a eulogistic editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>'s visit to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. "He fired the pride of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African Americans</ENAMEX> and touched a deep
desire in the psyche of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, both black and white, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who might
rekindle the bi-racial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> that destroyed their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s own version of
apartheid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, the racism they are still fighting to eradicate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
and the never-ending scandals. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> may lack the rousing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
oratory of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, but his
manner and his unflappable dignity show him as a disciplined, persistent leader
who is willing to sacrifice short-term gratification for long-term achievement,
the kind of moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> we need everywhere. A real, untarnished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of flawed public figures such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
