
   
   
      
         
            Who's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sorry Now</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> still refuses to be
ousted from its dominant position in the world's press. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s most
prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-impotence</ENAMEX> drug was almost
certain to be excluded from the list of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> approved for free
prescriptions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> state social security system. In a front-page
comment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>, celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianni Riotta</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX> trap" and asked whether it was really a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> against male
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impotence</ENAMEX> or, rather, "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX>'s aphrodisiac."

            "Does it
serve to cure an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> or to regulate eternal adolescence? Does it belong to
the world of pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or to that of aesthetic surgery, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">silicone breast implants</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riotta</ENAMEX> asked. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, he went on, creates the
illusion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time never ends</TIMEX> and that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> are forever renewed.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, who are already middle-aged, are described as
'young,' " he said. "But at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s funeral, the eternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Peck</ENAMEX> amazed
us with his beauty and his bearing." When <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> arrives, he concluded,
"the most beautiful and happiest old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> or no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, will be those
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peck</ENAMEX>, proud, aware, and strong in their imperfect human reality."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Sorry Day</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, but not in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, which, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akihito</ENAMEX>'s state visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, could
not bring itself to apologize unequivocally for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> atrocities
inflicted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British POWs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burma</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening Standard</ENAMEX> said in
an editorial that "no reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could feel any personal animus against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Akihito</ENAMEX>" but that "most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Londoners</ENAMEX> will feel little reason to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrate</ENAMEX>," because "the rising sun flag remains, for much of the world, a
symbol of terror and shame." "Former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>-of<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-war</ENAMEX> may be old, and
their grievances generated long ago," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> concluded. "But their
anger and bitterness deserve the sympathy of us all."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> was meanwhile
sharply divided over the need to apologize to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aborigines</ENAMEX> over their past
treatment by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. In the "red corner," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, was
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Sorry Day mob</ENAMEX>," while in the "blue corner" was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX>, heading the anti-apologizing "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Reconciliation</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> today
formally apologised to the 'stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>' of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborigines</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX>
was not among them." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> had told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> that "a formal
national apology, of the type sought by others, is not appropriate."

            While
Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opposition Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gareth Evans</ENAMEX> was reported as saying, "There's
something very sad about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who can't say sorry," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Sorry Books</ENAMEX>" had
been signed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> organisations." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> also quoted
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queensland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Borbidge</ENAMEX> as saying that "the whole sorry industry has
gotten a bit out of hand." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>, reported
that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Botany Bay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New South Wales</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Cook</ENAMEX> landed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1770</TIMEX> with the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, was to be renamed "to reflect its Aboriginal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heritage</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, in a front-page report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, said that one suggestion due to be
discussed by tribal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dharawal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Botany Bay</ENAMEX> (so
called because of the exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> life found there by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Cook</ENAMEX>) should
change its name to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gillingarie</ENAMEX>," a word in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Dharawal</ENAMEX> language meaning "land
that belongs to us all."

            
The big vote for democracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
was welcomed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Post</ENAMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> expressed concern in an editorial Monday
that the high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter turnout</ENAMEX>, despite torrential rain, might have been at least
partly due to "the offer by the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Giordano</ENAMEX>, of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 per cent</NUMEX>
discount to anyone who took along the commemorative card to show they had
voted."

            "This may just have been a
piece of clever marketing, but it comes perilously close to using a financial
incentive to influence the election," the editorial said. "What next--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> air
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>?" It said that "the first multi-party elections to be held on the soil of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People's Republic of China</ENAMEX>" might not please those who would wish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
to be a less political society, "but once it has been let out, the electoral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genie</ENAMEX> is hard to put back in the bottle."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, newspapers
have been competing to denounce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jusuf Habibie</ENAMEX>,
saying that during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology and Research</ENAMEX> he had
amassed a fortune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $60 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> said this
weekend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> was "not only short of political legitimacy" but was also
an "anti-market personality" who believed in "crony capitalism."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper L'Osservatore Romano</ENAMEX> defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican</ENAMEX> order's campaign to beatify
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girolamo Savonarola</ENAMEX>, the fire-and-brimstone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX> who was excommunicated,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hanged</ENAMEX>, and burned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> described him as an
"illuminated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of spirituality" and a "tireless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> for social
reform."

         
      
   
