
   
   
      
         
            Saying Sorry

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            The approach of the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> failed to generate
harmony in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> press, which continued in traditional abrasive form. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the humiliation inflicted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Tenet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. Under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>'s attempt to sidestep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> fails," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX> had returned a message from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to him because it appeared the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> was trying to bypass <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>.

            "This was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> attempt to get a message to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bringing Albright</ENAMEX> into the picture," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> reported. On the first
occasion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> had ignored the inference in the message that it should be
passed on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and had sent it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> instead, reported
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> 's military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ze'ev Schiff</ENAMEX>. But when the second
message was received, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX> decided to return it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> with an
explanation. In another report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
will decide whether to table its latest <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace initiative only after
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Ross</ENAMEX> talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX>.

            In an editorial
titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A needless</ENAMEX>, harmful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">annexation</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Olmert</ENAMEX> for wanting to expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s municipal boundaries to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west</ENAMEX>. This is another example of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s urban planning being influenced by
political considerations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "As in the past, a political concept
is totally overriding sensible urban considerations," it added. The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the news that, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> Finance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yaakov Neeman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will reach an agreement
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 days</TIMEX> to abolish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> civilian aid in exchange for an increase in
military aid.

            In an
op-ed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Wasserstein</ENAMEX> wrote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> 
               Post that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> should not "confess to their crimes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917 and 1948</TIMEX>." "Great historical apologies are much in fashion," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasserstein</ENAMEX>
wrote. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has apologized for slavery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen of England</ENAMEX> has
expressed regret for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amritsar</ENAMEX> massacre. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austrians</ENAMEX>, even
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>, have been induced to express remorse for sins of commission and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">omission</ENAMEX>." But the "disinterested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, reviewing the history of the
mandate, must conclude that the diplomatic framework for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX> state-building
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balfour</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bevin</ENAMEX> was, in large measure, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> construct. ... But in
the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> mandatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zionism</ENAMEX> the record should be
clear to all and the verdict unambiguous: No apology is required."

            
In an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Debt of Slavery</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should do more than just apologize to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> for the terrible damage done to them over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a period of 250 years</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> must "recognize their debt and pay it off," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "First,
by giving the rightful place in their policies to development aid for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>;
and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, by ceasing to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> no choice at all
apart from assimilation or exclusion." Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> led its front page
with the news that fierce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> opposition is causing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
government to prevaricate over its plans to recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>.

            The surprise success of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">far-right German People's Union</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s election in the east <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> state
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saxony-Anhalt</ENAMEX> made most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> front pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> but received less
prominence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> press. In a front-page comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by Bernardo
Valli, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> said the result diminished the chances that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> will
return as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next September</TIMEX>'s parliamentary elections. Other
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> included the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>'s landslide victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the dispute between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
over who should be appointed <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> to
supervise the single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency--a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutchman</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Observer</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> had "carried out a mass poisoning of defenceless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> and migrant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>" to "subdue them before repatriation." The poisoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> made the mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> detainees vomit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and "triggered riots
which were brutally suppressed," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> said. " 'Ringleaders' were
shot dead, and others tortured, beaten and robbed before being deported." In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> described these events as "the human cost of financial
carnage" and demanded "a new international financial architecture" under which
"developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> can insulate themselves from vicious reversals of
investment flows." Criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> concluded, "the
desolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX> is too high a price to pay for the freedom of
international finance."

             

         
      
   
