
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oslo Moves</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), "Pundit
Central" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), click
here.
            

            Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> May
peace parley," the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> splashed the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that there would
definitely be a new round of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>,
hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> and attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> attributed this
information to a "senior diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>." But the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> was
much more
cautious, with a front-page headline saying only that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> makes some
headway in brokering peace get-together." While several of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the possibility of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> meeting, none of them
took it as a done deal. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> might have a useful role in preparing the ground for
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> diplomatic effort, "anything more ambitious is pure
presumption."

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> was described
in the headline of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> 
               Post editorial as
a "most welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the idea "that the Stormont
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wizard</ENAMEX> can perform another miracle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX> is nice, but somewhat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unreal</ENAMEX>." He might, however, be "the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to talk bluntly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
about terrorism," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said. "If he were to do so, and communicate
this message to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, he would justify his newly-acquired
prominence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">world</ENAMEX> politics and facilitate a useful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> participation in
the peace process." In another editorial marking the arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to follow the example of "gutsy" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> and
meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Chalabi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s democratic opposition. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said it was "difficult to fathom why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> seems slavishly
attached to a policy [toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>], built upon 'containment' and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inspections</ENAMEX>, that is doomed to failure," when it should be supporting this
"viable democratic alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>" as "a strategic and moral
imperative."

            An
op-ed
piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Sadeh</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> "might well serve as an
efficient channel for the conduct of secret talks, particularly with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrians</ENAMEX>, who view <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> as a fairer and more balanced
intermediary than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." But it is unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> can restore
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s confidence in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> role in the peace process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadeh</ENAMEX> said,
because he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Foreign Office</ENAMEX>. The
main
editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> concerned an international campaign to obtain
the early release of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mordechai Vanunu</ENAMEX>, who was kidnapped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX>, taken back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and given an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year</TIMEX> prison sentence
for having revealed his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s nuclear secrets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> could
not "act permissively toward those who are entrusted with its deepest secrets
and then decide to breach their commitment," but it deplored the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanunu</ENAMEX> has been held in strict solitary confinement for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 12 years</TIMEX> on
the insistence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> security services. "The impression is that the
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> were not content with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanunu</ENAMEX>'s punishment and sought in
addition to drive him insane," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> ran an editorial congratulating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
for his role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s decision to send <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Dan</ENAMEX> into
exile in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It described this as a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s change
of policy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, when he decided to engage in dialogue with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> over human rights rather than link the issue to Most Favored
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> trading status. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said it was now clear "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> is moving in
the right direction." It added that the human rights situation is likely to go
on improving under new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX>, who sees it as "an
embarrassing legacy from a less open past which sits ill with his determined
policy of engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> with the world."

            But in a
news report, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> quoted several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> as
attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Dan</ENAMEX> as a pawn in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> relations. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Han Dongfang</ENAMEX> said exile was used by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as an effective way to
eliminate internal dissent. In continuing heavy coverage of the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> and its aftermath, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> revealed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
had crushed all religions and murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks and nuns had
held a private <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> ceremony in front of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> before his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cremation</ENAMEX>. It also claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who removed locks of hair from
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> had been acting at the request of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> disclosed on its front page that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul II</ENAMEX> is secretly completing a new encyclical for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third millennium</TIMEX>. It
said the encyclical, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> of his pontificate, will set out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>'s thinking on the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>, expressing fears about modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">materialism</ENAMEX> and urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to look into the real meaning of life. The same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported that among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turin Shroud</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathedral</ENAMEX> in that north <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> city <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andr√</ENAMEX>©
Agassi, who arrived there from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monte Carlo</ENAMEX> in a pale blue <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rolls Royce</ENAMEX>,
declaring himself to be "a deep believer."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> ran a
front-page feature titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, the 'Teflon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>,' " attempting
to explain why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> remains so popular despite all the bimbo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eruptions</ENAMEX>. It said he was benefiting not only from a national "state of
euphoria" about peace and the economy but also from the fact that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
are more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> than is generally believed in their reactions to sexual
matters." In another front-page piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> reported that Brigitte
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bardot</ENAMEX> has joined the ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> who deny
the crimes committed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX> and portray them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of "a
vast <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vatican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>." In an interview published in a
new pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> tract, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>," the former sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kitten</ENAMEX> turned animal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberationist</ENAMEX> said she supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> because the
latter "are overrunning the world, and their animal slaughter practices are an
abomination against which I fight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bardot</ENAMEX> added she hopes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> to
visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, "simply, without tralala." The death <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> of another animal
liberationist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX>, who even created a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">vegetarian dog</ENAMEX> food line,
was massively reported in papers all around the world.

             

         
      
   
