
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anti-Elitist Elite</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Nat</ENAMEX>,

            Maybe I was too prickly about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s treatment of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Civil Rights Initiative</ENAMEX>, but let me explain why. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX>, and
opposition to affirmative action generally, is popular with middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX> was extremely unpopular with the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the things the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> did during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX> fight was to use the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> power of their influence in the media and the culture to oppose,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discredit</ENAMEX>, and in many cases smear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. That's one of the reasons
most of the normal big-money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> wouldn't go near
it.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the educated-elite assault was not enough
to drive public support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX> below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>. That shows that the influence
of the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> is not dominant in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society (if it were,
campaign-finance reform would have passed long ago).

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> is writing a book lamenting the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has this new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>, selected at an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores and other
academic factors. He says this system of selecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so young is unfair to
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Good point. But if that is your argument, then in the major
public-policy dispute you cover in the book, you had better bend over backwards
to give voice to the majority of high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grads</ENAMEX> who supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX>. Instead,
the story is told--for the most part--through a bunch of Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and
highly educated political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. To simplify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s supple narrative a
bit: He decries the existence of the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>, but when push comes to
shove he seems more a creature of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> than an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> or a detached
cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>.

            But I don't want to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> is an old fashioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elitist</ENAMEX>. That is to fundamentally misunderstand the nature of the educated
elite, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> seems to be a paragon. The reality is much more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paradoxical</ENAMEX>. This is an elite raised to oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>. This is an elite with an
egalitarian sensibility. That's why it supports affirmative action--out of
concern for the less fortunate. That's why its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> write books like this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> oppose the middle class and sometimes trample
all over them, they are usually doing it in the name of egalitarianism. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> are more egalitarian than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the things that shines through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s writing
is his concern for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> less fortunate than himself. He is never
self-righteous or showy about this. Instead, his penchant for exhaustive
research seems to flow from a genuine social commitment. I've never met the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but I admire him through his writings. From what I know about him, he
seems to have had all the educational advantages. And here he is arguing
against the privileges of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, but without any radical-chic bravura--and
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> will agree with him.

            That's why this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>, for all its flaws, is
fundamentally different than and better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Establishment</ENAMEX> that
it replaced. That's why I'm not convinced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s concluding section in
which he says we should change the way we select our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>. The ethos he
describes in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> undercuts his case. If we are going to have an
elite--and we are--we should have one made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as egalitarian as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>. The current university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> seems to inculcate such values. I
mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that I just finished a book about the manners and morals of
this educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. When I wrote the proposal, I said that my last chapter
would be about the revolt against this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, for some of the same reasons that
Lemann hints at (without sufficiently detailing) in his book: They are selected
too early; they live in a culture that is detached from the rest of the
culture; the income gap between them and the rest of the culture is widening.
But as I traveled around doing my research, I couldn't find any evidence of
this class revolt. There didn't seem to be any mass movement to upend people
like us who went to or work at selective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
seems to want to learn how to drink espressos like we do. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
seemed genuinely upset about the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the educated
elite themselves.

            This sensibility oozes from the pores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Munger</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> describes fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX>. This sensibility
plays out over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many spheres</TIMEX>. This is an elite that dresses casually so it won't
appear elite (visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>). This is an elite that practices conscientious
consumption instead of conspicuous consumption. This is an elite in which
six-figure-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> churn out books on widening
wealth disparities. This is not too say they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX>. It is to say they
go to extraordinary lengths to mitigate their social advantages, at least
compared to the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Establishment</ENAMEX>.

            Indeed, I have a half-baked theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tolerates</ENAMEX> left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> because they serve as finishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for
the new ruling class. They give the coming elite an egalitarian sensibility, so
when they rise to the top, they won't give off offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vapors</ENAMEX> that might
arouse class resentments in the middle and lower class. In this way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> actually serve to solidify the current class structure.

            But that wacky theory aside, the point for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s
book is this: He brilliantly shows how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Establishment</ENAMEX> gave way to
the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. He tells for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time how the selective mechanism for
the educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>--came to occupy its current dominant role. He
underlines the problems with this arrangement. He makes a truncated plea for
reform. But he never shows the great harms perpetrated by this system. He
doesn't show how the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> have been corrupted by their status, or of the
misery of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How the Other Half Lives</ENAMEX>. On the contrary, he shows how educated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> like himself and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Munger</ENAMEX> are fighting against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Antoinette</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>. I don't agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> on a lot of issues, but I'm glad the
central flaw of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> is excessive egalitarianism. That's the least bad
flaw for an elite to have.

            You mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you were going to
take on his concluding section. I'm looking forward to that.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
