
   
   
      
         
            What is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> freed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that fought for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> independence (sometimes with bombs)
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. What, exactly, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>'s relationship to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>? And what alternatives have been proposed?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> took possession of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX> as part
of its spoils from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> governed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
island directly as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, when it expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>
autonomy by making it a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX>," allowing it to adopt a constitution and
create a locally elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with statelike powers. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a map of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>.)

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rico</ENAMEX> is subject to all federal laws, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> reserves the right
to repeal any locally enacted legislation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> granted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX>
statutory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, which can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revoked</ENAMEX>, as opposed to constitutional citizenship,
which is almost impossible to cancel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX> residing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>
cannot vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">delegate</ENAMEX> they elect to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has no vote.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are also exempt from federal income tax but qualify for
federal entitlements. And all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> must register for
the draft, just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX> are free to move to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> where their
rights of citizenship become constitutional, affording them the right to vote
in all elections. Currently, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX> live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 million</NUMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX> was designed as a temporary fix, but
periodic plebiscites have not resolved what relationship the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
want with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 and 1998</TIMEX>, support was evenly divided between
commonwealth status and pursuit of statehood. In both plebiscites, independence
got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 5 percent</NUMEX> of the vote. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is not likely to formalize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>'s status until a clearer consensus emerges.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> has benefited economically from being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commonwealth</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> poured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rican</ENAMEX> development, transforming it from one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>'s poorest
territories to one of the wealthiest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> still receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> in
assistance (including entitlements) each year. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> investing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> have long been exempted from income tax, making the island a
manufacturing and pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has begun to phase out the
tax exemption, reducing the attractiveness of investment there. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX> status becomes more permanent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizenship</ENAMEX> and economic assistance will, as well. But there is some debate as
to whether such guarantees are constitutionally possible.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statehood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> desire
the benefits of constitutional citizenship, the federal safety net, and the
economic stability that will likely follow. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of statehood
oppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s continued dependence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and worry that it might
eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> culture. (Indeed, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> have
proposed adoption of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as the official language as a prerequisite for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">statehood</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> oppose statehood on fiscal grounds. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>'s per capita income would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, currently
the poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> estimated statehood
would cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Treasury</ENAMEX> another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> benefits.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> continued ties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, including a free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> pact, a common currency, and joint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. Some also suggest that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> would continue to be responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s defense. But
independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dismiss it as unworkable, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> lacks the
infrastructure and natural resources to compete effectively.

            Next question?

         
      
   
