
   
   
      
         
            Go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>, Go

            The notion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> should evict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> advanced in this space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>--is gaining momentum.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>, endorsed the idea on
This Week With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie</ENAMEX> , saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
should urge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> to leave. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> compared the situation to what happened
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> showed the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Wallace</ENAMEX> the door.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> got on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dump Buchanan</ENAMEX>
bandwagon. "I don't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>
when he uses statements and beliefs that we should not have fought against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tojo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> elaborated. "I believe that we
should always stand on principle and not on polls when we decide whether
someone should remain in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or not. And I do not believe that that kind
of rhetoric represents <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, much less <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>."

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Sanford</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> chimed in. "I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanford</ENAMEX> said.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Dal Col</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, joined in the criticism--though both stopped short of
calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dal Col</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s statements in
his book questioning whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should have entered <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
"outrageous." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> released a statement saying that she was "appalled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s comments."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> has responded with his customary fury. Asked by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Couric</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today Show</ENAMEX> why he faces
accusations of anti-Semitism, he responded, "Because I speak truth to power and
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is probably the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> who will stand
up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question: What does the latest round of
criticism--fueled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s argument that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should have
tried to stay out of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>--have to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
lobby?

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s negotiations to take over the
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> appear to be stalled. In an interview on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News Radio</ENAMEX> released
today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> says that he has been trying to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>. So far, Perot
has not returned his calls.

         
      
   
