
   
   
      
         
            Double <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> Drubbings

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> earthquake leads with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> columns at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and is fronted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> (which puts it below the fold). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts the earthquake atop its
"Worldwide" box.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> leads with news first
hinted at in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> message: According
to anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will file a massive civil
racketeering lawsuit against the tobacco industry to reclaim <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of</NUMEX>
dollars of health payments for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>-related illnesses. This story is the top
non-local lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , which adds that the
suit would be the largest ever brought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Y2K report, to be
released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, stating that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX> computer glitches "will cause more
inconvenience than tragedy" (the report is also fronted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ). Most foul-ups will be isolated, the report
says, with the education, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, construction, agriculture, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> processing, and
health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> being the most vulnerable. A panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> assembled
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> predicts Y2K will not be more disruptive
than <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX>, which dislocated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several dozen</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> quake--which measured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX> on the Richter
scale (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.7</NUMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> )--has killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,700</NUMEX>,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,700</NUMEX> still trapped and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 4,000</NUMEX> injured. There have been more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> aftershocks, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that registered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>. Despite the enormous
casualties and continued neighborhood blackouts, much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was up and
running <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the quake, including major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that the quake may cause a spike in
the price of computer chips--one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s main exports--though a similar
report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is more optimistic. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> both
front an astounding photograph of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> perilously
perched over the street like a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tower of Pisa</ENAMEX>.

            With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> articles, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> coverage is the most thorough. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story helpfully notes that
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX> quake was actually twice as powerful as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX> quake which killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. (To learn how the Richter scale works, click
here; to learn what damage will typically result from
a given Richter reading, click here.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also says
that the spate of recent earthquakes has nothing to do with geology (they
happen with the same frequency as they always have) and everything to do with
demographics and geography (more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live near fault lines).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> attacks
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> policy on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s editorial page. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
personalized the relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, set
too-high expectations for democratization, slacked off on nuclear security, and
failed to properly monitor economic aid. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Summers</ENAMEX> defended
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> policy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. "At every step, we have been
clear-headed in endeavoring to strike a careful balance between ... what is
best economically and is also politically realistic," he said.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the
revelation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> "unequivocally opposed" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s recent release
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. In a draft letter (released at a congressional
hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> wrote that the clemency would "return committed,
experienced, sophisticated and hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> to the clandestine movement"
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> independence. In another letter released at the hearing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> provided his first detailed defense of the clemency.
Interestingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s story, run on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A2</TIMEX>,
is the inverse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ': It highlights
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s defense, and leaves until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">15th</NUMEX> paragraph <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>'s opposition. (The
story was reefered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .)

            The LAT fronts the news
that seat belts on school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> do not save lives, and may actually do harm. A
computer re-creation of several bus crashes by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Transportation</ENAMEX>
Safety <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> concluded that school-bus seats are too flat and slippery for the
belts to do any good. In some cases, the belts simply exacerbated whiplash. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> recommended that the seats be redesigned, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>,
promised to re-examine a school bus seat-belt law passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reefer the closing arguments of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial, which concluded after a lengthy recess. No new evidence was
presented. (To read 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
dispatch from the trial's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX>, click here.) 

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> gets its hands
on an advance copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>' controversial new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> , as well as the transcript of a forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. The
paper does not pronounce a verdict on the book (appropriate, since presumably
it has had the book for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than 24 hours</TIMEX>), but it does note <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' general
bewilderment with his subject. Among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> alleges that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> flirted with joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party; Morris</ENAMEX> fails, however, to
reach a conclusion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>. His provocative
use of fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> personas grew out of an "epiphany" that, "after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of deep research I was, in an almost occult sense, there when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was younger."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX>
gives one of his inimitable drubbings to would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apostate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>. "Recently in this space, I wrote unflatteringly of the entertainer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick J. Buchanan</ENAMEX>, suggesting that his material was old and that he was
perhaps overly preoccupied with the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and money," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> writes.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>] threatens to bolt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, hold the
door open for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, grease the skids and give him a helpful boot down the
steep, swift road to sure and deserved oblivion." (To read 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, click here.)

         
      
   
