
   
   
      
         
            Private-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet Sex</ENAMEX>
            

            Here's a cute-but-frightening true fact I just discovered: My 9-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">daughter</ENAMEX> knows the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. I'll be sure to forbid
her from traveling on private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>.

            You are, of course, completely correct about the chick-magnet effect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lears</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bombardiers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulfstreams</ENAMEX>. Private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> undoubtedly get rich men
laid--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> inhabiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HerbAllenWorld</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulfstream</ENAMEX> is a 'Vette to the Third
Power. In fact, as you know, my novel contains several private-jet scenes, and
a main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> specifically imagines his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> fucking her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>'
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>. (However, just to make clear that fiction isn't necessarily
autobiographical: My own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, when she worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>, once flew across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> on the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, and I never
entertained any thoughts at all about onboard fornication involving her and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner Redstone</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> generated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX>'s ghastliest show-business moments? Was
this on All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> ? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeez</ENAMEX> ... how perfectly, amazingly,
uncannily apt. I thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> as I watched The
Insider , the forthcoming All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> -ish movie in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> plays a crusading high-strung TV news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>. (By the way, in
the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> , is portrayed as a
completely craven asshole. I think he'll be unhappier than any of the other
real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> depicted in the film, including the tobacco<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-company</ENAMEX> P.R. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Scanlon, who is portrayed merely as evil, not unlikable.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, watching
Pacino, I wondered who feels more professional jealousy or competitiveness for
the other ethnic hyper-acting 1970s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pacino</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacino</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>? I also thought: How astounded we would
have been, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years ago</TIMEX>, to be told that the All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> -ish movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> would portray <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> as villainous and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.

            No, I haven't read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>'s book. What's frightening about it? To me,
his libertarianism and call<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-spade-a-spade</ENAMEX> plain-spokenness seem
attractive--since moral authoritarianism (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>) and
mealy-mouthed temporizing (practically every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> except the moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authoritarians Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX>) are the things that scare and disgust
me most in contemporary politics. I do confess that every time I actually hear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> speak I sort of hate him. However, if elections are won by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authenticity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+ Balls</ENAMEX> (your version of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Happiness + Guyism</ENAMEX>), then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> looks like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, doesn't he? And in any case, by both our reckonings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is a sure
loser.

            By the way, I disobeyed you. And <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coliseum Books</ENAMEX> was relieved when my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> called and suggested we might want to think about rescheduling the
reading there on account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>'s torrents. So, when you get back, I'll come
to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, read all the passages about private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> out loud, and sign
your copy of the book.

            P.S.: You say, apropos of the fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seems authentic and ballsy, that
"this is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> is so dangerous." I don't quite get this. I guess this is why
I'm not a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. First, aren't authenticity and ballsiness good things?
And "dangerous"? Tell me how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> would be
dangerous. Yes, I'd rather have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> picking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, and I'd rather have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> than either of them ... but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
doesn't scare me. This is, conversely, among the many reasons I could never be
a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>--I just don't get the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apoplexy. He's sort of
creepy, sure, but ... so what? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> kind of seem like the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to me, humanly and ideologically--fun but slippery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> without much
there there.

         
      
   
