
   
   
      
         
            There's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Worm in This Apple</ENAMEX>
            

            It's not too often that the market takes it as good news when a company
announces that its revenues and profits are going to fall well short of
expectations. And in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX>, which made precisely that
announcement after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the closing bell</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the market in fact did not take
it as good news. In the midst of a broad--if relatively mild--sell-off in
technology stocks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> was a notable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>, with its shares falling
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> points, or better than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX>.

            In the context of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, which has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s stock soar because
of all the buzz about the iMac, the iBook, and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Mac</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G4</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
tumble was unsurprising. But there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> interesting things about it,
nonetheless. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that the stock fell sharply despite the fact that
pretty much every serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> who covers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> said that if the stock
sold off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> should treat it as a buying opportunity. So we were greeted
with odd headlines on the newswires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple's Stock Tumbles; Street</ENAMEX>
Says It's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time To Buy</ENAMEX>." Considering the heavy volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>, it's clear that
lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the Street were in fact thinking it was time to sell. But
this is one case where it wasn't the brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that overreacted, even if
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> did trim their estimates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.

            The more interesting thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s announcement is that from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> angle
it really was good news, at least if you looked at things from the perspective
of the longue durée . What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> said was that its revenues and earnings
were going to be down because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>, which is the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of the
microprocessor for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G4</TIMEX>, hadn't been able to deliver enough chips to satisfy
a much heavier than expected demand for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G4</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> said it had already
received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> orders for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G4</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three weeks</TIMEX> since it went on sale,
but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> was not going to be able to produce anywhere near that many
chips.

            The obvious point here is that if you're going to have a problem, it's
better to have one that's the result of too much demand rather than too little.
(Though there is something deeply ironic about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>, which initially ran into
trouble because its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>--and now interim <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX>, wanted it to
build everything that went into the machines, is now having problems because
its sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> is struggling.) But there's also something else, which is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> said its profits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this quarter</TIMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 to 30 percent</NUMEX> less than
they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>.

            On the face of it, that's strange. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> were having trouble
with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G4</TIMEX>, which is a new product, why would that make it earn less money
than it did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G4</NUMEX> didn't even exist? But there's actually a
good reason for this, and it has to do with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> has pared back its
operations, concentrated on its best products, and placed a new premium on
technological innovation.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX>, there were still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> products in the pipeline and on store
shelves that were older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> or that served markets in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was
never going to thrive. Today, that's not true. The best thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> has
done in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year and a half</TIMEX>--actually, the best thing it's done in more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>--is return to its core competence as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that makes sharply
designed, user-friendly, high-performance products for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who are
willing to pay a premium for those characteristics. The best thing about the
G4, in that sense, is that there are no sub-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$999</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G4s</ENAMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s
return on invested capital is improving, its profit margins are improving, and
eventually, assuming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> gets its act together, its profits will improve
as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> will never be what it once was. But it has a chance to do a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> job of being what it is.

         
      
   
