
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barron</ENAMEX>'s on AOL: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Talk, No News</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX>'s stock price dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than six</NUMEX> points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. In
itself, this is of course hardly stop-the-presses news. In fact, given the
volatility of Internet stocks, it's more like the proverbial <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>-bites-man
story. But the drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s price was noteworthy because it seems to have been
provoked almost entirely by a negative item on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that appeared in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barron</ENAMEX>'s over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> was the centerpiece of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Abelson</ENAMEX>, as
bearish a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> on Wall Street as exists <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who bears a
special enmity toward Internet stocks, all of which--as far as I can tell--he
thinks are grossly overvalued. In essence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abelson</ENAMEX> gave a short-seller with a
significant short position in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>--meaning that he's betting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
stock price will drop--the opportunity to blast the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and explain why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s future is so bleak.

            Now, there's nothing wrong with quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">short-sellers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, even
when they stand to make a great deal of money if their comments knock those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' stock prices down. Short <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> are often founts of useful
information, and a certain kind of institutionalized skepticism seems to make
them adept at sniffing out fraud and deception, particularly in corporate
accounting. Certainly the financial press is full of more than enough fund
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> touting the stocks they love for there to be plenty of room for
short-sellers attacking the stocks they hate.

            What was striking about the attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, though, was just how obvious and
devoid of new information it was. We were informed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> growth
was slowing, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was facing increased competition and that the
advent of free Internet services, especially abroad, would hurt it. We were
also told that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> was already suffering, and would suffer more in the future,
from price cuts on the part of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, and that soon the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would have to rescind the price hike it was able to push through last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            The last point is, of course, pure speculation, and it rests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
fundamental misconceptions. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is just like any
other Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>. It's not, because even though it's
considerably more integrated with the Internet than ever before, its
proprietary services--including above all its chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>--continue to attract
and keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. There's no evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are price-sensitive. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> misconception is the idea that Net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are willing to abandon their
e-mail addresses to save a few bucks. This is just wrong. E-mail is the killer
app of the Internet, and it is a true source of customer stickiness. It may be
easier to change your e-mail address than your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> address, but for a lot of
us, we'd probably have to tell more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about the former than the
latter.

            In any case, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abelson</ENAMEX> was right or wrong is not really as interesting
as the fact that despite the familiarity of his critique, it was able to drive
down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s stock price by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 7 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single day</TIMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> who
read that piece could have come away from it thinking, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Damn</ENAMEX>. I was just wrong
about the business. I need to sell." In other words, there was no new
information in the story that needed to be incorporated into the stock
price.

            Except, of course, that the existence of the story itself was information
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. It's not that what was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abelson</ENAMEX>'s column drove the stock down. The
fact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX>'s column hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> assumed that the fact of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX>'s column would hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>.

            The real question is whether, in incorporating the reality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX>'s
column so quickly, the stock market was efficient or inefficient.
Unfortunately, this is almost a metaphysical question. An efficient market is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that assimilates everything meaningful that can be known about a company
into that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price. In the long run, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelson</ENAMEX>'s critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is
meaning less . But in the financial-news-saturated and twitchy market we
live in, in the short run a piece blasting a stock is almost sure to move that
stock, which would seem to make it meaningful. And so the snake ends up eating
its own tail.

            
               Illustration on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table of Contents</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stamaty</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
