
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley Green</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off, Part II</ENAMEX>

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> noted previously (see "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley Green</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Off, Part I"</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s lifetime legislative score from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Voters</ENAMEX> is a full <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> percentage
points ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al Earth</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balance Gore</ENAMEX>'s. Cutting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> every conceivable
break--restricting the comparison to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985-1992</TIMEX>) when both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and knocking out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1987</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s runs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> may have
caused him to miss key environmental votes-- narrowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore-Bradley</ENAMEX> gap to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
percentage points . But it didn't

               eliminate that gap. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> still ended up with the
better LCV score. How could that be?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> decided to attack this question by examining
causes for both the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-point gap (based on the raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LCV</ENAMEX> lifetime scores) and the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-point gap (based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s elaborate massaging of the LCV lifetime
scores). That way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> figured, he'd have answers for both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley partisans</ENAMEX> (who are likely to view any
alteration of the raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LCV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> with suspicion) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> (who are likely to view comparison of the raw LCV
scores as simplistic and unfair). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are presumably gleeful that this contest is being scored at all and
don't much care how big the gap is.

            
               
                  Analysis of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-point gap:
               
            

            Not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has the patience to comb through
every environmental vote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1977 and 1992</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> leaves that to certified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> of social science.) Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> zeroed in on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cast considerably more votes
considered "anti-environment" by the LCV than he did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other years</TIMEX>. These were
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cast "anti-environment" votes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times and received an LCV
rating of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> (his third-worst score ever);
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cast "anti-environment" votes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> times and received an LCV
rating of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> (his worst score ever).*

            What were these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> "anti-environment" votes?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> of them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would characterize (by way
of explaining, not necessarily condoning) as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX> votes," i.e., votes in
which powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> interests were at odds with national environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>:

            

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17, 1978</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted on phasing out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clinch River Breeder</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reactor</ENAMEX>, one of the more notorious boondoggles of the period. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> voted
against the de-funding measure, which lost, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">157-238</ENAMEX>.

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 5, 1978</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted on whether to
override <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s veto of a water projects appropriation bill, which
included funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>-Tombigbee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waterway</ENAMEX> (another famous boondoggle of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> voted in favor of
the veto override, which failed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">223</NUMEX>-190 (falling short of the necessary
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority).

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 14, 1978</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted on whether to
exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tellico Dam</ENAMEX>, which was believed
to represent a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX> darter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endangered</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Species Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> voted for the exemption, which was adopted, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">231-157</ENAMEX>.

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 1980</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted on whether to cut
funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tombigbee Waterway</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
voted against the cut, which was rejected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">196</NUMEX>-216.

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> additional
"anti-environment" votes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would call "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> penumbra votes,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, votes in which powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> interests might be harmed
indirectly by a pro-environment vote. These include
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> votes in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> and other water projects outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> ; probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> felt
he needed to support other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' water projects if they were going to
support his in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penumbra</ENAMEX> votes" benefited the nuclear power
industry and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonneville Power</ENAMEX>
Administration --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out-of-state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> whose influence no doubt
could be felt in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clinch River Breeder Reactor</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Valley Authority</ENAMEX>.

            That leaves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
anti-environment" votes whose connection to powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> interests are
unclear. These include several "energy crisis" votes (it is by now largely
forgotten that environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were often opposed to federal efforts to
ease the energy crisis). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> voted in favor of a solar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> program that the environmental movement opposed (according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LCV</ENAMEX>, because it was "costly and grandiose"); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> voted against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Energy</ENAMEX> Act of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> , which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LCV</ENAMEX> favored because it included a lot of conservation
measures, but which some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> opposed, because it also
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decontrolled</ENAMEX> natural gas prices; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> voted to create the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synthetic Fuels Corp.</ENAMEX> , an ill-considered and short-lived
alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> opposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> because it involved
strip-mining. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Environmentalists</ENAMEX> were also opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MX</ENAMEX> missile's underground basing mode, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> supported in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of votes during this period; eventually he would shift his support to an
expensive but strategically elegant alternative called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midgetman</ENAMEX>"
missile.

            
               
                  Analysis of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-point gap:
               
            

            Chatterbox, again, was too lazy to examine all the
environmental votes that occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1985 and 1992</TIMEX>, the period when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> served together in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>--even after omitting all votes in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-8 and 1992</TIMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> looked at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cast
his greatest number of "anti-environment" votes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. These were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> "anti-environment" votes, earning a combined LCV
score of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">67</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s third-worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> score); and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another four</NUMEX> "anti-environment" votes, earning an LCV
score of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">73</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>-worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> score).
**

            These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> "anti-environment" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> votes were: a
vote against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-funding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synfuels Corp.</ENAMEX>; a vote in favor of constructing a
highway along the boundary of a wilderness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>; a vote against
creating a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s compensation program under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Superfund</ENAMEX> program; a
votes; a vote against banning new billboard construction along federally
subsidized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>; and a vote against a moratorium on issuing federal patents
for hard-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> mining on public lands out west. Of these, only the Synfuels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> vote and the mining vote were clearly dreadful. The votes against
extending <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Superfund</ENAMEX> spending and effecting a wholesale ban on billboards was
clearly good. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> funding cut was probably bad, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would have
to know more about the circumstances.

            *<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> - worst score, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>,
occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987 and 1988</TIMEX>, but it was an aberration; during those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> actually cast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> "anti-environment" vote. He ended up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
percent because he was absent for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> LCV-scored votes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">**Gore</ENAMEX>'s two

               worst 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> scores
were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-8 and 1992</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-8</TIMEX> score of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> is explained in the
previous footnote. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> score, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX>, is entirely attributable to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
absences; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> didn't cast a single "anti-environment" vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, but
there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 12</NUMEX> LCV-scored votes.

         
      
   
