
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Rubble</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with yet another terrorist bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, a story also fronted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , which leads instead
with preparations being undertaken in connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, both bureaucratic at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> and
logistical in the militaries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> bottom-fronts some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> accounts
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> rampage, but stuffs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> terrorism, all in favor of
its lead about the latest fiscal gimmick gaining currency among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> as a way to continue spending while technically not violating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' previously agreed-upon spending caps: declare <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming fiscal year</TIMEX>
to be made up of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months</TIMEX> ("instead of the usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>," explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
ever so helpfully). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the decision in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to proceed with (separate) investigations into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> aid money
scandal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> bombing, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two weeks</TIMEX> (the cumulative death total: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 266</NUMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> )
is, report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, like its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, widely viewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> as the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> working with or sympathetic to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX> insurgencies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> responded with a
nationally televised address in which he stated that "Terrorism has declared
war on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." A major security effort is underway, including a
search of every apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and intensified paperwork for
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muscovites</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the explosions have prompted a
lengthy discussion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> about whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> should
drop an atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> former government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> likening the situation to that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>--in which terrorism
will go on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead, some things suspected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>
coverage are now confirmed: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is preparing to fulfill a primarily
logistical role, particularly by providing air transport to the ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>,
who will be supplied by other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> will probably be led by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> (and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX>); and the Indonesians
are expressing a preference for, but not insisting on, a predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ends its lead with a helpful explanation: Setting up a
security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> rather than a "full-dress" peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is
essential to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> strategy because of congressional restraints on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> participation and funding in operations of the latter sort. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> could have been more helpful still if it had explained what
constitutes "full-dress" peacekeeping.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> revelation made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX> showing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> used combustible
tear gas canisters at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> has been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s possession "for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" and was
even sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> no later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. Another piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> news is more
troublesome for the feds: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> released a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
stating in part that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>, in their Waco post-mortem, found spent
cartridges from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sniper rifles</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>--which
conflicts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>'s assertion that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> never fired a shot. The
paper points out, though, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">casings</ENAMEX> could have been from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ATF</ENAMEX> weapons
admittedly fired during the initial gunfight at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds to the buzz around that new book by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who defected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX>. Yes,
there is the usual trench-coat ineptitude--like trying to discredit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s
national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zbigniew Brzezinski</ENAMEX> by spreading the word that he was
having an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candice Bergen</ENAMEX> (note to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>: to discredit, try Bea
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>)--but there's also the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> managed to intercept fax
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> of top <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> concerning some of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most sensitive military projects. And that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, was the locus of a successful effort to intercept messages
between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Andrews Air Force Base</ENAMEX> and government aircraft used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, and other senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGBer</ENAMEX> is quoted
saying that the then-head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> loved listening to intercepted
conversations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> and his then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Maginnes</ENAMEX>.

            Inside stories at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>, in an attempt to convince other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to maintain tough
sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> released new evidence suggesting
that under the sanctions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> has enough money to feed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
provide them with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> but has chosen to spend it on other things. The
evidence includes aerial photos of a lakeside village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> complete with
Ferris wheel he recently completed, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for the exclusive use of his
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports that in a
survey of restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> admitted
stealing an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$218</NUMEX> in food and property, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$96</NUMEX> the
previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Those with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or alcohol problem stole <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonusers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a top-front "talker" about the decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>
running the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX> contest to relax its rules about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> marriage
and childbirth. The old requirement: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> must sign a document stating
that she has not been married and is not cohabitating, is not now nor has
previously been pregnant, and has never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. The new requirement:
Signing an affidavit affirming not being currently married and not being
currently pregnant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> says the change was motivated by the pageant's fear
of discrimination lawsuits. In a related development, it's now OK if Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congeniality</ENAMEX> used to be a pain in the ass.

         
      
   
