
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            The trade deficit is soaring, the dollar is weakening against the yen, oil
prices are high. Damn, it feels like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> all over again. Except that
inflation is still nonexistent, corporate earnings are high, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> is still barely limping along, and the trade deficit seems to have more
to do with roaring consumer demand and foreign demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> assets than any
fundamental weakness in the overall economy. Maybe the fact that all this is
going on at once explains this market's complete unwillingness to commit in one
direction or another. Or maybe enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just haven't read Dow
36,000 yet. On to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cocktail Chat</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mindspring</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earthlink</ENAMEX> agreed to merge, in a deal that would make the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> largest Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> in the world ,
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. Of course, the real question is not whether the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> corporate
cultures will mesh. Unfortunately, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will be called
Earthlink , robbing us of the chance to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> called
Mindearthspringlink, which would have been cool."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McDonough</ENAMEX> reiterated that, as part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s attempt to ensure that fears about Y2K won't cause any
liquidity problems, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> would be adopting a 'no questions asked'
policy at the window where it lends money to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. Not even: 'Will you pay
us back?' Is there any chance at all that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> are not figuring out
how to take advantage of this?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first day</TIMEX> of trading, Internet stock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E.piphany</ENAMEX> saw its shares
leap <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 150 percent</NUMEX> . I'm sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is really just terrific,
but could its name be more s.tupid?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E.piphany</ENAMEX>'s popularity is due in part to the fact that it's involved
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s hottest technology sector , namely business-to-business
e-commerce. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> we had content, then portals, then e-commerce, then free
e-mail, then business-to-consumer e-commerce again, and now it's
business-to-business that's all the rage . Next, presumably, will be
computer-to-computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commerce</ENAMEX>, which will have the great virtue of eliminating
humans entirely. Another alternative would be business-to-aliens commerce."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX>'s Believe It or Not file , this headline from the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journal : 'Once Just Seat-Pocket Promotions, In-Flight</ENAMEX>
Magazines Find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Devotees</ENAMEX> .' Look, there were actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who watched
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear John</ENAMEX> , too. Incredibly bad taste is just not news."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> filed a lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rite-Aid</ENAMEX>, alleging
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> systematically overcharged uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for
prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> . When asked about the lawsuit, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rite-Aid</ENAMEX> said, 'I don't know anything about it.' This is not the ideal
response from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> flack . 'The charges are utterly without merit, and
the lawsuit is baseless' would have been better. 'I don't know anything about
it' sounds more like 'I didn't know anything about it while it was going
on.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX> Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> named former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Ride</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> , ensuring that for the foreseeable future every article about the
site will contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s 'rocketing'
fortunes."

         
      
   
