
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan Speaks</ENAMEX>

            Endorsements are the frozen tundra of presidential
politics--unvarying, without interest, and seemingly infinite. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX>, the
presidential campaigns spam <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> by e-mail and fax with reports of the
latest, on the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s news flash from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lieutenant Governor Endorses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>." To actually read these press
releases is to risk stupor. Front-runners rack up endorsements by the bushel
because endorsements are mostly about who is likely to win--and thus be in a
position to pay his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">endorsers</ENAMEX> back.

            An exception to this rule was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s endorsement of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> by outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s most senior and revered elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. His endorsement carries a lot
of sway with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, who, according to the most recent polls,
are now split evenly in their allegiance between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. With the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> primary shaping up as a pivotal test for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, this
matters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s approval means something nationally as well. Alone among
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, he has respect and influence on the other side of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson River</ENAMEX>. Though his endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was anticipated, he delivered
it with deft timing in the midst of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> surge, giving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX> a significant boost.

            The event, which was held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">92nd Street Y</ENAMEX>, better known for poetry readings and chamber music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concerts</ENAMEX>, was a classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> performance. Dressed in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Club</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finest</ENAMEX> (a once-elegant pin-striped suit, college insignia tie, silk pocket
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">square</ENAMEX>), he shambled to the lectern with a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Present</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Past in hand. Looking slightly
bewildered by the TV lights and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, he began by reading aloud from a
dust jacket blurb by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX> that praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as a "respected
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statesman</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> then quoted a passage from the book in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> praises ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>. Part of the fun of watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> is that you
seldom have any idea what he will say next--and neither does he. Today,
however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> didn't get himself into any serious trouble. After a brief
discursion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodrow Wilson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> credited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> with bringing about
the tax reform of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, then kept talking and couldn't stop himself from
pointing out that this legacy has since been entirely erased. He then shuffled
back to his seat and allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to graciously accept his endorsement.

            Once the floor was opened to questions, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>, "What's wrong with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moynihan</ENAMEX> rose and made his
stooped, deliberate shuffle back to the microphone. "Nothing is the matter with
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> except he can't be elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> chirped, before
turning on his heel and scurrying back to his seat. As sound bites go, this was
just about perfect, a tiny dagger pitched into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s sternum.

            "Why not?" rose a universal cry from the assembled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> exited the stage. Laughter engulfed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> returned to give his reasons some minutes
later. "Do you want a list?" he asked, to more tumultuous laughter and
applause.

            "Yeah, we want a list!" cried out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>.

            "I think we have to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Buren</ENAMEX> to find a vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who succeeded as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GEORGE BUSH</ENAMEX>!" roared the press corps, delighted to
detect such an elemental boo-boo in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s usually unassailable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pedantry</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>, and, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> stammered. "It's
a rare and unusual event. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> was a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who really got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> term." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> has anything to do with it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> will not
get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.

         
      
   
