
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balances</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the intensifying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> air
assault against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, now in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifth day</TIMEX> (a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
had previously covered more than the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the revelation that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> turned
down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s request for bank statements, other
documents and audiotapes relating to the suspected diversion of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $15</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> described the
request, says the paper, as an "unnecessary intrusion." This contrasts with
previous claims by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of complete cooperation with the bank
probe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s
signing into law a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>-oriented rewrite of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> regulations, one
that could serve as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stimulant</ENAMEX> to similar managed care reform around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, the story points out, already has similar laws). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> reforms, but leads instead with local news: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> that's become the target of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s wrath for
exhibiting a dung-stained picture of the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> discussed with
city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> withdrawing the work, only to back out when the officials
revealed the talks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> off-leads another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
story: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s just-identified mosquito-borne West <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX> virus has stricken
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly twice as many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>--and over a much wider area than was previously
thought. The virus has now accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> deaths. The chief evidence for
the new dimensions of the problem, explains the paper, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX>
become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> of the virus by biting infected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, and scores of dead birds
are in evidence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries the
story inside, but look for more intense coverage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> to come, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> are about to fly south and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) So many of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> live inside the virus zone.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that among the targets of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> are
properties belonging to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> guerrilla <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>. The bombing has
created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who denies any
affiliation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX>, has requested a sit-down with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>,
but for now the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> aren't having any of it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the reasons for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> persistence, says the paper, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military is trying to
reverse the fumbling image it picked up from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994-95</TIMEX> attempt to best the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX>. Both this story and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s inside piece point out that the
air-only campaign seems modeled on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explain that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> HMO laws mandate plan
coverage of such previously uncovered areas as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> screening, give
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> the right to sue their health plans, to obtain <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> medical
opinions, and to appeal treatment funding decisions to an independent review
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>--in short the key features now being debated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in its attempts
to arrive at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' bill of rights. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> important grain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> that the
LAT waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">32nd</NUMEX> paragraph to sprinkle: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> still can (and the
implication is, will) prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> from suing under the bill by requiring
their agreement to binding arbitration as a condition of treatment.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> feature notes one political upshot of
the managed care imbroglio: It's turned a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Solid
numbers are hard to come by but, examples the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> recently
contributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story reports that the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> carries a favorable review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hair-loss products
without disclosing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has some financial ties to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, a situation expressly forbidden by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>'s
guidelines. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s explanation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> seems Pharisaical at
best: she stopped consulting for the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> when she embarked upon the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, although she expects to resume doing so now that it's been
published.

            Everybody reports inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, contending that both violated her privacy by unlawfully
disclosing information about her from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> file and other government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>. An example <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> gives in court papers is the unflattering New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> profile that revealed her teen-age grand larceny arrest and also
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> didn't disclose the arrest in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> security clearance form.
Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> named in the suit, not as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>, but as having "engaged
in communications" about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. Tripp claims that as a
result she suffered a loss of income. None of the papers mention a fact about
Tripp that makes this last claim puzzling: During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the time</TIMEX> frame she's
referring to she remained one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s highest-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, making
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX>-plus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K. She</ENAMEX> even got a raise.

            The LAT front reports that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX> has gone to court to
try to win the right to participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s Adopt-a-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway</ENAMEX> program, and
to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Missouri</ENAMEX>'s radio station's "All Things
Considered" broadcast. The paper points out that the highway program already
includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX>, who exclude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knights</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, who exclude non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story saying that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> has already seen the
largest number of executions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954--76</TIMEX> snuffers snuffed. The
story notes though that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1930 and 1967</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> averaged <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> features a tart op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Collins</ENAMEX> wondering about the
priorities involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s decision to skip the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convention</ENAMEX> to go watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder Cup</ENAMEX>. Not to mention his decision once
there to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and inspire the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to victory by comparing the
final day's competition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> appeals to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. In an apparent attempt to lock up the
inarticulate mesomorph vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> last night, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , got the
endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaquille O'Neal</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
