
   
   
      
         
            More on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boomers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Mossberg</ENAMEX>

            For those arriving late to this dispute: In an earlier item ("
FDR: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock 'n' Roll</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wrote that "boomer math
contradicts the boomer mythology that it was the baby boom that first absorbed
rock 'n' roll into the mass culture." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s proof was that the first
rock 'n' roll records that reached a large, mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Haley</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comets' "Rock Around the Clock</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX>'s "Heartbreak
Hotel"--were released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955 and 1956</TIMEX>. The oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 and 10</NUMEX>, respectively--too young, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> reasoned, to be buying
rock 'n' roll records.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter S. Mossberg</ENAMEX>, who writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Technology"</ENAMEX> column,

wrote in to dispute this last point. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, the link to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossberg</ENAMEX>'s
column that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> doesn't work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't
subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s online edition; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has now
substituted a link that will work for everyone, free of charge.) Mossberg
explained that he was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1947</TIMEX>, and that he was buying rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'n</ENAMEX>' roll records at the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, which of course would have been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> replied that he could easily picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossberg</ENAMEX> (with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>
formerly worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>) as a smart-alecky
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX> but that he doubted many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossberg</ENAMEX>'s cohort were
similarly precocious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> then invited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52- and 53-year-olds</TIMEX> to enlighten

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fray</ENAMEX>" as to whether,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossberg</ENAMEX>, they were buying rock 'n' roll records at the age of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>.

            Fray postings immediately started pouring in from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who said that yes,
they are about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossberg</ENAMEX>'s age, and yes, they were buying rock 'n' roll records
starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1950s</TIMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will now yield on this point--while
noting this doesn't really undermine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s larger point that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> is an
unacknowledged founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of rock 'n' roll. (For the details, see the

<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> item.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> were part of the record-buying public that
made rock 'n' roll an art form for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> (as opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and
a few white hipsters) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1950s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> continues to doubt, however,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> represented a majority of that public until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>.

            Please note the important distinction between listening to rock 'n'
roll music (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, was listening to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> well
before he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) and buying rock 'n' roll records (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> didn't buy
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> record--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LP</ENAMEX> or single--until long after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> breakup).
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraygrants</ENAMEX> (click here and
here
for examples) missed this distinction. Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraygrant Sharon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  I plugged (!) the family radio into the wall by my bed, turned it low and
listened past my bedtime to the real thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaVerne Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Richard</ENAMEX>, the
Cadillacs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coasters</ENAMEX>--just about every black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, every doo-wop group
around, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dion</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belmonts</ENAMEX> (fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronxites</ENAMEX>). Not only did we listen
to it, but us little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> actually stood under the lamppost and sang a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cappella</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            But, except in the highly attenuated sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX> was boosting the
ratings of radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> that were playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaVerne Baker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Richard</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cadillacs and the Coasters</ENAMEX>, she wasn't really putting money into these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>' pockets (or, as was more often the case, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>' record labels'
pockets)--as she would have been doing had she bought their records
after hearing them on the radio.

            That said, it must be conceded that several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraygrants</ENAMEX> did go
out and buy the records well before their teen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here and
here
and here for a
few examples.) "When 45s were king, pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> with limited finances were buying
them by the crateful," explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duffy Hawes</ENAMEX>.
Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Tso</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  I, too, was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> and bought rock 'n' roll records when I was in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> 45s I purchased was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lee Lewis</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balls of Fire</ENAMEX>." My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had purchased a custom hi-fi and I played the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> so
loud and danced <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all afternoon</TIMEX>. When he came home and heard the lyrics, he broke
the record in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. I was crushed and resented him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, I
finally realized why he thought "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Balls of Fire</ENAMEX>" was terrible for his
grade-school-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to be listening to. I had never associated the title
and lyrics to the vernacular use of the word "balls." Duh!
               

            

            Indeed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraygrant</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>--goes so far as to recall that she owned her very own copy of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>
Around the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clock"</ENAMEX> (though she's a little vague about whether she purchased it
when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years of age</TIMEX>):

            

               
                  I was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1946</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossberg</ENAMEX>, and grew up in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last day</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June of 1958</TIMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnett</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> the world has seen) let us have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. She
brought a record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, we brought our 45s (my contribution was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rock Around</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clock"</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen 11</NUMEX>- and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-olds</TIMEX> danced for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>! How had
we learned? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year</TIMEX> of watching <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Bandstand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> after school
and practicing in front of the TV.
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will give the final word to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mossberg</ENAMEX>, who has shown himself to be
a gracious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> in this argument:

            

               
                  Everybody, including me, concedes that the older non-boomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> played
some role in the adoption of early rock, even though ultimately these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> didn't get it and we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> did. And you're correct that boomer
propaganda never allows for this possibility. Your only mistake was totally
writing off the mystical power of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>. But how were
you to know? Born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>! You can't even remember black-and-white TV or those
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">transistor</ENAMEX> radios that one of the 
                  Fray
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">people</ENAMEX> 
                  mentioned [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ahem</ENAMEX>, actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can remember
these things, but that's a small point] ...
               

               
                  I honestly think this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-to-12-year-old</TIMEX> age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and
roll, against the wishes of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, cemented into us older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> two
lessons that were behind much of what happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>:
               

            

            

               

                  Question authority

                  Age matters

               

            

            

               Because of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, we had a lot in common with each other that neither our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> nor our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> or older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> shared. It was the start of the
feeling, right or wrong, of generational bonding, and of boomer exceptionalism,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX> so despise ... I can still vividly remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> I went to
buy my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> rpm record, using my own funds. And I wanted something like
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maybelline</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Berry</ENAMEX> or maybe "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wake Up Little Susie</ENAMEX>" by the Everly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX>. But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> forced me to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>, horrible pop tune
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melodie D'Amour</ENAMEX>
                  " by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills Brothers</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX> or some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame brothers</ENAMEX>. I never let him do that again, and I never
forgot that lesson about the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority figures</ENAMEX> can screw you.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interestingly</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and I later developed a great relationship, and he swore
he couldn't remember the incident. But it was etched in my mind.)
               

            

         
      
   
