
   
   
      
         
            Promises, Promises

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads
with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are likely to dip into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security surplus--despite repeated promises to the contrary--as they finalize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> bills <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The top story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is a highly critical
post-mortem on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> diplomacy, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reports abusive discipline meted out by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Youth Authority</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surplus for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 2000</TIMEX>, which
begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, has soared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $150 billion</NUMEX>. That's proved too large a
pile of cash for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to resist, even though party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> vowed to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who'd listen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> was
absolutely, thoroughly sacrosanct. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, already having
earmarked all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s general fund surpluses for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two fiscal</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, will likely take anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion to $30 billion</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> coffers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
on a constant lookout for mud to sling during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX>'s races, are observing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> flip-flop "in a state of barely restrained glee."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
efforts to keep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> independence vote from turning violent
may have been doomed from the start. In what it calls a "case study" of the
problems that plague <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> intervention, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> gives a blow-by-blow account
of how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> wriggled out of Western demands that it agree in advance to
shackle pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jarkata</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> and guarantee the safety of foreign
election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> preoccupied by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> as the negotiations
began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> requested that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>, its former colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX>,
sit across the bargaining table. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> quoted by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> "took <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> to the cleaners." Even
before the ink was dry on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5 election</TIMEX> agreement, many at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> were
privately predicting exactly the kind of violence and chaos that followed the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX> pro-independence landslide.

            Disciplinary excesses are commonplace at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth Authority</ENAMEX>, according a report prepared for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> and obtained
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Guard abuses included cavalierly
injecting disorderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> with anti-psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and isolating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
from rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> together in small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. In the latter cases, known inside the
prison as the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> fights," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> would sometimes put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crips</ENAMEX> in a holding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> with a hated <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood</ENAMEX>, lock the door, and stand back to
watch. The staged confrontations ostensibly were used to test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>' ability
to avoid fights and thus their readiness to enter the general prison
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, but the report says they often escalated into predictably bloody
violence.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager explores
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s criminal investigation of the tobacco industry
unraveled. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> announced a large-scale
civil lawsuit against cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s ambitious criminal
case wound up leading to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> charge: a misdemeanor count against a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that has admitted developing a high-nicotine tobacco
seed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown & Williamson</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> faces a lower burden of proof
in civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, it decided to make the bulk of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco
case there.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s top non-local
story is on the architectural wreckage that litters <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> in the wake of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s massive earthquake. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that construction shortcuts
were common in older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">high-rises</ENAMEX>, including cases where building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> used
vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> cans instead of bricks. Surprisingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
lowered the estimated death toll from the quake since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just over</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>, apparently because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were counted twice.

            Under a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-column photograph on its front page, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
considering the highly controversial step of dismantling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snake River</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX>, which went up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> and provide
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 4 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX>'s electricity, have killed off nearly
all the river's varieties of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX>. But even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> concede it's
far from clear if taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> out of service would revive the fish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> assembles his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, he is freezing out most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington GOP</ENAMEX> brain trust and hiring a steady stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> instead. The
paper says some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s reluctance to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> types stems from a
longstanding distrust of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>, which goes back to his
student <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a story on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">winemakers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Champagne</ENAMEX> region, who are telling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> not to
worry--there'll be plenty of authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> bubbly to go around come Y2K <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eve</TIMEX>.
After breathless references in its opening paragraphs to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Champagne</ENAMEX> rationing
and skyrocketing demand, the story goes on to report rather quietly that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
sales are expected to rise <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 15 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>, who
is pretty sure the world will survive, likes his front-page stories with a
little more fizz.

         
      
   
