
   
   
      
         
            Get Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where You Once Belonged</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Witold</ENAMEX>,

            And so, the last of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Raps</ENAMEX>, our chance encounters on this
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">neotraditionalist cyber-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street corner</ENAMEX>, a corner that suffers as an intellectual
environment (as does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> inform us) from having too much
traffic and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. It's an apt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, for all that: another attempt to
manufacture community out of a community-alienating, sprawl-inducing product,
in this case, the Internet. One wonders: Is 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Celebration</ENAMEX>? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration Disney</ENAMEX>'s

                  Slate
               ? Is our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX> a sock hop, and you and I
like the columns on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration</ENAMEX>'s city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>? I've wondered why that building
was engineered to present such an elaborate display of democracy in a town
where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> has been supplanted by corporate control. But then, why are we
being paid, by the medium that's supplanting print, to prop up the illusion of
print's importance?

            I'd like to end my side our conversation with a parable. I'm not sure what
it means. While researching my last book, in which I devote a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> to
talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX>, I lived in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fernandina Beach</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandina</ENAMEX> is exactly the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX> would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emulate</ENAMEX>: close, old, quaintly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX>, rife with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX>, history, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pedestrians</ENAMEX>, and all the forms of old-style <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. While
Celebration promotes itself as a model for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> innocence, hearkening back
to the way we were pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, before we were so corrupted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fernandina Beach</ENAMEX> was literally (and literarily) the model for another
and more cautionary rendition of that same '40s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ur-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> Metalious
lived there when she was writing Peyton Place (though her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> made
her relocate her novel to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>) and I must say from my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> residing
there that in the vividness of its intrigues the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> lives up to its
billing.

            As I took Celebration to task for its faux history and democracy, I
reflected back on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandina</ENAMEX>, which was, whatever else might be "Peyton
Place-ish," at least a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, the product of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of
conflicts bloodier by far than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parent</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> school disputes. It was also a
living temple of participatory democracy, and watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system work
there on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election nights</TIMEX> and at meetings of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Port Commissions</ENAMEX> and Mosquito
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Boards</ENAMEX> became my vision of what a corporate-confection like Celebration
could not replicate.

            Now along come <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ross</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Collins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Frantz</ENAMEX>, and
what they have to say about what they saw in Celebration troubles, or at least
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complicates</ENAMEX>, my formula. Because this is the problem: In the face of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">postwar</ENAMEX>, retail, mobile, corporate culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> is not only a seemingly
ineffectual anodyne to social blight; it becomes a part of the problem. Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> has become a hideous sprawl of ticky-tack in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
made it the largest tourist destination in the world. You could say that
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commerce</ENAMEX> created the problem. But only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> can seemingly
solve it, since the problem evidently thrives on the democratic turf, and not
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> campus (whose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kremlinesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, dominated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s apparatchik, levies its own taxes and polices its own zoning and
safety regulations under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> law) nor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX>. What are we to do
with this? What exactly does it mean?

            I returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandina</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to catch up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and I found it
changed. For a long while, now, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> discovered the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, sweatshirt and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knick</ENAMEX>-knack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> have been replacing the general merchandise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> of a
working <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, until now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre Street</ENAMEX> is one long tourist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. They even play
melodies from loudspeakers just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX> did until the influence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Eisner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A.M. Stern</ENAMEX> put a stop to it. Since I left,
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandina</ENAMEX> the place that neotraditionalist
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> wants so desperately to return to have disappeared: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> have
moved out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> has moved out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>.
Even the county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> has left its century-old brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with the clock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tower</ENAMEX> and moved out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> objected, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> didn't care, and the big money (much of it developer money) was
all on the side of turning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandina</ENAMEX> into a theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. So that's what
happened. Democracy is destroying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> of democracy.

            But that is not the ultimate point of my parable. At the same time as all
this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fernandina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have been enthralled by
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">development</ENAMEX> that has been zoned and permitted and is now rising to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandina</ENAMEX>'s east. I've talked with some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fernandina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who can't wait to
leave their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred-year-old</TIMEX>, history-laden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and move in there. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> is a neotraditionalist, new urbanist "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" that promises to
re-create the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> not unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernandina</ENAMEX>. It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">little Celebration</ENAMEX>, its mawkish marketing and sentimental architecture direct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seaside</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX> And what I want to know is: Where
are we when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> deserts its roots to race to a place that promises to
return it to its roots? What happens when the economic interests that are
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">destroying American</ENAMEX> society are pretending to reconstitute it right next door?
This is why the books of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ross</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Frantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Collins</ENAMEX>
are needed. It's why we have been corresponding, and why I've enjoyed the
chance, even on so noisy a street corner, to chat with you.

            Next time, let's get a drink.

            With regards and respect,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russ Rymer</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
