
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Trial 9/21/99

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahlia Lithwick</ENAMEX> worked for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in a family law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nev.</ENAMEX> She is writing a novel about how
divorce affects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. She writes a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> column for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottawa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizen</ENAMEX>.

            Such is the rhythm of our legal system: Something quite
simple ("I want a divorce") is made exceedingly complex ("What percentage of
your income goes to the phone bills?") only to be made too simple again
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> gets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter; Mother</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>.")

            One learns this phenomenon within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of entering
law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Simple facts ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angus</ENAMEX> refused to sing 'In<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gadda-Da-Vida</ENAMEX>' at the
Goldstein bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mitzvah</ENAMEX>") generate pages of abstract legal theory ("Was there a
meeting of the minds about whose version he was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">to sing?</ENAMEX>"). Your job as law
student is to distill all this down to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-paragraph summary in case you are
called upon in class. You will later boil it down to a one-sentence summary for
an outline you'll use to study for finals. The point may or may not appear in
the exam.

            Such expansion and contraction mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are
never quite certain how big or important things are. This is why we yell about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paperclips</ENAMEX> and sleep through death-penalty cases.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial has been called the antitrust trial
of the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. As have the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> antitrust trials
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. It began as a few disputed sentences in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> consent decree
limiting some alleged anti-competitive jiggery-pokery by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-to-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-week</TIMEX> trial" metastasized into a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">76-day</TIMEX> ordeal spanning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 months</TIMEX>
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of exhibits. It might have grown even
the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and kinds of testimony to prevent the legal entropy
that produces an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> trial.

            When testimony ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>, it looked for a moment
as though <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Computing</ENAMEX> as We Know It was on the line. But things got quiet, we
tried instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">messaging</ENAMEX>, we maybe upgraded, and we bought orange <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> vests
online.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> gave money away.

            Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> the case contracted even
more, with each side submitting proposed findings of fact, then revised
versions of same, each of which told a condensed version of their story from
trial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> used its monopoly power in the operating
systems market to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> and threaten its way into dominance over the browser
market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> argued that it acted competitively in a competitive market,
that distribution channels for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> were never foreclosed, and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> have not been harmed.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More paperclips</ENAMEX>!"

            Today, with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half hours</TIMEX> allocated to each side
for closing arguments, the case contracts once again until it is virtually
dancing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the pin. Except for the venue--proceedings moved
upstairs to a vast <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> District <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX> where we sit under
the watchful statue eyes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justinian, Hammurabi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solon</ENAMEX>--little has
changed. Except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have traded their fine brushes for broad
ones--paint rollers, perhaps--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case appears even smaller than
it did before.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boies</ENAMEX>,
who cross-examined some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star witnesses</ENAMEX> into sweaty little
ribbons at trial, simply hands out his outline to the class. He spends the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> walking us through the elements of antitrust law and offering evidence
from the record to support his claims. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who virtually commanded the
small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom downstairs</ENAMEX> during trial, seems somewhat diminished <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But
he makes his points: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has monopoly power for operating systems;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> maintained its operating system monopoly through anti-competitive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">practices; Microsoft</ENAMEX> used that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> to try to monopolize the browser
market; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> engaged in contracts and conspiracies in restraint of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Warden</ENAMEX> takes a different tack.
Speaking as though his mouth is full of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aquarium gravel</ENAMEX>, he paints everything
larger than it is. His job is simple: He must punch holes into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
soft places. He does not use an outline. He simply begins to roar. The
government has never, ever proved that their browser and operating systems are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">separable</ENAMEX>. (Whether they were designed to be
inseparable he leaves for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX>). In swinging away at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
weak spots (market definition, harm to consumer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s market
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penetration</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warden</ENAMEX> employs the kind of hyperbole usually reserved for
domestic fights about who does the dishes. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has offered
no evidence"; "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> offered
no analysis"; "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has never induced an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM</ENAMEX> to drop their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' products."

            ("But Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warden</ENAMEX>, we saw the contracts ...")

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never</ENAMEX>!" he roars. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baloney</ENAMEX>," he sputters. At some
point he coughs so hard that someone at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> table hands him a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cough</ENAMEX> drop.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX> and shams," he snarls. When he concludes, it is with an ominous
reference to central planning. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boies</ENAMEX> rises for his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX> rebuttal, you
can almost hear the drumbeats from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Square</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boies</ENAMEX> immediately agrees. Central planning is
bad. The balalaikas recede. Then he whips out his outline. He focuses narrowly,
perhaps too much so: The consumer has been harmed; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> did what they did
not to sell more copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>, but rather, to stop their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Now
we are all dancing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a pin.

            The trial ends without fanfare. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> pounds
his gavel and leaves the massive courtroom. Now he will reduce these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of facts to an even smaller opinion. In the interim, technologies will change
and change again. When the dust settles, if it ever settles, all of this will
stand for something very great in the casebooks and the exam papers.

            Unless it stands for something very small.

            
               
                  Click
here  for dispatches from the last session of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between October 1998 and February 1999</TIMEX>.
               
            

         
      
   
