
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin Cycle</ENAMEX>
            

            If you weren't paying attention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>--and even if you
were--you might have missed the dramatic fall in the stock of washing-machine
maker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX>, which began on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and continued through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> has gained a lot of attention recently for its fantastic high-end
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neptune</ENAMEX> washer and its high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, it's not exactly the kind of company
that makes your ears perk up. But the story of what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX>, or more
precisely the story of how Wall Street reacted to what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX>, is
such a clear illustration of the Street's conviction that there's nothing wrong
with inside information as to be almost a parody.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX>'s stock was driven down because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is
going to fall far short of earnings estimates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two quarters</TIMEX>.
Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> didn't find that out until the company
announced the shortfall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two full days</TIMEX> of massive selling
on no news at all. Well, no public news, that is. Clearly lots of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knew something.

            Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> insists that it didn't even know things were
going to be so bad until its sales numbers came in, and that it didn't tell any
of its big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> to get out before the bad news broke. Perhaps. But
trading volume on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times normal, and trading volume on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times normal. A lot of that, of course, was just momentum
selling, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leapt out of the way of what quickly became a falling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>.
But the size of the trades was such that the whole situation looks decidedly
sketchy.

            Here's the quirk in the whole story, though. Among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> raising the possibility that large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> were informed in advance
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> at some of Wall Street's biggest investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and brokerage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX>. And among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most annoyed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s late announcement
are those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. Why? Because when they talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag Thursday</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> reassured them that nothing was wrong, and that there would
be no change in their earnings forecasts.

            Let's get this straight. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> are annoyed because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> didn't tell them that something was wrong before it told the
public that something was wrong. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> didn't give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> the chance to tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to sell before other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
realized something was wrong.

            Of course, this reaction was accepted as par for the
course on the Street, even though if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> had told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> anything, it
would have been as blatant a case of selective disclosure as you can imagine.
And I'd say this was astonishing, except for the fact that selective disclosure
remains a painfully common practice. Non-institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are excluded
from company conference calls and snubbed by investor-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> continue to disclose material information to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> before issuing
press releases. And they spend far more time talking to large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> than
they do talking to the public.

            The ironic thing, then, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> did the right thing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, even if it looks as if someone at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maytag</ENAMEX> might have done the
wrong thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> before. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> call, looking for
information that will help their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and only their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
should just say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz</ENAMEX> off. If we have something important to say, you'll find
out when everyone else does." Oh, I how long to be a fly on the wall for that
conversation. (Well, actually, I don't want to be a fly, since they have short
and miserable lives. But you get the point.)

         
      
   
