
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outbreak</ENAMEX>
            

            Gosh, I don't know. I'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Salter's</ENAMEX>. Did you ever read A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pastime</ENAMEX> ? It's a fantastic novel, fantastic, and I wonder if
anyone even knows about it. Last night, while wasting time in the usual online
fashion, I came across a chance to vote for the novel of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, from a
list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> chosen by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wasting time in the usual online fashion,
and it certainly didn't include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Sport</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pastime</ENAMEX> , which it should
have. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> was on the list. Of course, I loved
Gone <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With the Wind</ENAMEX> . And it certainly fits the definition of literature
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salter</ENAMEX> put forth -"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Literature …</ENAMEX> is really only writing that never stops
being read"-for which definition alone I salute him. The point is, I liked the
Salter piece, even though it left me feeling absolutely helpless. I mean, what
am I to do? Should I finally read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plato</ENAMEX>? Should I give more money to the public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>? Should I stop making movies? No, yes, and no; so much for that. And by
the way, I don't believe for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> made up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> of the words he used. Where do statistics like that come from? I mean,
just because a word appears for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in a book doesn't mean the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> invented it. (Did you read the book about the convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> who
worked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX>? It's amazing.)

            I am berserk about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> , as is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, in
fact, could certainly have been the inspiration for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livia Soprano</ENAMEX>.

            I do not find the mosquito spraying quaint. Now that I am in the movie
business, I see everything as the beginning of a bad movie, and this one ends
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> dying before a cure is found. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the things I
always find so wonderful about life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is how oblivious we tend to be
to things like the possibility of natural disasters, but the encephalitis thing
made me happy to be leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, where there are only
earthquakes to worry about.

            What is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moebius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
