
   
   
      
         
            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taiwan Shake All Day</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s massive earthquake, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> reported that there
had already been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX> aftershocks. Even using conservative
estimates, this implies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> aftershock <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 24</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. Could this be true?

            Yes. Most large earthquakes produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of aftershocks, but the
majority of them are imperceptible. And although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s reported rate is
above average, it is not considered extraordinary.

            Earthquakes are caused by the sudden release of pressure that has built up
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tectonic plates. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> is rarely discharged in a
single jolt, earthquakes almost always occur in clusters: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, a few small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreshocks</ENAMEX>; then the strongest quake, or mainshock; then aftershocks. An
aftershock is defined as a quake that occurs on or near the original fault
(usually within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 miles</NUMEX> of the epicenter) and before the region's seismic
activity has returned to normal.

            Some faults, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Andreas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>, are seismically
active long after a major quake and can experience aftershocks up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
later. But most aftershocks happen soon after the primary quake. In fact,
seismologists have a rough method for predicting the number of aftershocks on a
given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>: It declines in inverse proportion to the time since the mainshock
(i.e., day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four</TIMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth</NUMEX> the number of quakes as day <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> estimate that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of aftershocks are below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> on the Richter
scale, and not generally perceived by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a
good explanation of the Richter scale and here for the effects of various quakes.) In the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>
following <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>'s mainshock, for example, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only seven</NUMEX> quakes that
would have done more than lightly rattle dishes. So, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> was technically
shaking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably didn't know it.

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks 
               
                  Slate
                
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reader Tom Castle</ENAMEX> for
submitting this question, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Peng</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>
Earthquake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Smith</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Geological Survey Earthquake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Center</ENAMEX> for helping to answer it.
            

         
      
   
