
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uses of Adversity</ENAMEX>
            

            Ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Witold</ENAMEX>,

            You are a gentleman, and have generously let me get
away with a couple of whoppers, which I must address before we get started on
this next round. In my zeal to defend our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ross</ENAMEX>, I've given myself the
necessity of defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Frantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Collins</ENAMEX>--from myself. One
of the only luxuries of traditional long-form prose is the chance to read over
in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> what one thought brilliant at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> and chuck it. But now we
have the Send key, that great enabler of the slipshod thought, and verily I
have not mastered the button, because as soon as the coffee kicked in this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, I cringed at what I saw. For anyone misled by my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> garbled posting
(quickly corrected), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> did interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>, and if
their conversation did not widen to encompass the far corners of the solar
system then that is no affront to their book, which is subtitled, after all,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living in Disney's Brave New Town</ENAMEX>," and not "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theorizing About Creation in Its</ENAMEX>
Enormity!"

            But my notes also remind me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>
have themselves leapt the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Vinyl Fence</ENAMEX> when they felt the urge, and have,
for instance, documented elegantly the plight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> unable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">afford Celebration</ENAMEX>, who must rely on impact fees to help with their mortgages.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mea dammit culpa</ENAMEX>. It is said it is the luxury of the Internet that what the
Send key giveth, the Send key can taketh away, but I still regret the error,
especially in a missive declaring the requirement to respect the literary
endeavor.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in both these books
fascinated me, especially insofar as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, though technically under the
aegis of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osceola County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, were such centerpieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s design and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s pitch. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> considered Celebration a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> before it
considered it a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point planning to situate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Institute</ENAMEX>
there. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> may be a hard-core, bottom-line business with a wealth of
real estate and construction experience, but because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has been an
entertainment medium for so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and been that before
all else, I believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> would locate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s heart closer
to education than town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> should conceivably have been the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>'s one ironclad asset.

            And in a curious way, it has turned out to be just
that. The question that in a real way motivates both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration, U.S.A.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Celebration</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronicles</ENAMEX> is this: How does an idealized place built by a dream factory
and marketed as a utopia become real? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration Company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> wanted
their artificial creation to rise up off the gurney, but didn't know what kind
of lightning bolt might galvanize their <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recount Celebration</ENAMEX>'s efforts to create "new traditions" through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-sponsored sock hops, pumpkin carvings, parades, and crafts fairs. But in
the long run, what has worked best is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could not at all
provide, except inadvertently: conflict and difficulty. You ask if the
Celebration's first committed crime was a setback or a victory, and your point
is well taken. Were I deputized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osceola County Sheriff's Office</ENAMEX> to look
into the matter, my primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> would be some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> "cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>" in a
company-supplied <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">burglar</ENAMEX>'s mask, so deftly did the crime advance the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s
necessary maturation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school kerfuffle</ENAMEX> did the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> reports,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrationites</ENAMEX> encountered obstacles to happiness that compelled them to
forge community bonds ... The strong community its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> had hoped for would
come into being as much in response to adversity as to the conveniences and
advantages built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s design."

            It's an encouraging irony that a creation as
poster-pretty and perfectly controlled as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX> would be sparked into
real vitality by the inevitability of a little discord, and that error would
favor it so. (Would that the errors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers shone</ENAMEX> so well to their
credit.)

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
