
   
   
      
         
            Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spake Groucho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>
            

            Do you remember the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time you ever heard the expression, "There's no
there there"? I do. I practically remember where I was sitting when I first
read it. Of course, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>, speaking of the place she grew up,
which I'm pretty sure was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cal</ENAMEX>. This is the sort of thing I could check
if I weren't in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. So, forgive me if it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>. Anyway, what a
great line. What a great great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX>! I mean, when I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> came across it, I
just stopped reading for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> and rolled that line around in my brain
and thought, I would kill to say something that amazing. There's no there
there. No there there. It's right up there with "Everyone will be famous for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>," which is definitely another of the other top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> lines of the last l00
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            Anyway, you are right about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and just about everyone: no
there there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> I find dangerous precisely because he will win according to
my criteria (and yours), and he knows absolutely nothing. Also, call me crazy,
but I hate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Could never vote for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Just couldn't. It's as close
as I get to being a practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. I mean, God would strike me dead if I voted
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. If I believed in God. And those horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> nominate really matter. (Although it's surprising and fascinating
to see what's happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor</ENAMEX> and--of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Souter</ENAMEX>
as they've carved out a middle-of-the-road pragmatism no one could ever have
predicted.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the things I always find interesting about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, where I grew up
waiting desperately for the moment I could get out, is how it found its "there"
(kind of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> did). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Allen</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> is great if you're an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orange</ENAMEX>." Another of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, don't you think?

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groucho Marx</ENAMEX>: "I wouldn't join any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> that would have me as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>."
(Probably not quite accurately quoted, but as I say, there's no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s in my hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.)

            I've been told that all sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have "worked with" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. I think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sydney Pollack</ENAMEX> tried to help, although I could be wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s TV-Q has
definitely improved: He was great on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>,
as relaxed as he'd been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> I saw him in person. But I've also been told
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, and it seems to be truly useless. I mean,
if you just tied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s hands together and lashed them down, it would be an
improvement. If I were trying to help him, I would tell him to never ever read
from a speech--that just makes the performance even more deadly. He should
always work from index cards with no more than a word or two written on them.
Well, so should anyone who gives a speech. I wanted to die when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> got up
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX> shootings and stood there holding a sheet of paper with a
speech on it that he dutifully read from. On the other hand, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> runs
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, we will both be voting for him, I guarantee it.

            More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> shot with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. Another thing I like about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
is his position on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> today there's an article
that says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX> has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> to be its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest speaker</ENAMEX> at a
fund-raiser <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> is anti-NRA, and this is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> who refuses to take a position against cop-killer bullets.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who booked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> for the speech has this to say: "I was unaware until
after he accepted that he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>."

            Well, I am off to work. And so this is the end of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> together. I feel
relieved, because frankly my entire life has ground to a halt for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> while I feverishly tried to think of things to say. But I also feel sad.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX>, there's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty to talk about, and while I'm sure
we'll both see it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, and maybe we'll even e-mail each other
about it now that we know each other's addresses, no one will be
listening .

            xoxoxox

         
      
   
