
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Doesn't Go Soft

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the imminent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landfall</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> somewhere along the southeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> coast. The storm is also
the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">runs Floyd</ENAMEX> top-front, but leads instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s passage <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> of
a campaign reform bill that would ban "soft money" and tightly regulate
"issues" ads in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two months</TIMEX> preceding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX>, to prevent these two
items from becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> for flouting contribution limits that are supposed
to apply to individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The other papers front the bill.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> killed, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.9 billion</NUMEX> damage,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> killed, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 billion</NUMEX> damage, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls it "one of the most dangerous storms of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> are grim enough that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took the
unprecedented step of declaring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> disaster areas even before
the storm arrived. The coverage ticks off some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassandra</ENAMEX> factors:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fleeing their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> (with all the fronts that run
pictures showing the resultant traffic jams); the mass cancellation of airline
flights; and the first-time-ever shutdown of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX>.

            The coverage notes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passed a nearly identical
campaign reform bill, which, despite drawing a majority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filibustered</ENAMEX> to death there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason for the extent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> antipathy to such measures: In a recent closed-door meeting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were told that for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-98</TIMEX> election cycle, their party
held a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $40 million</NUMEX> advantage over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in soft money. There
actually is one important new feature of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s reform bill: It contains a
provision requiring "a candidate for election for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> (other than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who holds Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>)" to reimburse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for federally
provided transportation used for campaign purposes. Can you say "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>"?
Apparently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> cannot. And by the way, why should
incumbents be able to fly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uncle Sugar Airlines</ENAMEX> without paying?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ignatius</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> column, identifies what he calls our
tendency toward "sequential hysteria," the phenomenon in which a problem is
well recognized long before it reaches a critical stage, then for a few brief
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> it becomes Topic A, but then before long it's back to inattention, all
without anything ever really being done about it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ignatius</ENAMEX> gives as examples
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> corruption scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> atomic espionage, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> nuclear threat, and genocide in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. A good point, but marred
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ignatius</ENAMEX>, trying to tie up his column too neatly with a bow made from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>'s news, adds <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX> to his list. The problem is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> hasn't been
known about for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and things are really being done in reaction to
it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" depends a little too much
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rossotti</ENAMEX>, judging from how frequently the good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> appears in the column being a ... well, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
effort, for instance, includes mention of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rossotti</ENAMEX> "always enjoyed solving
problems when he was in business. 'And now,' he says, 'I have an unlimited
supply of problems to solve.' " This is called "greasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>," and is a
major source of skewed coverage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homework</ENAMEX> assignment: find an example where the
"Tax Report" said something truly tough about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Fire Department</ENAMEX> is caught up in
a controversy stemming from the revelation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that for the neighborhoods
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bel</ENAMEX>-Air, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pacific Palisades</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brentwood</ENAMEX>, it has introduced maps
that identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with the highest risk of burning: those with wood
shingle roofs. The city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">councilman</ENAMEX> for the area involved has called for a full
public debate about whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAFD</ENAMEX> is in fact writing off certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> in case of fire. Fairly far in, the story mentions that maps of other
parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> also indicate areas of risky <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, apparently without
controversy. But the LAT utterly ignores the impact of this fact, which
is the real explanation for why the maps are now "news." The story never
mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bel</ENAMEX>-Air, etc., are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s lushest neighborhoods, housing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            Tucked away on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> story that bears
watching. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> is conducting a comprehensive review of the
battle damage inflicted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> during the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and it's already past
due. A delay like this is sometimes a sign that unwelcome figures are being
"massaged" into the most favorable shape possible. So it will be interesting to
see if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> scorecard goes the way of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Patriot</ENAMEX> missile
totting up, which went from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-war</TIMEX> near-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> intercept rate to a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning-</TIMEX>after count much closer to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>, if that. Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX>
stands ready to make an argument either way. If the numbers are good, then the
refrain will be, "See, this stuff works, give us more stuff." And if not, it'll
be, "This stuff didn't work as well as we'd like, we need better stuff."

         
      
   
