
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woman Bites Cop</ENAMEX>
            

            But what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to whom they wouldn't deign to speak if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in question weren't (check <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>) funny or charming or driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corvette</ENAMEX>
or head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> or the best bowler in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>? I mean, I wouldn't even
have known anyone I was ever in love with if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in question were
"mere wage-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX>," and I once lost all interest in someone because I didn't
like his writing. Which I didn't read until it was a little too late.

            No, I did not vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. I didn't vote at all in that
election. I couldn't. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delia</ENAMEX> didn't vote either, and turned it into a
very funny scene in You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> starts a fight with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Kinnear</ENAMEX> by announcing that instead of voting in that election, she went to
get a manicure.

            I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>'s a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, by the way, and a city probably needs a
Fascist to run it, etc. But a close woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine was jumped by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and arrested and held for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 24 hours</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in a case of
completely mistaken identity; the charges were dropped, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of trauma
for her and astronomical legal fees. The episode made me conscious, in a way I
might never have been (but any black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is), of what the cost of all this
zero tolerance is. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says that one of the side-effects of this lower
crime rate is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are arresting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
are already locked up. But promotions are based on the number of arrests, so
the cops are under increased pressure to arrest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-and sometimes that
pressure causes them to try to escalate a misdemeanor into a felony. My friend
who was arrested, for example, was not charged with the thing she was jumped
for-drug dealing, which she was completely innocent of-but of resisting arrest.
She did resist arrest, by the way; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> was in plainclothes, and she had no
idea he even was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, so she bit him.

            I feel bad about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, a place I had never heard of. These things
happen: You see the headline, and you think, please let this go away, please
don't make me have to learn about yet another place I have never heard of, and
then it doesn't. It took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> before I realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> wasn't exactly
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. I am glad to talk about it if you insist. You first, though.

            Meanwhile, here's a truly disturbing trend: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waiters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> have now
taken to not writing down your order. Is this yet another plot to make those of
us with short-term memory loss feel bad about it? Or is it just another bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> in restaurant life, like those horrible little designs made of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate syrup</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> plate?

         
      
   
