
   
   
      
         
            Starting Over
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Russ</ENAMEX>,

            I'm glad you mentioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Send Key Syndrome</ENAMEX>. Writing
these "reviews," in quick succession without the benefit of endless editing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rewriting</ENAMEX>, which is how I normally work (yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, those "readable" books
are the result of great effort), has brought home to me one quality of this
sort of communication--it is really more like a street-corner conversation than
anything else. Certainly not a debate, let alone an essay--or a considered book
review for that matter. In fact, it is more like gossiping than anything else.
So, perhaps 
                  Slate
               
should rename this section <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Chat, or Book Rap</ENAMEX>, or something like that.

            Getting back to Celebration. I agree entirely that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are cemented by adversity, although I don't think that absolves
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> from a royal screw-up with respect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. I can't think what
they imagined when they marketed an "old-fashioned town" and then put in place
an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that would be considered radical even in communities
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>. Incidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> offers the interesting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisner</ENAMEX> himself, who is a supporter of nontraditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, who had a lot to do with the revolutionary curriculum.

            Still, the question you ask is exactly right: How can a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> that markets escapism make a real place? The answer, I suspect, is
"with great difficulty." Which is the reason there will not be other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">towns</ENAMEX>. Nor should there be, in my view. That is why the fears expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross</ENAMEX>
and to a lesser extent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> about corporate urbanism are
misplaced. There won't be any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> built by mega-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsico</ENAMEX>. Of course, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>-planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are built by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, but they are relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that specialize in
"creating community." I'm thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that build places like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irvine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cal.</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vail</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Cities</ENAMEX>. And they are much more skillful at their
business than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> proved to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX>.

            Which is why, despite the excellent town planning and
generally high quality of the architecture, I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX> is a
model. I've talked to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the real estate industry, and the
consensus is that a) no one but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> could have built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Celebration</ENAMEX>, and b)
even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> can't be making money. No doubt we do need to find new urban models
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the millions</NUMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that will be built over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decades</TIMEX>. In
that regard, Celebration offers lessons, rather than a prototype.

            Or perhaps Celebration is really another manifestation
of a (uniquely?) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> phenomenon: the visionary community. Referring to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castro</ENAMEX> district in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>-inspired
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commune</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> wrote that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> were all
inspired by "the extraordinary notion that they could start all over again from
scratch." In many ways, that is the theme of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books we have been
chatting about: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to start over.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
Witold

         
      
   
