
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>. Not a
real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> she knew, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, the kind with spotlights
outside that shuts a neighborhood down. It was opening <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>
Zone, a shiny new theme restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suggestively</ENAMEX> located on the ground floor of
the shiny new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CondÃ© Nast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> was there, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martina Navratilova</ENAMEX> and hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Gretzky</ENAMEX> and
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Russell</ENAMEX>--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> only learned of their
attendance from the press release she picked up as she left. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, having
allowed themselves to be interviewed on the way in and broadcast on giant
screens to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> below, floated past in their bubbles of
protective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> so quickly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> never saw their faces.

            Some fun was had, though fun was not the point. (The point is reading about
everyone else's fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>.) There was the curiosity of being part of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>--as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at birthday
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>--likely ever to pack this dining-establishment-cum-gaming-center again.
There were the excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sushi</ENAMEX> and crab legs and lushly lit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> at the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Studio Grill</ENAMEX>," a food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> modeled on a TV sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, which will surely
not serve such fare in the future. There were bass fishing and skateboarding
and parachuting against computers. On the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> pushed past
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day of the LocustÂ</ENAMEX>­- like throng lining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">42nd Street</ENAMEX> and the
uniformed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> troublingly acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s bouncers,
there was the towering new entertainment complex that is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>, with all
the other theme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and studio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and the latest soon-to-open
tourist attractions, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> theater that offers neither plays nor
musicals but brief medleys of each and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> for
Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Morning America</ENAMEX> . And there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s urge to get out of
there as fast as she could.

            The economic value to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> of having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> renovate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> may be
indisputable, but when you get right down to it, or rather down in it, the
place is no fun. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> entertainment products (this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> included) belong on
television, in movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' books, on the computer, even in
amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, where there is no comparative sense of scale, such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> being
perfect, self-enclosed worlds. This is the paradox of mass culture: The more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impersonal</ENAMEX> and unreal the form, the more of a sense of direct connection you
feel. Beauty may be merely a cartoon character who exists on a variety of
so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>," but her charisma affects you as intimately as it does
her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX>. (It affects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> that way, anyway.) Project her image onto a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billboard</ENAMEX> or looming screen in a predefined geographical space, however, such
as the crowded heart of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s oldest urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, where passersby
will just have come from and will immediately go back to neighborhoods scaled
to their height and humanity, and you reveal her to be a virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> rather
than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> full of moxie. In the war between the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-style monumentalism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> predicts, monumentalism may
triumph in the short run, but street size will win out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> just
doesn't like to feel so small.

         
      
   
