
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> Takes the Plunge

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Pleasant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. C.</ENAMEX>--The usual insurgent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s strategy, which has
not actually worked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, is to score upsets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> has a slightly different idea. Because of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">long-standing</ENAMEX> opposition to ethanol subsidies, he is simply bypassing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caucuses</ENAMEX>. Instead, he's running in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, which
holds the next primary after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> is promising for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that
it's a state filled with conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>--for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> hopes to
emerge as the only viable alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> reason is
that it is rich in military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, who regard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> as one of
their own, just as they did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.

            Hence the setting for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX> announcement: a podium dressed with
black POW-MIA flags, with the carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Yorktown</ENAMEX> as a backdrop. The
ship was once part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> fleet commanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>--a connection noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. On the deck was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-4 Skyhawk</ENAMEX>, the
type of plane <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was flying when he was shot down over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX>--an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Grooms</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> who
introduced him. "While some were out dodging the draft, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> was
volunteering for active service in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grooms</ENAMEX> reminded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--which was sprinkled with purple- and orange-haired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> as well
as vets. Whether the reference was to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, or both, was
unclear.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s speech was a version of the one he gave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>,
culminating in his refrain "I am not afraid." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s speeches are extremely
well written, thanks to his gifted ghost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Salter</ENAMEX>, who helped write his book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> of My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX> . They are not terribly well delivered by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, who stumbles more in one speech than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> does in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s
worth of them. But both the prose and the delivery have the appeal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directness</ENAMEX> and sincerity.

            The most interesting thing about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s announcement was what was left out
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>. An earlier version of the prepared speech included a
semi-direct attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s education proposal. A preliminary draft
of his speech, passed out in advance, read: "There are those who would instead
propose a larger role for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> wants to
allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX> to cut off money to underprivileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
if those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do not improve their test scores over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a three-year</TIMEX>
period."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> did not deliver this criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Instead he cut straight
to the next paragraph, which draws an implicit distinction instead of an
explicit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. "While I applaud the effort to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> accountable for the
money they receive, I would strongly oppose any program that would give power
over the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> will certainly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attack Bush</ENAMEX>--he has to. But he may have decided that it makes sense to
establish a positive message before going negative on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-runner</ENAMEX>.

            It's interesting to compare the two education plans. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s plan is a
federally directed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quasi-</NUMEX>voucher scheme, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s is a federally funded voucher
experiment that emphasizes local control. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s plan is more honest than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s in some respects. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is willing to spend new
money--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.4 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. And he's explicit about where he'd get
it--by cutting corporate welfare, specifically federal subsidies for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>,
oil, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> (suggesting that he's intending to write off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s vouchers would be worth more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX>. The
problem is that that's still not enough to determine whether vouchers work.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> would pay tuition only at some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. This raises
Constitutional questions, but beyond that, it's not enough to create genuine
competitive pressure on bad public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, which is the point of
vouchers--unless you think the goal is to replace public education with private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>.

            That said, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> has some great lines about education. "There's no reason
on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> that a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> should be paid less than a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>," he
says.

            And this one, even better: "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just aren't meant to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>,
and we should help them find another line of work," he says. This draws wild
applause from the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at the front of the stage, who may think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
is promising to fire their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
