
   
   
      
         
            What Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD Scandal</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> lately have been filled with reports of
widespread corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Police Department</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX>'s worst
corruption scandal in  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX>. What is the gist of the story?

            The scandal began as a limited investigation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rampart Division</ENAMEX>, which covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight square miles</NUMEX> west
of downtown. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mack</ENAMEX> was arrested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1997</TIMEX> for robbing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of
more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months later</TIMEX>, his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael Perez</ENAMEX>, stole
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> from police evidence lockers. Believing that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> crimes
were connected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> began to examine whether other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rampart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
participated in or knowingly overlooked such misconduct.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX> agreed to cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
in exchange for a lighter sentence. Since then, he has accused several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
of dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, making wrongful arrests, planting evidence, and abusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>. He contends that such abuses of power are common--and largely
ignored--in the specialized anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> and anti-drug units of the Rampart
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX>. 

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> have been suspended so far. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX>'s
revelations have also forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to revisit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> cases that
may have relied on false testimony or evidence. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> was released after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX> admitted that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and then planted a gun on
him so they could claim self-defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> are now examining at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other shooting--this one fatal--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX> has called "dirty." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX>
could face <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multi-million-dollar</NUMEX> lawsuits from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of wrongdoing.

            No one has established any direct connections among the
various crimes yet. But federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are planning to investigate whether
the alleged misdeeds are "pattern and practice" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            Next question?

         
      
   
