
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'80s: The Decade That Wouldn't End</ENAMEX>
            

            Of course I know you know that designs on plates with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate syrup</ENAMEX> are
very <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '80s</TIMEX>. And the fact, as you note, that they haven't gone away supports
another of my theories--that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> themselves haven't gone away either. Just
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-63</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the '50s</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970-73</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the '60s</TIMEX>, we are
now a record-breaking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the present decade</TIMEX>, culturally speaking.
These may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the '80s</TIMEX> we're now living through, but I would argue
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> as a culturally distinct <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> (the Internet aside) does not
exist.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cornish game hens</ENAMEX>, drizzled chocolate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">syrup</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> sleeping with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>--food plus adultery! I am honored to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> for such a
thrilling outburst of classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ephronism</ENAMEX>. So ... How come this leitmotif informs
your fiction and now your public e-mails, but not your movies (except the one
based on your novel)? On the other hand, I guess You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>
involved quasi-adultery, and it did have the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>-scooping-up-the-caviar
scene. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mixed Nuts</ENAMEX> had a food title.

            I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Green</ENAMEX>. I've donated money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Green</ENAMEX>. Even though I guess
he's a notch or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to my left, I'd vote for him happily against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> for practically any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--because he has a sense of humor and seems like
a vital, mentally healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of strong character. So don't make me out to
be some kind of right-winger just because I voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and never much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liked Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and don't live on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX>.

            Back to hurricane readiness before I sign off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX> defense!
Yet again, I'm seeing all news through some <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'40s/'50s/</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early-'60s</TIMEX> prism. Maybe I
should have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> check this out.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, I have an impolitic question:
Have any of the big disasters we've been serially warned about for the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (multiple hurricanes, one or two comets, mobs of starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
post-welfare-reform, etc.) actually occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>? The media-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> cries
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX> an awful lot.

            OK, maybe I'm a conservative after all.

            And indeed, I'm afraid I do think most cops in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ticketing the
double-parked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> of a courteous black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> would speak exactly
the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> spoke to me on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Court Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>. In fact, it was his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stern</ENAMEX>, ridiculous policemanese--"Step away from the vehicle!"--that surprised
me, since I'm, you know, white, and middle-aged, and wear glasses.

            I too like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, and expect to vote for him in the primary. A friend
of mine who's a theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> recently told me that I should tell another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who's a speechwriter for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> that he, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, would
like to help coach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in big-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> performing skills. Which I
think would be a good idea. And which I also think is a very rich premise for a
comedy sketch.

            But my problem with politics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> (which I suppose can come across as
conservatism--and may well be, in the old-fashioned sense) is that politics
don't and really can't matter all that much in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>. There
are rough, large consensuses on all the big issues--economics, social welfare,
civil rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights, war and peace, even abortion. And they will
continue as long as the economy chugs along like this and we stay out of wars
any longer than a mini-series. Sure, there's a biggish, scary lunatic
right--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauerite</ENAMEX> creationist anti-gay regiments--but they're not going
to be running the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or amending the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> anytime soon. In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is right about the virtual indistinguishability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. I sympathize with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> viscerally,
if not ideologically. I really think national politics kind of needs to be
blown up and rebuilt. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the couple of weeks seven years ago</TIMEX> before he
revealed himself to be a horrible, crazy gnome, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> seemed to me like a
great idea. And if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next November</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, it isn't inconceivable that I would pull the lever for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>.
And I certainly wouldn't be very upset if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> won, even if he can't name a
single book he's ever read. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> final theory of mine: In presidential
elections, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who wins is the one who seems <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) most convincingly
like a sportsman and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) happiest. I think the only clear exception to the rule
from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FDR-Hoover</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, but that one was very close, and
it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, when all bets were off.)

            Have a safe trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
