
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars Attacks</ENAMEX>!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s long-expected veto of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-sponsored tax cut
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
but is carried inside elsewhere--Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s passage of a bill that would, if it became
law, make it "difficult, it not impossible" to bring large class-action suits
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as cigarette or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. The bill draws scant
attention elsewhere--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> item about
it on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> student
street riots over a just-passed bill that has raised fears of a coup because it
bestows new emergency powers on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> military. The riots are carried
inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead is what it sees as a
quiet but major shift in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> policy: dropping
opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. The story credits the
change to unnamed senior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, while quoting national security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adviser Sandy Berger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rubin</ENAMEX> as denying it. Other evidence
cited: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has not resisted the adoption inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> mark
as the legal currency and has been supportive of a plan to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>
to form a new protective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> for the region.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead explains that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill would require most class action claims to be transferred
to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, where the rules about who gets to participate in the class
and how such cases may proceed are more stringent. The bill, says the paper,
enjoys philosophical and/or lobbying support from some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s biggest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> include the trial lawyers'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls the bill's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> prospects uncertain,
whereas according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> a similar bill there
enjoys bipartisan support.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is the only one of
the papers to front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s comments <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> tech stocks are absurdly overpriced, which prompted large sell-offs at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes a stock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>'s observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s timing was bizarre, coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> announced plans to sell shares of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expedia</ENAMEX> site as a way to
participate in the Internet stock trend. The story also observes another
non-self-aggrandizing angle: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock holdings went down
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.17 billion</NUMEX> off his remarks. (By the way, would it have been illegal for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> to have sold tech stocks short before making his comments?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s realization <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mars Climate Orbiter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> has
probably burned up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>' atmosphere after flying too close to the planet.
Both stories go high with the gizmo's price: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125 million</NUMEX>.

            The WP fronts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever made a menopausal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> fertile again, by implanting her with
pieces of her own ovaries, which had been previously removed and frozen. She
hasn't got pregnant yet but has ovulated and menstruated. The development, the
paper explains, could be a boon to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> who want to have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> after treatment is concluded. And eventually it would allow healthy
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to put up a bunch of their youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> until they're ready to
have pregnancies using them later in life.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both go inside with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s
endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s primary reason for not endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> can't get elected. Both papers quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s
reaction: "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> really appreciated his support in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>."

            The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that energy commodity prices soared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s announcement that it will keep oil production low throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX>. This means, say quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and utility bills could keep
going up for some time.

            The papers carry outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> reactions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s recent comments about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>. It's noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, apparently
still working on his position on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> (or on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>?), has not addressed
the matter yet.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>"
gives an update on stances taken on the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clemency</ENAMEX> extended to
convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> never took a position, but that's
balanced out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> supported the deal, but now
opposes it. (For a look at another possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> switcheroo, click here.)

         
      
   
