
   
   
      
         
            Down With the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Popular Front</ENAMEX>
            

            I certainly wasn't suggesting that only conventionally handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> should
get laid. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take me</ENAMEX>, for instance-I should definitely get laid, frequently and
regardless of financial means.) No, I was just wondering about the thought
processes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who know or ought to know that their most profoundly and
disproportionately attractive quality is their net worth and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who marry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to whom they wouldn't deign to speak if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in question were mere
wage-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX>.

            Yes, the conventionally handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX> should run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> …
especially now that every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX> owns a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Greatest</ENAMEX>
Generation and loves him like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. (If not more than they love their
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>.) He, like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>, could be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX> has never taken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or had sex, at least not in my
presence.

            So you're "stunned" that all your "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>-who-are-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>-and-successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have no enthusiasm" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>? Well, I'm frankly heartened by the
emerging disapproval of that demographic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is a disingenuous weirdo (not
that that disqualifies her to serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>) and, even before her
pathetic interview in Talk , kind of a bad idea as an icon. And even
though I didn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> thrown out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, the cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reflexive</ENAMEX> and vigorous defense of him to the bitter end made me queasy. So if
the popular-front pro-Clintonism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> affluentials is now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disintegrating</ENAMEX>, I'm pleased. (By the way, did you vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>?
I did, twice. Could you conceivably vote for him for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>? I don't think I
could. I may have to vote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.)

            Do we need to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, to prove we're not just frivolous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>?

            Or should we just go with the frivolous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> idiot thing, and discuss
the renaissance in cinematic supernaturalism- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sixth</ENAMEX>
Sense , and now Stigmata ? Are there going to be ghosts and/or satanic
possessions in your next movie?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>, fondly, etc.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
