
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quasi-Pornography</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
            

            The pop culture of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> is turning out so differently from my
own-their Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX> may be divorcees, their WNEW-FM will be a rock-free
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-talk radio station (farewell, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vin Scelsa</ENAMEX>!), and they will grow up able to
watch milling half-naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> live <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX>, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            I discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vogue</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, which is evidently brand new. Looking at
those fresh, sharp, digital pictures beamed from the fashion shows in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> onto my <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">21-inch</NUMEX> computer screen at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>, I felt like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX>
villain-particularly when I found that you can click a button on the screen to
make Vogue.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> show only the swimsuit <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a given</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>'s
collection. Is this what they mean in bad novels and bad movies about
"technology falling into the wrong hands"?

            Quasi-pornography in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, too, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s
final accounting of the former Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support request: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22.3</NUMEX>
million over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 14 years</TIMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> a month for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>, by the way, also shows up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> lead
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal -a</ENAMEX> story about how entertainment and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
politics have become a seamless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hybrid</ENAMEX>. (Since this has been one of my personal
hobbyhorses for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX>, I was happy to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> certify the
phenomenon; I can stop talking about it now.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duff</ENAMEX> explained and
implicitly bemoaned the trend: "There's no reverence for the process," she said
of the citizenry's disregard for politics. "It's all irreverence." By the way,
did I mention that this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is asking for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9,953</NUMEX> a month from now
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2013</TIMEX> for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX>'s travel expenses?

            Why is the prospect of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> so rich and pleasurable? Not because I would enjoy voting for
either one, certainly. Entertainment value, I figure. Or am I wrong?

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
