
   
   
      
         
            Smoke This

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s filing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of
a lawsuit against the tobacco industry charging <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of fraud and seeking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billions</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> in damages. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> (which also lavishes a news
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> "cover story" on the suit) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front the story,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ,
which led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tipper</ENAMEX> on the filing, runs it inside, choosing
instead to go with the virtual certainty that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will not complete work
on the budget by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of the new fiscal year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>. The problem,
explains the paper, is that suddenly not touching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> trust
fund has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> goal, something hard to achieve without accepting
either spending cuts or tax increases. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
puts the story under a questionable headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HILL GOP SEEKS WAY TO AVOID</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHUTDOWN</ENAMEX>." What, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are perfectly willing to have one?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>'s lead is that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> now say
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> might have been used to launder <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 billion</NUMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> the paper mentions by name as suspected: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BankBoston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX>. None of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, nor
previously identified ones like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>, are accused of
wrongdoing, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> mentions, as does a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page NYT</ENAMEX> reefer, that in congressional
testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BoNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> said some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> used poor
judgment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s decision to
open a new and expanded investigation of possible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> penetration of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s nuclear weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
off-lead. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the development is tucked with
little ado midway into an inside story about the reorganization of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>.

            The papers explain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s civil fraud
suit seeks to recover the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monies</ENAMEX> spent over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> on
smoking-related health care through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, as well as through the budgets
for military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and federal civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, expenses not covered in
settlements the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> previously made of suits where states
filed to recover their smoking-related health
costs. It's also noted that the civil filing, despite its appeal to a
racketeering statute, marks the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s attempt to bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> charges against the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.


            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> accounts of the suit go higher with the
industry's adamant response that it will never settle this case out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s report says in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph that the suit is based on
a "risky interpretation of federal law." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question that doesn't get
addressed: How do the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> reconcile their denial of this suit
with their settlement of the state actions?

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> stories agree
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> spying do-over means that its
original effort, focusing on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamos</ENAMEX>), was inadequate. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which ran
hard with stories raising suspicions about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, is rather
measured about where this leaves things, settling for "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> does not yet
have any new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is much harsher,
saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> allegation "has effectively evaporated."

            The WP front runs a story
observing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> almost-a-campaign harbors <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> before being squeezed out: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy Grunwald</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Nussbaum</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts and other
carry inside, word that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have uncovered a new Internet
scam by which Web porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> clone legitimate Web pages of such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paine Webber</ENAMEX> so that clicks to them
automatically take you to their skin sites instead. The gambit is called
"pagejacking," and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> used to force the diverted surfer to click through
numerous pages at the porn site before escaping is known as
"mousetrapping."

            A story carried on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that a government report ordered up by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43 million</NUMEX>.
Referring to a speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made during the trip expressing remorse for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> slavery, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> said this was a "high price for an
apology." Most of the cost comes from the defense budget.

            A front page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story
reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
gone from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to ... 141
who do. The piece quotes various city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> defending the practice on
grounds of competitiveness, etc., but never cites any baseline specifics about
what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make. It would have been helpful to note, as did a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece on federal pay raises, that this is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost four</NUMEX> times what the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> makes and almost twice what
the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> makes.

            A similar loss of class and economic perspective is on
view on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> editorial page, where it is
proclaimed, "At last, a means is at hand to end a long-standing embarrassment
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>." Is the editorial about a fix for the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>' woefully
short supply of new textbooks, or about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s utter failure when it comes
to public mass transit? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Er</ENAMEX>, no, it's about the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> taking the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steps towards funding an official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
