
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Double Standard</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1988</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> asked him a series of questions designed to expose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deception</ENAMEX> and ignorance. In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, "As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
would you support measures such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> measures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre accords</ENAMEX>?" As
Will acidly recounted in a subsequent column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s "answer to [that]
question was, 'Explain that.'"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre accords</ENAMEX>, it turned out--to the enlightenment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX> and just
about everyone else--were an agreement reached in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX> to
stabilize currency exchange rates. When asked later whether his question was
designed to embarrass <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX> rather than elicit information, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> argued,
"That's information, too."

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> implied that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s attempt to embarrass him was racist, Will
took offense. To the contrary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> argued, "Because [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>] is black, his
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> sit silently beside him, leaving his foolishness unremarked. The
real racism in this campaign is the unspoken assumption that it is unreasonable
to expect a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to get rudimentary things right ... He should be
thankful for double standards."

            Now along comes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, with his fumbling references to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kosovians</ENAMEX>"
and his confusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovakia</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slovenia</ENAMEX>. And what does Will think of this?
In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 23</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> column--headlined "He's No
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Intellectual--And So What?</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> writes, "The headmaster of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s private
secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> aspired to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> 'a sense of style,' ... At
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX> graduation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headmaster</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> to 'take with you a
sense of style,' <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a 'distinction</NUMEX> in manner and bearing.' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, a virtuoso of
charm and guile, was more a manner than a mind, but in politics,
manner--style--can be a kind of program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seems to know this." As for the
intellectualism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> concludes, "such
intellect in politics is rare, and perhaps should be." What "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> understands,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> suggests, is that "the wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> should strive to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> on
tap and not be one himself."

            Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, hailed as a "wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>" when he fails "to get
rudimentary things right"? Is it racism? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't think so. There's a
simpler explanation that applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> in both parties, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan to Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. Whether you call a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> or a wise leader
depends on whether you're the kind of intellectual he plans to keep on tap.

         
      
   
