
   
   
      
         
            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> and of the World
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Russ</ENAMEX>,

            Well, OK, OK, so you liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' book.

            While I don't share your enthusiasm, I agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>-and you-make an
important point: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebration</ENAMEX> is not a world apart. It is-like all real estate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>-part of local politics, for example. It exists in a place where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have options where they want to live (which is also why it is unfair to
expect Celebration to be all things to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>).

            You point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> was "uniquely burdened." I think that's very well
put. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the parts of both books that most surprised me was the extent to
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homebuyers</ENAMEX> themselves saw Celebration as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">utopia …</ENAMEX> chiefly because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> was involved. On the other hand, especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
aggressively marketed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> as a solution-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX>-everything. So it
was disingenuous of them to withdraw from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> at a later stage. Another
aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s involvement that struck me was that while they were very
good at the architectural/scenographic aspects of creating Celebration-as one
would expect, and it is a beautiful place-when it came to education, they
seemed out of their depth. In hindsight, this, too, was to be expected. Why
should an entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> understand anything about education? The
Celebration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, it seems to me, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
slipped up, and slipped up badly. Both books tell that part of the story
well.

            The burdens that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> carries also mean that it would have been almost
impossible for Celebration to be, for example, a social experiment. Both books
bemoan the lack of affordable housing, for example. But almost no new private
residential developments, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Urbanism</ENAMEX>, have succeeded at mixing
incomes to any considerable degree (the exception are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hope VI</ENAMEX> projects, which
do achieve income mixing, although they are still too new to draw categorical
conclusions from). Could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> really have done better in this area? It is not
an issue of money-they could certainly afford it-it is one of risk.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> have money, and a certain degree of power-at the same time they
are vulnerable to public opinion. Look at what happened when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> failed.
An article immediately appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> quoting
disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. More recently, a crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX> was prominently
reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Which raises an interesting point: Does
the occurrence of crime make Celebration a failure-as the story implied-or
prove that it is a real place after all?

            Witold

         
      
   
