
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Book Club</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s book and his relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>' strange biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore-Bradley</ENAMEX>
race.

            If the chat shows are any indication, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> is
turning against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> )--as well as by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">co-host,</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ). Will calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> a fascist and compares him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>. Other
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kristol</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ) say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> should leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and good riddance. On
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> says, "Clearly, we're
leaning toward [bolting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>], but I don't want to make an irrevocable
decision." But according to some he already has: "His career as a significant
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> is over," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ). And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is "on
the cusp of becoming radioactive politically," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gigot</ENAMEX> criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> for refusing to
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> off. (For 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
ostracism from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "
Go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>, Go.")

            One conditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Captial Gang</ENAMEX> ), who says that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is wrong, he
"makes a considered argument that is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>" in his new book, A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> Not An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reclaiming America's Destiny</ENAMEX> (buy it here). An unconditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, who thinks "it is a brilliant book in many ways. It's not a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s book. ... I would say right now the assault on him by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> ... makes me a little ill."

            Grilled on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> by a hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brit Hume and Tony Snow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s appeal to him to remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> "gracious" and "smart." (On
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s criticism of his views
on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> hasn't read his book.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> notes that in his
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was right not to go to war with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stalin</ENAMEX>'s quasi-genocidal farm collectivization
program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> then asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>: Does this imply we should not have gone to
war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> replies that the point is moot,
since we were already at war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> by the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> began.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> then turns the tables, asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX>, "Should we have gone to war with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> [over farm <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">collectivization</ENAMEX>] and when<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX> cuts in with, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> [chuckles],  we're asking the questions here." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> tells
Snow that we should arm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> but not necessarily declare war on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> if it
invades the island. "Listen, I will not take my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into war with a nuclear
power," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> says, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>'s decision not to intervene
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> crackdown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> chew over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> excerpts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>' controversial biography,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>: A Memoir of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> (buy it here). As the only opinion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> who has read the entire book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Thomas</ENAMEX> pronounces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' use of a
fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> a noble risk but ultimately a failure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> interviewed on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Deaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Meese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn Nofziger</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzwater</ENAMEX>)--who have not read the whole thing--say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book is a fiction.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> confidants say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' bafflement with his subject is
absurd. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> was an open book who read himself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ).

            Among the apparent revelations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excerpt</ENAMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> came much closer to death after his assassination attempt
than previously disclosed. He insisted on walking into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> under his
own power, but then collapsed; he had lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> his blood. After
catching an infection he coughed up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bushes</ENAMEX> bitterly resented the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Reagans</ENAMEX> treated them as second-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, rarely inviting them to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-floor family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">On Fox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>--a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>--notes that he too was never invited <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> but is not bitter; Brit Hume
notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagans</ENAMEX> were private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to begin with.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> concede that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s
endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> gives his campaign another boost, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Richardson</ENAMEX> admits on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> that "this is going
to be a very contested campaign." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press and This</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> flash a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time /CNN</ENAMEX> poll of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley edges Gore</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent to 41 percent</NUMEX>. (Is this within the margin
of error? Neither show says.) Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> may be peaking
early and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> also endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerry</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gang</ENAMEX> ).

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Short History of Washington Week:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Duke</ENAMEX> reminisces with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> and welcomes new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Ifill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>
chronicles the program's history: "It all began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1967</TIMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ramshackle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> ..." There was the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> tried to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Week</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> coverage. There was that unfortunate
episode where the studio lights went out, and the one where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fly</ENAMEX> kept
landing on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX>'s nose. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators generously</ENAMEX> warn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ifill</ENAMEX> (who
does not appear on the program) of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the perils of being on television
frequently: the "recognition factor." To illustrate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Roberts</ENAMEX> tells of
all the mail he has received advising him to change his hairdo, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> shares the time he was recognized by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>. Stay tuned to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" to find out how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ifill</ENAMEX> handles the
privileges and responsibilities of pundit fame.

            
               Last Word:
            

            "We had every right, and we were more than right--right, just, and moral--to
smash both of those evil empires [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Japan</ENAMEX>]."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> )

            "Here [in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>] is a defeated, divided, demoralized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weimar Russia</ENAMEX> sitting
there, and we are pushing it, with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion, right into the arms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, which bears tremendous resentment toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
in particular. We are repeating the errors that led to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heaven</ENAMEX>'s sake let's stop it before [we get] <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX>."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> )

         
      
   
