
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auf Wiedersehen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>

            Leading figures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> have been doing their utmost
to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> to stay in their party. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> has sent goodwill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emissaries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX> has been begging for a
meeting. According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are near to
giving up hope of changing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s mind. This is the wrong attitude
entirely. For moral and tactical reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> should be cheering the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> that the bum might throw himself out.

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> first ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the
press has largely treated him as a legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> rather than an
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">extremist canker</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">รก la David Duke</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX>. Part
of the explanation for this is that he's one of us. Though few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have
any sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s views, some find it hard to reconcile evidence of
his bigotry with the friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> they know. For those covering his campaigns,
there are other disincentives. Once you brand him an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>, a racist, and
a fascist, it's not much fun riding around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> with him in a minivan.
What's more, there is a dimension of self-conscious theatricality to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
performances that makes his views easier to dismiss. He'll uncork a zinger
about not buying any more chopsticks until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> quit dumping cheap
imports, and then cackle at his no-no. You can write this kind of thing off as
just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> tomfooling around and building his brand for TV, rather than
dyed-in-the-wool bigotry. 

            Yet the bigotry is there all right. You can follow its
regular eruptions through his career, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> memo to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> suggesting that he link a primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> money,"
to the now infamous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> column I excavated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX> from the archives of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis Globe-Democrat</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> offers qualified praise for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, to dozens of subsequent utterances that mitigate fascism and cast
aspersions on nonwhites. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zhirinkovsky</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Marie Le</ENAMEX>
Pen.

            His prejudice is not the genteel country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> variety
that may linger in patches elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who know him say he
gives no sign of disliking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in person. His variety of bigotry is
far stranger, and in its way much more alarming. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is a kind of fascist
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>, who dabbles in an anachronistic style of populist demagoguery
that points to cosmopolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and to a lesser extent nonwhite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>,
as the source of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s problems. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, pro-fascism is such a bizarre
stance that it's almost easier to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> isn't saying what he seems
to be saying than to recognize his views for what they are.

            The charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX> often begins
with his penchant for defending accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. While this might
seem an eccentric crusade, there's nothing intrinsically wrong with it. Indeed,
the urge to defend the rights of deeply unpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is admirable. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
claimed a measure of vindication when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Demjanjuk</ENAMEX>, who was accused of being
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Terrible</ENAMEX>," a sadistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treblinka</ENAMEX>, had his conviction
overturned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. But the problem was never <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s
taking on the case of accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> per se. It was that in defending them, he
tried to cast doubt on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> itself. In one of his columns about
Demjanjuk, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> couldn't have been gassed to death at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treblinka</ENAMEX>. This isn't just an erroneous view. It's a staple of the literature
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> denial. Since I wrote about this in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, more
information has emerged about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s bizarre argument--a specious
comparison of the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treblinka</ENAMEX> and an accident in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> survived inhaling diesel exhaust fumes in an underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>.
An article posted on the Web by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie McCarthy</ENAMEX>
demonstrates persuasively that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> borrowed the analogy from the
newsletter of a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>-denying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that calls itself the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information and Education Association</ENAMEX>.

            If dabbling in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> denial doesn't convict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> of anti-Semitism on its own, it makes a powerful case in combination
with the many things he has said and written pointing to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as a
surreptitious, sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. The fuss about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> first
started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> when he blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neoconservatives</ENAMEX> of dragging the country
toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. In a similar vein in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> would
hint that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were to blame for much else, sarcastically enunciating the name
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bader Ginsburg</ENAMEX> when complaining about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. Or he would
attack "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>," often singling out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX>" (but
never <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear Stearns</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon Smith Barney</ENAMEX>). Or he might complain about the
globalist economic policies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>--not those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Bentsen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s neo-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1930s</NUMEX> protectionism and
isolationism, it isn't hard to hear the echoes of the radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest Father</ENAMEX>
Coughlin, who associated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> with rapacious capitalism.

            I expected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who took a lot of grief for
using this code in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, would be more circumspect this time around. Not a
chance. His new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Republic</ENAMEX> Not an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> ,
makes his complaints against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> more explicit than ever. A brief for
isolationism, the book includes a pocket history of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jewish Influence</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
foreign policy from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX> to the present. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> for dragging
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, thinks they also pushed us into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
II--mistakenly! His words echo those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lindburgh</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America First Committee</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> thinks was unfairly labeled an
anti-Semite for warning the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, whose campaign Web site sports an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America First</ENAMEX>" logo,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">echoes Lindbergh</ENAMEX> when he decries "the growing domination of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy
by ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> able to focus public attention and incite
public hysteria." Instead of agitating for entry into a specific war, he thinks
these "ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>" and the "media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>" (read <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>) are pushing us toward
general policies of interventionism and internationalism.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s bigotry isn't limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. In
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, he wrote memos arguing against integration. He stayed
on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> resigned in hopes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX> might
nominate him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, a position that would allow him help
forestall what he once called the "idiotic" idea of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-vote. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s most famous lines is about how "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zulus</ENAMEX>" just wouldn't fit in in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, but he has said far more explicit things about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> being a
"white" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> column, he defends flying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> flag over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> "did not
begin over slavery." (He says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s symbols shouldn't be chosen by
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>" and "modernists"--I wonder whom he could mean.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> doesn't
welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hispanics</ENAMEX> any more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zulus</ENAMEX>. He says in his book that we should spin
off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> as an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the island
don't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. But as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> notes in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> would like to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> statehood to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francophone Quebecois</ENAMEX>, who happen to be white.

            The more you learn about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s views, the more the
question becomes why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have tolerated a semi-fascist in their midst
for so long. Saying good riddance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> makes political sense, too. If, as
seems likely, he bolts and mounts a third-party campaign, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> would do well
to depict him as a hater from the fringe and not merely a conservative who
refused to compromise. According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent poll, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX>
of the vote in a three-way matchup with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. Would that many people
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> if they knew what he really thought? I don't think so. But
perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> do.

         
      
   
