
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Finance Guru</ENAMEX>

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kenneth Galbraith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great</ENAMEX>
Crash , financial speculation during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> grew so feverish that
"even the cathedral voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jennings Bryan</ENAMEX>, which once had thundered
against the cross of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>," was "enlisted in the sorry task of selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swampland</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Commoner</ENAMEX>'s famous speech to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> convention.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Seekers</ENAMEX> of morbid parallels between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929 and 1999</TIMEX>
will be interested to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> is following in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bryan</ENAMEX>'s
footsteps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> and his son, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson Jr.</ENAMEX>, are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of a forthcoming book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's About the Money</ENAMEX>! , due
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. According to the promotional copy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksons pere et</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fils</ENAMEX> have decided that accumulating wealth is "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
step in the movement to freedom," Steps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX> being, respectively,
"emancipation from slavery," "ending legal segregation," and "securing the
right to vote."

            Though the packaging of the book is clearly meant to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">communicate</ENAMEX>, "buy this and get rich!" (let's be grateful the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> didn't
make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> allusion more explicit and call the book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's About the Money, Stupid</ENAMEX>! ), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> would probably say
he's preaching not the gospel of wealth but the gospel of financial
responsibility and independence. Topics covered include laudable middle-class
goals such as "getting out of debt," "preparing a budget," "preparing for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retirement</ENAMEX>," and "avoiding financial scams." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> wrote the
forward to a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money Talks: Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Experts Talk to You About Money</ENAMEX> , and he has long spoken
compellingly of the need to increase <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>' access to capital. But
Money Talks was written by an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> (a black
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliette Fairley</ENAMEX>). And while the soundness of expert
opinion from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairley</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Bryant Quinn</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobias</ENAMEX> is easy to overestimate, surely some
training or experience is necessary before you start telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what to do
with their money. What financial expertise does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> have? According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s catalogue (this part, unfortunately, isn't online), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's About the Money</ENAMEX>! have "unparalleled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> and credibility." Yes, but not about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson pere</ENAMEX> is quite famous for starting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation PUSH</ENAMEX> and not keeping them especially
solvent. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree shaker</ENAMEX>, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>," is how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX> famously once
described his own management talents. This is not how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Bryant Quinn</ENAMEX> would
describe herself, even if you caught her in an unusually giddy mood.

         
      
   
