
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s Bunk
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX> spoke, and the stock market trembled. Too
bad it didn't yawn.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> (which,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incidentally</ENAMEX>--well, I hope just incidentally, since I sure do like my job--owns

                  Slate
               ), and last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, in a post-speech question-and-answer period, he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Business Editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers</ENAMEX> that the stock market's valuation of
"technology stocks," including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, was "absurd." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s comments
almost singlehandedly drove the tech-heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>--"tech-heavy" is an adjective
permanently attached to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>"--to its worst performance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> and
sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s shares (which, full disclosure, I own) down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>.

            As just about everyone has remarked, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s comments
were nothing new. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Maffei</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock valuation was "ludicrous," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> told those same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s future growth were
"outlandish." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> in general are well-known for downplaying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s future prospects. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> himself supposedly told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock soon after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> went public and saw its shares
soar to what then must have seemed like stratospheric levels. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensibly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> declined the advice.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> also has a clear incentive to talk down
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s stock price, at least in the short term. A higher stock price makes
it more difficult to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with stock options, and, more important,
makes existing options more expensive. And keeping investor expectations
moderate is a good way of making sure you meet those expectations.

            But even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s comments had been completely
unexpected and completely unrelated to any of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s broader corporate
goals, they should not have moved the market, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX> knows less
about the appropriate valuation of technology stocks than the market does.

            The value of a company depends essentially on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
things: the free cash flow (cash above and beyond expenses, including its cost
of capital, and reinvestment) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> generates and the length of time
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is able to continue generating free cash flow. In valuing companies
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX> (which I also own shares of), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX> so highly,
then the market is saying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things: These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are generating
extraordinary amounts of free cash flow (which they are), and they will be able
to continue generating that kind of cash for a considerable length of time.

            Now, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> point is not really arguable. By any
meaningful measure of economic performance, the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are among the most successful and profitable in the history of
the world. (I say that for effect, but I'm not exaggerating.) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> point,
which has to do with the sustainability of this domination, is presumably the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> finds so objectionable. With technology changing as rapidly as it
seems to be, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is arguing, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can really be sure of staying on
top for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.

            Now, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is wrong about these valuations,
which is to say wrong about the future. (That's why I own shares in some of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.) Now, the fact that I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is wrong is basically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irrelevant</ENAMEX> (except, perhaps, to my future here). The fact that the market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thinks Ballmer</ENAMEX> is wrong is, however, very important.

            Our natural inclination, after all, is to imagine that
someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s position must know a lot more than everybody else
about something like the valuation of technology stocks. But to succumb to that
inclination is to reject the most important lesson taught by the triumph of
capitalism, which is that markets process information, judge the future, and
allocate capital far more efficiently and successfully than any individual, no
matter how well-positioned, possibly can. We don't trust central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>
anymore because we know they can never know as much as or react as quickly as
markets can. And we shouldn't dump our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>
says it's too expensive for the very same reason.

         
      
   
