
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> Have <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Business in Show Business</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the bad things about a bull market is that the performance of
mediocre stocks can look great when presented in isolation. Combine that fact
with the willful neglect of the idea of the opportunity cost of investing--that
is, you have to measure the success of an investment against other potential
investments you might have made, not against "zero"--and you get a recipe for
real confusion.

            Take the very curious column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX>'s financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, in the most recent issue of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. In essence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> argues
that entertainment has been a great business to be in over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 15 years</TIMEX>,
that entertainment stocks have been often undervalued, and that they've been
undervalued for one real reason: Wall Street is jealous of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> make lots of money and have fun doing it.

            There are a lot of strange ideas packed into that argument. First, it
assumes that Wall Street somehow controls stock prices. In the long term, it
doesn't. Markets collectively set prices, and markets are much bigger, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smarter</ENAMEX>, than all the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the world put
together. If the market has looked skeptically on entertainment stocks, it's
probably for a very good reason. And even if Wall Street did set prices, the
idea that investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> have consistently foregone potential fortunes for
themselves and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> because their jealousy of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> made them
unwilling to buy or even recommend entertainment stocks is, at best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implausible</ENAMEX>. This is capitalism, remember? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who walk away from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bills
that are lying on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> eventually disappear.

            But there's also a deeper problem here, which is that entertainment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have not, in fact, been those proverbial free <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bills. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> points
out that "the revenue side of showbiz" has risen dramatically at home and
phenomenally abroad over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX>. But he doesn't say
anything about the profitability of showbiz as an industry, let alone about its
return on invested capital (the most important single metric of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
economic performance). That's because compared to industries such as software,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telecom</ENAMEX>, networking, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, the performance of the entertainment
industry has been anemic.

            Besides, haven't entertainment stocks been mediocre? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> mentions
that Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> often cite this point as justification for what he
calls their "long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">myopia</ENAMEX>." But then he shows--or believes he shows--that
in fact big entertainment stocks have done very well in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 15 years</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comcast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cablevision</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>--are up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-fold, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are up better
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-fold, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> are up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-fold, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> have "only
quadrupled."

            Now, set aside the fact that of the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouses</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> are cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that own hard assets, not part of what we usually think of as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>." Consider instead that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> 500 Index is up
better than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-fold (and better than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-fold</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>). So most of the
stocks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> cites have done about as well as or worse than the market as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX>. Then recognize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> is talking about the very best of the best
here, and you start to see how weak the industry as a whole has been.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX>-fold since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1993 and 1998</TIMEX> alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>'s stock rose
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s rose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>-fold, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsystems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI/Worldcom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, even recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">laggards</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>: All of these stocks did as
well as or significantly better than the best entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 15 years</TIMEX> (and many of them have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> for a significantly shorter
period of time).

            It's not that entertainment isn't a better business than it used to be. It
is, mainly because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> running these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are spending more time
running them and less time thinking about how to make them bigger. But by the
only standard that really matters--comparing how much money is put into a
company versus how much money that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> makes--entertainment is just not,
and never has been, a good business. There are exceptions--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Networks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>--but they are the exceptions. The bull market makes it
easy to obscure that fact. But even in a bull market, the real numbers don't
lie. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> is surely right that business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is a lot of
fun. Spending other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s money always is.

         
      
   
