
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rise of Weather</ENAMEX> Wimpiness
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> is making me believe more strongly in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine</ENAMEX>
Power: From the moment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that I professed to you my belief that acts of
God are now invariably overhyped, this one began heading directly toward
metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--toward me, I'm thinking, and my flip, callow hubris. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> canceled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 this morning</TIMEX>, which has led me in turn to
try to weasel out of a book-reading-and-signing I'm supposed to do tonight. I
do think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are bigger weather wimps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than they were when we were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canceling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>?) But then, I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, where weather wimpiness was literally unthinkable. In fact, extreme
weather is the most interesting part of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extreme</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather</ENAMEX> and,
briefly, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Starkweather</ENAMEX>, the real-life serial-murderer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Sheen</ENAMEX> played in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Badlands .</ENAMEX>) The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, that a
tornado actually touched down in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX>--a little tornado, but still--I was
away at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp. I have never regretted missing any event more.

            There's an idea for a new cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>: Weather
Planet!, a cooler, next-generation <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Weather Channel</ENAMEX> that would broadcast nothing
but radar and video images of extreme weather from all over the world--heavy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snow</ENAMEX>, flash floods, golf-ball-size hail, hurricanes, typhoons, tornadoes,
cyclones, temperatures less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero or more than 100</NUMEX>. As long as you're in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, why don't you go ahead and sell the idea <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diller or Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> or somebody. We'll split the money.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>'s headlines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: Although the story may not
have appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> edition of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> being placed right now outside the door of your splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peninsula</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,668</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> grade-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolers</ENAMEX> who were informed last
spring they'd flunked, and had to take remedial summer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, did not in fact
flunk. The tests were incorrectly scored by the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that gave them.
(You really would think that if a giant public-school system could do one thing
itself, aside from installing metal detectors, it would be to administer a
standardized test.) How many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> until one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> file suit
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for emotional distress?

            And I'll bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
national edition didn't include the story about the special new millennium
commemorative-edition manhole covers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ConEd</ENAMEX> is installing. They have a 3-D
psychedelic pattern--the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manhole Cover of the Future</ENAMEX>, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 1972</TIMEX>. At a
press conference, someone asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ConEd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> if the swirly new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Op Art</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underfoot</ENAMEX> might not dangerously addle drunks stumbling through the gutters of
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square</ENAMEX>--a splendid old-fashioned kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hildy Johnson</ENAMEX> question, I
thought.

            I know, I know what you're thinking: Enough with the
obsessive-compulsive glimpses of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>.

            OK, here's something wholly new: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beavis</ENAMEX> and
Butt-headification of society at every stratum. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> I happened to meet a
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> of a huge, ultra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Establishment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, a
conservative-looking middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a suit and tie, who described certain
Web sites as "sucky." "They suck," he also said. His language inclined me to
like him. But it was mildly shocking, as if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> were to call me tonight
and tell me she thought Action was "totally
awesome."

            Since this is our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX>, and Action premieres <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, we won't be able to discuss its merits
here, and whether you think it's true in its depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. But
reading the reviews of the show in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, I wondered: Do you
have your own ghastliest-show-business-moment? I'll bet you do.

         
      
   
