
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Prose</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> lead with the coming ashore of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Floyd</ENAMEX>, which is moving
over land northward from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with something far more lethal than a hurricane: a
semi-automatic handgun. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> hasn't killed anybody yet, but as the LAT
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">informs</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> walked into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and blew away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
parishioners before capping himself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe bomb</ENAMEX> was detonated
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> as well.

            An anthropomorphism as relentless as the storm itself colors the storm
coverage. "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">HURRICANE AIMS</ENAMEX> AT <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COAST OF CAROLINAS</ENAMEX>" blares the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
headline. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FLOYD STAYS 'REAL MEAN'</ENAMEX>" says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sub-head says,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Siblings Grow Up Without Influence of Jet Stream</ENAMEX>," and the piece
beneath it offers this scientific explanation: "With cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tropics</ENAMEX>, the chill, west-to-east, high-altitude winds known as the jet stream
no longer sensed the kind of temperature differential that attracted them
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southward</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">El Niño</ENAMEX>. Instead of hurtling across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and out
to sea in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, the jet stream retired northward...."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>-inspired feature
about the war in the southeast between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> over
requiring anti-hurricane features on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> take the position
that it's well-known what features help a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> survive a medium-sized
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">hurricane</ENAMEX> and therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> they are on the hook for should incorporate them.
Homebuyers protest the added cost of features that may never be used, and
accuse insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> of seeking the likes of storm shutters and high
impact windows so that they can charge higher rates to those who go
without.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> fronts report on a speech given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> piece was also based on an interview
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> gave to some of its senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> afterwards at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>).
The gist: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> says he should have let another independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> take on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation and expressed surprise that he would be portrayed
as someone with a vendetta. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s talk was received warmly by a luncheon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> civic and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>. There was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> picketer. His sign,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports, read, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hey Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Impeach This</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that a former top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> awaiting trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> on drug and money laundering charges
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> killed himself, apparently with an intentional overdose of
antidepressants, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, where he was under house arrest. He was also
wanted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> on drug charges and for involvement in the murder of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s long-dominant political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stories run inside. Given the large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, it's
a bit surprising that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does the same, albeit with the help of a
reefer on the front.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> write that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new reports commissioned by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> reveal that even as the economy has strengthened,
discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> in the home-buying
marketplace has gotten worse. Some of the research was based on the
experiences of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX>," equally financially qualified pairs of white and
minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> looking for identical home mortgages. The finding:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inorities</ENAMEX> were less likely to receive information about loan products,
received less time and information from loan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and were quoted higher
interest rates ..." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question the stories don't answer: Since this sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> is illegal, why don't these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testers</ENAMEX>' results lead to indictments of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> were looking at hard time for this crap, they'd cut it
out.

            A front-page feature story at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that a spy-scandal-inspired
reorganization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Energy</ENAMEX>, under which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
nuclear weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> will be moved into a new semi-autonomous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, is apparently headed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> approval.
The problem is, notes the story, that this new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> will be on its own
regarding safety and environmental protection, areas already weak in the
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a "clarification," saying that a headline on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
front page<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--WHITE MAN GETS MAYORAL NOMINATION IN BALTIMORE--</ENAMEX>"distorted the role
of race in the election and violated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> policy about
reporting racial identifications only in proper context." This gives rise to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very reasonable question: What, pray tell, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> policy? If
there actually is one, why not state it? Not stating it not only makes the
clarification utterly fail to clarify, but also raises the suspicion that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't really have a well-formed idea about what "in proper
context" means beyond "when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't get a lot of complaints."

         
      
   
