
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rock Cornish Game Hen Nostalgia</ENAMEX>
            

            I am on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center Honors</ENAMEX>. It's one of the nicest
things that's happened to me, and it means I get to go to it and to nominate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who never win. I mean, never. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> I nominated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day</ENAMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Lee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Turner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chet Atkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
Donen, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Lumet</ENAMEX> among others. I wish I had kept my list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>. It
was a lovely list. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Borge</ENAMEX> won, as you have noted. He always
reminds me of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Cornish</ENAMEX> game <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hens</ENAMEX>, which, as I recall, he raised and sold
and made famous. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Cornish</ENAMEX> game hen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> used to come with a
little tag with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Borge</ENAMEX>'s name on it. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One night</TIMEX>, when I was in college, I
went to dinner with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algonquin</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algonquin</ENAMEX>! My parents
were paying!--and we had <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock Cornish</ENAMEX> game hens stuffed with wild <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> and
chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">livers</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> vowed she would serve them at her wedding, and
she did. At her first wedding. Shortly thereafter, she slept with my first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. To whom I was married at the time. But never mind: Just thinking about
all this has made me not just nostalgic in an unexpectedly cheerful way but
also completely mellow about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Borge</ENAMEX>'s winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honors</ENAMEX>.

            The report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> about police misconduct was released by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Green, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> who will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>-for-<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a-minute</TIMEX> if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> beats <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. I bet you hate him. I don't. But I feel sad that so
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--myself included--have come to think that liberal solutions don't
have a whole lot to do with running a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. (I mean, honestly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>, do you
think cops in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> speak that way to double-parked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>?) And speaking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, which I probably am, do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>? I saw him speak this
summer in one of those small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> he's so good at speaking in, and like
everyone else who sees him in those circumstances, I was stunned at how smart
and charming and relaxed he was. There are a lot of small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>.

            I know that designs on plates with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate syrup</ENAMEX> are very <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-'80s</TIMEX>, but
they haven't gone away. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only yesterday</TIMEX> one appeared on my plate.

         
      
   
