
   
   
      
         
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Lawyers Happen to Bad People</ENAMEX>
            

            We are having a hurricane watch in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and all activity has halted
while we try to figure out whether the weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know what they're talking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> and whether it is safe to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed Ex</ENAMEX> (which flies through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>) and
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> ever fixed the front door that
doesn't close. The last time there was a hurricane we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> came and actually said the words "Seek higher
ground."

            Which brings me to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duff-Perelman</ENAMEX> news: Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duff</ENAMEX> has hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, bringing the total of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> she has employed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>, and the
22nd of them is the divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who argued the custody case in
the divorce of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">21st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, who was still on the case this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, but not for long. I know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">21st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and have watched
horrified as he argued that anyone's 5-year-old deserves a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26,000</NUMEX> antique
desk, so I hope he has learned something.

            Here is a serious thing for a moment: The world is full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who can't
get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support, and it won't be long before even the
ones on food stamps will be attacked by their ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for being as
greedy as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> are fascinating things, aren't they? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Puccio</ENAMEX>, once someone I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admired</ENAMEX>, took the case of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist-</ENAMEX>who-went-on-the-lam from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, and
tried to smear his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>. And there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marvyn Kornberg</ENAMEX>, who (fortunately) lost
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louima</ENAMEX> case, but not before he had stood up in court and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Louima</ENAMEX> of being sodomized not by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> but by consensual sex in a
gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> always fall back on the time-tested everyone-deserves-a-lawyer
thing, everyone-is-entitled-to-a-defense, but the truth is there's no excuse
for what these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> say in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>-- for which they never ever even seem to
say they're sorry . And just because everyone deserves a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> doesn't mean
it has to be you. Incidentally, that's another side-effect of the dropping
crime rate: fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, and therefore fewer cases for criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. As
it is, there's fierce competition among them for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity criminals</ENAMEX>: You
could see it most clearly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Brown Simpson</ENAMEX> was
murdered, when virtually every good criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> TV auditioning
for the gig.

            You're right about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>: The criteria for advancement in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> should be changed now that the crime rate has dropped. But I had no
idea that you get bonus points for correctly challenging someone at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scrabble</ENAMEX>.

            I think it's interesting you sign off. I almost never do. It's one of the
liberating things about e-mail, that you don't quite have to say hello or
goodbye.

            Today, among other things, I am grateful my name is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
