
   
   
      
         
            Why Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin Leaving</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>?

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> didn't know better, she would say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> was driven
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> by the shame of almost having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Siegel</ENAMEX> agree
with her.

            
               Wait a minute. Maslin, the lead film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, is leaving the
Times ? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yup</ENAMEX>. According to a memo circulated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>
by arts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Darnton</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> "she will leave the paper
and try life without deadlines." Did she quit or was she fired? It's a
pretty abrupt departure, and she has no other job lined up, but who knows?
What else did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darnton</ENAMEX> say? He hinted that the job wore her out: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> turned out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">229</NUMEX> movies. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the figure was more than
double--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">475</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>'s workload doubled correspondingly but she bore it with
customary grace and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stakhanovite</ENAMEX> fortitude." What is Stakhanovite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fortitude</ENAMEX>? Stakhanov was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">miner</ENAMEX> famous for regularly exceeding his
quotas. His prolific labors were celebrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> and reviled by everyone
else. In the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> era, the adjective merely denotes a hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>,
though there's a slight hint that one's being accused of being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pet</ENAMEX>.

            
               Is that why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> got rid of 
               her, if that's what
it did? Who gets fired for working too hard? But she has taken a lot of
flak
lately for being so chipper and enthusiastic about movies everyone else hated,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace and Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX>. Another
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, even wrote an essay implicitly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticizing Maslin</ENAMEX> for credulously embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s last film. Wouldn't
it be unusual to fire a film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for not being harsh enough? It would
certainly say something about the difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> coasts.
Can you imagine the arts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> dressing down
his lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for sucking up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> too much? Well, why did
she suck up so much? In his novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Jamison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilfrid Sheed</ENAMEX>
shows how the rigors of reviewing crap can reduce a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to an embittered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hack</ENAMEX>. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX>, striving to avoid that fate, stumbled onto one equally
unfortunate--she let hope triumph over experience. What would you do if
you had to watch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">475</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies a year?

            
               OK, I buy that, sort of. But who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Siegel</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Siegel</ENAMEX> is a
regular contributor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> who has become famous for
taking a hatchet to all subjects great and small. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novelists Barbara Kingsolver</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Andersen</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> and Ideas" page, a private
salon of left-leaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>--all are
treated with the same withering contempt. All are seen with the same unwavering
certainty as avatars of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s cultural decline. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s latest cause,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">espoused</ENAMEX> in the current issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> ,
which only he among all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has realized is a great work of art.
All the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--"our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> arbiters of culture"--"have
lost the gift of being able to comprehend a work of art that does not reflect
their immediate experience; they have become afraid of genuine art." All except
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Siegelesque</ENAMEX> fashion, can't quite bring himself to give
her credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>, even though she was practically the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to
praise the film: "Not a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, not even those few who claimed to like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> , made any attempt to understand the film on its own
artistic terms."

            
               So what does he have to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>? Well,
nothing, now that you mention it. They couldn't have less in common or less
sympathy for one another's worldviews (if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> is even aware of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s, she
is not likely to be kindly disposed toward it). If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> were making a
point, rather than manufacturing a conceit, it would be this: that these two
extremes of contrarian opinion--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maslin</ENAMEX>'s brittle cheerfulness and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s
apocalyptic dourness--have somehow brought their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> to the same lonely
place. If I were her, I'd leave too. 

         
      
   
