
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Speech</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broken Windows</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear George</ENAMEX>,

            It is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the a.m.</TIMEX>, and since I woke up thinking
about your letter, it seemed like a good time to reply. I don't really love the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, despite the fact that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to be on the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> (now my
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> takes the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>) by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:10</TIMEX>. While this may seem unusual to anyone
living in the suburbs, I feel both blessed and liberated not being the family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX>. City living, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working women</ENAMEX> are beginning to understand,
provides much more flexibility and precious time than the suburban commuter
life. While we will never have enough space for all our books (or even our
clothes!) or a backyard with a swing set, our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> is a happy clutter
where no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> will be forgotten in the bowels of a finished <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riverside Park</ENAMEX> has plenty of grass and ball fields. OK. I can hear you saying,
"Where is she going with all of this. Wasn't Sukkoth enough of a digression
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>?" But it's all connected, as some famous philosopher once said, or
maybe that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.

            I have spent a lot of time thinking and writing about
the quality of urban life for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and not just for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> think are the key to urban regeneration. Not only have I read your
Broken Windows article and value it's important
impact on criminal justice policy, but its thesis goes to the heart of how we
make urban areas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> again, places where we can work and live. Before
we go more deeply into your crime-prevention theories and your work in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, I think its important to consider the
relationship between free speech and crime control. I have been struck with how
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have used the issue of crime to justify autocratic, if
not authoritarian, policies. Street crime is not usually rampant in
non-democratic regimes, whether it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">authoritarian Taiwan</ENAMEX>. Public order, however, has been a challenge for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">democracies</ENAMEX>. To what extent are we willing to suspend individual rights for the
safety of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>? Do we have to tolerate police misconduct? Do we bar
political demonstrations from the steps of city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>? Do we take away
government contracts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Works</ENAMEX> for protesting current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City AIDS</ENAMEX> policy? All of these have been policies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>.
While all these questions do not have an obvious relationship to public safety,
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> they are all part of keeping public order. By
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">extension</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has the right to close down an art exhibit if it offends
his sense of public decency. Where does free speech end and public order begin?
For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, its obvious: It all begins and ends with his own personal
preferences and there's no need to worry about the democratic process.

            I know it's still early, but what do you think?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warmest</ENAMEX> regards,
Ester

         
      
   
