
   
   
      
         
            You <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can't Go Home Again</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Russ</ENAMEX>,

            I like your story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernandina</ENAMEX>. To me, it precisely illustrates the
impossibility of starting over from scratch, which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> like
Celebration promise.

            I like many aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration</ENAMEX>. The emphasis on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX> and
walkability, the traditional design of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> that give a
sense of place to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> that put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in the
background, and the planning that gives equal importance to the individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX> and the common shared spaces. What I am skeptical of is turning one's
back on so many aspects of everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. For example, I happen to
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX>. If I lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX>, I would have to drive some distance
to find one. Nor do I remember seeing a service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. Nor a car wash. Nor a
storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. There is no motel, but there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bed and breakfast</ENAMEX> (I happen
to prefer the former). So much of what is necessary to the way we live today is
relegated to "out there."

            Celebration doesn't tell us anything about how we could better arrange our
present lives, how we could integrate and knit together convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depots</ENAMEX>, for example, or neighborhoods and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip malls</ENAMEX>. Inexpensive strip
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">malls</ENAMEX>, whatever their appearance, are where little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> are born, since
budding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> can't afford the rents that elegant town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> charge.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Jacobs</ENAMEX> long ago wrote that successful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> needed a variety of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, old as well as new, which could serve a variety of functions. The
contradiction of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is that everything is new, hence expensive. That is
one explanation for the lack of cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> and
Frantz-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> bemoan. There are no fixer-uppers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celebration</ENAMEX>. This is
obviously an unfair criticism, yet it underlines the real limitations of
starting over.

            There is another, final aspect to this conundrum. I teach a course about
architecture and urban design to budding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharton School</ENAMEX>.
After a class on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Urbanism</ENAMEX>, where I showed them several projects and took
them to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kentlands</ENAMEX>, a large planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, I asked them to
write a paper about the subject. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> wrote: "If there was one
question I would like to ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live in these neotraditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, it would be: What would it take to make you move?" It was a
perceptive observation. Starting over always promises stability--"this time we
are going to do it right"--but, of course, the world will not stop. Somebody
will come up with a better idea. Or, at least, what seems to be a better idea
at the time.

            Celebration is in many ways a better idea. No doubt, it is destined to take
its place among a long list of admirable experiments in visionary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>-making: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savannah, Forest Hills Gardens</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radburn</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seaside</ENAMEX>. But they are experiments, the mainstream will make its
own way, as it always has done.

            All the best,
Witold

         
      
   
