
   
   
      
         
            Does It Pass?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Nat</ENAMEX>,

            I've been looking forward to this book for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>, and I find myself
impressed, annoyed, and disappointed. I'm tremendously impressed by the first
chunk of the book, which is a description of the emergence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>-tested
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meritocracy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> is emerging as our leading chronicler of hugely important
but under-reported events. And the social transformation he captures here is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">momentous</ENAMEX>. It is nothing less than the death of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>--the WASP
Establishment--and the rise of another--the meritocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>.

            We all sense that this transformation occurred sometime after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> won't like me invoking them, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Herrnstein</ENAMEX> include one fact that starkly illustrates the
shift. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, the average verbal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> score for incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">583</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> had gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
were admitted. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, the average verbal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> score was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">678</NUMEX>. The middle
student in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> class would have been at the bottom of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> class. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> had been replaced by brainy strivers.

            What many of us didn't appreciate until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> book is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>
Establishment committed suicide, for the highest of motives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> identifies
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bryant Conant</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
Chauncey, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> who went on to become the head the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Testing Service</ENAMEX>. Conant was alarmed by the thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
might be developing a hereditary aristocracy. He sought to replace it with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Platonic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guardians</ENAMEX> who would be selected by merit and who would
selflessly serve the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Chauncey</ENAMEX> didn't have this sort of grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> vision, but he was enthralled by the possibility of testing, with the
thought that human beings could be measured and sorted by these fantastic new
scientific evaluations. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chauncey</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>
Establishment, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Groton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> stock.
These unsung <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> helped push through the changes that are the basis for our
current social setup.

            While telling us about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chauncey, Lemann</ENAMEX> keeps reminding us about
the fundamental issues at stake and the central problems inherent in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meritocracy</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> gave some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more opportunity but
also closed off opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who couldn't ace the tests. Furthermore,
weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chauncey</ENAMEX> just undermining one system of social rank and
replacing it with another, and possibly even more rigid, one? I am much
friendlier to the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> is, but he is right to raise all
these issues.

            Having described this fundamental change, the decline of the elite based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and breeding and the rise of the elite based on brains, it seems to me
the next obvious question is: What does this mean for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>? What culture and
values get adopted by a meritocratic elite? How do they see themselves? What
does a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> led by brainiac strivers look like? I confess I read this book
with some trepidation because I have just completed a book that attempts to
answer just these questions. So it was with some relief tinged with
disappointment that I found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> veers off and avoids them.

            The next big chunk of the book is about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Kerr</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and the fight over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Civil Rights Initiative</ENAMEX>.
There must be some law somewhere that says when a liberal starts talking about
merit he must immediately move on and talk about race. Obviously, the
affirmative-action debate is an important if well-worn controversy. But it is
not central to the issues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> raises in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of the book, which
are the problematics of meritocracy. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> admits at the end of the book,
both sides in the affirmative-action debate accept the assumptions of
meritocracy, "that it's good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to have a designated,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">educationally</ENAMEX> derived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>." So why does he let this book on meritocracy get
taken over by affirmative action?

            This section on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX> is a journalistic account about some of the liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who fought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRI</ENAMEX>. The story is told through their eyes, and it is a
biased account. I am a nervous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of affirmative action, and through this
whole section I felt my point of view was not being treated fairly. When I read
it again, I got angrier. It is incredibly unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX>, a leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> who is treated like a hollow front <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. It treats other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of
affirmative action as oddballs. So <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> opponent is described living in "an
isolated mountaintop aerie" and spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> "talking in a low
confidential mumble on the telephone." Another is a "ferociously quiet young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a shaved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>." What does "ferociously quiet" mean? Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> use
such a menacing phrase to describe a liberal? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> is generally not crudely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biased</ENAMEX>, but liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will find themselves flattered and conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will find themselves feeling that they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of an injustice.

            In the final pages of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> gets off race and returns to the core
issues. He asserts that our meritocratic system is unfair, that it is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affront</ENAMEX> to our egalitarian ideals. He asserts that our system measures only a
narrow set of skills, and selects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too early in their lives. These are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> assertions, but he never really makes the case in the center of his book.
This last section is only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> pages long, and contains none of the sociological
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> or journalistic reportage that would flesh out his assertions. He says we
should close the gap between selective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and non-selective ones. That
might be fine for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, but what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, who
are rarely discussed in this book. Won't the ramifications be grave if elite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> are disbanded? Not everybody on earth is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, despite the impression we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> often give. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> doesn't
have time in this final tacked-on section to address such issues.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Big Test</ENAMEX> is worth reading for the superb section on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conant</ENAMEX>. I learned a lot. But I come away thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> let his narrative
sidetrack him from the issue he cares about most: The huge question of whether
our current meritocratic system is just or unjust, and what we can do about
it?

            I'm looking forward to your reaction to the book.

            Highest regards,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
