
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chocolate-Syrup Designs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Isolationism
            

            Coming up in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford Book of Quotations:</ENAMEX>

            "A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> probably needs a Fascist to run it."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX>

            "And a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> definitely needs an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchorman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> to run
it."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Andersen</ENAMEX>, paraphrasing Ephron

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> is right, as he surely is, that the cops are driven to bust more
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in order to keep their arrest numbers up, isn't it just a
(non-simple) matter of tweaking the incentivization scheme? What I mean is,
couldn't they build in some bad-arrest penalty provision--so that the
apprehension of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> would make the policeperson lose
credit for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> good arrests? I'm sort of serious. It would be like
when you challenge somebody's word in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scrabble</ENAMEX> and you're wrong, you lose
points.

            The memorized-order phenomenon in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> is meant, I think, to suggest
an extreme competence, as well as some more subtextual kind of intimacy--as if
the waiter is really just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know and you're telling him what you'd like
to eat as long as he's going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> anyway. Also, maybe, it's another
form of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid/late-'90s</TIMEX> minimalism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Less</ENAMEX> is more, and nothing is everything.
Maybe I should become a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientologist</ENAMEX>.

            And those horrible little designs made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate syrup</ENAMEX> on the dessert
plate, by the way, are also about show-offy competence, but so very, very
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.

            I didn't really want to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, by the way. I have no
opinion, no information, nothing to say. I feel the same way you do about it
and wars like it. To me they're not unlike those roving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> malathion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trucks</ENAMEX>--by which I mean international crises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> also seem like
something out of an earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>. Which is to say, before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War II</ENAMEX>, when this is how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> registered nearly all foreign wars ...
isolated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-month</TIMEX> news stories, a sudden ghastly horror show in some obscure
exotic place where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has no obvious national interest, wars that fit into
no grand struggle (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">e.g.</ENAMEX> capitalism vs. communism) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> or inflames
us. I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> default mode is still isolationist, intellectually as
well as militarily (if not economically). So maybe we wince a little at the
headlines and photographs from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, and then, like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> did
when they read about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armenia</ENAMEX>, turn the page to read about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Duke</ENAMEX>--I mean,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caleigh Duff-Perelman</ENAMEX>.

            On that happy note, I'm off to cook dinner, and remain

            Yours truly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
