
   
   
      
         
            Easy Generalizations and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meta-Guilt</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>:

            The only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Salter</ENAMEX> novel I've read is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Light Years</ENAMEX> , which I thought was
just great. But I find any generalized public whining about the decline of the
literary culture annoying, even when I essentially agree with the sentiment-in
part, as you say, because of the helplessness it inspires. And the flip side of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salter</ENAMEX>'s argument in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>'s essay-all pop culture is garbage-seems to
me just so easy and specious.

            Inspired to despair helplessly: That has been my ongoing reaction to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Singer</ENAMEX> piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> magazine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> before last, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tierney</ENAMEX> refers in his column in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> as
well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> argued that we should regard every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> we spend on anything
inessential as the heartless crypto-murder of a Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, since the
donation of that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxfam</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNICEF</ENAMEX> would prevent an infant from dying. Do
you think there's any real counter-argument to the notion that none of us have
any moral right to buy expensive clothes or eat at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> or go on fancy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vacations</ENAMEX>? The fact that I was left feeling upset and more or less speechless
by that piece, meta-guiltier than I've felt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, made me wonder if this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> isn't about to experience a resurgence of old-fashioned circa<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-1965</TIMEX>
liberalism.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moebius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> is a self-contained closed loop-the thing discovered
(invented?) by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moebius</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> that's a
two-dimensional surface with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> side. (You take a strip of paper, give it
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> twist, and paste the ends together, enabling you to draw a continuous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">never-ending</ENAMEX> line on it.) It is the one thing from my junior-high-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">topology</ENAMEX> studies that I remember. It's been striking me lately as a useful
metaphor.

            I don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> invented a twelfth of the words he used, either.
And I was also skeptical of another statistic in the paper (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ,
I think) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning:</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> CDs released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 600</NUMEX>-2
percent-make money. If it's true, it would make the movie business look
rational.

            You are, as you mentioned, in the movie business, and you're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> momentarily; OK, I have a question. Why don't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX>
own the copyrights to their scripts, as playwrights do, and as (I'm told)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> do? Why, in other words, doesn't a screenplay that I
co-wrote revert to me to sell elsewhere after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to whom I sold it decide
they don't want to make it into a movie? Couldn't (and shouldn't) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers</ENAMEX>
Guild simply make this a non-negotiable issue and change the custom
overnight?

            Also, how did your toes turn out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
