
   
   
      
         
            To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Think Hard Before Getting Hitched</ENAMEX>
            

            In the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>'s acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, which,
among other things, paired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>' television network with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>'s
television-production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, the reigning conventional wisdom is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, now
the only network without a studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, needs to find one as fast as it can.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> are oft-mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.) But the conventional wisdom
is wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> needs a studio much less than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> need it. Even with the
erosion in popularity of broadcast television, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> remains a real catch. It
doesn't need to rush into the arms of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitor</ENAMEX> who comes along.

            The vogue for vertical integration--in which a network
produces and distributes its own shows--does reflect an important new reality,
which is that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> networks have been able to have a financial interest
in their own programming. (From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970 to 1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> forbade that, which is
what made independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carsey-Werner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorimar billion</ENAMEX>
dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.) And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio business</ENAMEX> can be an immensely profitable one
because of the myriad opportunities for merchandising, licensing, and
syndication. Just look at what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> did with The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX> . But the studio
business is also, by its very nature, erratic and expensive. For every
Simpsons , there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddies</ENAMEX> . It might be nice for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> to be able to produce
and own its own shows (as it already does with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dateline and the Tonight Show</ENAMEX> ). But
it's not necessary.

            Just look at the numbers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, which is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>,
brings in somewhere <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $500 million and $1 billion</NUMEX> in net income every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. If you valued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> the same way the stock market values <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, it would be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 billion</NUMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was hurt when it lost
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> and had to pay through the nose to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX> , it remains the most profitable
broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, its cable properties are booming, and even its Internet
strategy appears to be taking off.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s allying itself with a studio point
to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> an episode the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> had to shell out to keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX> an episode it paid for the
final season of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> and say, "Look at the
money it could have saved." But even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, there's no guarantee
that it would have made <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, for instance,
has yet to produce a hit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> merged. More important, if
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> and gave its sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> a
price break, it would be wrecking its own business.

            The great delusion in the way the media write about
vertical integration is the assumption that merging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> makes it
economically sensible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to sell its products to the other below the price
that it could charge in the marketplace. But in fact it doesn't. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>
starts charging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> less for its programs than it could get from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, it will
become less valuable. And conversely, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> starts taking programs from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX> that it would otherwise have rejected, it will become less valuable.
"A bad program is a bad program, and the only thing that happens if you put a
bad program on a network is that your ratings drop," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis McAlpine</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beck</ENAMEX>. "And if you do good programming, you're going to
get picked up. Vertical integration doesn't change that."

            The other pro-merger argument being offered is that if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, it would have an easier time bargaining with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>
owned by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> would know that if it didn't give
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> a break on the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> would drive a
hard bargain when it sold shows to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB Network</ENAMEX>. This argument is, of course,
crazy. No one takes less money than they can get because they might be rewarded
for their generosity later on.

            In the space of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> have gone in and
out of favor more often than the Who has mounted comeback tours. But through it
all, and even with the continued erosion of viewership, one thing has remained
unchanged: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcast</ENAMEX> television offers unparalleled access to huge numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fragmentation</ENAMEX> is a problem, and it will continue to be,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Networks</ENAMEX> told me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX>. "But the ability to
aggregate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 20, 30</TIMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of all living <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
makes broadcast an enormously powerful medium." When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> come calling,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> should (and it looks right now, with its recent investment in Paxson
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>, as if it will) remember that.

         
      
   
