
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raisa</ENAMEX> and Raises

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
lead with the sodden aftermath of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> inspecting. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times fronts that, but leads instead with the tremendous earthquake
(magnitude <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.6</NUMEX>) that hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, and trapping
perhaps just as many in toppled-over and collapsed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. Everybody else
fronts the quake. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , however, leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s dollop of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s metastasizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> brutality and corruption scandal: that a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> chose to ignore
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>' allegations of a stationhouse beating of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>'s
nationwide toll, favoring numbers to do so: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
ordered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to boil their tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>; total damages possibly as high
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26.5 billion</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> record; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> deaths in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and one in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes more for narrative, with
such passages as: "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> confronted
hardships that seemed almost biblical in scope: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffins</ENAMEX> sent floating away from
low-lying cemeteries; portable incinerators being assembled to dispose of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> dead hogs and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> drowned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX>; oceanfront <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> being swept
away; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> living without safe tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, telephones or
mail service."

            The insertion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-supported peacekeeping force
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> is going so uneventfully thus far that it's off everybody's
front save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s.

            Everybody but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
(which runs it inside) fronts the death from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raisa Gorbachev</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> especially
capture the sense in which she broke <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> ground as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>: less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dowdy</ENAMEX>, more fashion-conscious, if not downright materialistic (with her own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reminds). But the
coverage fails to deliver a bit in its attempts to depict any further
contribution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says she "drew criticism for
speaking out" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says she emerged as
someone "who had her own mind," but neither describes any position she ever
took on anything.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a long story
inside claiming to move the ball forward on the question of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
came to get a slot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air National Guard</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">then-speaker</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> had been saying that although he often received requests for
Guard placement, he never received such a request from anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
family, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GWB</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. But now, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-speaker</ENAMEX> says he did intervene, at the request of a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that according to the latest government stats, labor
productivity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> manufacturing sector rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.1 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the
same as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kuttner</ENAMEX>, in his WP
op-ed advocating further raises in the minimum wage, observes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have shown that raising the minimum wage doesn't detract from job
creation. The just-quoted statistic suggests that they've shown it also doesn't
detract from--maybe stimulates--productivity.

            The WP fronts the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in
its well-reported series looking inside
the high echelons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> military during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> war. Today
the emphasis is on the war-long dispute between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate</ENAMEX>, air warfare chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Short</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> wanted to use his air assets to target tactical assets, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artillery</ENAMEX> pieces in the field, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short</ENAMEX> wanted to hit strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>,
such as ministry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. In noting that, according to the
recently released bomb damage figures from the war, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
army assets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> survived intact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
campaign--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short</ENAMEX>'s target list--that made the difference.

            Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> scandal for a beat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are bracing
for a raft of legal claims likely to be brought against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> by suspects
who've been arrested or questioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> implicated thus far.
Question about that: Just as papers routinely appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to provide
information they might have about unsolved crimes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fugitives</ENAMEX>, why doesn't the
LAT invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who think they've been
mistreated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in question to come forward? Of course, this would
be easier if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> knew what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> look like--which raises another
question: Why hasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run their
pictures?

         
      
   
