
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Skip West Wing; Watch Roswell</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> premiere of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The West Wing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>),
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> suggests that, come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 6th</TIMEX>, you spin your dial to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roswell</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>) instead. Here's proof that hybridization can succeed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Generically</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX> is the spawn of The 
               X-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Files</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> , but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode, at least, has more charm than
both. It's the story of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, of course--it's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>! She's a
normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who fears she looks like a freak (she doesn't); he's an alien boy
who looks like the kind of shy dreamboat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> could get a crush on (he is).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girl</ENAMEX>, who has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> job, takes hit from passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> in coffee-shop
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">altercation</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, who has special powers, heals her with his unearthly touch.
This prompts the revelation of his ancestry--he descended to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> as an
incubating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>'s notorious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> alien spaceship crash--the
suspicions of a grim-faced local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>, and, of course, a star-crossed
romance.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>
(an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-Files <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My So-Called Life</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>) originally
offered it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, which demanded changes and planned to launch it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-season</TIMEX>.
They then took it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>, which put it in the best slot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>,
immediately after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> . Once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> has demonstrated
its superior programming abilites. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roswell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siri Appleby</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Behr</ENAMEX>) are fine-tuned combinations of poise, awkwardness, and eloquence.
The hunger on the alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>'s face when he looks at the forbidden <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz</ENAMEX> is as raw
yet sublimated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX>'s displaced homoeroticism. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz</ENAMEX> processes the
facts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>'s non-humanity, the scene lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, an eternity in TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, in order to register her sequence of expressions: incredulity, hilarity,
disgust at the cheesiness of the whole idea, terror, longing.

            But what makes the show endearing is the tone: matter-of-fact in the manner
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy</ENAMEX> (you feel alien? You are alien), yet with a lighter
touch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roswell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>  have clearly studied their teen romantic
comedy history, and understand that an adequate representation of the teen
condition requires the presence of well-meaning but oppressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who try and try but just don't get it, but also an absence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condescension</ENAMEX>. Ignore the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naysayers</ENAMEX> who will complain, as they do about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> don't talk like
that--that they lack such advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> of introspection. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teens</ENAMEX> never talked
the way <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX> do, or agonized as deeply, and who takes their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>
to task for that?

         
      
   
