
   
   
      
         
            Crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> 101
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ester</ENAMEX>:

            As I noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, I too had hoped to get on e-mail
earlier. Class preparation, however, delayed me.

            As you may know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of interest is crime
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, especially police activities to prevent crime through order
maintenance. You mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> in your note <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>. While the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s position on the merits of certain art has been highly topical and
controversial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> (and for those who read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> in other areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>), in most of the
sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> he is best known for his record on crime control. And
as you may know, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of his crime-control strategy has been to deal with
minor offenses--a strategy that he has openly acknowledged is derived from an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article I</ENAMEX> wrote with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Q. Wilson</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. The article was known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Broken Windows</ENAMEX>."

            Art criticism and order maintenance might be quite
different issues on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> level, but on another they are linked. Both raise
free-speech issues. I know little about free-speech issues as they relate to
art, however, although not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, I have become quite familiar with the
issues as they relate to certain aspects of disorderly behavior, especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">panhandling</ENAMEX> in public spaces (begging). (You may or may not know that I was
extensively involved during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX> in restoring order in the New York
City <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX> and that panhandling was, perhaps, the most divisive issue.)

            In respects, the subway experience (both in dealing
with graffiti and with other forms of disorderly behavior) became the prototype
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s anti-crime efforts, at least in its early stages. Later,
new managerial and tactical innovations seemed to accelerate declines in
crime.

            This issue, crime control and how it is accomplished,
is the basis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s reputation outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. But, as
you suggest, we are going into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX> and it will be interesting to
see how reputations play themselves out over time.

            I hope that you had a good holiday. I will look forward
to hearing from you and will write more early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m.</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George L. Kelling</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
