
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strangers in Town</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ester</ENAMEX>:

            I understand your appreciation for urban life. I, too, love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>--as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resident</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourist</ENAMEX>, professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>, etc. It generally is one of the
conditions of my visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to lecture or consult that I stay at a
"downtown" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> rather than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on a highway someplace. The inspiration for
much of my work has been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Jacob</ENAMEX>'s wonderful book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Death and Life of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great American Cities</ENAMEX> .

            I take your point about making the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> a place for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>" at the
expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and neighborhoods. Certainly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, although I was
concerned about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, my primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> was the fact that
travel on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> had become intolerable for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had to use it:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and so on. The rich were using limos and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cabs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in the broadest sense, deserved better
than they were getting.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> level, while I am primarily concerned about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of
neighborhoods and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, I am also concerned about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>": that is,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who come into neighborhoods to shop, provide services, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> watch,"
and all the other things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of public spaces do. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobs</ENAMEX>
has pointed out, for neighborhoods to thrive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> must both feel
comfortable entering neighborhoods and behave in ways that don't threaten the
neighborhood. "Isolated" neighborhoods such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Robert Taylor Homes</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, become dangerous places--not only for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> but for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> as
well.

            But, of course, this takes us into murky areas. Clearly both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>" can take offense too easily. Moreover, despite the popular view
that neighborhoods are cozy and warm, they also have enormous capacity for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pettiness</ENAMEX> and hostility. And, it also can be true that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s "disorder"
is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s uniqueness. Nonetheless, I have found this resolvable if
one is attentive to the law, the constitution, and issues of freedom and
responsibility.

            The issues you raise about possibilities of abuse, however, are appropriate.
In my own work, I have seen the misinterpretation of "broken windows" for their
own purposes by both the far left and the far right. Part of the trouble is
that now everybody "understands" the ideas in broken windows. And for many, it
is "zero tolerance" of any forms of disorderly behavior--a phrase that I hate
and have never used except to distance myself from it. It is both unrealistic
and smacking of zealotry. The far left likes to substitute it for broken
windows because it proves that I am a fascist conducting a war on "homeless"
and the poor; the far right loves the term "zero tolerance" as a replacement
for broken windows because it justifies police "ass kicking."

            Well, I have gone on a bit. Since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is now traveling, I will have
another cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and get set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.

            Be well,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Kelling</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
