
   
   
      
         
            Policy Corner: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Ed</ENAMEX>

            The reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s proposal for education
reform, unveiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, have been largely favorable.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sober-</ENAMEX>minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> and education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> have praised the plan, which
hinges on taking federal money away from failing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and giving it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to use elsewhere. But the analysis has neglected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> salient point
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> program: It already exists in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. And it's a failure.

            Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s proposal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would be required to test
their "disadvantaged" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> on academic basics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
test scores didn't improve after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three consecutive years</TIMEX>, the federal
government would take away its contribution that comes under an aid program
known as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 1</ENAMEX>. This federal money would then go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who could use it
as a voucher to pay for a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, tutoring, or another public
school--"for whatever offers hope," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> put it. In announcing the plan, he
estimated that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Title1</NUMEX> chit would be worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1,500</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>.

            You can find the details of how something similar
actually works in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 3</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Markley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Walt</ENAMEX>. Under a program that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has promoted (but did not initiate), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> tests all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> just as he envisions doing nationally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> have to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment of Academic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Skills</ENAMEX> (TAAS). On the basis of that test and a few other
factors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are rated in one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> categories: "low-performing,"
"acceptable," "recognized," or "exemplary." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the entire
state--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodrich Elementary School</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 miles</NUMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>--has been rated
"low-performing" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three consecutive years</TIMEX>. What would happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodrich</ENAMEX>
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> plan? This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, which has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $47,000</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 1</ENAMEX> funds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. This means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would receive a voucher worth
not <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$313.33</NUMEX>. That doesn't buy a lot of hope, even in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. In fact, there are no private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the vicinity, which
means that there wouldn't even be anyone to turn down this sorry-assed excuse
for tuition.

            What about urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>? It so happens that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
has a program that is both more generous and more stringent than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
proposal. It says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who fail the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> test and who attend schools
rated "low-performing" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one year</TIMEX>, can receive a credit of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,575</NUMEX> to attend private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. It's not exactly a voucher, since the school
district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">negotiates</ENAMEX> directly with private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to place these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,147</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Independent School District</ENAMEX> qualify to opt out
of failing public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> under this program. How many have taken advantage of
it? Zero.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> story offers
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of explanations for this. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> school district
didn't identify which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> qualified for the program until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, by which
time it was too late to enroll elsewhere for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. But the bigger problem
is that even <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,575</NUMEX> isn't enough to pay tuition at a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four or five</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> did contact the school district to express
interest in the program, but all considered a payment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,600</NUMEX> too low.
Tuition at run-of-the-mill private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> runs more like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,500</NUMEX> for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school year</TIMEX>. At elite academies, it can be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $12,000</NUMEX> per year.
Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> story was published, one
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has agreed to accept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. It's a mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, which intends to create a separate secular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for the
public-school transfer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            If private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> won't accept a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,600</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">voucher</ENAMEX>, it's pretty clear that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX> voucher won't produce any real choice
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. And if there's no choice, there's no competitive pressure on
failing public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, which is the chief justification for the program. To
find out whether vouchers can actually improve education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would have to
offer an additional incentive worth several times the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 1</ENAMEX> spending (currently <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $8 billion</NUMEX>). But even the compassionate one
isn't prepared to run afoul of conservative dogma to the extent of proposing
spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of billions of additional</NUMEX> federal dollars on education.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> story points to another fatal flaw in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
proposal. How is it that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the whole state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has been
rated "low-performing" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three consecutive years</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> might have you believe
that it's because he has done so much to improve education in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. In fact,
it's because the state standards are riddled with loopholes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> can exempt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> judged to have learning disabilities, or who have limited English
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skills</ENAMEX>, from taking the state test. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> do this--and the state permits
it--to avoid punishment and embarrassment. It's the bureaucratic equivalent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> promotion. How likely is it that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would set up stringent systems
of evaluation and accountability for the sake of having their federal education
funding taken away? Not very. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is proposing that federal education dollars
come with strings attached. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> receiving the dollars get to pull
the strings.

            There's a way around this problem: set federal
education standards. Reading at a fourth-grade level should mean the same thing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, that it does in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bismarck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.D.</ENAMEX> With a single standard, you
could measure any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> against any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and truly assess their
progress or failure against a common baseline. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Checker Finn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Ravich</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, have championed this idea in the past. Yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s plan steers entirely clear of national standards in favor of state ones.
The implicit reason is, once again, that anything the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does
runs afoul of the conservative dogma, which says that education is an
exclusively local responsibility.

            More money and strict federal standards would make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s plan plausible and interesting. Until his work improves, he deserves a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
