
   
   
      
         
            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> Ever Use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cocaine</ENAMEX>? Part II

            Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>-question
playbook <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> (see "
Did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cokie Roberts Ever Use Cocaine?</ENAMEX>"). That is to say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, when asked
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> whether he'd ever used any illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, turned the tables
and asked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> about their own drug histories.

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" column has an excellent summary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of this column will want to scrutinize the text for
every last ambiguity (for the complete transcript, click here):

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BILL BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: I have used marijuana several times in my life, but never
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>.
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COKIE ROBERTS</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and violence ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAM DONALDSON</ENAMEX>: Excuse me, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cokie</ENAMEX>. Recently in your life?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: No.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAM</ENAMEX>: When you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY Well</ENAMEX>, yes. Right. Have you?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAM</ENAMEX>: I think a couple of times I've tried it. And I inhaled.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">BRADLEY Have you, Cokie</ENAMEX>?

               COKIE: Oh, listen, I was so pregnant during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>? Who wants to know?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GEORGE</ENAMEX> WILL: No.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAM</ENAMEX>: How come you give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> a pass?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GEORGE</ENAMEX>: No. I'm from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falstaff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>.

               COKIE: Can we get to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and violence?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GEORGE</ENAMEX>: That's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRADLEY</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, that's right.

               COKIE: The--you wrote an Op-Ed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> ...

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s post-game analysis:
            

            

               The context suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, is admitting

                  only 
                  youthful marijuana use . But it's possible he's being cagey
and is ducking the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> question. (It's also possible--this is
admittedly a fanciful reading--that in saying "I inhaled," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s referring to
both marijuana and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>; though if that were the case he'd probably
say, "I tried them ," not "I tried it .")

               
                  Cokie keeps trying to change the subject. That may be because she
agrees with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that it's a phony issue. Or, it may be because
she doesn't want to answer the question. In fact, she doesn't
answer the question; she just says she was "so pregnant during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX>."
This answer implies that she couldn't take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> because she was
constantly pregnant during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. But obviously she wasn't pregnant
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire decade</TIMEX> . (She has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.) Hence this is not only a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-answer</ENAMEX> , but a non-alibi . Does this mean she's hiding past
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (who opined in his 
previous item that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> is "almost certainly not" a past <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>)
guesses not. Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie</ENAMEX> of being too embarrassed to
admit that she's one of those goody-goodies who never tried

                  marijuana 
                  or 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> .)

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> answers "no" twice (for some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> thinks he
hasn't answered the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time). It doesn't seem especially surprising that he
never tried 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> . But what does he mean when he
says he's "from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Falstaff</ENAMEX> generation"? It's possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> means that his
generation's drug of choice was alcohol (presumably not "sack," Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falstaff</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX>). Specifically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> may mean that when he was
in college he drank a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Falstaff Beer</ENAMEX>. (For an unofficial history of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falstaff Brewing Co.</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brewer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>'s
college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--click here.) More likely, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> is alluding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falstaff</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation in Henry IV</ENAMEX>, Part I
                  , that "the better part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">valor</ENAMEX> is discretion" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Act V</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scene iv</ENAMEX>, line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>). In this context, that might
mean that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> was young and relatively irresponsible, he didn't want to
mess with dangerous and illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>. Or, it might mean that today
he doesn't want to discuss the matter at all (in which case we'd need to
reinterpret his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> "no"s to mean "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, I don't want to talk about this").

               The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>--didn't have to answer the question
because he wasn't present during this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George S.</ENAMEX> previously
told 
this column that he'd never used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> . Chatterbox forgot to ask
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George S.</ENAMEX> whether he'd ever used marijuana, but doesn't feel like calling him
back to ask now.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>) is never around when this question gets asked.
He was out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was phoning around for the 
earlier item, and, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George S.</ENAMEX>, didn't appear during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this</TIMEX> segment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> continues to have no 
                  opinion about whether
he ever used illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               Addendum: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Lamb</ENAMEX> got asked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Journal</ENAMEX> whether he'd ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> or any
other illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. He said 
               no . Also on the show was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
Drudge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> , who said, "I haven't done <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>"
but declined to say whether he's used any illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> . Through
a bizarre sequence of events, 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
ended up being the one who asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> about past <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> said
he'd answer the question if asked, but no one asked. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> refused to
ask, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> seemed about to ask, but then didn't.) However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> long ago
confessed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column that he "experimented
with marijuana in the distant past," and wrote, "I deeply regret this
youthful indiscretion." (The column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regrets Only</ENAMEX>," is included in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> collection, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Big Babies</ENAMEX> .) After taking his first puff during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">freshman year</TIMEX> in college,

            

               
                  I found the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> had no effect on me whatsoever, and I determined
not to experiment with illicit substances any further ... However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>
later I experimented with marijuana once again. On that occasion I enjoyed it a
good deal more. This youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indiscretion</ENAMEX> I also deeply regret. During the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next several years</TIMEX>, overcome by the spirit of scientific inquiry, I
experimented with marijuana perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> or more times ...
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley now</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that he also tried
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> who got all this started identified himself as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HC</ENAMEX>" from a satirical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Website</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C3F</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for its
witless 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spoof</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HC</ENAMEX> said he was "stoned," inspiring
this classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN exchange</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BRIAN</ENAMEX>: Why are you stoned?
               

               HC: Because I enjoy it.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BRIAN</ENAMEX>: What are you stoned on?

               HC: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marijuana</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> deplores self-righteousness and
hypocrisy regarding illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, he also deplores illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use itself.
Specifically regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, a lesson of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> was that its use is both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addictive</ENAMEX> and potentially deadly--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> facts that were unknown to youthful baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> who tried it during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. That doesn't justify the ongoing
disparity between criminal sentences for possession of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder cocaine</ENAMEX> and
possession of crack--crack is much more likely to be used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, and is
punished much more harshly--but it does justify the tougher approach law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> take in general <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, as compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
