
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inhaling Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coughing Up Al</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s increasingly competitive race
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s likely jump to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>.

            Grilled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cokie</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> appears relaxed and
confident. He admits to using marijuana but not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, then asks his
interrogators the same question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX> says he has used marijuana, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>
says neither <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>--can you guess?--also says neither). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> says
he supports limited experiments with vouchers, but in general opposes them. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
read 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tightrope</ENAMEX> walk on vouchers,
click here.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was wrong to grant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clemency</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>, and he argues that the apparent success of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s welfare reform is due largely to the strong economy.

            Most programs flash polls showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> even with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is
finished. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit Hume</ENAMEX>)
note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'96</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'84</TIMEX>--still has the
party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> behind him and a sizable national lead.

            Appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>
says nothing new but sounds more bitter than ever. ("They gave my speaking spot
[at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">'96 GOP Convention</ENAMEX>] to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> ," he mutters.) Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think his jump to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Pary</ENAMEX> is
certain. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Germond</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> )--think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> should show
Buchanan the door.

            Others think there is ample reason for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
to be "quaking in their wingtips" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>): He'll steal votes
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. ("That giant sucking sound you hear is the sound of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> sucking up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">quips McLaughlin's Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX>.) On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nicholson</ENAMEX> looks humbled
and frightened. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> asks him whether his upcoming meeting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or his own, he stutters and then refuses
to answer. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s support is tepid to begin with,
and that he may actually draw labor votes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN Late Edition</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Barone</ENAMEX>).
Most shows note that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, I-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> have
threatened to run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> nomination to block <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>. (Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump attacked Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s isolationism in a fax sent to several shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.) (To read 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s apostasy, click here.)

            
               Predicting (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Path On This</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>,
will endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. It should be noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>'s record
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> intelligence is not good: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> what would happen next in the then-exploding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kristol</ENAMEX>
predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, principally <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Moynihan</ENAMEX>, would "go to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--and I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>; it could be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>--and tell
him this is insupportable, you cannot put the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> through this." Of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> never did this. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> did seem to be fishing for his
endorsement on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> : When asked about
welfare reform, he began, "I agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Moynihan</ENAMEX> on this issue, who I
think knows more about welfare than anybody else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." When asked
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s clemency, he noted that he "agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>."

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louis</ENAMEX>. Love and
Kisses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>."<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>'s love
affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> continues. (See the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>.) On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, informs us that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> "is a very honest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>--and frankly he's the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> I've seen in my whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. He's an honest, decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He gets in trouble with this
administration because he is honest and doesn't play the [political] game."
Earlier in the program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> aired a leaked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
surveillance video allegedly depicting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>--recently
sprung by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--making a mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>.

            
               Last Word From an exchange on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> :

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX>: "You
mean if somebody found a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, [and] they had a surveillance
videotape [of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> making bombs, but] they weren't directly linked to
the bombing [in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>], that it wouldn't be justified to draw a conclusion from
that?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>: "I would say that if you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX>, that were not
directly tied to the murder--that they did not do the murder--that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 years</TIMEX> [in
jail] would be excessive. You know it, and I know it."

         
      
   
