
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> Comes Out as a Cultural Conservative!

            
               Click 
here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s art criticism.
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation"</ENAMEX>--the show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum of Art</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is trying to quash by threatening to withdraw city funding from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX>--is not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> exhibition of so-called "sick stuff" to be shown
by a publicly funded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX>
tenure. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October of 1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> P.S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>--which receives, according to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX>'s estimate, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX> of its budget from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>--installed continuous showings of an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourlong</TIMEX> film of a simulated
homosexual orgy by underground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Smith</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> didn't utter a
word. Nor did he comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 Biennial</TIMEX>, which included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCarthy</ENAMEX>'s videos of a half-naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> dressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Red</ENAMEX>-Nosed
Reindeer frolicking with nude female "elves" as they defecated, stirred the
excrement up with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>, and ate it.

            But now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s attacking this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" exhibit, which includes: a self-portrait made of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>'s
frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>; vivisections of dead livestock preserved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>; and a
painting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Virgin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> decorated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant droppings</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> is threatening to cut city funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>--that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMA</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget--if it opens the exhibit. It's a move that's
obviously designed to bolster his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> candidacy: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> are his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souljah</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luckily</ENAMEX> for him, being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
supplies him with richer material than a mere upscale single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> or a cussing
rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is signaling to upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> and to the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> that although he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sin City</ENAMEX>, he can't abide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sinners</ENAMEX> himself.

            Culturebox can't help but think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation" artists</ENAMEX>
deserve one another, since they share a common goal of drawing as much
attention to themselves as possible. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, though, are doing
the better job. Brilliantly orchestrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Saatchi</ENAMEX>
to increase the value of his extensive holdings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' work, the show
has already drawn flattering notices in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. And that was before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">condemnatory</ENAMEX> fit. Now, if the show doesn't go on, it will be martyred; if it
does, it will draw even bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> than originally
anticipated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> will have given the show's name more credence than it
ever had on its own.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is coming off as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coward</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>. He's
too <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> to pick on a more established cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MoMA</ENAMEX>,
which now owns P.S. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Forcing the show to be canceled at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> will
arouse the ire of culture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, the wrath of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigade</ENAMEX>, and
the sympathies of anyone who's ever tried to organize ... well,
anything . (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> did win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s approval, though; click

here to read why.)

            But the worst part is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is screwing his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> needs
avant-garde art just as it needs fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> shows. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> put us at the center of the art
world, and bring us untold riches from art-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> who
come to patronize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. The art industry is also
responsible for resuscitating--some would say gentrifying--some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
most desolate neighborhoods, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TriBeCa</ENAMEX>, the meatpacking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DUMBO</ENAMEX> section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>.

            It's no surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is coming out as a cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX>. But
selling out his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to do so is pretty sick stuff indeed.

         
      
   
