
   
   
      
         
            Merger Attempt Denied

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timor</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, which is also the top non-local story at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post off-leads this development, but goes instead with continuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-Floyd</ENAMEX> power outages up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times gives plenty of pagefront property to the storm's aftermath in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> but leads with what is emerging as perhaps the
largest source of Medicare fraud: not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> but illicit schemes
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to administer claims. The
Times says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have paid more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$275 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (since when? the story isn't that clear) to
settle fraud and other charges relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> payouts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> complaint: The
story relies on the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>" in the early going, holding
off until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> paragraph before using any actual names of offending
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Colorado</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico Blue Cross</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Shield</ENAMEX>."

            The coverage reports that although the (mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>) peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> found calm at the airstrip where they touched
down, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> in overall command said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> would respond
"robustly" to any armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
WP quote the general praising the cooperation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes so far as to say
their reaction was a "cordial welcome." All this in contrast to the stark scene
evident everywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls
"the most vicious and thorough scorched-earth exercise that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> has
seen since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II." (For a primer on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>, click 
here.) The plan is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, for the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to make
possible a large-scale humanitarian aid effort very shortly.

            The USAT front-page "cover
story" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> terror says that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> there to observe the independence
referendum made a tape, from a radio scanner, of communications between
Indonesian special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and the marauding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>. One
quote alleged to be on tape says of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>: "Those white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should
be put in the river."

            The LAT fronts the buildup of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> border and reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> told a national TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that the region is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> said his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s air attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> would
continue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the mood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is similar
to the height of the war with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception: now there doesn't
appear to be any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> anti-war sentiment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> will announce a
new alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> under which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Carpoint</ENAMEX> auto shopping Web site
will be able to provide increased information online about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords</ENAMEX>--such as
particulars about new car inventory or used-car service records--to potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. (Laws currently prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> sales from being consummated online--a
franchise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> must still be involved.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> hopes to reach similar arrangements with other car
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. It's good that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carpoint</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who might buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords</ENAMEX> as a result of
Carpoint research are put on notice up front that there is some connection
between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, which brings us to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
bombshell <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> revealing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> paid for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institute</ENAMEX>'s newspaper ads supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s position in its antitrust
tussle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: If, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> insists, there was nothing wrong
with helping to disseminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX>'s ads, then why didn't the company
simply announce the help at the time?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that a rising corporate Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> was
arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Monica Pier</ENAMEX> for attempting to use the
Web to arrange a sexual encounter with an underage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, who was actually an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undercover FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> piece says the man
worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infoseek</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says he works
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports the results of
a survey among <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> about what the next
election should be about. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,400</NUMEX> total ballots <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.1 percent</NUMEX> picked
campaign finance. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was health, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.1 percent</NUMEX>.

            
               Guess he didn't write 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , another of those millennial issues, contained an
annotated photo cum pensee cum fashion spread wherein <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William H. Macy</ENAMEX>
"revisit[s] major milestones from midcentury <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macy</ENAMEX>
reveals: "When I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50s</TIMEX>, we had these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> exercises where
we'd stick our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> under our desks to protect ourselves from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. How
utterly naïve we were."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Video</ENAMEX> recently conducted a poll of pay per view <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. Among the
results: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountants</ENAMEX> were the most likely to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPV</ENAMEX> movies in the nude.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> came in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. Where was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> on that one?

         
      
   
