
   
   
      
         
            Oh, No! Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>!

            There was endless hype for the premiere of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>--tapes of which had been
withheld from the press--because it was to provide the answer to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX>'s
Perils of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline</ENAMEX> -like cliffhanger: Would the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX> college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman Felicity</ENAMEX> fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> with her handsome and
intelligent though overly chatty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX> or drive home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
with the exceedingly handsome but markedly less intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>, an ex-crush
who had become her best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>?

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> know by now,
she chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>. This was disastrous for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity</ENAMEX> personally, of course, but
also, surprisingly, for us. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> didn't just alienate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX> and her best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> and land herself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> who gives every sign of being a sleazebag
(and whom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hopes she'll slough off within an episode or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>). She set
herself back to exactly where she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> at the beginning
of the show's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> rushed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>, on whom
she had a goofy unrequited crush. (She had been planning to enroll at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>
and become a premed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>.) She spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the year</TIMEX> getting over it
and growing up, so convincingly that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> speculated she might have become too
sophisticated even for the neurotic brainiac <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX>.

            All of which brings up a troubling fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>, the
network-wannabe that became a network <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> on the basis of its hit teen
shows, will be forced to face more and more in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming years</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Adolescents</ENAMEX> grow
up fast. This gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> three choices: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) They can keep coming
up with new shows but risk losing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> from the last ones; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) They can
find a way to retard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' development; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) They can figure out how to
let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> grow without abandoning of original concept for the show. Many
television series face this quandary, of course; how they respond is one
measure of their merit.

            The sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> choosing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> is the sight of the
WB flunking that test. It's as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie Morningstar</ENAMEX> had gotten back together
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel Airman</ENAMEX>--your classic if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglicized Luftmensch</ENAMEX> --once she had come to her senses. But then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Wouk</ENAMEX>
didn't write his classic coming-of-age novel on the basis of female teen-age
focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> can't help suspecting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>, being cuter, tested
better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX>.) Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity</ENAMEX> was a sweet romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>,
alternately flaky and smart. Plus she had the best curls on television. The
curls are still there, thank God--they won't be sheared till later in the
season--but everything else on the show now seems like a grim and ugly parody
of itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> has become hangdog and whiny. Her and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX>'s banter has
soured into spite. "I can't believe how horrible it is that we're speaking like
this to each other," she tells him quaveringly, as he punitively regales her
with details of sex he had with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicity</ENAMEX> is
again paired unhappily with her bitchy punk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, only this time the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roommate</ENAMEX> is less amusing and more scarily invasive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>'s ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> has
moved back in with him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, which has the effect of turning a
hitherto delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> into something just short of a stalker.

            And on it goes, in details too creepy to enumerate.
You'd think that all this would just add interest--who needs more artificial
sunniness from television, anyway?--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alas</ENAMEX>, is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ingmar Bergman</ENAMEX> movie, or even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX> one, and the
darkness just turns some delightful teen-age fare into an exercise in viewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masochism</ENAMEX>. If you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, it seems, growing up is impossible to
do.

         
      
   
