
   
   
      
         
            How <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Accurate Is Once and Again</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remarkably</ENAMEX>, as it turns out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> isn't a divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> in the suburbs,
but she did conduct an informal survey of divorced suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> she knows
on the realism of Once and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Again</ENAMEX> . That's the much-touted new drama by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers/producers</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Zwick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Herskovitz</ENAMEX> (who is divorced)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in the suburbs who meet cute--while dropping their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> off at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>--and date even cuter. (It airs <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>)

            Here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> picayune but quite common details of the separated life that
Culturebox, for one, has never seen on a TV series before. (If you have, please
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">write Culturebox</ENAMEX> and tell her where.)

            

               The endless shlepping. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> in joint-custody arrangements invariably
forget stuff at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and make the other one take them there late
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>. At the beginning of the episode, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli</ENAMEX>
Sammler, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11th</NUMEX> -grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the male <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
Sammler, announces he has to be taken to his mother's because he's left his
history notes there.

               The homework-falling-through-holes syndrome. It's completely understandable
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who don't communicate well would have a hard time keeping track of
schoolwork done by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> during the course of a single
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. This comes up in Once and Again when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli</ENAMEX> starts failing two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> doesn't make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> buckle down on the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> he sleeps at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.

            

            Many of the other details of divorce on Once and Again are the
regular fare of family sitcoms or dramas. There's the slightly tired riff about
deadbeat dads: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-husband</ENAMEX> promises to show up at their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s soccer
game, but forgets about it until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX> angrily reminds him. There are the mutual
accusations of denial or neurosis, with each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> accusing the other either
of refusing to face their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s problems or of making too much of them.
There's the way the smart-aleck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> discuss the details of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>'
sex lives with them.

            That last, in fact, strikes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the falsest</TIMEX> note in Once and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Again</ENAMEX> , since
it has been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s experience that real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will go to some lengths
to avoid the disgusting details of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s sex life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zwick</ENAMEX> and Herskovitz
grasp this, in principle, since at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> asking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plaintively</ENAMEX>, "Why can't they keep their private lives private ?" But the
needs of dramatic exposition clearly proved too much for the show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>:
How else are you going to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> to go into their feelings for each
other, or at least about dating, if they aren't going to share with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?
After all, who else do divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spend their time with? (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX> gossips
some with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, an annoyingly perky single <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>, but  goes on and on
about her fears of dating with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> mostly keeps things to
himself, but is interrogated by curious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.) Despite lapses like these,
Once and Again strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> as the first show to make an attempt
to capture divorce as it is lived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. With a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> divorce rate in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> run by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as many
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>), Once and Again seems poised to become for joint
custody what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirtysomething</ENAMEX> was for yuppie angst.

         
      
   
