
   
   
      
         
            Just Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planned Community</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Russ</ENAMEX>,

            Since you mention reviews of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration</ENAMEX> books, I
thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Andersen</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6, 1999</TIMEX>) was on the money. It had a touch of skepticism
regarding the subject (after all, this was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ), but took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s town-building attempt seriously--except for the
preposterous name, of course, although preposterous town names are hardly
unknown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hope</ENAMEX>, for example, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Harmony</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mentions</ENAMEX>, or my favorite, also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panacea</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX> raises an interesting point regarding the town
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration</ENAMEX>: That is, it is not really such a novelty. Most of what the two
books describe about their experience of living in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> (covenants,
problems with house construction, issues of governance, questions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exclusivity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s motivations for "starting over," and so on) is found in
any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>-planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that are built in this
country <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. The experience of moving into a brand-new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is
interesting, but neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration, U.S.A.</ENAMEX> nor
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Celebration Chronicles</ENAMEX> (pretentious title, no?)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sufficiently</ENAMEX> acknowledges that it is an ordinary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX>, like
clockwork, we build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 1 million and 2 million</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, the majority of
which are in master-planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, some of which, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Cities</ENAMEX>, are
much larger. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> has written interestingly about
the subject of contemporary new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX>
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> . A much more thoughtful book than either of the ones we are
considering.)

            Of course, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebration, U.S.A.</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Celebration</ENAMEX>
Chronicles would have been written had not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Co.</ENAMEX> been a part of
the story. In that sense, there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX>'s Believe-It-or-Not quality to
these books. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> wishes for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Kidder</ENAMEX> to write about the same subject.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidder</ENAMEX>'s gift is to draw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out, and to keep himself in the background.
What mars both these books, in my opinion, is that one finds out altogether too
much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' opinions, which are, frankly, neither original nor all
that interesting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frantz</ENAMEX> (full disclosure here, I correspond with him) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> tend to be earnest and well-meaning, hence sometimes a tad pompous.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX>, never lets us forget that he is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and not easily
to be taken in. I tend to agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX>, that Frantz/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> are the
better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, and have done their homework--and produced a better book.

            I'm not sure I agree with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archeology</ENAMEX>-in-reverse
analogy. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, I have seen many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>, and
planned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> completed but without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>. It is spooky, I agree,
but hardly unusual. Again, with Celebration there is the tendency to inflate
the ordinary into the extraordinary, as if the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> raised the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ante</ENAMEX>, somehow. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s involvement did alter what happened (the
school, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homebuyers</ENAMEX>' expectations). Maybe we can talk about
that next time.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
Witold

         
      
   
