
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meritocratic Revolution</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>,

            I, too, was very impressed with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Big Test</ENAMEX> . I
also thought better of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part, which starts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Kerr</ENAMEX>'s role in
the creation of the three-level <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> higher-education system, and ends
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann's</ENAMEX> detailed account of the political battle over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights</ENAMEX> Initiative, than you did, but I'll get to that later.

            I will confess I began the book with the weary expectation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Testing Service</ENAMEX> (ETS) would be attacked again, as they have
been so often in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banesh Hoffman</ENAMEX> because of the ambiguity built
into short-answer tests, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Nairn</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> tries to
keep its test questions private, and by many because of the common charge that
all the tests do is to confirm the advantages of those from good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
with educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. The book is after all subtitled "The secret history of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meritocracy</ENAMEX>," which arouses the suspicion that there is something
disreputable that has been kept secret and will now be revealed. But of course
the large outline of this history of how academic qualifications became the key
consideration for college and university admissions isn't very secret at
all--it's been told by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Jencks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Riesman</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic</ENAMEX>
Revolution , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 30 years ago</TIMEX>, and in other studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> higher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, and part of the story is also told in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX>
               ,
as you suggest.

            But the detailed story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> has constructed on
the basis of really impressive research in the ETS archives is indeed new. In
view of earlier attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX>, I would have been interested in knowing if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> had any problems in gaining such full access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> archives.

            There is no question that the shift to meritocracy in college admissions,
combined with the growing significance of college as the entry point to key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">professions</ENAMEX> and occupations, does amount to a revolution. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> had
remained less important--it once was: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX> for example was
dismissive of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>--it would have mattered less just what the
standards for admission were.

            I do think a few nuances in this well-told story have been neglected by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bryant Conant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Chauncey</ENAMEX> play key roles, and clearly the
effect of the shift to an exam like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> is to make it possible for those
with fewer social advantages and who have not attended high-status prep schools
to successfully compete for places like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> if they are academically able.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chauncey</ENAMEX> truly wanted to create an elite based on merit, and in
doing so were reducing the opportunities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and
background. But when this story begins in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930s</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conant</ENAMEX> becomes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and is thinking of ways of selecting able <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> and elsewhere outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s traditional recruiting area,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> were still to some degree discriminating
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Indeed, one reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> was extending its reach
beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> metropolitan area from which most of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> came was in order to reduce the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Going
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> had its own good reasons, but were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> being overly suspicious in
thinking that one reason, which they did not think was so good, was to recruit
from areas in which fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> lived? I would have been interested in knowing
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX>, on the basis of his research, believes this factor was at work
in trying to recruit a more nationally representative student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.

            I would also note that the meritocratic process was not only self-initiated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. There was also pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, resulting in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state law banning discrimination on the
basis of religion just after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and this law was fought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
and other private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> effect of the law was to forbid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to ask for pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> followed New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in passing such laws. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> had good reason for
preserving their right to make their own decisions in admissions, but was one
reason the effort to reduce the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who would have
qualified on academic merit alone?

            This is prehistory but not entirely irrelevant. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> were opposed to affirmative action in admissions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> was
because it had not been so long since they had been fighting discrimination
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. Indeed, even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were not all convinced that
this was only history. I recall that a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX> met
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of admissions at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> because some of them wondered
whether any vestiges of these practices remained. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of admissions
did at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point say there was a problem of an oversupply of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from
the suburbs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the doughnut, as he called it, and it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Rosovsky</ENAMEX>, I recall, who commented that to some of those present that it
was not a doughnut but a bagel. But it was not long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosovsky</ENAMEX> himself
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascended</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most important position at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> of the leading Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>.

            At the time, to replace non-academic criteria of any kind with academic
criteria--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> is an academic criterion: Doing well on it means that one
will do well at the things one does in college--seemed a gain for justice and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equality</ENAMEX>, and there was no one ready to attack this development. But then
almost immediately, the question came up: It might be justice, but was it
equality? And we began to struggle, and we still struggle, with the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> do not do well in these tests. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> uncovers an early
effort, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, to create an adjusted score on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> that takes into
account the socio-economic background of the test-taker. It stands to reason
that if test results are correlated with income or other measures of social
background, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who do better than "expected" on the basis of their
socio-economic background, may be stronger than their test results indicate.
The adjusted score would be called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAT</ENAMEX>, measure of academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. This is
surprisingly similar to recent efforts in ETS research to create a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strivers</ENAMEX>'
score." But neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAT</ENAMEX>, which did not take account of race, or the new
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strivers</ENAMEX>' " score, which may, would have solved the problem created for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meritocratic</ENAMEX> system by low black achievement on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX>, because that is not
accounted for by the lower economic and educational background of black
test-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>.

            That problem was there at the beginning, when meritocracy appeared to have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">triumphed</ENAMEX>, whether at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, and it is still
with us. So it made sense for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> to move from the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX> to the
history of affirmative action, as it affected higher education admissions. He
tells this story in a rather different way from the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ETS</ENAMEX>, with an
emphasis on the role of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and others, who entered college
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> at a time when meritocratic considerations were not yet affected
in a major way by racial considerations, and when a number of young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>-
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had opportunities to attend elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> they would
probably have not been able to in the pre-meritocratic age. Some of them became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the effort to maintain affirmative action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. Themselves
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of meritocracy, they were now ready to reduce its weight for
those who did not do well in the tests created to serve meritocracy. This part
of the story is based more on interview and less on research in archives, but I
think it is told well. I think, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, you are being too prickly in responding
to it. It is true it is told from the point of view primarily of those who
tried to save preference, and one may be able to take issue with some of the
journalistic flourishes, as you do, but aside from characterization of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> I don't detect bias.

            But I agree with you that when it comes to the upshot of the whole story,
those scanty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last few</TIMEX> pages on what it all means, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> just throws up his
hands, and leaves a lot dangling. If not these tests, which? None? Aiming at
what kinds of characteristics? How do we discover them? Are there really any
alternatives?

            But this letter is long enough, possibly too long for the format, so I will
leave discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX>'s attempt to sum up to the next letter. I would be
interested in knowing more of what you make of this last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, and his
position. He seems to be struggling between some distaste for the role of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> and an inability to formulate an alternative.

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Glazer</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
