
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeasement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Time</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">asking Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> to stay with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Though disturbed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s views on
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, positioning himself as the clear <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX>,
claims he needs a unified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> to win. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with
a federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s rejection of late-term abortion bans passed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> dismissed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> bans because they
could unconstitutionally restrict <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-trimester abortions (the
story is stuffed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes local, describing a battery of reforms to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s ailing
child support program.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s desire to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, expressed in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>
interview, puts him at odds with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, who feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> would do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> a favor by leaving. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also notes that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, in an address to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> announced that he wouldn't fuel the debate by
entering it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explicates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s theory: 
the same "liberal interventionism" that spurred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s aggression now
threatens to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> "straight into the arms of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Communist</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> agree that the abortion bans were deemed
unconstitutional because their wording could also prohibit procedures used in
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-trimester abortions. The ruling will likely endanger the ban
passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, as well as a similarly worded bill pending in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The papers disagree about how many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have passed such bans
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>), and
how many of these bans have been temporarily or permanently blocked by appeals
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>). Further appeals are guaranteed: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, here we come," one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activist</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> seems to agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s child
support programs needed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s legislative fix, but the LAT waits until after the jump to describe what's wrong, and how
the reforms will fix it. Previously, cases were handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s
district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, with little statewide supervision. This fragmented system
proved ineffective: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, only one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> cases filed led to collection,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were wrongly billed, and attempts to create a statewide child
support computer system failed, resulting in large federal fines. The new laws
transfer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' duties to new county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, which will be overseen by
a new statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Child Support</ENAMEX>.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager reports
that, in the face of violent protests, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> delayed signing a
law concerning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s emergency powers. The bill was rushed through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and engendered protest from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who feared that the
law could lead to a military coup. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> claim that the act would actually
decrease military power. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> and a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> were killed
during the protests.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stuffs the story, but
mentions early on that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> was apparently killed by a sniper
using live ammunition, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> claims only rubber <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> were
used. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says why this is important: A similar
discrepancy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX> helped fuel protests that toppled the Suharto
regime.

            The WP front tells of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s growing fund-raising role in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is targeting his
past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, many of them generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, claiming that no matter who
wins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>'s campaign is good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
actually combed through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> for contact names (a violation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> regulations). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s redoubled efforts are
"penance" for disparaging comments he had made about the campaign.

            The LAT fronts a scrutiny
of online chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> stings. Though the growing number of stings are leading to
a lot of arrests, they may draw attention away from what is overwhelmingly an
offline problem. Child advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> make <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> contact
with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> online in only a tiny fraction of the cases they handle. And
in such cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> is usually initiated in mainstream chat areas. The more
hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, it seems, are now frequented largely by undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Liberté , égalité ,</ENAMEX>
T&A: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marianne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s buxom equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX>, is best known as
the topless revolutionary in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delacroix</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liberty Leading the People</ENAMEX> .
But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two centuries</TIMEX>, she has appeared in many guises, modeled after
many different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. A front page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story
reports that controversy has erupted over who will be the model for Marianne
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">finalists</ENAMEX> are a model, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, a game show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>/windsurfer, and a model/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> want a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marianne</ENAMEX> who
represents the achievements of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX>
thinks they've already got her: past <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Marianne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> include Bridgitte Bardot
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Deneuve</ENAMEX>, whose supple republican fervor and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, curvaceous
civic virtues are an inspiration to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">patriots</ENAMEX> everywhere.

         
      
   
