
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> Primer
            

            Immediately after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> voted for independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, militia <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> armed forces began attacking
pro-independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. They then expanded the terror to all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX>,
killing and destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">indiscriminately</ENAMEX>. What is the back story to the current
events?

            The mountainous island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>, which is twice the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, lies
in the eastern <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,000-</NUMEX>mile-long <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archipelago</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX> from northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for map of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Timorese</ENAMEX> (and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX>) are descendents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who emigrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> about
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4,500 years ago</TIMEX>. Isolated from one another by mountains, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> settlements have
developed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a dozen</NUMEX> distinct languages and religions over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> landed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1520</TIMEX>, declaring it a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A century</TIMEX>
later the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> established a competing claim on the island, and for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 200 years</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> colonial powers produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> for burgeoning trade in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Indies</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1800s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> controlled most of present-day
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> had little besides their claim on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Timor</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> empires agreed to divide the island, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> ruling the eastern
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> the western.

            During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> seized most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>' island
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holdings</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> retreated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> declared
independence. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX> became part of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of Indonesia</ENAMEX>,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> remained a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>'s control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> declined over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three decades</TIMEX>, as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> agitated for independence. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> granted limited
self-rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, the elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> seceded and
established the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Democratic Republic of East Timor</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> took
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> by bloody <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and declared it its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">27th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrilla force</ENAMEX> has battled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX> from the mountains ever since.

            Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX> remain quite similar. While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 90 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX> are predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>--a vestige of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> missions. Bahasa <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
official tongue, is the language of business in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timors</ENAMEX>, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Timorese</ENAMEX>
continue to speak traditional dialects. And though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
GDP comes from the service sector, both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Timor</ENAMEX>'s economies remain
firmly rooted in agriculture.

         
      
   
