
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mini-Cops and Salad-Bar Gouging</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>:

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> once again everything in the paper seems like an artifact from my
boyhood: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Borge</ENAMEX> getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> national-cultural-treasure
award (I know it's churlish to begrudge a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> ... but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Borge</ENAMEX>?), the putative excitement over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMAX</ENAMEX> movies (it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinerama</ENAMEX> circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> all over again), ur-suburboid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX> products in the news
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cheer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jif</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Richards</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrissie Hynde</ENAMEX> performing en masse on tour. Maybe turning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> the
other day has put me in some kind of permanent nostalgic fugue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            Apropos of my proposal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to disincentivize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> cops from making
unjustified arrests. Maybe I was being naive, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are ignored.
Still, cops in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> are the only cops on earth who don't scare me a little
by their nature. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX> a short <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> (this new generation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> is, for me, a problem) was about to ticket me for double-parking
outside the veterinarian, where I was picking up our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. He said to me
very seriously, raising his hands in a quick protective motion, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sir</ENAMEX>, step away
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>--I don't know you and you don't know me." I was holding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> in their carrying cases, and he thought I was going to pull a gun on
him? I literally had to restrain myself from laughing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Hirschfeld</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speaking of Breakfast Clubs</ENAMEX>, I once had
breakfast with him, at his behest. He spit flecks of baked goods every time he
spoke.) Are his antics maybe too over-the-top to enjoy? How did I manage to
miss the story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> about his paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500 to 11</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> who
acquitted him of tax fraud? (That story was mentioned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s story about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hirschfeld</ENAMEX> can't pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> in his impending
murder-for-hire trial.)

            But this is, after all, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> of consumer affairs
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> held a news conference on location in front of a display of "tofu
triangles" to present his findings that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deli customers</ENAMEX> are routinely
overcharged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 cents</NUMEX> for salads at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad bars</ENAMEX> because the delis charge for the
plastic containers. This is exactly the kind of press conference that makes me
feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is podunky at heart. Local TV news makes me feel the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, why do we always and only "brace" for hurricanes?

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
