
   
   
      
         
            Fly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me to the Moon</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of favorite things about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is how weather-proof
it mostly is. How it takes a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three-foot</NUMEX> snowstorm to shut it down, and even
then the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX> work. But all this changed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>, when there
was a flash flood that shut down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> completely. Absolutely flooded the
subway system. Do you know why? I do. Because they're not spending enough money
keeping the drains clean. This was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, I think, but it's one of
the nice side-effects of living with a former political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on all sorts of things like tertiary sewage-treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. I just
heard from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> that everyone is being sent home from work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 o'clock</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>; that would never have happened but for the incident <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.

            So you are thinking of canceling a book signing just because no one will
come?  You must go. I insist.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> you wrote that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> don't exist as a culturally distinct
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. You are so wrong. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> began in around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> ended.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> were about sex, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> were about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> are about
money. There were no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">'80s</ENAMEX>. They never happened. I know this: I am about to make
a movie that takes place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, and when you make a list of what the '80s
were, you come down to a list of what they weren't: no cell phones, no color
computers, no SUVs, no botox, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starbucks</ENAMEX>, no Web sites, no *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">69</TIMEX>, etc. For the
purposes of the movie, I think of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> as the moment just before everything
that is currently happening happened.

            This brings me to a thing I love to think about, especially when I fly to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>: the private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. I didn't fly on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, I hasten to say. But I did
read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, and if you look at their list of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Establishment</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of them have private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> or access to them.
I'm sure the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> think of nothing but how to get them. There are people
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> who would truly rather die than be seen flying commercial. In
fact, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> was visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and said he
was going back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> I saw him and said, "I
thought you were going home." "We couldn't get out," he said. Now, what he
meant was not that he couldn't get a flight home--there are, as you know,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of flights to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>--but that he couldn't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> jet.
He actually stayed an extra day in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> rather than submit to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humiliation of American Airlines</ENAMEX>.

            And guess what! This brings me to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yay</ENAMEX>. Or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelmans</ENAMEX> of
the world. Because if you really want to know how these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get beautiful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to sleep with them, I'll tell you: They take them on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>. The jet
is a powerful aphrodisiac. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> is the thing that causes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duffs</ENAMEX>
of the world to lose their minds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> is the thing that makes them all do
the I'll-never-go-hungry-again thing. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Back to Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> , so
maybe it belongs on that list of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 best</TIMEX> after all.) In fact,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX> broke up, at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> convention
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> told everyone (without irony) that one of the
injustices of the breakup event was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX> was forced to fly
commercial back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> .

            I wish you would write about private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. Really.  I could go on
forever.

            My ghastliest show-business moments were spent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>, but bad
as they were, there were nowhere near as bad as being told you've flunked an
exam you haven't flunked and being forced to go to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer school</TIMEX> (and, as the
Times notes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, being punished by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> for flunking said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exam</ENAMEX>). The story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s paper is truly horrible: These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with
serious self-esteem issues anyway.

            By the way, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is an article about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, who gave a speech here in which he admitted to some qualms about
his career as a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is clearly looking for a job.

            I have a rule about who wins the presidency, too. Mine is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
the most authenticity and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the biggest balls. This is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> is so dangerous.
And your remark about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> truly strikes fear into my heart. Although
someone gave me his autobiography for my birthday, and I feel you could not
possibly have read it if you believe you could pull even the smallest lever for
him.

         
      
   
