
   
   
      
         
            What Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Entrapment</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Naughton</ENAMEX>, a top Internet company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, was arrested last week
for allegedly crossing state lines with the intent to have sex with a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, whom he had met in an Internet chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The 13-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> turned out to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. Why is this not entrapment?

            In most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, a successful entrapment defense requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> to
prove <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things:

            

               
                  The idea of committing the crime came from law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>,
rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> .

               
                  The law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> induced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to commit the
crime . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> have traditionally maintained a high burden of proof for
inducement. Simply affording the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> the opportunity to commit the crime
does not constitute inducement. For inducement to be proved, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> must have
used coercive or persuasive tactics.

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> was not ready and willing to commit this type of crime
before being induced to do so . If an undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> carrying a kilogram of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> could not plead entrapment,
even if coercion were involved in the sale, since his intent to sell was clear.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> also allow a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>'s predisposition to be demonstrated through
prior conduct or reputation.

            

            The reported facts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naughton</ENAMEX> case do not appear
consistent with these requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naughton</ENAMEX> is alleged to have carried on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-month</TIMEX> Internet relationship with the undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> during which he
repeatedly solicited sex and ignored warnings that her age might get him in
trouble. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naughton</ENAMEX> purportedly frequented chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult men</ENAMEX> to
contact teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and is alleged to have had sexually explicit images of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on his laptop computer.

            Next question?

         
      
   
