
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taint Necessarily News</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with what it describes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s refusal, on
grounds of executive privilege, to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with documents it requested
for its investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX> clemency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> each run this as their off-leads,
choosing to lead instead with the continued course northward of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX>, now
downgraded to a tropical storm. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times has its very own storm to lead with, a widening police scandal,
called by the paper the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s worst in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX>, featuring allegations of
shooting unarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>, planting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> and of drug dealing and
sending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> on totally false court testimony. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX> investigation does not make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s front.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes high up that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s citation of executive privilege is
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> such in his presidency. The WP sets the clemency dustup
inside a broader context, noting that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is investigating the FALN
clemency, it is also probing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s role in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>
banking improprieties, as well as the possibility of a cover-up about its
conduct in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> confrontation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gives a more nuanced account
of the standoff than the others. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> refused to
hand over documents, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says it's saying no to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> too,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will release some clemency documents it
feels are not covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege and will allow three
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to appear at congressional hearings. But everybody
agrees that there is now considerable friction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. On
both sides of the aisle: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a critical quote about the clemency
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>.

            The fronts feature the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now-routine day</TIMEX>-after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> profiles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> churchgoers and then himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The LAT
headline is almost a template, calling him a "loner, full of rage." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> effort is typical in finding out that he was prone to mood swings,
fantasized about murder, and was feared by several of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. Since this
sort of information can evidently be put together in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, wouldn't it be
better to require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to do so before a gun purchase could legally be
made, rather waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to do so after a shooting?

            The WP front reports that high tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> appear to have
prevailed in the long-simmering debate about whether or not national security
concerns should prevent them from exporting software that encrypts electronic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX>. (This story fronts the LAT business section and was
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the online version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> said exporting encryption is okay, while it also gave
law enforcement increased power to combat criminal uses of computers, although
not as much as had been contemplated in several working drafts of the
decision.

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> estimating that tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> sickens <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 76 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and kills
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. This is double the last authoritative estimate, made
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. What with all the attention paid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">toll</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen or so</NUMEX>
deaths), you'd think that a story about a phenomenon said to have claimed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of lives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> would get a lot of front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>. Think again.
Apparently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't deem this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for thought. It's not on anybody's
front.

            What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> tipped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, everybody has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> donating <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> towards financing for college and advanced
studies for minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the sciences, engineering and education. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Negro College Fund</ENAMEX> is quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> saying the
gift would increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 to 40 percent</NUMEX> the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> who receive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doctorates</ENAMEX> in the targeted fields. The coverage reports that the decision has
drawn some fire from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> complaining that it shuts out qualified white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that, soon
after a top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> was court martialed for having sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, another top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> was just removed from his big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> job
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> sees if he did the same thing. Fortunately, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> brass
hat looks a lot better in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed, a retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admiral</ENAMEX> argues that since it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s direct interest to have
access to the improved manpower pool that would come out of better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, the
military should get behind a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX> program to repair every public school,
fully finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head Start</ENAMEX> and reduce class size from kindergarten through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
grade. How do you come up with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$230 billion</NUMEX> this would cost? By canceling
all the unnecessary <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, subs and nukes in the defense budget, says the
former <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.

            Where, oh where, are the stories about the presidential and congressional
pay raises passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>? Not on anybody's front. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> effort is
typical: It puts the congressional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,600</NUMEX> raise (to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$141,300</NUMEX>) on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> and
doesn't say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s salary is being doubled (to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>). And the
whole thing is buried deep in a story under a headline that doesn't even
mention the raises.

         
      
   
