
   
   
      
         
            Who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Framed Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>?

            The consensus so far on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>: A Memoir of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> who inserted a fictionalized version of himself
into his work, is just this side of insane and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> just that side of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exploitative</ENAMEX> and corrupt. This strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> as distinctly possible but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shortsighted</ENAMEX>, literarily speaking. Not wanting to steal thunder from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Brinkley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX>, who are scheduled to debate
the book in 
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> won't defend what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
has written--she can't, anyway, having read only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excerpt</ENAMEX>--but will lay out a few arguments for why he has, in principle, every
right to try to write this way, but can't make it work.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Just because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> was driven to do what he did by desperation, as he
has admitted in interviews, doesn't mean it lacks legitimate precedent. The
history of literary biography is like a yoyo--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one century</TIMEX> it careers toward the
facts, the next it swings away from them. It has ever been thus, at least since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mythologizer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plutarch</ENAMEX> published his Lives , and continues to be
thus in the debates over footnotes, etc., between academic and journalistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biographers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> thinks the outcry about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> resembles the
furor over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lytton Strachey</ENAMEX>. His masterwork was Eminent
Victorians , a collection of brief revisionist essays about great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> that contributed no new facts but rather a
mocking spin on existing ones.  In a time of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-tome biographies, his were
short and to the point, which has a lot to do with his popularity. His more
enduring innovation, though, was, as one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> has put it, "liberating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> from the enslavement of data." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strachey</ENAMEX>'s most controversial liberty
came at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of a later</TIMEX> biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>, in which he made
himself free to enter her mind as she died:

            

               She herself, as she lay blind and silent, seemed to those who watched her to
be divested of all thinking--to have glided already, unawares, into oblivion.
Yet, perhaps, in the secret <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> of consciousness, she had her thoughts
too. Perhaps her fading mind called up once more the shadows of the past to
float before it, and retraced, for the last time, the vanished visions of that
long history--passing back and back, through the cloud of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, to older and
ever older memories--to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> woods at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osborne</ENAMEX>, so full of primroses for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Beaconsfield</ENAMEX>--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmerston</ENAMEX>'s queer clothes and high demeanour, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>'s face under the green lamp, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>'s first stag at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balmoral</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> in his blue and silver uniform, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baron</ENAMEX> coming in through a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">doorway</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord M. dreaming at Windsor</ENAMEX> with the rooks cawing in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">elm-trees</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Archbishop</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canterbury</ENAMEX> on his knees in the dawn, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old King</ENAMEX>'s turkeycock ejaculations, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Leopold</ENAMEX>'s soft voice at
Claremont, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehzen</ENAMEX> with the globes, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s feathers sweeping down
towards her, and a great old repeater-watch of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s in its tortoise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shell</ENAMEX> case, and a yellow rug, and some friendly flounces of sprigged muslin,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kensington</ENAMEX>.

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Interpolations such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strachey's</ENAMEX>, above, have become commonplace. No one
complains about the tiny fictionalizations that abound in almost every
biography written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, award-winning biography
The Rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX> . For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> spotted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
bits of fantasy on the very first page! The scene being set is that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> reception for the public on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year's Day, 1907</TIMEX>:

            

               A shiver of excitement strikes the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-breast
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s front gate, and runs in serpentine reflex along
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Avenue</ENAMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seventeenth Street</ENAMEX>, before whipping south and
dissipating itself over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a mile a way. The shiver is accompanied by a
murmur: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s on his way downstairs."

               There is some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shifting</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX>, but no eager pushing forward.

            

            Was this based on known fact? Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> have documentation for a snake-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quiver</ENAMEX> rushing through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, or for its <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">foot-shuffling</NUMEX>? Let's face it: He
speculated, and we let him get away with it, because his writing has the ring
of truth. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> excerpt of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> , there are many
similar tours de force , some imaginatively construed as celebrity
question-and-answer interviews (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>), others set inside some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. In short, literary biography in our time is more literature than
biography--we believe it if it's well-imagined. Acting on that truth and
playing around with form is anything but a moral shortcoming. Inventing
fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has done in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> , however--clever as it
is--seems doomed to fail as a literary device. Mainly, it's intrusive.
It destroys the illusion of transparency. In theater one would say it calls
attention to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, the proscenium framing the play. Even in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strachey's</ENAMEX> and the earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' wildest speculations, they hewed to an
implied contract between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, We'll go along
with you as long as you make what you say sound like it had some basis, once
upon a time, in verifiable or even plausible fact. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX> who is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chum</ENAMEX> is neither a verifiable nor a plausible fact; he's a
hypothetical. He's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Rabbit</ENAMEX> of biography, a cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> inserted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">into Reagan</ENAMEX>'s more straightforwardly filmed movie. He may not be less true than
the  little fabrications and self-inventions in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> specialized; in
fact, given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>'s greater levels of alertness and perspicuity, his
self-inventions are probably more true. The problem is they're like the
anthropological definition of garbage: matter out of place.

         
      
   
