
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Can the weather move markets? I'm sure there's an academic study on this
question somewhere, but in lieu of actually finding it, let's speculate based
on a single sample: the performance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of stock markets based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, all bets were off, since volume was thin and a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> went home, in expectation of a disaster that has yet to arrive. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Are</ENAMEX>
hardnosed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> really supposed to be taking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-days because of a
little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>?) But it was interesting that just when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> was falling
hardest, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> seemed gloomiest, stocks were selling off sharply, while
by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mid-afternoon</TIMEX>, as the rain slackened and then disappeared, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> came back
into the market in force, so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>, for example, finished the day
almost even. I don't want to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moody</ENAMEX>, but ... investors
are moody. And so, on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cocktail Chat</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "Despite yet another benign inflation number, the bond and stock
markets sold off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, apparently because no one really believes
that everybody can keep spending without prices starting to go up. Maybe we
should have the equivalent of those 'No TV' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, except we
can call them 'No frivolous spending' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Of course, I don't know what I'd do
with myself on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Most unsurprising headline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Russian Loan From IMF</ENAMEX> Seen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unfairly Aiding Group of Banks</ENAMEX>.' At this point, isn't it clear that
fairness for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> is about as real as leprechauns
are to the rest of us?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Financial news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> took an equity stake in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archipelago</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest electronic communications network for
stock trading. Now, when we finally get interactive TV, you'll be able to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">click on Ron Insana</ENAMEX> as soon as he mentions a stock and
instantly make a trade. It'll be paradise."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> is going to bring in a host of Wall
Street securities <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and let them work in a local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> expressed skepticism to the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , saying, 'I try not to eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.' He added
that he often told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> it had to improve its food
quality . I'd love to hear the rest of that conversation: 'I don't
drive, either. But damn, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> has got to improve the handling in that new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">528s</ENAMEX>.
And what's with the cut of those new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> suits ? I only wear
T-shirts and khakis. Television? Never watch it. But why is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> still airing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX> ?'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "According to a recent survey, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> of all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-olds</TIMEX>
believe that they will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of
those <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> believe that they will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading
Internet stocks."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX> announced that, beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, it will start paying advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> based not
on a percentage of overall ad spending, but rather on how successful
the advertising is in boosting sales . Ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> immediately hailed
this as a brilliant innovation. Of course, if they thought it was so brilliant,
you wonder why they've been content to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few decades</TIMEX> collecting
hefty checks for ads that didn't move sales a bit. Oh, yeah, you really have to
wonder."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> announced that it would be offering high-speed Internet
access through DSL technology, even as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> announced that it
would start unrolling cable-modem service more widely. Of course, you have to
live on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper East Side of New York</ENAMEX> or in certain magic
suburbs to get any of the above. It's just what I want. More and more excellent
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that will forever remain just of out my reach."

         
      
   
