
   
   
      
         
            

            
               An Odd
Request
            

            Or, at least, an odd place
to put this request. We are looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, or potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, who have e-mail but don't do the Web thing. We suspect that a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fall into this category, and we would like to make sure they have the
opportunity to sign up for our e-mail delivery during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, while it's still free. If you're reading these words on the Web, you're
clearly not one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but you may have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who
are. And many of you are reading this on a printout, or (our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> tell us) on
a photocopy or a hand-me-down of a printout. (We don't mind! Be our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guest</ENAMEX>--until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>.) If so, you should sign yourself and/or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> up
for e-mail delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. What you get, every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, is a file,
nicely formatted and ready to be printed out on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8½ x 11</ENAMEX> paper. But you can also
read it on screen, directly off your own hard disk, as many choose to do.
Signing up is easy: Just go to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate Help</ENAMEX>" page (or click here, you
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lazy bum</ENAMEX>) and type in your e-mail address. But if, for any reason, you cannot
or would prefer not to perform this function (as the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> like to
say), just e-mail us at slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Say that you'd like e-mail delivery, give us your
e-mail address (essential, obviously) and the name of your service provider
(not essential, but helpful in straightening out problems), and we'll take it
from there. Paranoid considerations: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) You will 
               not be billed ,
now or in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, when the free period ends, unless you sign up all over
again. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) You can cancel delivery at any time . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every weekly</TIMEX> delivery
explains how. Prominently. It's easy. Honest. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) We won't give your address
to anyone else , or abuse it ourselves. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> will 
               not
have you killed . By the way, e-mail delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> makes a marvelous
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas present</TIMEX>. No wrapping needed. And you can't beat the price.

            
               Slate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader Survey</ENAMEX>
            

            On a scale
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 to 5</TIMEX>, in which (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) is "not at all willing" and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) is "desperately eager,"
how willing are you to take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> to fill out an online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> survey?
(E-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will get the survey by--well, obviously--e-mail.) If you
are anything from mildly to extremely willing, we'd appreciate your input. And
you may even enjoy the exercise. This survey consists of a few simple questions
merely designed to strip you bare psychologically and to allow us to compile an
exhaustive medical and financial dossier on you that could be used for
unimaginable purposes. You may wonder, for example, why we need to know the
answer to Question <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47b</TIMEX>: "When was the last time you cut your toenails?" Or
(Part <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">II, Section 7, Line 3</ENAMEX>): "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Chekhov's Uncle Vanya</ENAMEX> a tragedy or a
comedy<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The answer is nothing nefarious or mysterious. It's simple morbid
curiosity. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers Weed</ENAMEX> (and isn't that a name you can
trust?) has an insatiable desire for knowledge. He watches tapes of old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
Moyers programs in the shower. His slogan is: If you know it, I'd like to know
it too. So, help him out, and fill out the survey. (Actually, it's completely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harmless</ENAMEX> and fairly short.) Many thanks.

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley

         
      
   
