
   
   
      
         
            Norse by Norsewest

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this summer</TIMEX>, an
out-of-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and I were taking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ballard Seafood Festival</ENAMEX>, an annual
celebration of music, troll dolls, and pickled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
neighborhood that serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scandinavia</ENAMEX>'s unofficial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpost</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballard</ENAMEX>, annexed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>
many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, maintains its culture and loyalties without much consideration
for national or civic boundaries. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, solid and conservative in look
and outlook, are often referred to as "square heads," which suggests a stolid
stupidity many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedes</ENAMEX>, but all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> flags fly here.
The kindly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harald V</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> visits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year or so</TIMEX> to ensure that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballard</ENAMEX> remains within the realm. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> grow strong by enduring the pain
and suffering of having to eat lutefisk , the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> that offers a
challenge to the character, much like haggis for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutefisk</ENAMEX> is
cod that is treated with lye and is transformed, in the process, into a
gelatinous, fishy, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass</ENAMEX> that, I imagine, is not unlike sperm <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> ...
sperm. When I was growing up, we had to eat it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eve</TIMEX>. "No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lutefisk</ENAMEX> --no gifts" was, no doubt, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> law.

            As we
strolled the festival, I mentioned to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that a statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leif Ericson</ENAMEX>
stands <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Shilshole Bay</ENAMEX>. He gave me a sideways look. "Leif
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ericson</ENAMEX>!" he sneered. "Did he ever come here ?"

            The question and the tone turned me snarky. Why the hell do
I have to justify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leif Ericson</ENAMEX>? Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Columbus</ENAMEX> ever sleep in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>? Did he ever reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Columbia River</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> are monuments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who never came here,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amerigo Vespucci</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is named for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Rainier</ENAMEX>
is named for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rainier</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> admiral and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
who never sailed these waters. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strait</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan de Fuca</ENAMEX> is named for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navigator</ENAMEX> who likely never existed at all. And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> questions Leif
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ericson</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s
ship traffic passes under the statue's gaze. Undoubtedly, it brings good luck
to local seafarers, many of them named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Einer</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ole</ENAMEX>. But it is also a
great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>. When this bold figure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ericson</ENAMEX> was unveiled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, and
later used in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postage-stamp design, it stood for the righting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
history's great wrongs. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> had the guts to tell the truth, and to cut
that truth in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>, by paying tribute to the real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> "discoverer" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who explored and settled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Vinland half</NUMEX> a millennium
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> pretender acting for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.

            
My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, sad to say, had revealed himself
with his inquiry as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vinland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubter</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has not read The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sagas</ENAMEX> ,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> still waiting for more proof than contemporary maps, detailed written
accounts, and carbon-dated archaeological evidence. In short, a typical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>.

            I am feeling less snarky and
more cocky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, however, because the answer to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s question
might actually be closer to a "yes" than I ever expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ericson</ENAMEX> might not
have slept here, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norse</ENAMEX> ancestors might have, you betcha. A recent
discovery along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Columbia River</ENAMEX> may provide key scientific
evidence that proves it.

            But
before we get to the science, let me introduce a pet theory of mine: that there
was an ancient link between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Indians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norsemen</ENAMEX>.

            Consider the parallels. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forayed</ENAMEX> south from their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> in the north along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbia</ENAMEX> coast and lived off the sea and plunder. They raided in canoes not
unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>. They were also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> and whalers, as many are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic Peninsula</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Makah Indians</ENAMEX> have asked for permission to
join the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegians</ENAMEX> in resuming <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale hunts</ENAMEX>, an ancient custom the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scandinavians</ENAMEX> never gave up despite international pressures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Coast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tlingit</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and slaves, as did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>. And they
have a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mythology</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and themes not unlike those found in the
Norse myths: Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raven</ENAMEX> brought daylight to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> world, he also
whispered words of advice into the ears of the supreme god, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Odin</ENAMEX>. At the very
least, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were kindred spirits with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yore</ENAMEX>.

            But the
links may also be genetic or, at the very least, the result of ancient
ancestral contact. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last July</TIMEX>, a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> found a skeleton along the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash. Carbon</ENAMEX>-dating traced the remains of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennewick Man</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 7265 and 7535</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX> The bones proved to be those of a
male who was tall for his time (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 feet 9 inches</NUMEX>). He was also a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--a
spear point was found lodged in his pelvis along with evidence of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>
wounds. He survived these, and lived to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50</NUMEX>. Oh yes, it also appears,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who have carefully examined the skeleton, that he was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasian</ENAMEX>.

            
No horned helmet was found, but the discovery
is complicating--perhaps overturning--theories about the settlement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Did the ancestors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> really come from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> over the
Aleutian land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">bridge</ENAMEX>? Or did they arrive after an earlier migration or
settlement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>, or early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>? Could
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick Man</ENAMEX> have come by a route similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ericson</ENAMEX>'s, say via skin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> or
over an ice mass connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon State</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Bonnichsen</ENAMEX> thinks the latter is a possibility,
which would explain why some ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tools are more similar to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> ones than to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> ones.

            Not surprisingly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an Indian</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Umatilla</ENAMEX>, has already demanded that the bones be reburied as if they
were ancient native relics, and federal law backs them up. They argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are merely desecrating the dead. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> a "national treasure," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologists</ENAMEX> want to conduct DNA tests, which
might offer clues to his origin. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> already resent suggestions they
are descended from ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>--such contentions fly in the face of their
creation myths. Imagine how they'd feel if tests revealed their ancient
ancestors were white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> . Worse, imagine how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Burns</ENAMEX> would feel.

            I suggest a test to resolve
the matter. Check to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick Man</ENAMEX>'s skull is slightly squared around
the edges, suggestive of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a cube</NUMEX>. Look for evidence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> cut and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>-reliant diet. If such evidence is present, return <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick Man</ENAMEX> to his
rightful tribal reservation. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballard</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
