
   
   
      
         
            Money Talks

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>
walks.
            

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,048</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 12</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 19</TIMEX>)
            

            
               By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years ago</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> made a mess of campaign-finance reform. A <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>-inspired law
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> had placed dollar limits on campaign contributions and campaign
spending for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valeo</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>), the court
ruled that spending limits violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> cannot
restrict your right to spend money communicating the message of your choice.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> upheld contribution limits on the reasoning that contributing money
to someone else is not an act of speech. (Spending limits for presidential
campaigns were allowed as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quid</NUMEX> pro quo for accepting federal funds.)

            Having
contribution limits but no spending limits creates all sorts of weird
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anomalies</ENAMEX>, above all the shadowy and often farcical distinction between
"independent" and "coordinated" expenditure. If your spending is coordinated in
any way with the campaign you're supporting, it's held to be an in-kind
contribution, subject to limits. Unless, that is, you yourself are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, in which case you may spend and coordinate to your heart's content.
It all makes perfect sense--in theory.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> wandered back into this thicket <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, and
wandered out again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Republican Federal Campaign Committee</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> held that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> cannot restrict
spending by the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> on behalf of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. But the opinions were all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX> said that the
spending was independent and therefore OK. Some said it was coordinated, but OK
anyway in the case of a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Some said it was coordinated and
therefore not OK. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> said the whole game was absurd
because contributions deserve <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> protection just like
expenditure.

            The
official goo-goo position for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> has been that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valeo</ENAMEX>
is wrong for the opposite reason: Spending limits should be OK too. The
shorthand argument is that "money isn't speech." Spending limits don't prevent
anyone from expressing an opinion. At most they regulate the volume of speech,
not the content. Efforts to level the playing field of politics and reduce
political corruption, by reducing the role of money, actually serve First
Amendment interests. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> has published innumerable
editorial riffs on these themes.

            But how would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> feel about a
"reform" that did the same thing in the field of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>? That is, a law
designed to level the playing field and promote diversity in an increasingly
concentrated industry vital to the political debate. The law would limit the
amount anyone could spend in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> for the purpose of publishing a newspaper.
The law would place no limits on what could be said in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>--only
on what could be spent on a newspaper. And suppose that the limit were
somewhat less than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> now spends (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less</NUMEX>, even, than its in-house
downsizers dream of spending). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , I think, would find serious
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> Amendment difficulties with such a law.

            As this
example shows, money indeed is speech. Restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s right to spend
money expressing themselves is a very real--and unconstitutional--restriction
on their right of free speech. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> certainly may address the problem
of unequal voices in the political debate. It may do so through devices that
increase the quantity or volume of speech, such as financial subsidies or free
TV time. To some extent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needn't be impartial: It can promote the
messages it prefers ("<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are bad") over messages it doesn't ("<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are
fun"). What it should not be allowed to do is to level the debate by reducing
the volume or quantity of someone's speech. And that means money.

            So is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> right? Are contribution limits no
different? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' opinion is part of an increasingly popular line among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> that the best campaign reform would be to repeal the old rules,
not to pass new ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> killed a reform bill that
would have cracked down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX>, "soft money," and other current arrangements
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't care for. A major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> talking point was that
contribution limits are an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> against freedom of speech.

            It's
fun to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> calling for anti-majoritarian
judicial activism. What they are saying is that even though contribution limits
are so popular that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are clamoring for more, and even though these limits
are embodied in a law duly enacted by a majority in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and signed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>"--I believe that's the usual epithet--should tell
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they can't have their way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> has written column after
column sermonizing about <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> excesses, lecturing sternly about the
difference between "speech" and "action," and ridiculing the idea that (for
example) flag-burning sends a political message and therefore qualifies for
First <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> protection. Yet there he is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> last week
huffing that campaign-finance reform "has done more damage to constitutional
values than <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>," and endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' notion that political
contributions "are acts of political expression, as well as exercises in
freedom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>."

            That's the argument, and it's pretty weak. Unlike, say,
burning the flag, the act of making a political contribution is not primarily
intended to send a message. In fact the contribution would often be unknown if
it weren't for federal reporting regulations. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> reasoned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>,
the message implicit in a campaign contribution--"I support <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Candidate X</ENAMEX>"--has
little to do with the size of the contribution. (A bigger contribution may or
may not mean, "I really, really support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X."</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX>" is an even bigger stretch--one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> would laugh out
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> if some liberal proposed it. Contribution limits don't stop you from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">associating</ENAMEX> publicly or privately with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> or cause, working for the
campaign, or even signifying your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> by donating money. They may
prevent you from associating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> at an exclusive cocktail party
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and other large givers--but that's the whole idea.

            A muddy distinction, like
the one between "independent" and "coordinated" campaign spending, usually
signifies that the underlying principle needs work. In this case the
principle--giving <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> protection to campaign spending but not to
contributions--is widely mocked from both directions. As it happens, though,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> got it just about right <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>.

             

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
