
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>: A
Fashion Statement
            

            We certainly don't intend to
be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of fashion, either in the sense of being about clothing or in the
sense of following the fashion in general matters. Yet, by one of those weird
coincidences that less scrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> sometimes turn into "special
issues," we have posted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> features relating to fashion (in the clothing
sense) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, and will post <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a third Wednesday</TIMEX>.

            Our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Letter From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" concerns an admirable (but possibly doomed) campaign to improve
the style sense on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> campus. Our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tangled Web</ENAMEX>"
column reports on (and follows, through links) the bizarre theories bouncing
around the Internet about the unlikely figure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of
somewhat mysterious ads in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and, apparently, of a line of
clothing as well. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16</TIMEX>) brings "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clothes Sense</ENAMEX>," our regular
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> column from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>'s subject <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> isn't exactly
clothes--she writes about a show of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartier</ENAMEX> jewelry at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. But that's still fashion.

            You would
assume, from this onslaught of sartorial hectoring, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
must dress in exquisite taste. And you would be correct. Any one of us could be
transported from this sylvan landscape in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, strewn with cow
chips, computer chips, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato chips</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">haughty elevators</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cond√</ENAMEX>©
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nast Building</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX>, and instantly fit right in--stylewise, at
least. We pride ourselves on our fabrics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spats</ENAMEX>; we wear them. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> employ heels; we wear them. Not long ago,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Randall</ENAMEX>, walking across
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>, and observed, to no one in particular, "I'd kill for that tie." But
that turned out not to be necessary.

            
               Lawyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cake</ENAMEX>
            

            If you haven't checked in
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogues</ENAMEX>" have started. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> more might have
started by the time you read this. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Dworkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of jurisprudence
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, is debating assisted suicide with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael McConnell</ENAMEX>, who recently left
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago Law School for the University of Utah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Edelman</ENAMEX>,
a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who has become the most vocal critic
of the welfare reform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, is being
challenged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of Equality</ENAMEX> , who supports
the reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX> will be engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akhil Reed</ENAMEX>
Amar of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX> on whether the truth gets short shrift in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
criminal-justice system. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dershowitz</ENAMEX> recently reviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amar</ENAMEX>'s book on this subject
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>, will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">engaging Wendell Willkie II</ENAMEX>, general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, on the subject of human rights and trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            Coming soon: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Undersecretary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strobe Talbott</ENAMEX> and the managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fareed Zakaria</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> support for the expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. (Read our recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" on this
subject if you need to get up to speed.)

            These dialogues, conducted by
e-mail, are fulfilling our hope that they would develop into a new mode of
civilized debate. E-mail (at its best) combines the immediacy of talking with
the reflectiveness of writing. It also seems to lend itself--more than "live"
debates--to actual dialectical progress. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s dialogues tend to feature not
just thesis and antithesis, but a bit of synthesis as well. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occasionally</ENAMEX>, of
course, a dialogue serves to reveal the utter superiority of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the
argument, as in the recent discussion of the capital-gains
tax.)

            Often, we've discovered, the
best way to frame an interesting and useful dialogue is not to get a liberal
vs. a conservative, but to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from roughly the same part of the
spectrum who disagree on the application of their shared values to a particular
issue. In our current lineup, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willkie and Bauer</ENAMEX> are both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dershowitz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amar</ENAMEX> are both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. But we're not beyond the occasional
ideological dust-up, such as the recently concluded exchange on divorce between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Blankenhorn</ENAMEX>.

            We do seem
to end up with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Sorry about that.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley
            

         
      
   
