
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Do As We
Say
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> scolded in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, is "often too quick to
dilute the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourth Amendment</ENAMEX>'s protections against unreasonable searches in the
name of fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>." On this particular occasion, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
congratulated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for sending "a welcome message ... that there are some
searches the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> cannot justify." The message was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8-to-1</ENAMEX> decision
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> throwing out a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> law that required political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to take
a urine test. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> noted that "there is no reason to suspect a drug
problem among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>."

            Those of us who rely on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> for moral guidance on all important issues were deeply
alarmed by this sermonette. Not that we disagree, of course. Disagreement with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial page verges on logical fallacy. One might
as well disagree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niagara Falls</ENAMEX> about the effect of gravity on large
amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s editorial therefore raises the troubling
issue: Is there "reason to suspect a drug problem" among staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ? We ask because we happen to know that the New York
Times requires its own new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to take a urine test for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. At
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent hire was told that flunking the test once would eliminate any
chance of being hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --now or at any time in the future.
When this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> attempted to wash up after providing the required sample, it
turned out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tester</ENAMEX> had removed the handles from the faucets (apparently to
prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> from diluting the product).

            There
must be some explanation! It's true that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is not the
government, so its drug-testing policy isn't unconstitutional. But that alone
doesn't make the policy any less "unreasonable." It's also true, of course,
that a junior copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is obviously more vital
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> than an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>. But it would be
useful to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial page spell out the exact difference
here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who must decide between doing what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says and
doing what it does.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow</ENAMEX>
Journalism
            

            Slate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will naturally wonder what our own drug-testing policy is. It is very
simple: All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>, free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> must produce a urine sample under the direct
observation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colleagues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> often join
in, turning what could be (and, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , apparently is) a
grim ritual into a festive and sentimental occasion. Photographs are taken and
posted on the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Intranet</ENAMEX>. For those who will be writing about
software-related <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, the ceremony is conducted once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>
himself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX>. ("I used to do these
individually in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> says with a sigh, "but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s gotten
so darn large!") We don't know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , but at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate,</ENAMEX>
we don't actually send any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing. We just sorta
like having them around.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
267,090,705 Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Americans</ENAMEX>
            

            As our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Other Magazines</ENAMEX>"
column notes, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> chose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to celebrate
large numbers of allegedly remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anoints America</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> "most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , perhaps
foreseeing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> would repeat this device from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, upped the
ante with a list of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Century</ENAMEX>." We here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> wish
to make it clear that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> can play this game. We have, of course, the
long-established tradition (well, dating back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost five months</TIMEX> now) of the
Slate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>--our list of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s biggest givers to charity. Our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> report for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> is published in this issue.

            But is that enough? The
Slate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>, we confess, is discriminatory. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might like to make the
list by giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> to charity are unfairly handicapped by the lack of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>. Furthermore, something must be done to stop this insane
competition between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> --and many other
magazines--to come up with ever larger and less coherent lists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The
only solution is a pre-emptive strike. We at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> have pondered the situation
and concluded that every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> is influential in his or her own way. Some,
for example, are bad influences--but influential nevertheless. And, although we
have not asked each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, a random survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> indicates that none of
them is opposed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>.

            
Therefore, we proudly announce that the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">267,090,705</NUMEX> wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s population clock--is on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s Most
Influential <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Americans With the Hottest Bods and Biggest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salaries</ENAMEX> Not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mention Intriguing Personalities and Best Restaurants</ENAMEX> Under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>. Our heartiest congratulations to each of you. And we are confident
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s list contains more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will make history in the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's list does. To find your name, try the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Pages</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WhoWhere?</ENAMEX>,
or PC411, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phone Book</ENAMEX>. (The last of these, however, includes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> among its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX>
million listings--tragically, they do not qualify. After all, somebody has to
be excluded, or it isn't much of an honor, is it?)

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
