
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Medal
Detector
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hackworth</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America's Most Decorated Living Soldier</ENAMEX>" according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> himself, is back
in the news. Hackworth was instrumental in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> ago
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Boorda</ENAMEX> was wearing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> medals he wasn't
entitled to wear. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorda</ENAMEX> committed suicide. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackworth</ENAMEX> wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
"It is simply unthinkable an experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> would wear decorations he is
not entitled to, awards that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> bled for. There is no greater disgrace."
Now it has come out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackworth</ENAMEX> himself was claiming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> military
decorations he wasn't entitled to claim: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger Tab</ENAMEX> (indicating membership in
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">commando</TIMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry unit</ENAMEX>) and a second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distinguished Flying Cross</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackworth</ENAMEX> has now removed these decorations from the résumé on his home page.

            We can't
resist noting that the first skeptical examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackworth</ENAMEX>'s career, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, his military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">decorations</ENAMEX>, and his general trustworthiness occurred
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's Major
Embarrassment: He's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Called Col. Hackworth</ENAMEX>"). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>
(associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krohn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, retired).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackworth</ENAMEX> as a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> article went on to win a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Magazine Award</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer, and the Nobel Prize for Literature</ENAMEX>.

            
               Life
After Death
            

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Bedfellow"</ENAMEX> column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Such a Deal: The</ENAMEX>
Romance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent Control</ENAMEX>," misstated the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Jacobs</ENAMEX>' famous book,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death and Life of Great American Cities</ENAMEX> . We had it as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Life and</ENAMEX>
Death ...," and, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Luscher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> points out, "The
difference is meaningful."

            
               More
Stuff
            

            Slate uncorks a gusher of
new editorial features <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Look for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Egghead</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the
other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28</TIMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is
available on the Web around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">PDT</TIMEX>.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primer</ENAMEX>" is a weekly briefing on issues in foreign policy and world events.
It will be prepared for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford Analytica</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that specializes in analysis of global political trends.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egghead</ENAMEX> is a reasonably
lighthearted look at recent developments in scholarship and academia. Egghead
will be laid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingua Franca</ENAMEX> , the lively print
magazine of academic life.

            "Chatterbox" is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first for Slate</ENAMEX>: a totally "live," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-days-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-week</TIMEX> feature. Using the same
technology we use in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>-discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will be
updated whenever the fancy strikes, independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s official daily
posting schedule. It will contain whatever news scooplets, insights, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reflections</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX> can either solicit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> or, if necessary, download from his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. The consensus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> contributions are essential. A button on the
"Chatterbox" page will make this easy, so please do join in.

            

               Who?
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" for
Memorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day week</TIMEX> will be written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> has no idea who or what
this is. But everyone else around here seems quite excited about it. So maybe
you will be too. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX>'s first contribution will appear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. Happy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
