
   
   
      
         
            Cruising the Cybermansions

             

            
               Click on the icons at
the bottom of this page for an interactive tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cybermansions</ENAMEX>.
            

            Not long
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, the rich in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> were earnest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bores</ENAMEX> who lived in interchangeable Tudors
tucked into old gated communities. They were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stimsons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeings</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nordstroms</ENAMEX>,
and they made their money cutting down <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, building <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>, and selling
shoes. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cascade Mountains</ENAMEX>, they were "partially visible some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, and completely visible none of time," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> once said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascades</ENAMEX> are still a rumor for much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. But
the rich have come out in force in this corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> once known for
its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> reserve. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Washington</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18-</NUMEX>mile-long moat
that separates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastside</ENAMEX> locales of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bellevue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mercer Island,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirkland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>--global <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
               . The
transition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Washington</ENAMEX> from a decent water-skiing pond into something
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatsbyesque</ENAMEX> and gawk-worthy has been so dramatic that now some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> visit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> for the sole purpose of staring at all the man-made creations on and
around the lake. Rather than disparage this trend or try to describe it with
one-dimensional, snide remarks, we offer instead our own tour.
Semiauthoritative, free, and interactive--with a few snide remarks
nonetheless.

            
               Click to start the
tour.
            

            On the tour, click on a
numbered circle to advance to that tour stop.

             

             

            Click for
text-mostly version.

             

         
      
   
