
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Cybermag
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tabloid Love Nest</ENAMEX>
            

            One goal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is to help
you to stay efficiently abreast of developments you aren't wildly interested
in. You may have skipped all those worthy newspaper articles about that coup in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burundi</ENAMEX>, but we hope you'll feel guilty enough to read a short "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist"</ENAMEX> column on
the subject. (Relax, that's only a theoretical example. There wasn't a coup in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burundi</ENAMEX>. As far as we know.) In that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, we introduce a new feature this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>," which will track developments in the world of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>. (It will be posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 6</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, of
course, are much too morally austere to have any genuine interest in the sex
lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, the diets of talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, and suchlike paranormal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phenomena</ENAMEX>. But we all have a duty to stay well informed of what engages other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Yoffe</ENAMEX> has heroically volunteered to wallow
in the mud on our behalf and distill it into a palatable essence.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>
Done
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> was not the first
time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX> quit a high-profile job in a high-profile manner. At dinner in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">leafy Washington</ENAMEX> neighborhood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, the talk turned to real estate: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welds</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is for sale. Is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Division</ENAMEX>? Is he leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>? Yes, he's moving
back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s up there now, checking out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks later</TIMEX>, a front-page story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> and another top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> "abruptly announced their resignations
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>" as an act of "conscience" over revelations about ethically
questionable behavior by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Meese</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX> had no advance
warning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s "mounting frustration" had reached the breaking point. So
we have long harbored the suspicion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX>, jolly and appealing
character that he is, might be a bit, um, self-styled--an impression discussed
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>."

            That said, it should be noted
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is forever in the debt of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Weld</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and then a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, came up with the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, at a moment when we had almost despaired of finding any name for our
magazine that was both euphonious and trademarkable.

            
               In Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interface</ENAMEX>
            

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new ways to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enjoy Slate</ENAMEX> without soiling your fingers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>. Our popular new
feature, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"--a summary and analysis of the front pages of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--can be e-mailed to you every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, free as sunshine (for now). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> appears on our site
overnight and soon (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, we hope) will be in your e-mail box by breakfast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>. At the moment it's a bit later than that. There's an
easy e-mail sign-up form at the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>. Or you can sign up by
sending e-mail to microsoft-request@microsoft.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nwnet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, with the message
"subscribe papers" on a line by itself.

            Then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX>, a "push" service that
puts news and information on your screensaver. A selection of articles from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is now among the features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PointCast</ENAMEX> will automatically download for you.
Getting your Slate this way is as easy as dismantling a medium-sized nuclear
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. Simply go to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pointcast</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, download the PointCast
installation software, install the software, configure the software (using the
easy-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">misunderstand</NUMEX> instructions), then go looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, which can be
found by simply right-clicking on the box labeled "connections," choosing the
"personalize" option, clicking the "add" button, then clicking on "news and
weather," then scrolling halfway to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> until you come to a listing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate,</ENAMEX>
and then clicking on "subscribe." That's all there is to it!

            And don't forget the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways Slate</ENAMEX> can come to you, instead of your having to come to us. Slate on
Paper, our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> all-text edition, formatted for print-out on standard <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8½ x</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>
paper, is also available by e-mail (free) or on actual paper by actual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
mail (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>). To sign up for e-mail delivery click here or e-mail read@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. To get the paper mail delivery, call
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-555-4995</ENAMEX>.

            If you sign up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotmail</ENAMEX>, a (free, natch) Web-based e-mail service, you can get
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s table of contents delivered to you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. And we also continue to
support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> delivery by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FreeLoader</ENAMEX>, another "push" software product that,
sadly, has gone to its reward.

            The new version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s Web browser, Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>, due out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, will allow
(but--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Microphobes</ENAMEX> please note--not require ) automatic download of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.
(You can download a trial version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IE4</ENAMEX> now, if you want.) We have humbly petitioned
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poo-bahs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape Corp.</ENAMEX> to include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inbox Direct</ENAMEX> feature of
their own new browser, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Netscape Alligator 4.0</ENAMEX> (we think it's called). But so far
they seem determined to deny their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> this valuable opportunity.

            Down the road, we anticipate
even more advanced "push" features. Our "Summary
Judgment" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, which saves you the trouble of reading reviews, will
be upgraded into a service that will implant the consensus opinion on all the
new movies, books, television shows, etc., directly into your brain, saving you
the trouble of reading and seeing the books and shows themselves. Also, while
PointCast packages news and information as your screensaver,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SlateCast TM</ENAMEX> will package acute witticisms about the news directly
onto your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">voice-mail</ENAMEX> answering message--in your own voice--thereby completely
eliminating the need to develop or even to express your own opinions.

            Finally, for those who still
enjoy having their own opinions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> will soon offer a new "personalization"
feature. The inspiration is published accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, which
reportedly learns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>' preferences in music and art and adjusts itself
accordingly as you stroll from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate BiasServer</ENAMEX> TM
applies this concept to the magazine world: You'll register your views just
once, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> will thereafter recognize your browser and serve up opinion and
analysis that reconfirm your prejudices. You'll be able to cruise from article
to review to column to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with a growing feeling that you're absolutely
right about everything. Just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> ourselves.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
