
   
   
      
         
            

            
               One
Year
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24</TIMEX> marked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s first
anniversary. The occasion was celebrated, here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, with a gala
black-tie dinner and a nude "fun run" around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> campus. It was
declared a national holiday in several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> (for a
small fee). The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congo</ENAMEX> issued a stamp (ditto). And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> were released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in a general amnesty for plagiarists and
other violators of intellectual-property rights.

            Do we deserve such honors?
On balance, we think we do. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year has, of course, brought both
successes and disappointments. On the positive side, we have transformed the
nature of journalism, morally vindicated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>, vastly enriched
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX>, captured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>, and learned the correct spellings of
many difficult words. On the downside, we did get it slightly wrong about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> ( grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> ... it's an easy
mistake to make). There was the unfortunate occasion when we accidentally
(albeit repeatedly) linked the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Netscape</ENAMEX>" to a site for devil worshipers.
That litigation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> remains unresolved, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> believe our offer of free <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight Simulator TM</ENAMEX> software
upgrades was more than generous. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RealOdor TM</ENAMEX> streaming olfactory
feature does not as yet work as well as we had hoped, frankly. (We're talking
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">StenchMaster</ENAMEX> about a new strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year</TIMEX>!
We asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> should mark this historic occasion. He said,
"Give the whole staff enormous raises." It was, of course, a characteristically
insightful suggestion, brilliantly slicing through to the heart of the
strategic challenge we face at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the close of the second millennium</TIMEX>. But our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers Weed</ENAMEX>, was deeply offended by the idea. "That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> seems to
think money grows on <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>," he complained. And so, displaying the kind of
corporate independence our many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> think us incapable of, we told Mr.
Gates his idea sucked. (Well, actually, we told him that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX> thought his
idea sucked.) As an alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' suggestion we have put together a
special
selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> articles published during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our first year</TIMEX>. We all agree
that perusing some of the highlights from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is far more
pleasurable than a large raise. But try it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for yourself.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White and Read Online</ENAMEX>
            

            We inaugurate a new feature
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Today's Papers</ENAMEX>." To be updated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days a week</TIMEX>), it is a
summary and instant analysis of the lead stories in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>:
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the Wall

               Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> 
               Today , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>, will report what the
papers chose as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s big stories, assess how they played those stories
(both placement and content), and tell us about any exclusives or unique
pieces. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> will, of course, link where possible to the full stories
on these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>' own Web sites.

            We aim to
post <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 a.m. Pacific Time</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m. Eastern Time</TIMEX>) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of
publication, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. So if you're one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
doesn't bother to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> home delivered <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each morning</TIMEX>, go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> for a quick
briefing before you face the world so you can embarrass less informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.

            
               Gear
Alert
            

            Too many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, we regret to report, are attempting to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> without the proper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>. The proper equipment, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzine Safety Task Force</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Internet Bores</ENAMEX> (AAIB), is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> T-shirt and matching
baseball cap. Attempting to access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> while improperly dressed can lead to
slow download time and even, in some cases, to the implosion of your computer.
Please take a few moments to order the appropriate gear, directly from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> (scroll right to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> stuff) or, if you still use one of
those old telephone things, by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-380-3180</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>).

            
               Resting
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Laurels</ENAMEX>
            

            In honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s first
birthday, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States of America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">221</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">st , Slate</ENAMEX>
will not publish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. The site, of course, will still be available,
including all current contents, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> will be updated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> throughout
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. And there may even be the occasional "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" entry or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" item.
You never know. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will be spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> in
various mountain retreats, perfecting the spiritual arts of transcendental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meditation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTML</ENAMEX> coding. Regular posting of new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> will resume the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 7</TIMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
