
   
   
      
         
            

            
               A Tough
Decision
            

            You might notice in the next
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, we hope, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s pages are being served up to you a bit faster.
(Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX> we were still serving up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s edition for a good
part of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, but that's a different story.) The reason for the
increased speed is new Web server software. This is the software we use to
deliver pages to you.

            We knew
it was time to upgrade, but we faced a dilemma: Which new server software
should we choose? The software business is viciously competitive, of course,
and we didn't make our choice lightly. Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX> headed an
investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>, and a demographically
correct cross section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX> male, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> college
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.9 percent</NUMEX> cross-dressers, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchasers</ENAMEX> of a toaster or
other electrical appliance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three months</TIMEX>).

            Our ServerSearch 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> traveled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX> in pursuit of the very best software for serving you, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. In an
Eskimo <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic Circle</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, they sampled server software
made with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale blubber</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> have been doing it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who has developed server
software based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucian</ENAMEX> principles and the sayings of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiaoping</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTML</ENAMEX> than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donkey</ENAMEX> who knows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>"). In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>, they were wined, dined, and offered bribes by slick
twentysomething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with names like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraudicom, EgoSoft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems PLC</ENAMEX>.

            Back here
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, the team rigorously tested each piece of software on genetically
engineered laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> design a Web page with working
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperlinks</ENAMEX>? Did they develop <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> or brain tumors? Did they turn into
Internet bores? The software was then exposed to extreme conditions: zero
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gravity</ENAMEX>, below-freezing temperatures, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX> in the disk drive, elderly
grandparents with their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> computers, etc.

            
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> reassembled for a retreat at
a luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maui</ENAMEX>. Human-resource facilitators were brought in to conduct
trust games. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acupuncturist</ENAMEX> was hired to alleviate the stress of this
momentous decision. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> dropped out and had to be replaced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alternates</ENAMEX>. At a marathon all-night session, it took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX> ballots before a
consensus emerged. Bleary-eyed but triumphant, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> emerged into the moist
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hawaiian dawn</TIMEX> to announce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> to the awaiting world.

            "We have chosen," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shafer</ENAMEX>
declared, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Information Server 3.0</ENAMEX>. There were many fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> we decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s product had the edge in
ease of use, elegance, and--above all--job security."

            "Whew!"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. "That was a close <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
Schedule
            

            For new arrivals to our site
(welcome!) and for regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who are a bit confused about our schedule
(and who can blame them?), here is how it works. Slate posts new material every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weekday</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, we "go to press" with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>'s edition
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 5 p.m. PST</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, we publish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> edition at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m. PST</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). In general, arts and cultural articles are
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in the week</TIMEX>, and newsier and political stuff is posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. "The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week/</TIMEX>The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>" is updated throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" has a new
entry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, and contributions to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches & Dialogues</ENAMEX>" are posted as they arrive.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>," our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> forum, is active <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days a week</TIMEX>.

            Most articles remain in the
current contents list for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. All past articles, features, and columns
remain available in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>," our
specially formatted print-out version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, is e-mailed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around midday</TIMEX>. It also can be downloaded from our
site. Those services are free. An actual paper edition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>"
can be mailed to you (call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-555-4995</ENAMEX>), but that costs money and can take a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to arrive.

            Is all
that clear?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley
            

         
      
   
