
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Slatewear: It Had to Happen
            

            Well, for a while we thought
we'd try to be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in either the software or the magazine
business not to be peddling T-shirts on the side. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s technical-support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX> and a demoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>) reports that among the
most frequently asked questions is this one: "What am I supposed to wear while
reading an online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>?" We naturally consulted our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clothes</ENAMEX>
Sense" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX>, who advised that traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geekwear</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> shorts, T-shirt, and baseball cap--is appropriate for both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexes</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any hour of the day</TIMEX>.

            We're still working on the
boxer shorts, but the T-shirt and cap are now available. Scientific studies
indicate that they enhance the pleasure of reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from 19</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX>. They are also suitable for puttering in the garden, plea
bargaining on both the federal and state levels, or writing fiction or poetry
(blank verse only, please--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> cannot be held responsible for rhymes).

            The cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.95</NUMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-shirt</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.95</NUMEX> for the cap. To order (toll-free, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>), dial <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-380-3180</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> only). Or order directly off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>.
(This links you to the order form for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> logo products, and you have
to scroll down a bit to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> stuff. Ask for item no. MS0306SL
[T-shirt] or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">MS0403SL</NUMEX> [cap].) When we checked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
products were illustrated with a pile of golf balls. If that's still the case,
just ignore it.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
