
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Download Completed Successfully</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>
Lyall, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>, wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>, with more charm than enthusiasm, about the experience of being
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight-plus</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> pregnant. We are pleased to report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>'s ordeal is
over (or possibly just beginning): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice McCrum</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> pounds, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ounces</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mother</ENAMEX> and laptop are doing fine.

            
               Now Is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Winter of Our New Contents</ENAMEX>
            

            If you're here, and reading
this online, you probably got here by way of our new home page and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Table of</ENAMEX>
Contents." We hope you like it. For a site as packed with contents as this one
(and we speak only of quantity here), designing the contents page is a constant
trade-off between packing the information tightly, to minimize scrolling, and
presenting it attractively. This latest version--not a finished product, but
just another way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> on a journey who-knows-where--offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review Slate</ENAMEX>'s current offerings. If you click on the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Date</ENAMEX>" just below
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> logo on the contents page, you'll get a straight list of current
articles in reverse chronological order, with the most recent additions on top.
To revert to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Contents Classic</ENAMEX>, click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page Number</ENAMEX>." And let us know what you
think, at slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            We
previewed the new opening sequence for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, who studied it for a few
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> and said impatiently, "How do I find the place where I have people
killed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>?" We answered, It's usually buried somewhere in a column
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Readme</ENAMEX>." "Buried? But it's my favorite part. Whose idea was burying
it?" We mentioned the name of a dispensable subassistant to the deputy
assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bogotá</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>. "Have him killed," he said.

            
               Boycott
AutoSummarize
            

            In this
issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate, Karenna</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has some fun with a new feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Word 97</ENAMEX>, the
latest upgrade of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s word-processing program, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX>.
(See "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cogito Auto Sum</ENAMEX>.") She tests the product on texts ranging from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> to a recipe for cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>, but she
leaves it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to decide how good the summary is. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, we have mixed feelings about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX>. Naturally we
want our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> to thrive. (And doesn't everybody, really, wish the best for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>?) On the other hand, this nefarious bit of software--if it
works--threatens to allow computers to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX> are not
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We are skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artisans</ENAMEX>, backed by centuries of tradition, who
pursue the noble calling of making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> miserable by insensitively slashing
their lovely prose. It is one thing for machines to replace textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> (the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luddites</ENAMEX>), or industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, or even--if it comes to
that--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. But when the incomes, er, we mean professional talents of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> are imperiled, it is obvious that the technological revolution has gone
too far. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editors of America</ENAMEX>, arise! We may have to go on strike before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> can be perfected, and we become powerless. But rest assured: a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of being forced to read unedited copy will bring this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to its
knees.

            
               Waiting
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
            

            For
reasons too vitally important to bore you with, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>'s dispatch on the
delivery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> civil-trial verdict wasn't on the Web until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 7</TIMEX>. The trial actually ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 4</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three long days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may have been wondering how it all came out. We could have told you, of
course, but we didn't want to ruin the suspense. We knew you'd rather wait and
hear it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley
            

         
      
   
