
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rain O'er Me</ENAMEX>

            Summer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> like to say
that it doesn't rain that much in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. With a thumb in the almanac, they'll
tell you that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> collects <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less annual</TIMEX> precipitation than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>,
which is true. What they don't tell you is that come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, as the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supersaver</ENAMEX> flies out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SeaTac</ENAMEX>, the clouds roll in from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> and
hang around Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> like the stink of a dead rat in the wall. The
inexorable damp persists until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and washes away the civility that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Northwesterners</ENAMEX> wear like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lotion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managers</ENAMEX> snap at their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> or
turn scarily morose; the cubiclebound browse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webzines</ENAMEX> (hello, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>!) and
engage in marathon e-mail bitch sessions. It feels like nobody's showered or
shaved for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>.

            Few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> have captured the condition well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Altman</ENAMEX> came close in the
opening scene of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCabe</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> , his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
Beatty rides through a shower into a logging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> resemble
nothing so much as wet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. However, no account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>'s soaked
misery surpasses that of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">explorer</ENAMEX> and abysmal speller
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Clark</ENAMEX>, who recorded his observations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 200 years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> spent
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> coast, which is to rain as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antarctic</ENAMEX> is
to snow. "Rained all the after part of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> continues this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>," he wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1805</TIMEX>. "We are all wet cold and disagreeable." During
their coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wintering</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX> enjoyed a
total of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 days</TIMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point it poured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 days</TIMEX> straight "without
a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer intermition than 2 hours</TIMEX> at a time." The word "disagreeable" is
repeated like a mantra in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>. It's a curiously evocative
description; "miserable" would be the natural choice, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s word captures
a quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX> damp that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Kesey</ENAMEX> once wrote, you have to
go through a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> here to understand. The stuff puts you on edge. About the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ninth or 10 th day</TIMEX>, everybody looks at each other and says, "God
damn it's been raining." This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Clark</ENAMEX> felt, I think. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15, 1805</TIMEX>, he wrote, "The rainey weather continued ... from the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 th</NUMEX> in the morng. untill the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> rain,
and the most disagreeable time I have experienced. ..." Cold, wet, cooped up,
and hungry. I imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark</ENAMEX> waking to the sound of skyspatter on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX> and thinking: "I can't believe this shit."

            Ithought we'd settled the fight between free will and
predestination with a sophomore reading of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erasmus</ENAMEX>, but lately, it's popping up
all over life's syllabus. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, born of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alzheimer</ENAMEX>'s-afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, has been cracking wise about who got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gram</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>. Now they tell us that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX> has its own causal gene, which has spawned
so many jokes about worrying about carrying the worry gene that I'll spare you
my own. The coming of the rain has only added weight to the sinking realization
that I'm about as free as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pavlov</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, acting as it does as cold
evidence of geographical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determinism</ENAMEX>--the idea that the landscape shapes the
human culture that thrives within it.

            There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cultures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry</ENAMEX> and wet. Both are determined by
the raw fact of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> and an ocean. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> generates warm, moist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX>, which flows into Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and bumps into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cascade Mountains</ENAMEX>.
The air condenses into clouds; it rains.

            
The fact that we're locked into this bowl of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rain</ENAMEX> has given rise to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>'s distinctive (read: "bizarre")
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subcultures</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Egan</ENAMEX> branded as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Noir</ENAMEX>" the
dark, damp movements that creep out of this moldy greenhouse: grunge music,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> , serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>. The alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egan</ENAMEX>'s alternative is the
equally strange culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months of February</TIMEX>, choose
to fly straight into the teeth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>. I'm talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REI Army</ENAMEX>,
those legions of gear-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> who suit up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> and drive
into the hills, dead set on hunting down and killing their God-given portion of
wilderness transcendence. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> I've joined their
ranks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlistment</ENAMEX> begins with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> purchase of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tex</ENAMEX> jacket and rain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pants</ENAMEX>, and thereafter requires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> tithes for boots, socks, gloves,
goggles, trekking poles, interior-frame backpacks, gas stoves, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX>
cool wrist altimeter.

            REI
recently cashiered its funky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> warehouse store for a palatial
flagship pavilion visible from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate 5</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Needle</ENAMEX>, and probably the
space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX>, too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s prime attraction is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story climbing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinnacle</ENAMEX> that looks like a schmoo constructed of stucco. Shopping in the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">boot-hut</ENAMEX>-cum-theme-park is daunting, a little like leaving the roadside chapel
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Schuller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal Cathedral</ENAMEX>. And while the soul of local outdoor
culture still thrives at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, this is not necessarily a good thing.
Just below the happy nature's-bounty song promoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REI</ENAMEX> lies the low hum of
outdoor culture's ugliest trait, a possessive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> that keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> out
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> in. A humorless sense of moral superiority is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">de rigueur</TIMEX> ,
fostered by the belief that those of us who go out and stomp the natural world
under our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vibram</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soles</ENAMEX> are healing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaea</ENAMEX> while the rest of the world is tearing
her down. Anyone who began hiking/climbing/skiing/boarding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before you
did is considered an experienced pro; you and all those who purchased their
fleece jackets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after you did are pathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wannabes</ENAMEX>. A rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">climber</ENAMEX> who
trains with some of the world's most experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crag-hangers</ENAMEX> recently told me
she still considers herself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX>. "I figure you've got to put in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>
before you get past amateur status," she said. Nothing commands instant respect
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> like a low REI number. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX>'s membership list began with No. 1
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> and now runs into the low <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 millions</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Whittaker</ENAMEX>, the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
to climb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Everest</ENAMEX>, is No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">647</NUMEX>. I am No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,538,286</NUMEX>. I bear the shame every
day of my life.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, climbing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Fuji</ENAMEX> is a rite of the Shinto
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>. A sign near its summit reads, "Only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> has never climbed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fuji</ENAMEX>; only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> has climbed it more than once." Washingtonians haven't based
a religion on climbing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Rainier</ENAMEX>--yet--but, in all other ways, it assumes
the prominence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fuji</ENAMEX> in local culture. We name <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> and baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> after
it, which gives you some idea. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> peak, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainier</ENAMEX> draws <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>
fools <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> who strap spikes to their feet and attempt to walk nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> miles in the sky. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX> I was No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,001</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Climbing Rainier</ENAMEX> is a
rite of passage for some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northwesterners</ENAMEX>, an obsession for others. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> up it before their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> birthday. Local climbers
with ego-insecurity issues often scoff at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainier</ENAMEX>. Nothing but a long hike,
they say, putting me in mind of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty Python</ENAMEX> skit about who grew up
poorest. Climbing with shoes on your feet? Ooh, luxury !

            In a sense, the climbing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainier</ENAMEX> has become the sacred rite of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REI</ENAMEX> culture. It is a long, brutal slog up
dangerous gable-steep glaciers in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 50</NUMEX> previous aspirants are
buried. Those who make it up ("summit" as a verb) are offered the cruelest sort
of spiritual enlightenment: the realization that there is no spiritual
enlightenment on mountain tops. If I had kept a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> on the summit, it would
have read remarkably similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Clark</ENAMEX>'s: "We are all cold wet and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disagreeable</ENAMEX>." I may have added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words. "Get down." Sometimes rites of
passage, like the experience of suffering, lead to great wisdom. And sometimes,
suffering in the wilderness is just suffering in the wilderness, and the only
wisdom you gain is the knowledge that you don't want to do it again.

         
      
   
