
   
   
      
         
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curse of Slate</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday, April 18</TIMEX>, was a
good-news, bad-news kind of day for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Buntrock</ENAMEX>. The good news was that he
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> were No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate 60 Quarterly Update</ENAMEX>. That is, as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of March</TIMEX>,
they had donated more money to charity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that we
could find out about: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26 million</NUMEX>, to be exact, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Olaf College</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>. But no good deed goes unpunished. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same day</TIMEX>, a stockholder
rebellion more or less forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buntrock</ENAMEX> to offer to step aside as head of WMX
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> (formerly known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste Management Inc.</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he founded and has
run for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. We trust he takes comfort in the thought that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> appreciate him even if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> don't.

            
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Cullman</ENAMEX>, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> on the list with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>
million gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> and another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>,
were quick to note that they did not recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Cullman</ENAMEX> in our alleged
photograph of the generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. We did have a photograph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cullmans</ENAMEX>,
posing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul LeClerc</ENAMEX>. We then made the
classic error of cropping out the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. We hope nobody saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Cullman</ENAMEX>
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and thought: "Poor Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cullman</ENAMEX>. This is the thanks
he gets for his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>." In any event, through the magic of Internet
technology (i.e., the ability to erase your mistakes), we have restored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>
to the arms of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. Our apologies to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>.

            
               Fray of
Hope
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraymistress</ENAMEX>, Pavia
Rosati, has been on leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX> and will be out of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" for a few more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.
During her absence, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of our earliest and most energetic "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fraygrants</ENAMEX>" have
been filling in. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CoHost Nedfagan</ENAMEX> is the handle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ned Fagan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CoHost IrvSnod</ENAMEX>
is also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Snodgrass</ENAMEX>. Both of them lead rich nonvirtual lives in
faraway locales, so we appreciate their involvement in and dedication to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> bulletin board. If you haven't yet entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>, please
give it a try. You must register in order to post a message (it's easy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">free</ENAMEX>), but you can "lurk"--i.e., read what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are saying--without
registering.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
