
   
   
      
         
            

            
               From
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camels</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
            

            Having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disappointingly</ENAMEX> failed to settle the question of whether a camel can pass
through the eye of a needle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches & Dialogues</ENAMEX>" department
has moved on to new theological disputes (in addition to ongoing exchanges
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> divorce and global
capitalism). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> and a new
book, What It Means to Be a 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libertarian</ENAMEX> , is discussing libertarianism vs. communitarianism with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leading
philosopher of community, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sandel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX>,
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of a new book about
gay
marriage, is debating that subject with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
Standard . And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Goodman</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>'s TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for Policy Analysis</ENAMEX>, is exchanging words with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
Slate over the rights and wrongs of a capital-gains tax cut.

            
               Join the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>
            

            Exhausted by the ordeal of
trying to deny poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a capital-gains tax cut, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> turns this space
over to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus Krohn</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> of "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fray</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>-discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, have been clamoring for more than a
month for special Fray threads devoted to books. Because "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" exists to
serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraygrants</ENAMEX>, we arranged a real-time threaded discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>'s
Civilization and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Its Discontents</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>.

            The thread attracted heavy
traffic--so much traffic that we were encouraged to corral a living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> to
discuss his book with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraygrants</ENAMEX>. Our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The First $20 Million Is Always the Hardest</ENAMEX> , a novel
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> startup. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX> will join "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m. EST</TIMEX> to discuss his novel in a thread titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Readings: Po</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX>." Joining him will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>, whose review of The First <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Million</ENAMEX> will run in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX>.

            Your assignment--if you
should decide to accept it--is to buy the book and read it cover to cover in
preparation for asking questions. If reading a whole book sounds like too much
work, click here for excerpts of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronson</ENAMEX>'s
home page.

            Or, suit
yourself, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> did. When told that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> had assigned a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, he roared: "It sounds
like homework! Don't they know that that is why I dropped out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>?"

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley & Cyrus Krohn</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
