
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reich</ENAMEX>
Writes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rauch Writes on Reich</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>'s article in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert Reich, Quote Doctor"</ENAMEX>) suggesting that the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of labor fantasized large chunks of his recent memoir has stirred a
pleasing fuss in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Of course, like all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, we at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, when
we must make troubling accusations against public figures, do so more in sorrow
than in anger. It truly disappoints us when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in public life
fails to meet our standards of morality, literary ethics, or oral hygiene. Like
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, we would like nothing better than to be denied all such
opportunities for indignation. That said, however, we cannot deny a small
frisson of excitement when the opportunity comes along. No doubt we are
the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who suffer from this spiritual flaw.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> has asked us to
publish an article by him in reply to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>. Ordinarily this is tricky
territory for a publication. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are entitled to reply when criticized. But
usually that means a short letter. If you allow everyone who comes under
criticism in your pages to reply at equal or greater length, you won't have any
room left to criticize anyone new--should that become tragically necessary.

            In the
vastness of cyberspace, however, these considerations do not apply with the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. Therefore, in a special supplement to "E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>," we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publish Reich</ENAMEX>'s reply
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX>. We also publish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX>'s reply to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limbaugh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rush</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rauschenberg</ENAMEX> wishes to write about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich on Rauch</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch on Reich</ENAMEX>, we'll find room for them too.

            
               Cut to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase</ENAMEX>
            

            Forget
aesthetic judgments--the key overlooked question about film <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is: Why don't
the plots make any sense? To address this critical gap, we inaugurate an
occasional column called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Plot Holes"</ENAMEX> (to be posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX>),
which will analyze movies exclusively from the perspective of narrative logic.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Harrigan</ENAMEX>, will also try to explain where plot
holes come from. Aesthetic judgments will continue to be rendered by our
regular film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>. We were only kidding when we said you
should forget them.

            
               Forestry
Byproducts
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>-related authors
have books to push, and we're happy to help. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Bick</ENAMEX> is related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> by
marriage: Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers Weed</ENAMEX>, is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>'s new book, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket Books</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>), is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All I Really Need to Know in</ENAMEX>
Business I Learned at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> , which is more or less self-explanatory.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> at the well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>,
software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, and in this book she shares the management insights she gleaned
there. (Look for a forthcoming companion volume by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>,
All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Really Need to Know in Journalism I Learned Somewhere Else</ENAMEX> . For
more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bick</ENAMEX>'s book, click here.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trail Fever</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>) is an expansion of his reportage on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
presidential campaign for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> got a taste of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> in his recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> election. His take on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> and
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> will be posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 11</TIMEX>, and he will be writing
regularly for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> is best known for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liar</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> , his devastating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> memoir of the time he spent working as an
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> is largely credited with transforming
the investment-banking profession from the collection of arrogant greedheads it
was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> to the humble and public-spirited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Such is
the power of well-chosen words. To order <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trail Fever</ENAMEX> directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, online or by phone or
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fax,</ENAMEX> click here.

            
               How
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dismal Can You Get</ENAMEX>?
            

            Under
threat of litigation, we have had to abandon the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dismal Scientist</ENAMEX>"
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> column. The rights to that name have been claimed by another Web
site. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s column will henceforth be known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dismal Science</ENAMEX>," a
phrase too famous to be ownable by anyone, except possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Carlyle</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1795-1881</TIMEX>), who coined it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlyle</ENAMEX> was inspired, if that's the
word, by the writings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Malthus</ENAMEX>, who predicted that population growth
would always outpace economic growth, keeping most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in perpetual poverty.
That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two centuries ago</TIMEX>, and remarkably, it is the last time any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> made a faulty prediction.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey</ENAMEX>
Chaucer! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live on Slate</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Followers</ENAMEX> of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> poem
may have noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> poetry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinsky</ENAMEX> chose to run something by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Jonson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. It may seem remarkable that
Jonson, who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1637</TIMEX>, is still submitting poems to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. But poetry is
a rough business, requiring eternal optimism about the possibility of
publication, even if gloom is considered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Proper Poetical Stance</ENAMEX> on most
other issues. In the spirit of equal opportunity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinsky</ENAMEX> has decided to cease
discriminating against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poets</ENAMEX> who suffer the ultimate disability of being
deceased. Preference will be given to poetry of the past that is especially
suitable for reading aloud. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RealAudio</ENAMEX> has not yet perfected sound recordings
from beyond the grave, so poems by dead poets will be read by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinsky</ENAMEX> himself
rather than by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. Living poets will continue to be eligible as well.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">poem</ENAMEX> posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX>, for example, is by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carol Oates</ENAMEX>, who is
very much alive and reads it herself.

            Look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Dickinson</ENAMEX>'s
forthcoming poem, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All I Really Need to Know in Poetry I Learned at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
