
   
   
      
         
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compleat Harry</ENAMEX>
            

            Not since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
agree, has anyone produced an epic narrative like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s series of dispatches from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> civil trial. The entire
series is, of course, available in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>." But for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who wish to fondle this
classic of our times, bind it in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather</ENAMEX>, display it on their coffee tables,
and pass it along as a treasured heirloom to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, we are proud to
offer a new sort of instant book. The entire series has been repackaged as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX> document (also as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Acrobat</ENAMEX> document), which can be
downloaded, free as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, and printed out. Like our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> print-out edition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> itself, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>" is nicely formatted in double columns for
standard <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8½-by-11</NUMEX> paper.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surgeon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>'s Warning: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compleat O.J. by the Sea</ENAMEX>" is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94,025</NUMEX> words long, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">printout</ENAMEX> is exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX> pages. (The file takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six minutes</TIMEX> to download at
28.8K.) Keep in mind, though, that you can also download the file and read it
on-screen.

            
               Let's
Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About You</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 3,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
took the time to respond to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> survey <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> back, for which we
thank you. The results prove beyond a doubt that reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is good for you.
How else would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have acquired a median income of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> and a median net worth of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Eighty-six percent</NUMEX> of you claim to
be college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> have postgraduate degrees (not all, we
trust, from law school). You spend an average of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37 minutes</TIMEX> a week reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.

            Over half
of you use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> as your browser. Nothing wrong with that, you understand.
Some of our best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, of course, is happy--indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grateful</ENAMEX>--to welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of all races, religions, genders, and browser
preferences.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housekeeping Details</ENAMEX>
            

            If you haven't yet sampled
our new, alternative "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Table of Contents</ENAMEX>," go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Contents</ENAMEX> page and click on the word
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Date</ENAMEX>" right below the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> logo. Current articles will then be listed by the
date they were posted, with the most recent stuff <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. If you like that
better than our highly conceptual system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and page numbers,
that's fine with us. (To return to the regular Contents page, just click on
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page Number</ENAMEX>.")

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> might like to be reminded that you can sign up for free e-mail
delivery of our "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>" edition, nicely formatted for printing out
(just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Epic</ENAMEX>--only shorter). It's delivered automatically every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. You can also get an actual printed copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>,
but that'll cost you money. Call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-555-4995</ENAMEX> for details.

         
      
   
