
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snowball</ENAMEX>'s Chance

            Impeachment is still a
minority taste. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-August</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> supported impeachment; by
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of this week</TIMEX> almost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> did. But why is that number
growing at all? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s response, or just the slow
sinking-in of the story may all be factors. But opinion polls themselves can
change the results of opinion polls. They can even turn a minority view into a
majority <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> without anyone actually changing his or her mind about the rights
and wrongs.

            Here's
how. Start with a poll indicating that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
deserves to be sacked. Three-quarters think he doesn't. But of that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX>
who don't think he should quit or be impeached, many are disturbed at the
thought that he has lost the confidence of so many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, and some
will feel that, whatever their own views, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should go because he
has lost the ability to govern effectively. (This argument is already a
subtheme among the commentariat.)

            How many will feel this way? Impossible to say, of course.
If everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> except you felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was disqualified on
moral grounds, you would almost certainly conclude that he should go on
effectiveness grounds alone. If half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> disagreed with you, you might
or might not buy the effectiveness argument. If <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the country
favored impeachment, you almost surely would not worry that this made the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ineffective.

            Let's suppose that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
percent favoring impeachment, one out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> of the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX>
believes that having a quarter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> wishing him impeached makes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> dangerously ineffective. The next time a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> comes around,
this small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> tells him or her they think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should go. Thus the next
poll results show that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an additional 5 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> now want him out--and
the total for ouster is now <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>.

            Of the
remaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>, one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> thinks that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> favoring impeachment is
too much for effective governance, and thus the next poll publicizes the news
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should go. If an equal number of
pragmatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> (now one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> of the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>) think that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> is enough--they'll flip, and the next poll will show that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> think impeachment is warranted. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> iterations later, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> want to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to the showers. And that's enough for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is impeached by a snowball. A majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>
believes he must go, even though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> actually believe he deserves
to go.

            
The dynamic eventually loses steam, of course.
The halt comes when there is no one left who wishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would stay but
thinks the current level of impeachment sentiment means he should go. But is
the end north or south of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>? We don't know.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamic</ENAMEX> is perhaps easier to see in the stock market, as explained in a famous
passage by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> wrote of:

            Those
newspaper competitions in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> have to pick out the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prettiest</ENAMEX> faces from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> photographs, the prize being awarded to the
competitor whose choice most nearly corresponds to the average preferences of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> as a whole. ... It is not a case of choosing those which, to
the best of one's judgement, are really the prettiest, nor even those which
average opinion thinks the prettiest. We have reached the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> degree where we
devote our intelligences to anticipating what average opinion expects the
average opinion to be. And there are some, I believe, who practise the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>, and higher degrees.

            An example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>' point: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suppose AT&T</ENAMEX> stock trades
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>. A group of optimistic but thickheaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> suspects that a share
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> is actually worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are skeptical, correctly
divining that future earnings justify a price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $50</NUMEX>. But if some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX>
suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> will buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, then these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> will buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and drive the price to, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>. The fact that the market newly
contains <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> and speculating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> moves another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of more
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> to start buying, driving the price to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX>--even though
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> believes the stock is only worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>. After all, it's OK to buy a
stock you know to be overvalued as long as someone else--it doesn't matter
whether it's a skeptic or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX>--will pay even more for it.

            The process iterates,
bringing more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> aboard, until someone gets spooked about
finding a speculating skeptic or an idiotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX> who will continue the
game. The result is often a precipitous sell-off. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> writes, "The actual,
private object of the most skilled investment today is to 'beat the gun,' as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> so well express it, to outwit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, and to pass the bad, or
depreciating, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-crown to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Keynes</ENAMEX>
believed that this kind of speculation was pernicious. The reason is that it
diverts attention from something called "enterprise," by which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> means the
development of real operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. Can a similar argument apply to the
voting example? It is indeed troubling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could be driven out by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who don't necessarily deplore his conduct. Something smells rotten about
the idea that you must surrender your opinion to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>. The real
polity, like the real economy, ought to be what counts.

         
      
   
