
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night Courts</ENAMEX>

            It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> so secure
and austere it wouldn't look out of place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mission</ENAMEX>: Impossible .
Located on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, its double doors swing shut and seal themselves to the wall
when a button nearby is depressed; an oddly textured ceiling looms overhead.
Outside its doors, the seals of intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> adorn the walls.

            Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> doesn't sit
behind the bench, raised above <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> to symbolize his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>. Instead, he joins the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from the intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> at a single conference table. No defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> ever join these proceedings.

            It took
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 200 years</TIMEX> to establish this secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Surveillance Act Court</ENAMEX>--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 20 years</TIMEX> to craft a second
in its mold. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>--a k a the "removal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>"--was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Anti-Terrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996</ENAMEX>, with the
goal of easing the deportation of legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> suspects of
materially supporting terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, but who have committed no crimes.

            The creation of this super-secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> (which is likely to
share <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court</ENAMEX> space) was largely ignored in the debate over the
counter-terrorism bill and underreported by the press. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> claims
that it needs the removal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to protect national security in sensitive
deportation cases against suspected alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. It argues that publicly
disclosing key evidence, as normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> require, can expose and endanger its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and that the unspeakable alternative is to allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suspected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> to remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> covert courts
depart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s open legal culture, and endow the judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> with a
level of secrecy more typical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> bristle at the charge that the secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> also carve out a de
facto national-security exemption to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourth Amendment</ENAMEX>'s prohibition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">warrantless</ENAMEX> surveillance and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX>'s guarantees of due
process.

            That's
why civil-liberties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are crying foul at the new venue, saying that the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing the removal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will remove is constitutional protections for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who engage in politically unpopular speech.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stealth court</ENAMEX> are simple:
Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> will present classified evidence in secret to a
removal-court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> federal district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> serving on the court
at any one time. If convinced that a proposed deportee is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will authorize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> to initiate deportation proceedings
against the alien in a district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, where it will introduce as much secret
evidence as it sees fit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> will not know he has been targeted for
deportation during removal-court proceedings, and when the case reaches the
district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, he will see only a sketchy summary of the evidence against him.
The district court then will decide whether the alien should be deported.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> insists that removal-court procedures will be invoked only
in extreme cases where national security would be damaged by the public
disclosure of deportation evidence. But modifying judicial processes to
accommodate the executive branch risks upsetting the traditional role of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> as a check on executive power.

            Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> worry that the trend toward secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> begs for abuse by intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> seem incapable of
turning government requests down. Indeed, ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court</ENAMEX> was
established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> to approve secret warrants for surveillance of suspected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> has won approval for all its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,827</NUMEX> surveillance requests. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX>
hearings, to cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example, approved the surveillance used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheik Omar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdel Rahman</ENAMEX> investigation.) The appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court of Review</ENAMEX>, has
never even had to convene. Perhaps the cloak-and-dagger ambience and absence of
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the surveillance target persuade otherwise skeptical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to
give credence to government security claims. (Whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX>'s faults, it's
better than the previous federal wiretapping policy that permitted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attorney</ENAMEX>
general to authorize national-security wiretaps with no judicial review.)

            Are the
secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> constitutional? Probably. A host of legally significant
distinctions separates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and national-security
investigations from law-enforcement probes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has never ruled
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX>, and it did not overturn a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarthy-era</ENAMEX> statute which, like the removal
court, was used to deport noncriminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> based on their political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affiliations</ENAMEX>.

            But these legal arguments are pedantries to many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and
Irish residing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> who fear they will be unjustly targeted
under the new statute. And they don't calm civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>, who fear the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court</ENAMEX> is a mere rubber stamp for executive power.

            "Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> might
not lie about the facts," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Martin</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for National Security</ENAMEX>
Studies. "But they draft the applications in a way to say that these facts meet
the requirements, and by the time the application reaches the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, it is
unlikely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> really gets to notice deficiencies."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA Court</ENAMEX> deny that the latter is a
rubber stamp, attributing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s winning percentage to rigorous internal
review that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> out bad applications before they're filed. That's how
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presiding FISA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royce Lamberth</ENAMEX> feels. "There might be a concern that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> has been too conservative in what they are presenting to the
court if we're approving every one," he says.

            But the public doesn't have many independent guarantees
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are applying tough scrutiny to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s applications.
Secrecy prevents open investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>' methods and standards; there
is a paucity of serious journalistic coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>; and congressional
oversight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> is limited to the review (in closed session) of
classified reports. The only public indication that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> plays fair comes from
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. In their review of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> applications in the context of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> cases, they have yet to indicate that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> warrant was improperly
granted.

            "I understand that it's
hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't see the process," Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorelick</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. "We're not at liberty to make the kind of
disclosures that I agree would make the public more comfortable."

            Secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> require
great faith that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>--and future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Departments</ENAMEX>--will
act with integrity. In the absence of more openness, nobody outside the
national-security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> will know how much freedom the secret court
structures really cost.

         
      
   
