
   
   
      
         
            High and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mighty</ENAMEX>

            There's a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">It Girl</ENAMEX> on
television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>--a pale, sexy, raccoon-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> who looks like an
advertisement for shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>. The twist: The commercial is an ad for
not shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> smashes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX> and plumbing fixtures in the
commercial, screaming angrily about how <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> will ruin your life.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> spot is one of a
series of new anti-drug commercials that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> to
air over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>. The ads are produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug-Free America</ENAMEX>--the best funded and best connected propaganda machine in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. It's backed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the biggest of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, the
advertising industry, and the major media.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slickness</ENAMEX> and pervasiveness of the campaign conceals one flaw: The
message--that all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use leads to disaster--is a baldfaced lie.

            Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> by a group of advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX>'s
stated goal is to produce and place ads that persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> not to try <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, to
"denormalize" adult <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, and to make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use "less acceptable." Its
latest TV ads--created pro bono by leading ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>--will saturate prime
time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> thanks to a budget in excess of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> spent on TV
advertising in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> once relied on donated airtime, but in these
flush days network time is at a premium, hence the requisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>'
funds.) The budget dwarfs even the public service ad campaign run during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War II</ENAMEX> in support of the war effort.

            The ads focus solely on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
In addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> ad is one that depicts a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> answering
questions. Lesson: Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has told her not to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> but hasn't
told her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are bad. In another ad, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> sit at the breakfast
table in silence. Lesson: This time could have been spent talking about how
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are bad.

            Some have
attacked the efficacy of these ads. Indeed, no study conclusively demonstrates
a link between them and reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. Few have slammed the hypocrisy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and the ad agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> behind this campaign, who can't all be
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgins</ENAMEX>. But the greater scandal is the free pass that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, most of
whom have imbibed, have granted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX>'s propaganda blitz. (The lone
exception is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>.)

            
Let's be clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> can be awful. They can
destroy lives. But for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has died or ended up in a gutter,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> have dabbled in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and still led productive, sane, successful
lives. This is indisputable. In fact, some long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harmless--and</ENAMEX>, yes, even kind of fun. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> model offers only the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">salvation</ENAMEX> of abstinence or the perdition of addiction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX>'s Web site suggests you
tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> marijuana is "a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that can hurt your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>."

            While
it's true that marijuana smoke (like tobacco smoke) contains carcinogens and
the medical data suggest it compromises the immune system and can also lead to
short-term memory loss, honesty demands that the silent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> ad
admit to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that he smoked a good deal of pot when he was young, still
occasionally lights up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and has turned out just fine.

            Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> insists on using your tax dollars to lie
to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> hate and fear a friendly, well-adjusted, responsible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> who occasionally rolls a spliff? Should the culture denormalize
someone who does good work in a steady job, hurts no one, and once in a blue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moon</ENAMEX> sniffs some blow at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>? Are you on a hell-bound train if you take
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushrooms</ENAMEX>? Is all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use drug abuse? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> tells your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> "yes" when the
correct answer is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">no.</ENAMEX>"

            Perhaps
the most shameful thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> propaganda campaign is that its leaders
know better, having used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Didn't Inhale</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> have all admitted to having tried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in their early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. How can they tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> pot is an evil gateway <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> when they're stellar
proof that it isn't?

            
To succeed, a propaganda <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> need not
convince its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>; it need merely suck the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> out of the lungs of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>. Prior to its alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> merely hogged the
drug debate. Now it stands to monopolize it, thanks to its ad dollars and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ran,
without comment, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX>'s new ads. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Wood Johnson Foundation</ENAMEX>,
responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX>'s funding, also donated over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Co.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX> have supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> since its
inception. The editorial side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has only compliments for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX>, while the advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> has donated ad space to it. (The
paternalism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX>'s campaign has sunk in at major newsrooms. Click to
find out more.)

            We don't
trust Madison Avenue to tell us the truth about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric softener</ENAMEX>, so why are we
letting it brainwash our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>? Indeed, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> had a shred
of integrity, its ads would be battling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and tobacco, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most
injurious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most popular among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> no longer takes
money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Reynolds</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> and
smokes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but even so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> connection remains:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Margeotes/Fertitta and Partners</ENAMEX>, which created the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> spot, also designs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stolichnaya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> ads.)

            In a rational world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who decry the
anti-tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> as another appendage of the nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would see through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> campaign and reiterate their belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can be trusted to
make informed choices. For instance, contrary to what the raccoon-eyed waif
suggests, many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are able to use their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and conduct functional
lives. What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' life so crazy is that their dependence on an
illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> forces them to enter a criminal underworld. The PDFA ignores these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subtleties</ENAMEX>. Likewise with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>: Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who've
tried it have had no trouble walking away from it. And pot? No one has
ever overdosed.

            By
confusing propaganda with education, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDFA</ENAMEX> stands to reap the whirlwind. We
don't lie to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. Everyone knows from an early age what it can
do--and that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can handle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't. Eventually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> see through the drug hysteria, usually by the time they turn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 or 13</TIMEX> and
start observing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> for themselves. When they discover they've been lied
to, they stop trusting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>--their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or TV
commercials--and start trusting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. Whatever real opportunity we have
to reach them vanishes. Simply letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> know what the real risks are,
without hyperbole, should be enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> propaganda is
counterproductive.

            
               If you missed the link
in the article, on how newsrooms have succumbed to the anti-drug
hysteria.
            

         
      
   
