
   
   
      
         
            Welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>

            An
introduction and apologia.

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley

            The name? It means
nothing, or practically nothing. We chose it as an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> into which we
can pour meaning. We hope <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> will come to mean good original journalism in
this new medium. Beyond that, who knows? Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are exercises in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serendipity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit</ENAMEX>--or blame--for the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>," by the way, goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>, then of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, now of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cognisoft Corp.</ENAMEX>

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyberwag</ENAMEX> says
that the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SLATE</ENAMEX>" is appropriate, because whenever he asks anyone from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX>'s your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">project</ENAMEX> coming along?" the answer he usually gets is,
"'s late." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> , in fact, has been reasonably prompt. Less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-page memorandum and a single Internet naif. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> is
not the first "webzine," but everyone in this nascent business is still
struggling with some pretty basic issues. Starting an online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is like
starting a traditional paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> by asking: "OK, you chop down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.
Then what?"

            To be honest, we are
running late on a few things. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>--you--there is good news and bad
news here. The good news is that our billing system isn't ready yet. We intend
to charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> a year for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>. That is far less than the cost of equivalent
print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, because there's no paper, printing, or postage. But <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34.95</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>) is more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are used to
paying. We believe that expecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to share the cost, as they do in
print, is the only way serious journalism on the Web can be self-supporting.
Depending completely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> would not be healthy even if it were
possible.

            And we
want to be self-supporting. Indeed one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s main goals is to demonstrate,
if we can, that the economies of cyberspace make it easier for our kind of
journalism to pay for itself. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like SLATE depend on someone's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generosity</ENAMEX> or vanity or misplaced optimism to pay the bills. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">self-supporting</ENAMEX> journalism is freer journalism. (As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.J. Liebling</ENAMEX> said, freedom
of the press is for those who own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.) If the Web can make serious journalism
more easily self-supporting, that is a great gift from technology to
democracy.

            For the moment, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> is yours for free. So enjoy.
We expect to start requiring registration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, and to require
payment beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1</TIMEX>.

            The bad news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
is that some features aren't quite ready yet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX> among them is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>,"
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>-discussion forum. Meanwhile, though, please e-mail any comments you
may have to slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. We'll be publishing a traditional "Letters to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>" page until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Fray</ENAMEX> is up and running in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>.

            We
especially need, and appreciate, your comments in these early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. Every new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> is a "beta" version for a while, especially a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in a new
medium. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> has gotten enormous hype--some of it, to be sure, self-induced,
but much of it not. We appreciate the attention. But of course, it also makes
us nervous. We have a smaller budget and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> than most well-known
magazines--even smaller than some webzines. We don't claim to have all the
answers. But, with your help, we plan to have all the answers by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>.
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LINK TO TEXT BBB</ENAMEX>]

            
               So What's in It?
            

            First, let me urge you to
read a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> called Consider Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Options.</ENAMEX> This page explains and
executes the various ways you can receive and read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>. If you don't like
reading on a computer screen, for example, there's a special version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>
that you can print out in its entirety, reformatted like a traditional print
magazine. If you don't mind reading on a screen but hate waiting for pages to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">download</ENAMEX>--and hate running up those online charges from your Internet
provider--you will soon be able to download the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> at once and read
it offline.

            Also on the Consider Your
Options page, you can order SLATE to be delivered to your computer by e-mail.
(Caution: This may not work with your e-mail system.) We'll even send you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> 
               on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> compilation of highlights from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>,
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Mail</ENAMEX>. (The cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-555-4995</ENAMEX> to
order.)

            Individual copies of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> 
               on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX> will be available exclusively at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX>. And
selected articles from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> will also appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>.

            While you're on the
Consider Your Options page, please read about how to navigate around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>. We
use page numbers, like a traditional print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, and have tried to make it
as easy as possible either to "flip through" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or to and from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table of Contents</ENAMEX>.

            
               OK, But What's in
It??[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STET</ENAMEX> double "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">??</ENAMEX>"]
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>
is basically a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>: Most articles will appear for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. But there will be
something new to read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every day</TIMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> will change constantly.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> will appear and be removed throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. Every article
will indicate when it was "posted" and when it will be "composted." As a
general rule the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Back of the Book</ENAMEX>, containing cultural reviews and commentary,
will be posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>, the longer Features will be posted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wednesdays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thursdays</ENAMEX>, and the front-of-the-book Briefing section will be
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX>. If you miss something, you can easily call it up from our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">archive</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>."( THIS NEEDS TO BE A HOT LINK)
            

            Let me try to describe a typical issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Readme</ENAMEX> column will not
always be as solipsistic as this one. It will usually be a commentary on public
affairs by one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.

            Several regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Briefing</ENAMEX> section are attempts at "meta-news": the news about
the news, a sense of how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s big stories are being played and perceived.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week/The Spin</ENAMEX> takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen or so</NUMEX> topics, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
election-campaign developments to the latest big book from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>, and analyses,
as objectively [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO TEXT CCC</ENAMEX>]as possible, the spin they're getting, the
sub-angles that are emerging, and so on. In Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Magazines</ENAMEX> uses the covers and
contents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , etc., as a handy measure of what the
culture considers important. (We aim to have these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> even
before they reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> or your mailbox.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horse</ENAMEX> Race
tracks the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> like stocks, as priced by the opinion polls,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, and a genuine market in political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> run out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Iowa</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> will compute and analyze changes in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> index.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gist</ENAMEX>, by contrast, is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s effort to provide a quick education on some
current issue in a form as free of spin as possible. Also free of quotes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anecdotes</ENAMEX>, and other paraphernalia. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1,000</NUMEX> words you'll have to read
when you might rather read nothing at all.

            In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Varnish Remover</ENAMEX>, political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX> will deconstruct a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> TV spot from the election
campaign. You can download a video or audio clip of the spot itself.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" will be a short, judgmental profile of some figure in the news.
(Coming up soon: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s godfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroponte</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> writes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dismal Scientist</ENAMEX>, a once-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-month</TIMEX> column on economic policy.
(See his debut essay in this issue, about the economic war within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Landsburg</ENAMEX> writes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everyday Economics</ENAMEX>," using economic analysis to illuminate everyday
life. (His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> column, in our next issue, will explain how sexual promiscuity
can actually reduce the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Earthling</ENAMEX>" will be a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>, contributor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the acclaimed book on evolutionary psychology,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moral Animal</ENAMEX> . Other regular Briefing features will include a Press
column by our deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doodlennium</ENAMEX> is our weekly cartoon strip by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Alan Stamaty</ENAMEX>, whose
"Washingtoon" appeared for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE Diary</ENAMEX> will be an actual daily diary, written and posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekday</TIMEX> by someone with an interesting mind. Our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> diarist is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flirting With Disaster</ENAMEX> . Our second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diarist</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muriel Spark</ENAMEX>.

            
               Can There Possibly be More?
            

            Our Features section
begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee of Correspondence</ENAMEX>, our e-mail discussion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Economic Advisers</ENAMEX> best-known now for his witty columns
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . We have great hopes for e-mail as a medium
of debate that can combine the immediacy of talk-television with the
intellectual discipline of the written word. We hope for something halfway
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> and the correspondence page of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Review of Books</ENAMEX> . Will it work? Check out our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> attempt--Does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Play Fair</ENAMEX>?--and let us know what you think.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Features</ENAMEX> section is
also where we run longer articles [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO TEXT DDD</ENAMEX>] and occasional humor
pieces (that is, pieces that are intentionally, or at least aspirationally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humorous</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Temptation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Allen</ENAMEX>, cruelly analyzes the arguments for a tax cut. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX> writes on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Second</TIMEX> Place, about what happens to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> replace them at the top of the meritocracy. And the legendary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recluse Henry David Thoreau</ENAMEX> emerges to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> an exclusive peek at
his new Web page.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE Gallery</ENAMEX>, we have a continuous exhibition of computer-based art. You may
like or dislike this stuff (we'll have plenty of linked commentary to help you
decide). What appeals to us about computer art is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> can show you not
reproductions, but the actual art itself. We start with an offering by Jenny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holzer</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s reviews include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Hulbert</ENAMEX>'s book review of
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX>' latest encyclical; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s television review of the changing
fashions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> finales; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larissa MacFarquhar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Concept</ENAMEX> column, about
how managed care could improve psychotherapy; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cullen Murphy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Good</ENAMEX>
Word, about the difference between "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jesuitical</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmudic</ENAMEX>."

            In general, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> will contain a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> book review, alternating television and movie
reviews, and a rotating menu of columns on music (classical and popular),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX>, web sites, and other topics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Steingarten</ENAMEX> will be writing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Soup</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX> on fashion (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Clothes Sense"</ENAMEX>),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Talbot</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Men and Women</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audio</ENAMEX> and video clips will be offered
where appropriate.

            Every issue will have a
poem, read aloud by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, with text. In this issue is a new poem by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Heaney</ENAMEX>.

            And
coming up soon, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> additional Back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> features: an interactive
acrostic puzzle, and a stock-market contest.

            
               Does <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SLATE Have a Slant</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> is owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX>, and that bothers some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Can a giant software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> put
out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that is free to think for itself? All we can say is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has made all the right noises on this subject, and we look forward to
putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s hands-off commitment to the test. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> strikes
me as misplaced. In a day of media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> with myriad daily conflicts of
interest--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney-ABC</ENAMEX>--how can it be a
bad thing for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to begin competing in the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>? A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who worries about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> putting out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>
with a steady job.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> may also wonder
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> will have a particular political flavor. The answer is that we do
not set out with any ideological mission or agenda. On the other hand, we are
not committed to any artificial balance of views. We will publish articles from
various perspectives, but we will not agonize if the mix averages out to be
somewhere other than dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO TEXT EEE</ENAMEX>]

            A good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, though,
does develop a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, an attitude, [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO TEXT FFF</ENAMEX>]and some
prejudices--even crotchets. A few of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE's</ENAMEX> are already becoming clear. In
discussing current events, we have a preference for policy over politics. We'd
rather discuss the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s tax-cut proposal on the economy than
its effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. Within the policy arena, we seem to have a special
fondness for economics. This was not planned; it's one of those serendipitous
developments I mentioned. Whether it reflects good luck or bad luck is a matter
of taste (yours).

            Finally, we intend to take
a fairly skeptical stance toward the romance and rapidly escalating vanity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX>. We do not start out with the smug assumption that the Internet
changes the nature of human thought, or that all the restraints that society
imposes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in "real life" must melt away in cyberia. There is a
deadening conformity in the hipness of cyberspace culture in which we don't
intend to participate. Part of our mission at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> will be trying to bring
cyberspace down to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.

            Should be fun. Thanks for
joining us.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>.

             

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEXT AAA</ENAMEX>: No, this is
not a link to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cognisoft</ENAMEX> home page. As a general rule, we plan to
avoid hyperlinks to outside sites in the text of articles, and to group them at
the end instead. It's a small illustration of our general philosophy--better
call it a hope--that, even on the Web, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will want to read articles
in the traditional linear fashion--i.e., from beginning to end--rather than
darting constantly from site to site. Go back.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEXT BBB</ENAMEX>: Only kidding.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>. Go back.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TEXT CCC: Objectivity</ENAMEX>, we
hope, will distinguish this feature from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conventional Wisdom</ENAMEX>
Watch," which is often an effort to set the spin rather than describe it.
Anyway, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CW Watch</ENAMEX>" was a rip-off of a similar feature in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> when I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> there. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's feature itself was
lifted from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Paper</ENAMEX> , which was edited at the time
of the theft by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>, now deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>. Go back.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEXT DDD</ENAMEX>: Those dread
words "longer articles" raise one of the big uncertainties about this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX>: How long an article will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be willing to read on a computer
screen? We have several answers to this question: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) We don't know. Clearly
it's less than on paper, but how much less is uncertain. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) We're determined to
test the outer limits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) We'll do our best, graphically, to make reading on
screen a more pleasant experience (suggestions welcome). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) We'll also make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> as easy as possible to print out. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) This will become less of a problem
as screens are developed that can be taken to bed or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Two
thousand words. Or at least we're starting--optimistically, perhaps--with the
hope that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> words or so is not too much. (By contrast, a typical
print-magazine feature or cover story might run anywhere from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5000</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX>
words.)

            At least among
non-cyberheads, the computer-screen problem seems to be everyone's favorite
conversational thrust with regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX> I've been amazed
to learn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and postures in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. Bed
and bath are just the beginning. At a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> made the
interesting point that her problem isn't the screen: It's the chair. Even
"ergonomic" computer chairs are designed for typing, not for reading. For this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and for others who may feel the same way, we have asked several
furniture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> to sketch a real computer reading chair--one you can curl
up in with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and your cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> and read SLATE online. That
feature will appear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or two</TIMEX>. Go back.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEXT EEE</ENAMEX>: In this regard
we are more like the newsmagazines-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> --than the overtly political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> such as the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> . Each of
the newsmagazines may have an identifiable political tilt. But pushing a
particular line is not what they are fundamentally about, and knowing where
they average out won't tell you what any individual article will say. Go
back.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEXT FFF</ENAMEX>: This is
different from "attitude"--that free-floating, supercilious cynicism that is
much prized in the culture of cyberspace. We may develop an attitude--a
set of prejudices derived from logic and evidence, as best we can determine
them--but we'll leave "attitude" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Go back.

         
      
   
