
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Price ValuJet</ENAMEX>?

            Discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> ought to
be more dangerous.

            (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,228</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 5</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 12</TIMEX>)

Administration revealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3</TIMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ValuJet</ENAMEX> has applied to resume
flying. You can be pretty sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> is not going to approve this application
casually. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Regulators</ENAMEX> shut down the discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 11</TIMEX> crash in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The past two months</TIMEX> have seen a festival of
recriminations about sloppy practices at both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ValuJet</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> editorial declared, "The public needs evidence that the
government is insisting on the highest safety standards possible."

            A seemingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unobjectionable</ENAMEX> sentiment--but there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> problems with it. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is
that the highest safety standards possible are too high. You can always make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flying</ENAMEX>--or any other economic activity--safer by making it more expensive
(increasing the minimum distance between <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> or time between takeoffs,
requiring wider aisles, and so on). The inevitable trade-off between safety and
cost, plus the law of diminishing returns, dictates that you stop well short of
the highest possible standards.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
there is no reason every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> should meet the same level of safety. In fact,
it makes perfect sense for discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> to be less safe than traditional
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX>-price <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. This is no excuse for negligence and rule-breaking. But if
the rules don't recognize that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, quite rationally, will wish to buy
less safety for less money, they are doing the flying public a disservice.

            Try some rough math on the back of an envelope. According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Federico Peña</ENAMEX>, discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> have lowered
ticket prices, on routes where they compete, by an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54</NUMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX> to or
from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> "hub"). The standard statistic on airline safety is that you
could fly once a day, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21,000 years</TIMEX> before dying in an airplane
crash. So suppose that flying discount made it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times more likely that
you would die in a crash. Now the odds are on a fatal crash in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 2,100</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Is it worth it--just to save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54</NUMEX>? Well, by my calculation (checked with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> whose grounding in mathematics is sturdier and more recent), you're
increasing your chance of a fatal crash by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">855,000</NUMEX>. Looked at the
other way, paying the extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54</NUMEX> to avoid the added risk (and leaving
aside other advantages of grown-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious meals</ENAMEX>, roomy
seats, punctual departures, on-board golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, etc.), puts an implicit
value on your life of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $46 million</NUMEX>.

            Now you
may think your life is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46 million</NUMEX>, but unless you've got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46 million</NUMEX> to
spend on it, that's a hollow boast. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> you make decisions--probably
including the decision to step outside your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and risk being torn apart by
hounds as you pick up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> (you could, after all, hire someone to
bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> inside for you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, just to be safe)--that implicitly
value your own life at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $46 million</NUMEX>. Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom of Neuroses</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> liberties we celebrate this Independence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day weekend</TIMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be free to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54</NUMEX> to avoid a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-in-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">855,000</NUMEX> risk if they
so desire. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society</ENAMEX> should not force them to do so. And society, in setting
its rules, cannot possibly value each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s life at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46 million</NUMEX>, without
grinding to a halt.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> has been struggling with the
question of whether to require small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to fly in safety seats. The rule
has long been that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-years-old may sit in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s lap--and
therefore, usually, fly for free. Flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of
safety seats make a good argument that it's a bit odd for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
require that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> pots, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, be strapped down, but not little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>-commissioned study determined that requiring safety seats
would actually cost lives. How? By leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to drive instead of
fly. The study figured that the end of small-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>-fly-free would raise the
average fare for affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$185</NUMEX>, causing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fifth</NUMEX> of them to take
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> instead. Whereas the safety seats would save an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s
life per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, the extra driving (far more dangerous than flying) would cost
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> lives. Or so the study figured. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> objected to the calculations, but
the principle of thinking about safety in this way survives any quibbling about
the numbers.

            You could think about the
discount-airline question the same way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discounters</ENAMEX> carried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 47 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. What fraction of that number chose to fly instead of
drive because of the cheap fare, and how many of those would have died in
traffic accidents if they'd driven? Even in the trade-off of lives for lives,
let alone the less appealing trade-off of lives for dollars, making airlines
too safe may be a bad deal.

            The discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> deny
vehemently that they are less safe than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, and the statistics show no
clear connection between price and safety. But if there isn't a connection,
that's too bad. Flying at a discount should be more dangerous. Otherwise,
you're overpaying.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE News</ENAMEX>

            Of all the
good stuff in this issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>, I'm probably most excited at having the
wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muriel Spark</ENAMEX> writing our diary column. Her Memento
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mori</ENAMEX> is one of my all-time favorites (short, mean, and funny--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
priceless qualities). She doesn't have a computer, but she'll be faxing daily
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscany</ENAMEX>.

            Check out
our newest feature, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ask Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, our program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> (chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tech guy</ENAMEX>)
answers questions about problems and possibilities in reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX>. "Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>"
is part of our E-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors page</ENAMEX>. We've received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of e-mail
messages since our launch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24</TIMEX> (most of them friendly, thanks), and this is
a small taste.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee of Correspondence</ENAMEX> was redesigned on the fly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> after our
launch, when it became clear the original design (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very long page)
was too cumbersome. Try the new model; we think you'll like it. Other design
changes and "tweaks" will be coming along as this experiment continues.

            What's
known around our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Battle of the Curly Quotes</ENAMEX>" was fought this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. To make our pages more attractive, we had been using quotation marks and
apostrophes that curl left or right, as appropriate, rather than all-purpose
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> that are straight vertical. But it turns out that curly quotes don't show
up at all on UNIX computers. The issue: Should we improve our appearance in a
small way for the majority, or avoid a major problem for a small (but vocal)
minority? Such are the issues that bedevil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cyberpublishing</ENAMEX>. You can see for
yourself how it came out.

            
               When
does SLATE "go to press"? Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are asking this, and the
answer does take some getting used to. There is new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> in SLATE every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weekday</ENAMEX>. In general, the cultural reviews are posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the
feature articles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, and the newsiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> updated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. Perhaps the best time to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLATE</ENAMEX> is over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>. But
every article in SLATE stays "live" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a week</TIMEX>, so you can read or
print out SLATE on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> and get a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. And if you do miss
something, you can always retrieve it (free) from our archive, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compost</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
