
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Geeks</ENAMEX> Don't Need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX>

            The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multibillion-dollar</NUMEX>
computer industry is adamant about doing things its own way, insisting that the
government stay out of its business. So why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28 million</NUMEX> to remedy an alleged shortage of "information technology"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>?

            The
info-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> shortfall cited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is documented in a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Tech</ENAMEX> study, which claims that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">346,000</NUMEX> computer-related jobs are going
begging for lack of trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. This shortage, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Riley</ENAMEX>, "translates into <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in unearned wages and
the volume of vacant high-tech positions will increase fivefold in the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>--but the number of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> majoring in computer science is
shrinking. "Today," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> mournfully, "many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
report difficulty in recruiting enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with these skills."

            Assuming that there is a shortage of info-tech
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28 million</NUMEX> remedy, announced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, won't
fix it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plan is an amalgam of several modest programs divided among
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. (For comparison's sake, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsystems</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on education and training.) Much of the
effort is little more than exhortation, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>'s plan to
hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> town hall meetings to examine the shortage and discuss ways to
alleviate it. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are only coincidentally helpful. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>
Department touts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pell</ENAMEX> grants and HOPE scholarships, and calls for national
testing and better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>--which are no more helpful to computer-related
businesses than to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">breweries</ENAMEX>, or oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            Much of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s program is mere packaging--the rest is well-meaning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chatter</ENAMEX>, notably a plan to launch an advertising campaign to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that
computer jobs are not just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX> anymore. There is a little meat on these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bones</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> to fund local efforts to retrain dislocated workers
for information-technology jobs and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> for a computer job <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> on the
Internet. But neither promises to make a dent in the supposed shortage.

            
I keep writing about a "supposed" or "alleged"
shortage, because the dearth of info-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> is an illusion. Translated
into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> are saying is that businesses
can't hire all the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> they want at prevailing rates. They're
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> could make use of more of these trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> if they
were abundant and cheap--just as I could drink <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dom Perignon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> if it
were priced like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Milwaukee</ENAMEX>. When the unemployment rate is below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>,
as it has been since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>, a lot of industries find that hiring is not
quite as easy as it used to be. In a fast-growing industry that requires
technical skills, it's no shock that demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> is rising faster than
the supply. (The cheapest way to close the "gap" would be to increase the
number of essential-skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>--currently fixed at a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>--but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> rejects that proposal.)

            
Fortunately, there is a simple solution to the shortage: higher pay. Since last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, salaries for new college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> with computer science degrees
have jumped by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.6 percent</NUMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Technology Association of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. That may be painful for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> signing the paychecks, but it's
good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> who had the foresight to enter the field. It also
advances the goal of encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to consider computer careers. What's more
likely to dispel the nerdy image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> and software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--public-service commercials on TV or a big pile of cash? Even if higher
pay doesn't improve the image of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jockeys</ENAMEX>, it will doubtless provide
sufficient consolation to enable more young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to live with it. Rising
salaries will also encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">midcareer adults</ENAMEX> to enroll in the nearest
community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> to retool for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> career. It should also induce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to
provide more computer training for existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITAA</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> raising the visa limit, says the
industry it represents can't wait for the market to fix the problem. "We
operate on Internet time," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris Miller</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Quarterly</TIMEX> . Well, everybody operates on Internet time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. The notion
that the computer industry is uniquely important is common but groundless. All
sorts of industries are important to national prosperity, yet the federal
government doesn't take on the responsibility of monitoring and adjusting the
flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> into each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley</ENAMEX> claims that all those unfilled jobs
represent lost wages and profits. But the money that would be spent doesn't
vanish up the chimney--it ends up in paychecks and dividends in other
industries whose products are also valued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.

            As with
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposals, this one's modesty is meant to disarm. The natural
response is: Oh, what could it hurt? Not much. But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will be
induced to study computer science rather than some other subject, and each one
of these gains for computer-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> is a loss for other businesses.
A lot of the money is likely to be simply wasted, though.

            
Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s infatuation with the idea,
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s record in training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for better jobs is not
studded with triumphs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Job Training Partnership Act</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>-long federal
program, appears to be almost entirely futile. "It's been a failure overall,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Heckman</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> survey by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of market economies, found "remarkably meager support for the
hypothesis that such programs are effective." The best programs, nearly
everyone agrees, are those conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Why?
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have strong reasons to tailor the training to assure its
practical value and to avoid wasting funds on feel-good exercises.

            If it makes cold economic
sense to invest more in training computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and attracting more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
high-tech jobs, we can sleep easy knowing that the relentlessly rational
propeller-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> who run computer-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> will do so, eliminating the
need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> to do it for them. Corporate welfare is a bad enough idea
without adding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> to the rolls.

         
      
   
