
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EDITORIAL: A Dangerous Medium</ENAMEX>
            

            Just a reminder: A weekly
edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is now available on paper, delivered through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mail, by
subscription only, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-555-4995</ENAMEX> to subscribe.

            We hesitate, frankly, to
offer a paper edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. Why? Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is a dangerous medium, all
too prone to misuse by pedophiles, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>, paranoid conspiracy
mongers, and purveyors of bad casserole recipes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s Mein

               Kampf was written on paper. So were many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s most bestial orders
for mass executions. Those of us at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> must naturally wonder
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> should be allowed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can read
or--worse--write on it.

            As many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>,
magazines, and other timber-industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">byproducts</ENAMEX> have pointed out in the wake of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> mass suicide, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s preferred medium of the Internet has
some darker byways of its own. That's true. But this anti-Internet alarmism is
a heavy-handed attempt to distract attention from the really dangerous medium:
paper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J'accuse</ENAMEX>. Quis custodiet ipsos custodes? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Et</ENAMEX> cetera.
            

            The earliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of paper
were ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egyptians</ENAMEX>, with their bizarre worship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun God</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ra</ENAMEX>. (A
distant relation, perhaps, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do and Ti?</ENAMEX>) In
the modern era, the practice of writing on paper was first taken up, and
monopolized for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monks</ENAMEX>, all of whom had taken vows of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">celibacy</ENAMEX>. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, reading paper products is a lonely habit whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> often spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> at a time silently and obsessively
turning pages, immersed in a world of fantasy, isolated from normal society. No
wonder some of them lose all grip on reality. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> was a known book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>. So was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attila the Hun</ENAMEX> (according to his former political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>). Yet society ignored the clues until it was too late.

            Mere words cannot describe
the vast range of content now available on paper. Much of this, to be sure, is
harmless nonsense, such as the installation instructions that come with popular
software products. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is by far the favorite medium of pornographers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ransom</ENAMEX> notes use paper as well. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years ago</TIMEX> a scientific journal
published instructions for building a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. Where? On paper!

            In a culture where Internet
reality is dismissed as "virtual," the appearance of words on paper lends them
instant credibility--credibility that may not be deserved. An irresponsible
rumor can be set in type, and then printed and distributed by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>,
with no guarantee whatsoever of its accuracy. And yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say, "I only know
what I read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>." At best, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s materiality creates an unjustified
impression of trustworthiness; at worst, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> can be folded into an airplane
that can poke someone's eye out.

            Paper poses a special peril
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Unlike a computer, a filthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> can easily be snuck into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> in an innocent-looking lunchbox. It can be hidden under a pile of sweat
clothes in the bottom dresser drawer. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> can be folded, placed in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pocket</ENAMEX>, and secretly transported or shared with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Books can even
be read by flashlight in bed, long after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> has requisitioned the family
computer and is trying to log on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, naively believing that junior is safe
from corruption just because he is tucked in and offline.

            It is fine to say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are responsible for what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> read. But no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> can
realistically patrol a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s access to paper. It's everywhere--even at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>-supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Rating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> do not exist.
Filtering software is not available.

            What is the moral? The first
moral is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are never safer than when staring at a computer screen.
At least you know they're not reading a book or anything. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, government
regulation of paper is clearly needed. We look to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper Decency</ENAMEX>
Act, to close the giant loophole left open when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s Communications
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Decency Act</ENAMEX> was limited to electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the recent ruling of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Parole Board</ENAMEX> forbidding paroled federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> to use the
Internet must be extended to forbid books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> as well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrupting</ENAMEX> influences are everywhere.

            Finally,
read Slate online. Or subscribe (free) to our e-mail edition. If you
must use paper, please do so with extreme caution. Thank you.

            

               Correction
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>," posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>, now in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>," inaccurately
identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Kagam√</ENAMEX>© as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>. He is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. The mistake has been corrected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the archived</TIMEX> article but, as is our
policy, we note the error here for purposes of self-flagellation.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kinsley
            

         
      
   
