
   
   
      
         
            

            
               But
enough about us--what do you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>?
            

            As we noted in this space
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slate reader</ENAMEX> is intelligent, discerning, politically
involved, culturally aware, and physically attractive. Also, of course,
skeptical of cant and immune to flattery. But we'd like to know even more about
you. Do you consume vast quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>? Do you drive expensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>--and trade them in often? Are you, by any chance, in the market for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet fighter</ENAMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX> undershirt? A good book? A carton of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>?
How many times a week do you have sex? Would you be willing to pay for it? Say,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>? (Or are you one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think that sex, like Web sites,
ought to always be free?) Are you, in short, the kind of reader <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> are
looking for? (Please say "yes.") Actually, what we mainly want to know about is
you and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>: how often you read it, in what form, what you like--and don't
like--about it, and so on. Toward that end, we have composed an online reader
survey. (Our e-mail delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will receive their own version.) We would
be grateful if you took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> to fill it out. Thanks very much.
Go to survey.

            
               Warning:
Do not read this book review
            

            Also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, we post a
review by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James J. Cramer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Microsoft Way</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall E. Stross</ENAMEX>, a big new
book about the well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>--uh, we mean software--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s official editorial position about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is, of course, scrupulously
neutral. We believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is a marvelous flowering of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
entrepreneurial spirit, a boon to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>, a splendid example of employer
benevolence at its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">finest</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> beyond legitimate criticism of any
sort, with a damned fine tuna tostada every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX>. But
beyond that, we take no view. It is unfortunate, therefore, that we were
tricked into publishing the highly biased opinions of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cramer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of no
discernible qualifications whatsoever--beyond extensive experience in both
business and journalism, a brilliant track record on Wall Street, and a lively
writing style, that is. When we showed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cramer</ENAMEX>'s review to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> (not
because it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, of course, but because he insists on reading
every word of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> before publication, in an admirable effort to improve his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX>), his reaction was swift. "Have it killed," he observed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reflectively</ENAMEX>. We said, "You mean, 'Have him killed.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> shrieked,
"No, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX>. What kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> do you take me for? Kill the piece .
Kill the piece!" But by that time, the review had already been loaded into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "doomsday server," a device designed to ensure that this magazine
continues to be propagated into cyberspace in the event of a nuclear war. Once
loaded, an article cannot be retrieved. There was nothing we could do. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Honest,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>.

            
               Listen
and learn
            

            If you haven't done so yet,
check out the new format for our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches & Dialogues," and the Slate "Diary</ENAMEX>." It's
part of our continuing effort to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> more user-friendly. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>,
however, were quick to tell us they regarded one particular change--a reduction
in the type size of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches & Dialogues"</ENAMEX>--anything but friendly. (A
sample: "I'm as frumpy as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brinkley</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s dispatches are
posted in print that's too goddamned small!!") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honestly</ENAMEX>, we were only trying to
help: Smaller type means more words per screen, and therefore, less scrolling.
(Especially helpful, or so we thought, in consuming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>'s hilarious
but epic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> trial dispatches.) The smaller type also, we thought, enhanced
the "e-mail" look and feel of the feature. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> were clear: The type
was not (clear, that is). So we're back to the normal point size, in a more
legible typeface (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times New Roman</ENAMEX>) to boot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> were also clear in their
responses to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s query about saving space in the print-out edition by
removing the "links" discussion at the end of each piece. By an overwhelming
margin, those who responded prefer to learn about Internet links, even when
they're not reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> online. So we'll continue as before. Your wish is our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX>.

            
               Another
party heard from
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" now has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 15,000</NUMEX> registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
them, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Jackson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Ahab</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Whale</ENAMEX>, and the orchestrator of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' lawsuit. (His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frayhandle</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mugwumps</ENAMEX>." To read what he has to say, type this address after
you've registered: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/</ENAMEX>The/fray/main.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asp</ENAMEX>?thread=<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> has
some choice words for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX>, who has been engaged in a lively dialogue with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>. Feel free to enter "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" and
talk back.

         
      
   
