
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Change
of Address
            

            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s founding, way
back in the mists of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, its e-mail address has always been slate@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
Beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, though, we will have our very own e-mail domain,
"slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>." This will allow us to generate a confusing proliferation of
different e-mail addresses, a process we begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>:

            To sign up for free e-mail
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> itself, send a message to help@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Don't forget to include which e-mail
software program and provider you use. (For actual delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>,
call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800-555-4995</ENAMEX>.)

            To sign up for a free weekly
e-mail announcement of what's new in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, send a message to read@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            For technical information,
answers to questions, and solutions to problems with receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> (or,
perchance, to thank our technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> for the flawless technical performance
of this site and its ancillary products), e-mail help@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            To send a letter to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, you can e-mail letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>-specific e-mail
addresses will be operating soon, including, of course, a private e-mail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, havethemkilled@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Instant
Book
            

            As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,369</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> had downloaded our special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collector</ENAMEX>'s Edition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O.J. Simpson Civil Trial</ENAMEX>. The download page is
still available in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>." If you're feeling nostalgic for wonderful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> saga like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Fung</ENAMEX>, click here to
download a copy for yourself.

            
               "Name
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scandal" Contest</ENAMEX>
            

            A good shorthand name for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> set of controversies
seems as elusive as the story itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> responding to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
invitation to name the scandal have not covered themselves in literary glory. A
few of the more bearable suggestions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cash Inn, China Pattern, The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wilkes Toll Booth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sheets for Treats</ENAMEX>. None of these do it, in the
considered opinion of our distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. Please keep trying,
either in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray"</ENAMEX> or by e-mail to letters@msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Art
History
            

            
               The
Hard Way by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Ritchie</ENAMEX>, which first appeared in "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Gallery</ENAMEX>," has
been added to the permanent Web site collection (yes, there is one) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francisco Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>. It is also part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> magazine permanent
collection, a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>," and you can see it again by clicking
here.

         
      
   
