
   
   
      
         
            

             

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>
in my cross-divisional capacity, I have been formulating plans for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to
operate as a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY/LA Media and Entertainment</ENAMEX> nexus. This is
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a number of directives I plan to issue to that end.

            As you are all aware,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has moved heavily into media, and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> is a key part of that
strategy. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> of study I have determined--through a ton of
research and collaboration--that one of the key elements missing in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> culture is some sense of the hype, buzz, style, and attitude that are
so key to success in the media and entertainment industries.

            If we want to play with
the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, we have to dress like the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>--even if we are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.

            I hope that we will have
your support in this effort to make us more competitive and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> a real hub
for media and entertainment.

            Effective immediately, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> and editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> will conform to the following dress code:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Wear more black. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX> is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece of black clothing be immediately visible at all
times. Not only is it a good idea and slimming, it can help us to identify the
greater and greater numbers of editorial- and media-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> now working on
our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RedWest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>. (I wouldn't be surprised if traditional Microsofties
started incorporating our fashion sense as well.) Which brings me to ...

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polar</ENAMEX> fleece will be
worn only under other items of clothing and only for the purpose of warmth on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that the thermometer in the cafeteria dips below freezing point at
noon.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Training</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Certification</ENAMEX> will immediately launch a new series of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Dressing</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>." Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> will take only one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to complete, and I think
that all will find it quite useful. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Lopez</ENAMEX>, a new employee from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX> , will be leading <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> sessions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and is
spearheading creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day to Evening Makeup</ENAMEX> Web site. (Though it was
originally intended only for the internal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, we hope to eventually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">establish Pamela</ENAMEX>'s Web site as a platform, much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expedia</ENAMEX>, and to sell it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maybelline</ENAMEX>, etc.) The focus will be very much along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDA</ENAMEX>--gain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>-make decisions-take actions--lines of the enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Journalism</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX> that has been evangelized for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>. Let's remember that it's
not that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> don't want to look chic--it's just that they need help
choosing which shade of blue eye shadow works <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Our next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISM Editorial</ENAMEX>
Lead meeting will be an offsite to discuss "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bringing Fashion to RedWest</ENAMEX>." It
will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barneys</ENAMEX> downtown.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Our cafeteria
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contractor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX>, has agreed to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISM</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> to reserve tables
upstairs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro Cafe</ENAMEX>. Involved with this is a major re-org. Chief
latte-puller <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> will be moving to a new and more appropriate position as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maitre d'</ENAMEX>, stationed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Building</ENAMEX> A entrance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has agreed to
purchase a limited number of white tablecloths, real <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, and nonrecyclable
crystal. Full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> holding a blue ID card may reserve tables on a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-come-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-served basis. An orange <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> card automatically gets you
seated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>. Sorry, the tax laws. You know.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gucci</ENAMEX> will be
opening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Company Store</ENAMEX>. Estimated date of arrival:
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> (but that could slip).

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) We will have Casual
Fridays like all other good media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but that doesn't mean you should
just slip back into your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">97</TIMEX> jacket or that favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-shirt</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) No shorts before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) No Teva sandals after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Day</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemp</ENAMEX> is not an
approved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> T-shirts are
not chic.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>) If you're pulling an
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-nighter, bring a change of clothing, please.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gentlemen</ENAMEX> may remove
their jackets if attending an offsite at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GameWorks</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> hair is
appropriate only for those who have graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous 12</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>-guard chic
went out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Displaying your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee ID badge</ENAMEX> outside your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothing</ENAMEX> will not win you a place on Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackwell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Dressed List</ENAMEX>, and is
no longer acceptable.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>) Wear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sunglasses</ENAMEX>--preferably black--inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incognito</ENAMEX> is mandatory for media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>.
(And it's good cover when your eyes glaze over during discussions of SQL
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">servers</ENAMEX>.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>) Finally, to raise our
profile as media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola StarTAC</ENAMEX> cell phones will be issued to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. However, as part of our attempt to participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
program to control the cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>, they will not be connected for service.

         
      
   
