
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Calls</ENAMEX>

            You never know you belong to
a demographic until you start to spend money. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> I finally had enough to
buy a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jetta</ENAMEX>, which seemed terribly original. Then I drove
around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and saw <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> filled with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30ish</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel girls</ENAMEX> in their
... black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jettas</ENAMEX>.

            When my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">husband Bruce</ENAMEX> and I decided to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, we found that we were part of
another socioeconomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Well, we fit the socio part but were sadly lacking
in the economic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Starwave</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>-area companies
employ a bunch of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-30s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just like us--only rich--and they've bid up
the real-estate market. We all want to live in the same unpretentious
neighborhoods, and we all love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craftsman</ENAMEX> bungalows. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years ago</TIMEX>, perfect
1920s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> lay scattered unappreciated throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> like so many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">windfallen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX>. Not anymore. The average price of a home here has increased
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From the first quarter of 1997</TIMEX> to the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter of 1998</TIMEX>, the average sale price of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominiums</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">county</ENAMEX> rose from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$201,251 to $224,697</NUMEX>.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> , could probably get better paying jobs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starwave</ENAMEX>. But
we haven't, for high-minded reasons--or so we told ourselves. We won't work for
a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>--never mind that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> was recently sold to a pet
food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--and believe that print is intrinsically superior to online. The
truth is, we don't want to waste time commuting across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Washington</ENAMEX> to the
Eastside, home to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starwave</ENAMEX>. As we house shopped, we realized we
were being punished for our sanctimonious attitudes and for enjoying our easy
bus ride to work.

            To compete
against the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX>, we enrolled in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>-buying class where
almost everyone looked like us--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 to 35 years old</TIMEX>, white, groovy enough. I
recognized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from dance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>: We were dressed identically in striped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-shirts</ENAMEX>, leather jackets, and floppily tied-up hair. She glared at me as if
from a mirror, already seeing me as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> for a charm-filled fixer with
peekaboo views. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class leader</ENAMEX>, a loan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince</ENAMEX>, spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
sessions explaining how none of us would ever, ever own a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Not one we
wanted. And certainly not one in a neighborhood where we'd feel safe. A view?
Forget it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>? Out of the question. Crack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> for all of you!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince</ENAMEX>, it turned out, lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX> and commuted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> every
day. There were deals, he rhapsodized, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> dutifully took notes on
adjustable rate mortgages vs. traditional mortgages while I daydreamed about
our new life working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tacoma News Tribune</ENAMEX> . Finally, a real-estate
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX> dropped in to reiterate the impossibility of anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX> ever
becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX>, and we had graduated.

            
Through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-worker</ENAMEX>'s recommendation, we
acquired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie realtor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX>, who could read the energy of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
("Oh, I know if there's been abuse in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.") But she dropped her woo-woo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> when it came time to bargain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX> found us rather wonderful because we
were so terrified of the market that we bid on every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that was not falling
down. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a roof! we would gasp, feeling terribly lucky to have found
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. We signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> on a very cute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1918</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> just big enough for our bed
and dishes. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> the loquacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> told us in his nonjudgmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was fine as long as we didn't mind a foundation you could
put your foot through. We bailed on the deal.

            Open
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> were crowded with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsofties</ENAMEX>, usually younger than we, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cashier</ENAMEX>'s checks dangling out of their back pockets. We bid like addicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gamblers</ENAMEX>, placing opening bids <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> over the asking price with a clause to
increase our price another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> if necessary. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> refused to
bid up, and she'd been shopping for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year</TIMEX>. Her lowest point came when she
considered buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that you entered through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Every night</TIMEX> we
returned depressed to our rental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sycamore Street</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phinney Ridge</ENAMEX>
neighborhood. I had lived there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and loved the funny hillside street
with its old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> populated by fanatical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardeners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX>.
The neighborhood was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro</ENAMEX>-targeted, so there was no hope of buying there.
Meanwhile, a family of squirrels had moved into our crawlspace, and the house
reeked of vermin poo, furthering our desperation to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Kahn</ENAMEX> wrote, "If you're a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, who isn't?" Today, she'd have to write, "If you're a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan Buddhist</ENAMEX>--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, who isn't?" Our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">miraculously</ENAMEX> found a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> for us on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sycamore</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan Buddhism</ENAMEX>.
We loved his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. To encourage him to vote a straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire</ENAMEX>
ticket, I turned on all my charm. I'm lucky I didn't sprain something. I also
tried to appear serene--hoping to convey a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> quality. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX> just looked
befuddled behind his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health</ENAMEX>-style wire-frame glasses. The scent of
incense clung to him.

            Before I
flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, to cover a film festival, at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynn</ENAMEX>'s request we put
together a little promo package to present at the bidding--she makes all her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> do this. The goal was to convey how good we'd be at inhabiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house.</ENAMEX> We included a wedding photo that makes us look carefree and golden and
relaxed if you squint. The picture captures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> in a rare moment when his
eyebrows aren't beetled together, a photographic achievement commensurate with
getting a snapshot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nessie</ENAMEX>. I look somehow blonder than in real life. We also
included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>'s recent book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mount Rainier</ENAMEX>, a copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
with my byline on the cover, a sniveling love letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX> in which we
highlighted my travels in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhism</ENAMEX> thing), and a mention
that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> played guitar in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. (Why not whore the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> wrote the letter so I could
cast it back in his face later if we didn't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX> cooed over our
package. It seemed she had never before seen a letter to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> that
contained complete sentences.

            
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, I sat next to a
conservative-looking, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40ish</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who turned out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> proselytizer.
Closing her copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Mists of Avalon</ENAMEX> , she explained that my only hope
of getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was chanting. She phonetically wrote down the familiar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chant NAM YOHO REN GAY KYO</ENAMEX> and said that by chanting it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> I'd manifest
my wishes in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> dimension. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chanting</ENAMEX>, she said, had given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Turner</ENAMEX>
the strength to divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX>.

            That night in the Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin Room</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> B-and-B <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are named, not numbered), I opened my
book to read and out fluttered the chant. What the hell? If anyone would
respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> chanting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX> would. He'd probably pick it up in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fillings</ENAMEX>. I began to chant. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">third night</TIMEX> of chanting, the
phone rang under its chintz cozy. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>. Cyrus loved us. He felt a bond
with us as fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. (Thank God we weren't editing encyclopedias at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>!) Ignoring the software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> and the other suck-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>,
he had agreed to sell us his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>--at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> over the list price.

         
      
   
