
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Sire,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Technology Is</ENAMEX> Revolting
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, technological
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snafus</ENAMEX> conspired to delay both our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> "prop" of new material on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>
and our weekly e-mail delivery. We apologize to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of both versions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. These computer thingamabobs--gosh, they really are confusing and
complicated! Just so you know how it's supposed to work (and usually does):
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each day</TIMEX>'s edition is supposed to be available on the Web <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">around 5 p.m. Pacific time</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. Eastern time</TIMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception is the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> edition. This is the edition with the most new and updated material. It
is usually available on the Web by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> time. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> e-mail delivery should arrive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> as well. (You can
also download this same file, which is formatted for easy print-out,
directly from the Web.)

            Our No. 1
concern <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was trying to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> from finding out about these
problems we were having, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> where nothing ever goes
wrong. (Our No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, of course, was you, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>.) At an emergency
staff meeting, we considered our options. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-word
suggestion that doesn't bear repeating. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> offered to distract <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
with their vaudeville act while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sobel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hohlt</ENAMEX> snuck the pages into his
browser cache. Finally, though, we decided to tell him the truth. He took it
pretty well. "That's OK," he said. "I'm still busy looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investor</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> or
Sunshine?
            

            In her
dispatches <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> from the inauguration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karenna Gore</ENAMEX> invited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to help her choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> code name superior to the one
she regrets having chosen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smurfette</ENAMEX>. It must have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> syllables
and begin with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>, for some reason. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> suggestions (in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray"</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> reports, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sultry, Sexy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sassy</ENAMEX> seem superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schoolmarm, Shapeless</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzer</ENAMEX>." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandstorm, Seraph, Scylla</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fends</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX>,"
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> points out). Scrounger, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shameless, Snorer, Slimfast</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spoiler</ENAMEX> did
not appeal, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stripper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stoner</ENAMEX> were positively alarming. Bottom line: She
is still looking.

            
               Top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draft Choice</ENAMEX>
            

            We're
pleased to announce that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> will be joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> as a regular
contributor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> , the best-selling
memoir of life as an investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Losers</ENAMEX> , an expanded
version of his coverage of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential campaign, will be published
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>. He also writes a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> column for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> . Look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s regular contributions starting in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, with occasional appetizers before then.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
