
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>: A
Policy Statement
            

            In light of continuing
concerns about the power and ambitions of our parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, we at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> would like to offer the following declaration of our own
policy and goals. This policy statement was prepared without consultation, and
applies only to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.

            Our goal at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, quite
simply, is to own political and cultural commentary in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, and ultimately in the developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> as well. The
whole world, basically. We will use any means necessary to achieve this end,
including competition, both fair and unfair, wholesale buying up of potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> and alliances, strategic betrayals of partners
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, theft, bribery, murder, and, if necessary, putting out a
high-quality <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX>.

            Someday, if you want an
opera criticism, an analysis of the latest tax proposal, or a profile of some
obscure academic, you'll have no choice but to come to us. Building on our
domination of these areas, we will extend our reach into popular culture,
gradually monopolizing movie and television reviews and interviews with
brainless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. Ultimately, our towering position, as well as economies
of scale in the production of opinion and analysis, will make resistance
futile. At that point, we will control the industry and be able to extract the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> monopoly profits waiting to be had from poetry, book reviews, essays
pleading for entitlement reform, explanations of developments in foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and similar product lines.

            We will, of course, continue
to support all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>, conservative, libertarian, vegetarian, UNIX.
We are committed to producing opinions that are compatible with all standard
political labels and work equally well for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. We
foresee a day when all viewpoints on every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> are equally comfortable for
anyone to swallow, and when the frustrating cacophony of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s political and
cultural debate is replaced by easy-to-use modules of predigested viewpoints
that can be downloaded from the Web with a simple credit-card transaction.

            Or at
least, that's the plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Alan</ENAMEX>
Stamaty: Recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Works</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Stamaty, author of the cartoon strips <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">McDoodle Street</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtoon</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , didn't know
from computers when we approached him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> to create a strip for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.
He still doesn't know a lot about computers but, to our great delight, he's
really got into some of the technical possibilities of publishing on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>--and into some of the limitations as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>'s remarkably clever
animated cartoons also use remarkably few data bits, meaning that they can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">downloaded</ENAMEX> quickly by a normal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28.8</NUMEX> modem. Check out the current Doodlennium
for an example. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> also does the delightful jumpy illustrations for "Summary
Judgment" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. And all of us on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> staff especially loved his
recent drawing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX> confronting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dispatches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dialogues</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jinga</ENAMEX>-Linga
            

            If you haven't already done
so, check out our new design for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches & Dialogues" and the "Diary</ENAMEX>." We
hope you'll find the revised layout more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> friendly.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
