
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fool</ENAMEX>'s
Paradise
            

            In the business world there
used to be deals or, sometimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, there are strategic
alliances. The term "strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>" is intended to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) sound glamorous and
forward-thinking; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) obscure the actual nature of the relationship. It can
cover anything from an actual merger to an occasional lunch. (It is an
entertaining parlor game to read about some new strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>, especially
in the high-tech world, and try to guess who--if anyone--is paying whom. The
answer is often far from obvious.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, of course, wishes to
be glamorous and forward-thinking. So we are pleased to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> a
strategic alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fool</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fool</ENAMEX>, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are aware, is one of the
most entertaining, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illuminating</ENAMEX>, and successful online financial sites, with
outlets on both <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> and the Web. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate/Fool</ENAMEX> strategic alliance
will consist of lavish expressions of mutual admiration, cross-links between
our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> at even the least plausible opportunity, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> of T-shirts,
baseball caps, and other logo paraphernalia. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fool</ENAMEX> will be
providing, exclusively for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> column. The column is not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> stock tips or breaking news, but rather is intended to be a discerning
backgrounder on business issues, somewhat in the style of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>." (And who's paying
whom? Guess.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s first "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fool</ENAMEX>" is about the corporate fashion for changing
names.

            Next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, by the way, we will continue to ramp up our business coverage with
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maximum Wage</ENAMEX>," a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graef</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> compensation. (His article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s notorious <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX>
million severance package from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> back.) Each column
will analyze the pay of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or more</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> who are of interest for
being paid too much or (occasionally) too little. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graef</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> column,
to be posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, will focus on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from each category--both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            
               A Doctor
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
            

            A common
complaint about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>--and, indeed, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzines</ENAMEX> in general--is that we don't
write enough about castration. Like hang gliding and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>, this is
a subject most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would rather read about than try for themselves. We are
delighted, therefore, that our new "Medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> has chosen castration as the subject of his first
column. Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX> will appear every other week in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. We cannot
promise that every column will be about castration. In fact, we can pretty much
promise that no more columns will be about castration. But they all will
deal with the general subject of health, science, and society. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atul Gawande</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX>, who wrote a fascinating <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate "Diary</ENAMEX>" a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> about his life as a surgical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atul</ENAMEX> also
worked on health-care reform as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> during the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
term--an experience about which he has mixed feelings.

            
               Playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX>
            

            We've had some complaints
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who say they've signed up for (free) e-mail delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> on
Paper, our weekly text-only print-out edition, but haven't started receiving
it. We think we've got the situation under control, but we would really
appreciate hearing from anyone who's had this problem. Please click here, or e-mail us at
help@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. And if you'd like to get e-mail delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate,</ENAMEX> click
here. (If you'd
rather just get a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> announcement of what's in the new issue, click
here.)

            By the way, for those who
have been enjoying our new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> feature, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers"--which summarizes and analyzes the front pages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>--you'll soon be able to get overnight e-mail delivery of that
column. Or at least you'll be able to sign up for it.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
