
   
   
      
         
            Future Splash

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> fantasized about
becoming the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX> when it hosted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fair of 1962</ENAMEX>. But the fair's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> were less than prescient about
what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX> would bring. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">newfangled monorail</ENAMEX> that ferried
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s dowdy downtown to the fair's gleaming pavilions owed
more to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland of the 1950s</ENAMEX> than it did to the future. Inside the fair, the
exhibits hawked a similarly conservative <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. Easy-to-maintain kitchens,
direct-dial long-distance telephone service, and a machine that made change
from a greenback were among the big hits. Even the fair's futurist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">skyscraper-tall Space Needle</ENAMEX> that contains a revolving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>--had more to
do with selling overpriced and overcooked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> than it did with space or space
travel.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade</TIMEX>
after the fair, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> was on the move again, but it was moving backward.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> had more in common with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX> than
with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>, the area's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, wallowed
in the deepest of its periodic slumps, dragging the entire economy down with
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s self-image as a big-league <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had taken a separate beating two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> previously, when its major-league-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pilots</ENAMEX>--fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> (!) after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one season</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> seemed on the
verge of slipping into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puget Sound</ENAMEX> and disappearing forever.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> didn't disappear. Far from it. Three-and-a-half
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> after its fair, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has emerged as an international destination
for the ambitious and the fashionable. Visiting the city <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> convention, I smelled the unmistakable air of self-importance wherever
I went. Downtown was filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> noshing trendy food late into the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tourists</ENAMEX> wandered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> wondering which incipient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> trend
would be the next big thing. The science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> attending the convention
with me made their pilgrimage to the technological <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mecca</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, just a
few <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> away in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX>-side suburbs. Other conference goers, taking a
cue from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleepless</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> , hatched plans to move into their own
houseboats on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Union</ENAMEX>.

            How did
this happen? I wondered. How did this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, and airplane <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> transform itself into a strutting, moneyed, hard-driving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of the
future?

            
Igrew up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1970s</TIMEX> in a town
called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gig Harbor</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about an hour</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. Back then, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> was as
isolated, provincial, insecure, and wet as it is connected, worldly, smug, and
wet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Growing up as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>, we rightly ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and
concentrated our energies on snowshoeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cascade</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> ranges,
fishing for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX> from dinghies, or just prowling the mysterious undergrowth
of the rainforest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> back then was like the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> of coming-of-age
novels--anybody with the slightest ambition longed to leave. Nobody was
surprised if, after charting nationally, regional hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingsmen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Revere</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonics</ENAMEX> chose to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Who
could blame them?

            For that
matter, who could blame me for decamping to attend college back <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>? In my
absence, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> slowly changed its mind about how to get to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>. Maybe the idea dawned on young <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>
as they watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, heavy with fir and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cedar</ENAMEX>, depart for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and return
filled with exotic electronic goods. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> lesson was clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making</ENAMEX>
money by extracting natural resources was capitalism for chumps. The way to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> was to add value to commodities.

            Several local fortunes were made based on this concept. A
shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nordstrom</ENAMEX>, for example, reinvented the department store by
adding service, and took the idea nationally. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> updated the
4-by-4 noise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonics</ENAMEX> and invented <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grunge</ENAMEX>, temporarily making <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
music <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> (and this time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s rock 'n' roll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> stayed put rather
than fleeing to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Salmon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">glorified tuna fish</ENAMEX> in my youth, became
exportable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">haute cuisine</ENAMEX> , thanks to cheap air transport. Then Starbucks
figured out how to sell a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 cent</NUMEX> product for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25</NUMEX>, and took the concept
internationally. It's only a matter of time before the timberfolk steal a page
from this playbook and start peddling gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>.

            The
futurists of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> were on safe ground when they predicted that the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX> would be shaped by computers like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNIVAC</ENAMEX> mainframe
they displayed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>. What they couldn't have foreseen was that
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> and other software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> would figure out how to
market bits of plastic worth just a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> each (floppy disks) for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of dollars. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, as is well known, started <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>
before relocating to his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>. I often wonder if the future would have
burst upon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> with quite the same ferocity if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>'s sun had cast
the sort of spell on him that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s rain obviously did.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s spacey <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> fantasy about itself is
finally coming true <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and another home-grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig McCaw</ENAMEX>, have partnered in a telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> by the name of
Teledesic, which intends to loft <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">840</NUMEX> satellites into orbit by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> to create an
"Internet in the sky." <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Thirty-five</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> invited the world to
visit. Now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> plan to encircle it.

            With the passing of each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Needle</ENAMEX> looks more and more like a prop from a bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science-fiction</ENAMEX> movie. Although it hasn't dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s skyline since the
'80s, when the economic boom sprouted a host of taller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, it remains
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s symbol of progress. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> insists on calling the big black
skyscraper that soars over downtown the "box" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Needle</ENAMEX> arrived
in.

         
      
   
