
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Upside Down</ENAMEX>

            Everyone he consulted,
including me, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor</ENAMEX> he'd be in the doghouse if he went to work for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> article forced the world to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> seriously. Since
then, in print and on television, he has been a prominent anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor</ENAMEX>
told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> no thanks. But now he's in the doghouse anyway--for even
considering a job with the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. "A massive conflict,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spinner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX>. "He conveyed a sense of independence and
objectivity that I now think is fraudulent." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had not previously
revealed its admiration for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stu Taylor</ENAMEX>'s independence and objectivity. But many
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, who do admire those qualities, agree that
they are now called into question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> thus finds himself dropped into the
maw of a journalistic ethics controversy. This is a simultaneously terrifying,
infuriating, and boring place to be. (While there, perhaps, he may even bond
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who is suffering a similar--and, in my
view, similarly unjust--torment for taking a job in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.)

            With a flurry of documents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> can demonstrate--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX>, if you don't stop him--that he was never concurrently considering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
offer and writing about the case. Furthermore, what he considered seriously was
not exactly a job but a full-time unpaid advisory role. But the interesting
question is: So what? What if he had considered an actual job? What if he had
actually gone to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>? Why should that taint his past output or harm
his future career as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>?

            "Conflict
of interest" is an overused and underanalyzed concept. Why is a conflict of
interest a bad thing? For a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible answers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The
conflict causes some kind of personal advantage to distort either your
perception of the truth or your willingness to honestly state what you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perceive</ENAMEX>. In other words, it amounts to a bribe. Or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) the conflict reveals a
previously hidden incentive or tendency to misperceive or misstate the
truth.

            
As it happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> of mine--is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX> for the truth and driven to distraction by lying. That's what got him
into this mess. He is not a conservative or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. He voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'92</TIMEX>. But he believes, as he wrote in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , that there is "powerful evidence ... implicating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perjuries</ENAMEX> [and] efforts to obstruct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> and cover up" matters both sexual and financial. And he sincerely
believes it would be a tragedy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was allowed to
get away with "mendacity" on this scale, if proved. You may find this a bit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overwrought</ENAMEX> (I do), you may question the facts or take a more worldly view of
what should be done about them. But these are his views, and he has made no
attempt to hide them.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> and says: Please work for me. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> thinks: If I really
believe what I've been writing, don't I have a patriotic duty to do whatever I
can to prevent this tragedy? In other words, he feels an ethical obligation to
live according to his publicly expressed beliefs. But in the topsy-turvy world
of "conflict of interest," it seems there is an ethical obligation not
to act on your publicly expressed beliefs. To act on your beliefs discredits
your expression of them and taints any beliefs you might express in the
future.

            But how? Was the job offer, in effect, a bribe? Hardly.
Even before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>--not a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--proposed working at no charge for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, he would have made far less than he makes now. It would have meant
quitting a brand-new, prestigious journalism job, giving up all those TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appearances</ENAMEX>, and the prospect, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, of unemployment lethally
combined with extreme unpopularity. No doubt the frisson of history was
a plus in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s calculations, but only the call of duty--however unwelcome
and however misheard--can really explain why he would even consider giving up
what he had for what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was offering. If you're trying to corrupt Stu
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>, it's hard to think of anything less promising than this particular job
offer.

            So does
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> paused to consider these questions (rather
than--what?--immediately declaring, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, no, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> times no!" and running
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> through with his scimitar?) reveal a disqualifying lack of "independence
and objectivity"? It certainly suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> is generally sympathetic to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s mission--but that is clear enough from his writings. There's nothing
wrong with having an opinion--especially if your job, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s, allows you
to express it. Anyone who can study and write about controversial topics
without ever developing an opinion is an idiot, not an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. An
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> is someone whose views are based on an honest assessment of
the facts and arguments. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> considered a job offer totally
consistent with his expressed views casts no light at all on the question of
his "independence." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Click for</ENAMEX> .)

            
The fallback ethics argument against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> is
that he should at least have disclosed the approach from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> has a complicated defense of this one, too, but on balance and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, sure: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclosure</ENAMEX> is a good idea. How can a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> be against
disclosure? Keep in mind a couple of things, though. First, if there is no
actual conflict of interest involved, all you are protecting with disclosure is
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' right to reach the wrong conclusion. That's his or her right, all
right, but it's surely one of the lesser rights around. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> is not like, say, a stock picker, the value of whose words depends
heavily on whether he can be trusted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> makes arguments based largely on
public facts. These arguments stand or fall on their own, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> don't
need to trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> in order to evaluate them. Original reporting can't be
evaluated by the lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> sitting in his or her armchair. But even here, an
ethical evaluation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> isn't crucial. Especially on a big,
competitive story like this one, no one need be imprisoned in some biased
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s web of falsehoods unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s biases are comfortably
compatible with one's own.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor</ENAMEX>
says the job discussions provided valuable information and insights that helped
him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. That's easy to believe. Suppose, then, that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
approached him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> had strung the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> along, not overtly lying, but
milking him for information while only pretending to be interested in the job.
And then he published a triumphal scoop. Would the ethics cops have complained?
Unlikely. He'd be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the profession. It's only the sincere consideration
of a job doing something you truly believe in that can wreck your career in
journalism.

            
               Missed the link to more
blather on independence? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
