
   
   
      
         
            Then and Now

            
               Then and
Now
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Bedfellow"</ENAMEX> column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> comes to the defense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s new book on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, which is surfing a tidal wave of derision to
the best-seller list. We hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s revelation that the book is not as
awful as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say it is won't hurt its sales too much. Meanwhile, the
reminder of how much fun <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> had in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> raises once again the
question: Could a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> get away with it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? And the even more
intriguing question: OK, how? Fortunately, those vital questions were answered
by 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in his definitive study
"Could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Cheat</ENAMEX>? The logistics of presidential adultery." As far as we
know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has not taken advantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s advice during the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            
               Heads
Up
            

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of weeks</TIMEX>
we have been posting quietly, in primitive form, a new 
                  Slate
               
feature that emerges fully <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Called "Pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>," it is, to start, a summary and analysis--posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>--of who said what on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> political talk shows and how the ball
was moved as a result on various issues. It will also treat the print <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>,
though less comprehensively. Like our other Briefing features, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>
can be used either as a guide for what to read and watch or as an efficient
(and, we hope, entertaining) substitute for reading and watching.

            In case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> whets
your appetite instead of sating it, the page includes an extensive set of links
to Web sites where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panjandrums</ENAMEX> can be found in their full
glory. Come to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>, and you'll never want for an opinion again.
You'll be able to mix 'n' match, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post on the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> fashions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
on local traffic conditions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Smith</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>
currency crisis to create your own op-ed dream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> also includes
links to talk-show transcripts and newspaper editorial pages.

            But what
is the best collective noun for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make their living spouting opinions
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> medium or another (or, as is increasingly the case, in all of them)?
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Punditocracy</ENAMEX>," the term most often used, is clumsy. The "commentariat," a word
coined in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>, is much wittier.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX> uses both. It attempts to avoid the stale dismissive cliché
"talking heads," but sometimes, in a hurry, does refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX>, with
simple dignity, as "the heads."

            
               Having
Written
            

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Readme</ENAMEX>," touting 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hackathlon</ENAMEX>"--a
contest among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> for the title (to be awarded by

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' vote) of world's biggest hack--credited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX>
Steinem with the remark "I don't like writing. I like having written." A reader
wrote in to say the remark actually belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>, which we were
prepared to believe until another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> sent indignant e-mail on behalf of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Parker</ENAMEX>, which seems even more plausible. No one so far has nominated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Hellman</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Loos</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine the Great</ENAMEX>, but if anyone can supply
actual evidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>) who made this remark, we'd be grateful,
and we'll let the rest of you know. E-mail read@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Do You
Still Beat Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Husband</ENAMEX>?
            

            As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 13</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after it was posted, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5,000</NUMEX> 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> had
responded to our online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> survey. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> we were pretty thrilled to get
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000-plus</NUMEX> responses in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. Thanks to all who've spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>
telling us about themselves. If you haven't filled it out yet, click here for
the survey. We'd appreciate it.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
