
   
   
      
         
            Free, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cool</ENAMEX>, and Out of Beta

            
               Free,
Cool, and Out of Beta
            

            Slate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> is out of beta, meaning that it is no longer considered experimental.
It is safe to download--and we strongly urge you to do so without fear. Slate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> is a free little program that makes it easier to find your way around
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. It tells you what's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>'s issue; it takes you to the page you
want; and it even fires up your browser for you if you're not online at the
moment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slate Explorer</ENAMEX> has been awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool Software of the</ENAMEX>
Month" citation, beating out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>, among other
products. "It's um, you know, really cool," explained the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Software Design Engineer David Milligan</ENAMEX>. Click here to find out more, and to download <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slate Explorer</ENAMEX>. Just to
clarify what it is, it is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) free and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) cool. That's, um, what it is.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Baked</ENAMEX>
While <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Sleep</ENAMEX>
            

            Our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
feature, begun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago</TIMEX>, is a big success. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
signed up for e-mail delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 8,000 to 10,000</NUMEX>
read it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days a week</TIMEX>) on the Web. (You can sign up for e-mail
delivery right on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> page or by clicking here.) Most of the feedback we get is positive. But we do get
several complaints a week about misspellings, grammatical errors, and so on.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> ask: Don't you edit this thing?

            The simple, eloquent answer
is: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No. Here</ENAMEX> is why. The author of this feature, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>, lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>. He cannot start work until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are posted on the Web
at various times in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, and he must have it finished by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 a.m. PDT</TIMEX>
so that we can get it posted on our site and delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s e-mail by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>. We think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> does a remarkable job given
these working conditions, and that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> ought to excuse a few typos and
other minor mistakes. The reason we don't catch them is that the rest of us are
not as dedicated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> is, and are not inclined to be up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> to edit and proofread <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>'s copy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> files his column
directly onto our Web site from his computer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>. At a
specified moment, a computer at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that handles our e-mail delivery
then grabs the copy from our site and mails it to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> list. Except
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> himself, the whole process is automated. And we're working on that
loophole.

            Meanwhile,
it is every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s fantasy to be able to mainline prose directly into a
publication without the interference of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. And there aren't many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> we would trust with this kind of power. But we do trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, a former
naval-intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monthly</ENAMEX> . Though
if the typos get any worse, we may need to e-mail him a supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s
favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
