
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms Ballet</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX> around this time,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rite of Spring</ENAMEX> is performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Sadly, this is not the great
Stravinksy-Diaghilev collaboration, but a less distinguished ballet
choreographed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>. Here's the synopsis: In the first scene, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> trots onto the stage and declares himself mortally offended by some
bit of raunchiness connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>. (This year
it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Hoekstra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, who is distraught over The Watermelon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Woman</ENAMEX> , a film about black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>.) As percussive storm clouds gather,
distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Silver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX> swoosh in to defend
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. The battle rages; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> eludes destruction. The curtain falls
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> shaking their fists and vowing to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NEA</ENAMEX> next time, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snoopy cursing the Red Baron</ENAMEX>.

            But does
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> really escape? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Alexander</ENAMEX>, who has chaired the endowment since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, has been a formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for continued culture funding. She has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">successfully</ENAMEX> walked a tightrope in the censorship debates, using her
administrative power to block grants that would have spelled trouble while
sticking up for those that came under attack after they were awarded. Neither
left-wing performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> nor right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have called for her head.
Her shrewdness and star appeal may have kept the endowment alive through
troubled times. But the well-intentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> may ultimately be seen as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Westmoreland</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>. For the sake of preserving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, she
has come close to destroying it.

            Take a look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>'s just-announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> grants. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chairwoman</ENAMEX> is not to blame for how few there are. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> cut the
culture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s budget from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$170 million to $99.5 million</NUMEX>, and banned awards
to individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. What is largely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s doing, however, is that the
remaining grants reflect not a serious commitment to high culture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
but a kind of passive, middlebrow populism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s survival strategy has
been to slosh a thin gruel of artistic mediocrity around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The
strategy has worked, and may have been necessary, and of course it's easy to
carp from the outside. But I think she has carried it a bit too far.

            Until the
budget cuts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> gave awards in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> categories corresponding to familiar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disciplines</ENAMEX> in the fine arts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s forced reorganization collapsed the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17</TIMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planning & Stabilization</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Education & Access</ENAMEX>,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage & Preservation</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Creation & Presentation</ENAMEX>." Even the
names reflect a kind of pre-emptive surrender--no art here, they declare. The
biggest chunk of change--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.5 million</NUMEX>--now goes as block grants to state and
regional arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Most of what's left goes to arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX> education. The little direct support remaining is geared to sound
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inoffensive</ENAMEX>. In fact, much of it is political, but in a mushy
identity-diversity way. The result is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
alike may die of boredom before they turn up anything either offensive or
inspiring.

            
Turn to a page of the new awards at random.
Fifty-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> dollars goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballet Hispanico of New York</ENAMEX>, "to support
the development of a model study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, utilizing concerts, study guides,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> training and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>, to celebrate the cultural contributions made
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> grand for an
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Pacific American Audience Initiative</ENAMEX>." An "international festival of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wheelchair Dance</ENAMEX>" gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>. Elsewhere, there's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Tennessee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Design Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Knoxville</ENAMEX>, to help "design <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>" bring
"alternative design" to "underserved areas." Another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX> goes to the
Concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens for Humanity Ltd.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hartford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, "to support the
creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STOPAIDS</ENAMEX>, a statewide design project tailored to educate at-risk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with hearing disabilities on the problems of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>."

            The NEA
does still support some elitist high culture, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Opera</ENAMEX>. But the drift toward art as self-esteem <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and
away from art for art's sake is clear. In part this reflects trends in the art
world. It also reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s strategy of encouraging conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> to rethink their philosophical objections to arts spending through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> but effective device of putting money in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>. In recent
congressional testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> began her litany of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>'s good works
with "important folk arts <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> like the one sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folklife Association</ENAMEX> to publish and document primitive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hymns</ENAMEX>." Do I
detect a subtle jab even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> outmaneuvered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>?

            The endowment's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> in the entertainment industry
are less deft. At a rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> composer
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Adler</ENAMEX> sat down at the piano and declared, "I dedicate this medley
of my songs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>--to their destruction."
In the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX>, who heads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creative Coalition</ENAMEX>, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are really rotten, nasty, horrible
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>." Such comments can hardly make life easier for the civilized
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amo Houghton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Lazio</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, whose dissent from
party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX> is all that is keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> alive at present.

            The
arguments made by movie stars in defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> are even sillier. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Actors</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX> seem incapable of grasping that denying
someone a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> grant doesn't violate the right to free speech. Hardly
more persuasive is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Murray Abraham</ENAMEX>'s line that "if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> can be subsidized
for not growing things, why can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> be subsidized for producing<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are quick to point out that they're phasing out farm subsidies. But
even if they weren't, arts subsidies can't be justified on the basis that they
even out the spending score for urbanites. The justification for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> is
that we as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> want a more robust cultural and intellectual life than the
market will otherwise provide. Claiming an equal right to pork-barrel
undermines that case.

            
There is, to be sure, plenty of idiocy among
the NEA-bashers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, argued at a recent press
conference that government funding for the arts is censorship. Others at
the same event made the facile case that federal funding produces bad art.
"This is about an elite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> who want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to define what art is
good," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> added that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
will get better art once the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> gets out of the way."

            It is fun to speculate about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>'s idea of "better art." Maybe fewer pictures of whips in rectums and
more of rectitudinous whips? It's strange that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who insist that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must make more forceful moral judgments take the relativistic
position that it's incapable of ever making aesthetic ones. And their
criticisms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> are self-fulfilling. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, nobody paid much
attention, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> on NEA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> were free to make meritorious
decisions. They supported a lot of great and good art. Now, in an environment
politicized by the right, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> is supporting more of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> deems
"bureaucratic art." Whose fault is that?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> is alive, but it's
on life support. Know-nothing attacks and a desperate defense strategy have
conspired to wreck what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX> stood as a well-functioning, valuable, and
inexpensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> is still complaining, but he's
having the last laugh just the same.

         
      
   
