
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinagate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Winner</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1995</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> made a strategic decision to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of</NUMEX>
dollars on early television advertising. This unprecedented media blitz, which
began in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX> before the election, had
far-ranging consequences for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s future.

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, the chief effect was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s re-election. "In my opinion," he
writes in Behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> , "the key to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s victory was his
early television advertising." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> argues that by stealthily airing the ads
in places where they wouldn't be noticed by the national media, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> gained
an advantage that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> was never able to counter. This claim is highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">debatable</ENAMEX>. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other results of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' early ad strategy are harder to
dispute. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, which was unintended, is the campaign-finance scandal that is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ruining Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term. The other, very much intended, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>'
rise to riches.

            Though it is now conventional wisdom that the ads worked,
the evidence for this consists entirely of unsubstantiated assertions by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who made the ads. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, whom I spoke to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, continues to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extravagant</ENAMEX> claims. In the areas where they ran, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> says, the ads boosted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s numbers <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>, compared with places where they did not run. This
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-point difference, he says, held through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>. Others who watched
the numbers with a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> are dubious of this boast. "There's no
question they were great ads," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Mellman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>. "But
there's a lot of question about how central they were to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ultimate
victory." Another well-regarded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoff Garin</ENAMEX>, expresses his
doubts more strongly: "My sense is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s situation improved in places
where they weren't advertising pretty much to the extent that they did in
places where they were advertising."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> bases his explanations
on polls done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Penn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Schoen</ENAMEX>. Neither he nor they are willing to
share the numbers. But independent comparisons of places where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> says the
ads ran and places where they didn't do not appear to substantiate his claim.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, where the early ads did run, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s net favorable rating dropped
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1995</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> points in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, where the ads did not run, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> matchup poll
went from a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-point lead for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early spring</TIMEX> to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-point lead
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-October</TIMEX>--that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did significantly better in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> where
there were no early ads. Of course, these numbers don't prove the ads were
useless. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, the ads ran in media markets, which are generally only
parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and are sometimes made up of parts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. But
even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn and Schoen's</ENAMEX> secret data support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' claim of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-point
bump "in-buy," it doesn't prove the ads worked. All the early ads ran in swing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, where you would expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s numbers to move more. As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
himself acknowledges, "It's easier to change someone's mind in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>."

            Defending
a fallback position, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> argues that the ads helped because they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strengthened Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hand in resisting a budget deal on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> terms. "We
had to win the battle of budget to win the war of re-election," he says. "The
ads helped win the battle." What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> conveniently forgets is that at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, he had wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to compromise with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the budget. The
purpose of the ads can hardly have been to achieve a result <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> opposed.

            
Amore demonstrable effect of the ads was the
incitement of the campaign-financing scandal that now dominates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> opposed the early ad
strategy, because he thought it was a waste of money. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> involved in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund raising explains: "Asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> for money in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1995</TIMEX>
raised a question of whether they would be tapped out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. You either have
to go back to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and ask for an even bigger percentage, or
you have to find new systems, new pockets of money." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> that have
budgeted for contributions of a certain size are loath to allot large amounts
of additional cash in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the year</TIMEX>. To get more soft money out of
them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> turned to new perks, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coffees</ENAMEX>. But fund-raisers leaned more heavily on the second
alternative--finding new, untapped pools of cash. That's where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> came
in.

            The one
indisputable consequence of the ads was that they generated a great deal of
money for those who created them. As a rule, media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> get a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>
commission. In a presidential campaign, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> being spent,
these fees can be enormous. Ordinarily, a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
would not share in them. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> called the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 5</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group Inc.</ENAMEX> to split the rake-off. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Knapp</ENAMEX>, who did the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> buys; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Sheinkopf</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marius Penczner</ENAMEX>, who collaborated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knapp</ENAMEX> in producing the spots; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pollsters Penn and Schoen</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> himself. Details of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> are
not subject to disclosure under federal election laws. But, according to a
source with knowledge of the deal, the split was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-25-10-10-5</NUMEX>. Half of the
commission went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knapp</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A quarter</TIMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> went to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schoen</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another tenth</NUMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheinkopf</ENAMEX>. The final <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> went
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penczner</ENAMEX>.

            Consider this deal from the perspective of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1995</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> was making a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.75 percent</NUMEX> commission (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>) on as
much commercial time as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> bought. That means that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> urged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to spend an unprecedented <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> in early ads, he stood to earn
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX> for himself on top of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred thousand</NUMEX> being paid to him
as salary by the campaign. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Choice :</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> was so anxious for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to have as much money as possible for
political advertising on television that he proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> forgo federal
matching funds of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $15 million</NUMEX> so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would not have to abide by
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $30 million</NUMEX> limit on fund raising during the primary season."
Unfortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ignored this particular advice and decided to
stay within the limits.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> made
somewhat less than he might have hoped. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX> pushed hard to whittle down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, reducing it to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> by the end of the campaign.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knapp</ENAMEX>, the total commission shared by the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>
worked out to an average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX> per dollar spent. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> did not
get his <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> cut on the full <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 million</NUMEX> he says was spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
TV advertising. After he resigned in disgrace in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">5 Group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> cut him out of the action. As it was, according to a
knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $1.5 million</NUMEX> on the ads.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> says the real
profligacy was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX>' insistence on keeping large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> in key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> long
after the danger of a primary threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had evaporated. He disputes
that the ads played a role in the current scandal. On the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
aggressive fund raising, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> recently told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> ,
"I just think he overdid it." That's some chutzpah, considering who the chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beneficiary</ENAMEX> was. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> alone amounts to more than all the money
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have had to give back to suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
