
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commie Martyr</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> my column earns
its name--though "strange bedfellow" might be a better title for something by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>. Brock, in case you've forgotten, is that young, gay, conservative
investigative sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who specializes in the reverse beatification of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal saints</ENAMEX> in the gay-baiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> . After
making his name with a best seller arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> had mixed up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> with someone else, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> became even more notorious by
breaking, in the pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> , the lurid tale that came to be
known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troopergate</ENAMEX>." Though many of the "revelations" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s former
bodyguards were clearly baloney (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX> groping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> in
public, Bill consuming whole baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> in a single bite), the fantasy was
blended with elements of reality in an artful way. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> product of the mixture
was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit, which was filed not only against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but also
against one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s own trooper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, who alleged that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paula</ENAMEX>" did not
flee the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> as promptly as she recalls.

            Given
that background, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Seduction</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham</ENAMEX> has been much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">awaited</ENAMEX>, eagerly by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> camp, less so by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The hype succeeded
in getting my hopes up, but not for long. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> has gotten its hands on a
bootleg copy of the book, marked "confidential," and embargoed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 8</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is woefully disappointed.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> allegations here that even vaguely
resemble news:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. While
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> contemplated buying black votes in
order to steal the election, but ultimately did not.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> hired a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> to find out about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tomcatting</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> hired another private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> to intimidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bimbos</ENAMEX>. This
detective obliquely threatened the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. On the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> of the inauguration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> had a frank exchange of views
on the steps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, trading such endearments as "fucking bitch," and
"stupid motherfucker."

            These
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nuggets</ENAMEX> all have the same problems. First, they are remarkably thinly sourced,
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a disgruntled former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who was disbarred for bribery; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> who had his license revoked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Arkansas</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) Gennifer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Flowers</ENAMEX>' ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Police</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, none of them implicates
either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> in anything that is actually or even nearly
illegal. It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>, who wanted to buy votes.
Campaigns hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> all the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profanity</ENAMEX> isn't a crime. But worst of
all, these bombshells aren't particularly juicy, and to find them, you have to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wade</ENAMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> pages of stupefying rehash.

            
Possibly because he returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>
without the goods, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> takes a new authorial tack. He casts himself as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>-minded, quasi-objective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>, appalled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>-hating
right. To do this, of course, he must distance himself from himself, and this
he does with aplomb. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> piece of his about the travel-office
firings "was even accompanied by a facetious caricature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> as a witch!"
he notes. Fancy that. The new, evenhanded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is "neither an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">icon</ENAMEX> nor a demon."

            Actually,
he veers drunkenly between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> poles, now mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> for thick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ankles</ENAMEX>, dowdy outfits, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">résumé padding</ENAMEX>, now excusing her involvement in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> as "an undesirable,
foul-mouthed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harridan</ENAMEX> who had brought the mistreatment and neglect on herself."
Not so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> assures us, gallantly fending off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rogues</ENAMEX>. "It seems fairer to
conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s flaring temper was an understandable reaction to the
humiliation to which she was subjected on a regular basis."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s disingenuousness is monumental, and takes place at
several levels. At the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brock</ENAMEX>, under the guise of fairness, slings enough
mud to drown a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bangladeshi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. His particular obsession is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is, I <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you not, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Ogelsby</ENAMEX>, whose writings influenced her
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley</ENAMEX>, was a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maoist</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Alinsky</ENAMEX>, about whom she wrote her
senior thesis ("now under lock and key") was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> to "the socialist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">agitator Staughton Lynd</ENAMEX>, who had gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hayden</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> to meet
with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>." At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> "uniform"
consisted of white socks, sandals, "and the loosefitting, flowing pants favored
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Cong</ENAMEX>." She studied the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommie the Commie</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX> and was seen around the "influential circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Borosage</ENAMEX>," later
connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Policy Studies</ENAMEX> which "promoted pro-Soviet
movements in the Third World at the height of the renewed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>." She spent
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Truehaft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Garry</ENAMEX>,
who were--you guessed it--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>.

            And on it
goes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, on whose board <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> sat, was a hotbed of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marxists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk singers</ENAMEX>. She later joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World Foundation</ENAMEX>, on whose
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian W. DeWind</ENAMEX>, "who during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee for Public Justice</ENAMEX>, founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Hellman</ENAMEX>." Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mentor Marian Wright Edelman</ENAMEX> was "at the height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1980s U.S.-Soviet</ENAMEX>
tensions ... a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SANE/FREEZE</ENAMEX>, a leading disarmament <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
and she has been affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington School</ENAMEX>, a project of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Policy Studies</ENAMEX>." After the election, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> responded to
a congratulatory note from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Lawyers' Guild</ENAMEX>, "which had been founded
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> as an adjunct of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>." She thought about
appointing as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of education <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnetta Cole</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a committee
"connected to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Peace Council</ENAMEX>." Even
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to intimidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bimbos</ENAMEX> was a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">People's Detective"</ENAMEX>!

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Truehaft</ENAMEX> actually was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>--long
before his association with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>; "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommy the Commie</ENAMEX>" was a McCarthyite
nickname for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who never was. In either case, so what? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s
anachronistic redbaiting resembles the fashionable game "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Degrees of Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon</ENAMEX>," in which it is shown that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> can be associated with any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> in the world in a series of short steps. He then makes a laughingstock
out of himself by accusing right-wing "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>" of practicing "smear" tactics
and "guilt by association." When it comes to such subjects as lesbianism,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and witchcraft, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s technique is slightly different. He retails
various "suspicions," then assures us that they are "contemptuous." I think he
means "contemptible," but you get the idea.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> level of falsity is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> only to elevate his own,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proprietary</ENAMEX> scandal. As he indicates, he thinks the media focused on Whitewater
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> as higher-minded alternatives to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopergate</ENAMEX>. His agenda
is to convince us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McDougal</ENAMEX> doesn't matter, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
does. If he has to grant immunity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> to prosecute her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, so be
it. Deep down, he assures us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> is not. Unlike the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtuous Hillary</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> "slept around," he tells us,
without any further elaboration. She even "ministered to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>," whatever
that means. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Blythe</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "claims as his natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>," was
with a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX>, is an empty vessel, or
at least a vessel with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> at the tiller. He has always been a parasite on
her political acumen, her intelligence, and her income.

            At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> undermines his fainthearted defense
by arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is a closet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary cadre</ENAMEX>, a committed radical
who takes as her creed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Alinsky</ENAMEX>'s admonition that the struggle to help the
poor is a struggle for power in which the ends always justify the means. He
even describes her journey to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as a Maoist "long march." This
theory demands a certain creative use of evidence. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alinsky</ENAMEX> offered her a
job after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> turned him down, saying in a letter that she
disapproved of his methods and preferred to work inside the system. But to
Brock, this only enhances the point. Her chance to foist socialism on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
finally came with health-care reform. Never mind that lefties hated her
managed-competition plan. Never mind that she didn't even try to stop her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> from repealing the welfare entitlement. She is a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX>," making
tactical concessions in the name of the ultimate radical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>.

            Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s primary theme
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s clandestine pursuit of her own idea of justice, he intersperses it
with his own titular one about how a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was "seduced" by an amoral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and the seedy realities of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> political life. Unexplained is how
one can be a dedicated revolutionary and a sellout to the status quo at the
same time. But then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> need to have it both ways about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> still hasn't decided whether his opponent is a "closet
liberal" or a chameleon. You can make either case, but you have to make up your
mind.

         
      
   
