
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Don't
Readme
            

            The sole purpose of this
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme"</ENAMEX> column is to draw your attention to our cornucopious coverage of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandal. If you've missed the news at all, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
will catch you up on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> developments from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Earlier Papers</ENAMEX>
are, of course, accessible from the current column.) For the world's reaction,
check out "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Papers</ENAMEX>." "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>" supplies the big picture in a small
package--plus our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintometer</ENAMEX>, which scientifically measures within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-percent
accuracy the chance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> not finishing his term. It is updated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," we file random tidbits, insights, observations, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">factoids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is updated at least once a day, usually more often.
"In Other
Magazines" synthesizes the coverage in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and so
on. If you miss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> talk shows, "Pundit
Central" will have them all neatly packaged for you by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               'schief
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> has been filing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> epicenter. Catch up
on his reports
in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches & Dialogues</ENAMEX>." While you're there, read the latest exchanges
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
Drudge, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cybergossip</ENAMEX> who broke the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>"
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is a composite portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s dream date. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie</ENAMEX> T.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> denies having slept with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. (Not one of her more
persuasive essays, in the view of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>.) "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" brings together all
the varying explanations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s alleged behavior, looking for a
unified theory. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> analyzes how the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are
struggling to position <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in the public mind. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jared Hohlt</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Web Sites</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> is your guide to the many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> sites that have already sprung up.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next Week</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Scandal--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Overkill</ENAMEX>?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

            P.S. Not everything in

                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Harrigan</ENAMEX>
returns with his latest tally of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plot Holes</ENAMEX>" in
current movies. The "Medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atul Gawande</ENAMEX>, offers a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s novel argument on abortion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollander</ENAMEX>, our fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, praises fake fur. And that's not all ...

         
      
   
