
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spinmaster Aptitude Test</ENAMEX>

            Contrary to popular belief,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> did not invent spin. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> have
produced an extraordinary amount of it. This is partly because they have a lot
to spin about, and partly because they just seem to like spinning.

            Lately
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outpouring</ENAMEX> has been especially torrential. In addition to the spin coming
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ("The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX> was never sold") and the vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ("There is no controlling legal authority"), there has been a steady
gush from administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokespersons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Lewis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX>
at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> briefings and on television. Judged in terms of how
effective it is at defusing the fund-raising scandal, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> work ranges from
catastrophically bad to fairly good. What is odd is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration, spin-happy as it is, doesn't seem to have any sense of which
kinds of spin are effective and which only make matters worse.

            To get a taste of the different styles, I put some generic
scandal questions to various administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flacks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Lewis</ENAMEX>, the deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of communications, was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one I reached. I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> to
explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising calls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> did not violate the
law prohibiting the solicitation of funds on government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>. She said only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> could discuss legal issues, so I asked, on a
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> note, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> was in any trouble. "Obviously I don't think
he's in trouble," she said. Why not? "Well, I think what we have so far
learned, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> seems to have learned, to their great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astonishment</ENAMEX>, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for re-election would actually campaign on
their own behalf. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>--at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was
shutting down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, repealing the ban on assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, and trying
to shut down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>--would have taken seriously the issues
that were at stake. Shocking!" That was all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> had time for.

            My next
call was to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Weiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tobe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>. I pressed her on a different issue--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> sleepovers. I
accepted, I said, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s position that there was no price on
staying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX>. But wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX> one of the tools
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used to help raise money for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
handwritten "Ready to start overnights right away?" note clearly indicates?
"There was no link," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobe</ENAMEX> said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can invite whomever he chooses
to stay over. He invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and others. There was no ticket
price." Understood, I said, but weren't sleepovers used as a fund-raising tool?
"I don't believe so," she said. "Again, there was no price on it." After a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> try, I gave up trying to get her to admit the obvious.

            
Finally, I reached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>. When I asked why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> hadn't broken the law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> me to a story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , which suggested
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> might have broken the letter but not the spirit of the law. "If you
look at the history of the [law], it was intended to make it impossible for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to extract payments from federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>," he said. On the
blanket prohibition against raising money on federal property, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>
suggested that it couldn't sensibly apply to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>,
who actually live on federal property. But, he added, "this issue has not been
tested." Next I tried the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX> question. Wasn't it used as a
fund-raising tool<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Staying over at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was certainly a tool. I
wouldn't dispute that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> said. "It was a tool <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> enjoyed using."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, he added, used a variety of fund-raising tools as well.

            Let's
look a bit more closely at these approaches. Asked a direct question, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>
immediately changes the subject to some other issue, like gun control. She
never gives so much as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> in admitting wrongdoing. At a news briefing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> offered the following kerfuffle: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
enjoy spending time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. They regularly asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to stay at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> ... especially old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they ... met
more recently and--here's the key--wanted an opportunity to talk to ... in a
personal and nonofficial setting when they could. ... And I'll also say, having
gone over the list and having read through it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, I can now see why
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are proud of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who came to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as their personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> went on to explain that one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> was an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. This unctuous display
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infuriated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the press corps--several told me they avoid talking to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>. One prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national reporter</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' style as commenting on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> outside by claiming that the sun is shining. Because she is viewed as
an apparatchik, anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> says is discounted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX> (the official scandal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--who never called me back) are less spin-happy than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>. They
will not try to tell you that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sleepovers</ENAMEX> were really about
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Rather, they stick to an authorized script--and
when that fails, they retreat into a fog of obscurantism. At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 25</TIMEX> White
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> briefing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> was asked whether "access" had been sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>.
"Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> have access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> by
definition, because he's there. But we regard the notion of special access
because a contribution is made as something that is contrary to our policies."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>? That <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> repeatedly told an incredulous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s note about sleepovers was meant to refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>, I'm struck by how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are looking at dots,
connecting them where there's no evidence to connect them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has
clearly said that there was absolutely no requirement, no price tag. These were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of his coming to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>." This mirrored the
low-spin style of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Ziegler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> acknowledges that a wide variety of meteorological conditions,
including precipitation, are common <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX>. You might call that
"rain," but we don't . It provokes a mixture of sadism and sympathy from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, who proceed to turn the hapless flack into a human punching bag.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> takes a different
approach. Rather than sticking to a line that is obviously absurd, he admits
problems. He then goes into impressive detail about what the law is, and how it
might or might not have been broken. Having proved that he is a sentient human
being, he subtly points his questioner in a different direction--weren't
practices similar to this one actually common under previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>, who would fully engage with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>,
occasionally deflect a question with humor, and seldom--if ever--get caught
out. Is it raining outside? Sure it's raining , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> tells you. In
fact, it has rained <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.23 inches</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--average for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> .

            Only the
last of these approaches works. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>, who dislike and distrust the
press themselves, seem not to have learned the obvious lesson. Instead of
credibility, they have looked for the quality of ultimate loyalty in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flacks</ENAMEX>. The previous scandal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Fabiani</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX>-style
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spinner</ENAMEX> who was liked and trusted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and who managed, almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">single-handedly</ENAMEX>, to cure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>-file scandal with a dose of openness. But the
administration replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fabiani</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, whose main qualification was that
he had volunteered to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> . It hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
for the same reason--she devised the "Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pillory Hillary"</ENAMEX> campaign on her
own. As their relations with the press deteriorate to levels of hostility not
seen since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> are failing once again to recognize that a lack
of loyalty is not their biggest problem. A lack of credibility is.

         
      
   
