
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boredom</ENAMEX>

            We now know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>
did wrong. He got caught cheating on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> too early. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX> embarked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Monkey</ENAMEX> Business with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Rice</ENAMEX>, public exposure of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infidelity</ENAMEX> was a career-wrecker. Today, the episode would play out differently.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX>'s adultery would get reported, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> would yawn. The story would
vanish quickly from the news, and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> would say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>'s
wandering eye was less important than his expertise on weapons procurement.

            That, at
least, is the revised scenario suggested by the two sex scandals that broke
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. Reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> were actively unfaithful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>--and no
one cared. According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> of those
surveyed said that charges in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> article that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>
was having an affair with his communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> would have no impact on
how they voted. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 7 percent</NUMEX> said the information would make them less likely
to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>. There has been no comparable poll about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "fondled" a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> during a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> job
interview in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. But there is no sign of harm to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
approval rating, which continues to hover in the low <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60s</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years ago</TIMEX>, both
these stories would have launched full-dress feeding frenzies, which as likely
as not would have chewed up successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and spat them out onto the
refuse heap.

            Now such stories don't even rate as scandals. They mainly
provoke orgies of media self-examination, which usually take the form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who got scooped beating up those who broke the story. As ever before,
it was amusing to watch the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> organs resist temptation as best
they could, only to yield hypocritically <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days later</TIMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> broke the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> characteristically
turned up its nose, printing only a brief mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s denial on Page
B4. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days later</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Haberman</ENAMEX> slipped more detail in
under the guise of discussing whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> was spending too much time at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. "When you think about it, the most interesting part of this
flapdoodle over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gracie Mansion</ENAMEX> is what it tells us
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph W. Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s frenetic work habits," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haberman</ENAMEX> wrote,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">implausibly</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> gave similar backdoor treatment to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> affair, mentioning it only in the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Willey</ENAMEX> being subpoenaed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> subsequently covered it in much greater
detail as a press story about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>, who publishes an Internet tip
sheet, scooped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> by reporting what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was about to
report.

            The Drudge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angle</ENAMEX> is significant. By reporting gossip about gossip, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> has
single-handedly lowered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> for what constitutes "news." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days ago</TIMEX>, he
reported a rumor that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who is now a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, was once accused in court filings of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spousal</ENAMEX> abuse." This
was utterly false, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> retracted it under threat of a lawsuit. But all
this was reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and elsewhere, putting the falsehood into
wider circulation. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket tabloids</ENAMEX> have shown, the ethical standard
of the bottom-feeding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> is the one that ultimately prevails. Once
something is published by anyone, it becomes fair game for analysis and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repetition</ENAMEX>. Irresponsible, inaccurate postings on the Internet are now a back
door for stories that don't even meet the standards of the tabloids.

            
But as the standards of journalistic legitimacy
have declined, the formerly godlike power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment media</ENAMEX> to decide
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> will live or die has also diminished. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> were inclined to withhold information
about the personal lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> on the assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> couldn't
handle it. While sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> might understand that an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extramarital</ENAMEX> affair wasn't such a big deal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at large was too bigoted
and judgmental to put such information in proper perspective. A frequent lament
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that era</TIMEX> was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> wasn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' sex lives were considered their own business.

            That
attitude was condescending and undemocratic. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> considered all Ten
Commandments pertinent to their decision about whom to vote for, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> had no business suppressing information about one that it
thought was OK. But on the evidence of the most recent cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in
flyover <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have grown more worldly than big-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> give them
credit for. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may be extremely interested in details about any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous person</ENAMEX>'s sex life, they don't deem that information particularly useful
or relevant when casting their votes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one 1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71 percent</NUMEX> said
it was none of their business whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> had been unfaithful to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992 and 1996</TIMEX>, the election results suggested that they were telling
the truth about how they felt.

            Admittedly, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, and
information that might not harm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> could still destroy a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case, everyone has fully assimilated the
notion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as an adulterer, or worse. An added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">datum</NUMEX> weighs far
less than does a novel accusation against someone previously considered a good
family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But something clearly has changed. Even conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, now hesitate to make blanket condemnations of adultery.
Ironically, while the press in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has moved toward an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
standard of private-life investigation over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
public seems to have evolved a more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> attitude. We're more concerned
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' performance in office than about the condition of their
marriage vows.

            This new
maturity argues not for an advance, but for a retreat on the part of the press.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't deem personal lives politically relevant, there's no
justification for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> invading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s privacy to find out about them.
This open-ended assault by the press is one of the main factors driving many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we want in public life away from public life. And if the public
doesn't think adultery matters, the press is exploiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> merely for
its own aggrandizement. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> story was defective, among other reasons, because its
evidence fell short of the photographic. But getting better evidence means even
more disagreeable snooping, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">à la Gary Hart</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> need is a stricter
standard of relevance, not a higher burden of proof.

            
One might make a case that the latest sex
stories are relevant just the same. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s inner circle have broken with him over a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> values for more than her spin. It was getting absurd for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to
analyze developments at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX> without referring to a romantic attachment
they believed to be a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in events. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> case, appointment to a
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and a trip to a conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> raise the question of
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> misused government resources. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> can always
find pretexts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind or another: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is a hypocrite, is lying
about it, is doing it on government time, or--the old standby--that the issue
raises questions of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." It's time to quit fishing. When it comes to
simple adultery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> should listen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. If they don't care,
there's no reason why we should, either.

         
      
   
