
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldilocks</ENAMEX> in Cyberspace

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldilocks</ENAMEX> in Cyberspace
            

            As breathlessly reported in
the new "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Circuits</ENAMEX>" section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> twentysomething
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shapiro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shenk</ENAMEX> were "commiserating over lunch in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day last summer</TIMEX>" over "their problem." How sad that a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer day</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX> should have been clouded by a shared problem.
And what was their problem? Had they both lost a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> recently? Spent their
last nickel? Found out their girlfriends had been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> interns? Been
diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>? No. "Their problem: In writing and speaking they spend a
lot of time in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linguistic contortions</ENAMEX>, trying to explain that they neither love
nor hate technology."

            What a
problem! This may well be the most boring problem anyone has ever had. (Or at
least, we would like to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> claims for that honor.) Still, questions
remain. Why the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">linguistic contortions</ENAMEX>"? Exactly what is so difficult about
explaining that you neither love nor hate technology? Maybe the problem was
getting anyone to listen. ("Who gives a shit? Go away!") For that matter, why
do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messrs Shapiro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shenk</ENAMEX> themselves feel such a passionate need to share
their lack of passion with others? Why don't they just continue having lunch
with each other, engaging in delightfully desultory, contortion-free
conversations, and leave the rest of us out of it?

            "How do you like your new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DVD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>?"

            "Oh, it's OK. I neither
love it nor hate it. And what do you think of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Windows 98 beta?</ENAMEX>"

            "My feelings are mixed.
There are good things and bad things about it."

            And so on, as lunch turns
into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>, then dinner, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX> slowly darkens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> sky.

            Or,
here's a little tip: If there's a subject on which you have no feelings one way
or another, try talking about something else! You'll be amazed how well that
can work!

            But no. Instead of these sensible solutions to their
problem, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> have taken the paradoxically agitated step of founding a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>--the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Technorealists</ENAMEX>"--and issuing a manifesto about their lack of strong
feelings. The manifesto is on the Web, natch, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technorealism</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>, but
we are so stupefied by this problem that we are unable to summon the will to
click on the link. Somebody tell us what it says. Or, on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought,
don't.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technorealism</ENAMEX> will be seen by history as a tragic movement. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldilocks</ENAMEX>
without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bear, Technorealists</ENAMEX> roam the landscape, tasting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porridge</ENAMEX>,
always finding it too hot or too cold and never just right. Their linguistic
contortions turn into bodily contortions as they literally tie themselves in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knots</ENAMEX>, their desperation for attention doing battle with their determination to
say nothing worthy of it. Ultimately they die (not of boredom: of that they're
merely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>). Their last words are, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honest</ENAMEX>, I wish I could persuade you
that I neither love nor hate technology. I know you find that hard to accept,
but really, it's true. Technology to me has its good points and its bad points.
It's a mixed bag. I know this is a terribly iconoclastic proposition, and
that's why I'm not asking you to believe it, I'm only asking you to believe
that I believe it. Why are you coming at me with that pillow? Urgggghhhh
..."

            

               Technorealists Wanted
            

            Now
here's a real problem. 
                  Slate
                is looking for a software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX>,
or maybe even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, to work on various features we hope to add. Our program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> (i.e., software supremo), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX>, says the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> will
be "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C SQL</ENAMEX> jockey with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three years</TIMEX> of Web experience." So the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">qualification</ENAMEX> is knowing what the heck "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C SQL</ENAMEX> jockey" is. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> is a
tolerance for working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have a clue what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C SQL</ENAMEX> jockey is.
But if the idea of being surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, instead of the usual
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX>, strikes you as appealing rather than appalling, we'd like to
hear from you before you come to your senses. E-mail a brief note, your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>,
and a review of any recently published book of poetry to kinsley@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Anyone who
actually sends a poetry review is automatically disqualified. Being able to
recognize when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> is making a joke is essential, although actually
appreciating the joke is strictly optional. Faking appreciation is always, of
course, er, appreciated.

            
               New
Pru
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, our advice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, has retired, and her column has been taken over by her niece, also
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>. We go through this twee song and dance--for an anonymous column
written by a fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--to alert you to an actual new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and to
explain the inevitable change in tone. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> is younger and of a
different gender. S/he brings a somewhat different life experience to the task
of solving all your problems. In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Pru</ENAMEX> is--as s/he admits--not as
well versed in macroeconomics as his/her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
Pru may have deeper insights regarding marriage--having had several more of
those than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Pru</ENAMEX>. You can go to "Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>" by clicking here. And you
can write to him/her at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            Another
plug: If you haven't tried our Web linking game, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Degrees of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bacon</ENAMEX>," give it a whirl. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> novices, it's a fun method to
learn your way around. For the Web savvy (or even Web weary), it's a good way
to show off.

            

               Frayunion
            

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> to

                  Slate
                are entitled to participate in our discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, "The
Fray." Regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the Fray call themselves "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fraygrants</ENAMEX>" and have
formed friendships that seep out of cyberspace and into real life. A Fraygrant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reunion</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frayunion</ENAMEX>") is occurring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, featuring a golf
tournament, among other activities. Another gathering is planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraygrants</ENAMEX> attending from as far away as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>.

            A popular Fray thread is the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> choose a book to discuss (currently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Bloom</ENAMEX>'s
The Closing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Mind</ENAMEX> ), elect a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraygrant</ENAMEX> to lead the
discussion, and have themselves an electronic book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            Fraygrants have even created
their own Web page, entirely outside 
                  Slate
               . Check it out at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geocities</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com/Tokyo/Bay/2167</ENAMEX>. To get more information
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frayunions</ENAMEX> and other Fray activities, go there. Or, of course,
enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX> and
introduce yourself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
