
   
   
      
         
            This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Your Network on Drugs</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is devoting the full
range of its resources to a month-long "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">March Against Drugs</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> says
it will forgo <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> in advertising revenue to air anti-drug
public-service announcements. World <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Tonight</ENAMEX> , as well as Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning America</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turning Point</ENAMEX> , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> , is featuring
stories about the dangers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>, "D<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Day</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>
will host a "town meeting." Non-news shows, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> 
               Improvement , have been drafted into
service too. On the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14</TIMEX> episode of the sitcom Grace 
               Under
Fire , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> finds <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, she
finds it hard to raise the issue with him. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publicist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace</ENAMEX> decides to take a "hard line."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> in what is known in the trade as "cause-related marketing" is
the most serious episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyfication</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mouseketeers</ENAMEX> took over the
network in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> replaces journalism (and
entertainment) with agitprop. Beyond that, the willingness of a top news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> to suspend all skepticism is one more sign that the drug war has
reached another baroque period.

            The story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s descent into this morass begins with
family. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Burke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug-Free America</ENAMEX>, is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Burke</ENAMEX>, who, until shortly before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> takeover, was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Cities/ABC</ENAMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Burke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> tried to
distinguish itself as the anti-drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> among the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, running a
plethora of partnership-produced public-service announcements, including the
famous fried-egg commercial, "This is your brain on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Cities</ENAMEX>
instituted a pre-employment urine-testing program that covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsroom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Westin</ENAMEX>, who recently replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roone Arledge</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
News, has redoubled these efforts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> presented
research indicating a national rise in teen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX> hatched the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">March</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drugs</ENAMEX>" idea.

            The first
question <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX> should have asked himself is whether it ever makes sense for a
news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> to climb into bed with an advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>. Fighting racism and protecting the environment are good causes
too. But had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> allied itself with even mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX>, alarm bells would have gone off--and rightly so.
Despite the worthiness of these causes, questions arise about the methods,
tactics, reliability of information, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of funding of any advocacy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nonprofits</ENAMEX> often provide essential help for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, but it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Journalism 101</ENAMEX> that you treat them skeptically--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, not as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in a
crusade.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug-Free America</ENAMEX> is a
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that produces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>slick TV and print advertising to try to
"unsell" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Until very recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> was heavily supported by
the cigarette and liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>, which want to distinguish their products
from illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> no longer accepts smoking and
drinking money, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> its support comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Wood Johnson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, whose wealth is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>.

            These biases are reflected
in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>. Drinking by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> is arguably a bigger problem than
the use of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powders</ENAMEX>. According to surveys, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>
of high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> say they have been drunk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 10</NUMEX>
percent say they use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> isn't talking about that. "Most experts
agree that it is OK if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> see you having an occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>," says an
educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pamphlet</ENAMEX> distributed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> in connection with the march.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> has aired no stories about the abuse of prescription drugs so far this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. It did, however, run an alarmist story on Good 
               Morning

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> sniffing toxic household chemicals, which it claimed
kills <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a year--a statistic that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say has no basis.

            What's a
little exaggeration in a good cause? The air of hyperbole that surrounds the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> march is in keeping with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> attitude that a
message doesn't have to be accurate if it sells. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> famous partnership ad
suggested that smoking pot produces the flat-line brainwave of a comatose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> would never knowingly be a party to the dissemination of such
crude and dishonest propaganda during a real war, as opposed to a metaphorical
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> like the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, it seems to be dropping all its
usual standards.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Evans</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who wrote a piece in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> about the difficulty of talking honestly to one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>,
was flown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to participate in a taped round-table dialogue for
Good 
               Morning 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> . He says his comments criticizing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX> were edited out of the discussion before it aired. Perhaps this was
because of time constraints or because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> was inarticulate--though he was
pretty cogent on the phone. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> has made some efforts in the direction of
balance. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World News Tonight</ENAMEX> ran a fair-minded story about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Schmoke</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> treating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> as a public-health
problem rather than a law-enforcement one. But if another dissenter is
presented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, it will probably be some stoned freak with a ponytail.
It's your choice: communism or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe McCarthy</ENAMEX>. That's not atypical of TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, which thrives on the conflict of extremes. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> used to do
better. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of years ago</TIMEX>, it broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>: The
Search for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solutions</ENAMEX> , a much praised <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour-long</TIMEX> special that questioned the
tactics and methods of the drug war.

            There is a crudeness to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drugs</ENAMEX> campaign that must make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX> wince. A pamphlet called
How to Raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Drug-Free Kids</ENAMEX> (produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digest</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> for the project) makes the
project of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-rearing sound like growing seedless watermelons. Never
experimenting with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is seen as the chief goal of growing up. "Drug-Free
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>" might sound like just another dumb slogan <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">à la "Just Say No.</ENAMEX>" But these
slogans have consequences. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zero Tolerance"</ENAMEX> led to the near-expulsion of a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midol</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drug-Free Kids</ENAMEX>" is
already encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to drug-test their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--something Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning America</ENAMEX> thinks might not be such a bad idea.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Historians</ENAMEX> are likely to look
back on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> as a high-water mark in the anti-drug
irrationalism of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'90s</TIMEX>. There's a returning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>-cartons sense
of hysteria to the whole crusade. This would have been a good story for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
News, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> hadn't been so busy being part of the problem.

         
      
   
