
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked SLATE</ENAMEX>.

            
               Naked
Slate
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">styles</ENAMEX> himself "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, has
offered a considerable challenge to magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> everywhere by posing nude
in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> issue of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. For too long, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have been
content to expose other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Is it not time for them to start exposing
themselves? The thought of naked magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>--with the exception of JFK
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, of course--is not one many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will find appealing. Whatever reason
one might have for subscribing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is
unlikely to be a major selling point for, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .
But we in the magazine industry believe deeply--if we believe anything at
all--that a trend is a trend and cannot be resisted. Therefore, naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
it is.

            Here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, though, we
eschew grandiose titles like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief," let alone "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>." At the
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> meeting called to discuss the issue of who should bare all for
the good of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, there was a groundswell of support for calling upon
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--but no one volunteered to make the call. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> decided to delegate the challenge of self-exposure to the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, who delegated it to an associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, who delegated it to an
assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, who delegated it to the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aidan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Weed</ENAMEX>, whose title is Special Issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX>.

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weed</ENAMEX> does not
technically bare all, he does--unlike his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> --refrain from
making clever use of light and shadow to hide the aspects of the story that
interest his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> the most. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Weed</ENAMEX> uses the occasion to
vent some controversial opinions about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reveals</ENAMEX>, are "just terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. They're driving me crazy with their 'eat
this ... drink this ... go to sleep ... stop crying.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weed</ENAMEX> shares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s
tart views about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>' relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>. "They just use
her for their own pleasure," he says. "I get stuck with her, while they go out
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. It's incredibly immature."

            And why did Weed agree to
put his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> on the line--or, rather, online<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "It's a statement on the need for
... well, it's a symbol of ... oh, heck, I don't know--I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only nine months</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>.

            "But I'd
do anything for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>," he adds. "I just love that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>."

            
               Index
Investing
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akst</ENAMEX>'s recent article, arguing that investing in index mutual funds is "evil,"
has produced a heated response from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Porter</ENAMEX>, a mutual fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> at
Morningstar, an independent financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akst</ENAMEX> could not be enticed into
a dialogue on the subject (to continue the theme of the previous item, he and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>), but we publish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX>'s response in "E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>,"
and take this opportunity to draw special attention to it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>
            

            Among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
join the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, way back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Davis</ENAMEX>
and Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Barnes</ENAMEX>. Both were longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX>'s case) who happily embraced this different sort of software
product and the different sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>) it brought with
it. Now, after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Slate</ENAMEX> careers that span <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 18 months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> are
both retiring--at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 40 and 30</TIMEX> respectively. From which you may conclude
either that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is a horrible place to work, or that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is a great
place to work.

            As production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and
then associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX> designed and supervised the process by which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> gets from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to you. Publishing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is still
very new, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate's</ENAMEX> publication process--with its daily postings, e-mail and
print versions, constant redesigns, and so on--is very complicated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX>'s
logical mind and wonderful laugh, among other gifts, made it all happen (well,
most of the time).

            And what, exactly, is a
"program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>"? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> liked to explain that on normal software projects, the
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> is just that: in charge of the program. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, the program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> is, in essence, the chief computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in a nest of cybernaifs. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> took amiably and skillfully to his ambassadorial function, and is more
responsible than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for designing the actual technology behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. He also has written our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webhead"</ENAMEX> column, and will continue to contribute to it.

            All of us at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> wish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy</ENAMEX> and Bill the best as they enter their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Golden Years</TIMEX>. We'll miss you.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
