
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Turns Yellow</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weisberg</ENAMEX>

            
               (I<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,531</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 25</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 1</TIMEX>)
            

            In a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the
West <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>, sits an
intense, wiry political operative named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX>. Though he is not among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s best-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
most diabolically effective tactician. On the issue of crime, in which he
mostly specializes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> has gotten celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brady</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Klaas</ENAMEX> to appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> TV spots. He is also largely responsible for
moving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign beyond mere "rapid response" to pre-emptive
strikes--engineering, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s endorsement by the Fraternal
Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> on the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> was set to launch a major attack on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s crime record.

            So it wasn't hard to guess
the origin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s latest "little things" proposal: to require drug
testing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> who want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for
presiding over an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use by young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had the potential to
bite; by tossing out the drug-testing idea, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could claim to be doing
something about the problem. "Our message should be simple," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said in
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> radio address. "No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "simple" proposal
might be better described as simple-minded, not to mention impractical,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">useless</ENAMEX>, and offensive to notions of privacy and constitutional rights. But the
truth is that though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> pushed the proposal--along with domestic policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adviser Bruce Reed</ENAMEX>--it can't be blamed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, or even laid at the
doorstep of "election-year politics." No one had to work very hard to talk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> into accepting yet another abridgment of individual freedom for the
sake of political expediency. What the drug-testing proposal should remind us
is not just that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>, who, with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-point lead, is now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pandering</ENAMEX> beyond the call of victory. It should also put us on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> about
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, if he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> at all, is a liberal of an odd sort: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> with no
instinctive regard for civil liberties or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s abysmal record
on liberty goes back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>. The low moment was in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, when, under no pressure from anyone, he proposed a law to ban
"desecration" of both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> flags. "It was totally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gratuitous</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Jacobson</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties Union</ENAMEX> at the time. Under a then-recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
decision, "It wasn't even in doubt that it was unconstitutional." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
seemed more <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>-friendly after he was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, when he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reversed</ENAMEX> himself and opposed amending the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> to ban flag burning. But
that stance turned out to be a false positive for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberties</ENAMEX>. Since then he has consistently insulted both the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> amendments. (Some would say he has disregarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Amendment</ENAMEX>,
too. But that's a different discussion.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> slovenliness first
became apparent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, when he boxed his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor general</ENAMEX> on the ears
for having been on the wrong side in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knox</ENAMEX> case, in which a graduate student
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> was convicted for possessing videotapes of
teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> wearing bikinis and underwear. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> overturned
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate student</ENAMEX>'s conviction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> joined in the chorus condemning the
court's decision.

            You might grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> as a necessary surrender--no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in his right mind wants to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allied</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> pornographers. But what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Decency Act</ENAMEX> is truly unforgivable. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Exon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> introduced
a foolish bill which would have criminalized the transmission of "indecent" or
"patently offensive" material via the Internet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> backed
it.

            It was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, more
than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, who tried unsuccessfully to derail the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. One
oddity of this political moment is that while our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has no
special love of civil liberties, civil libertarian sentiment is growing in the
unlikely soil of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>--where vilification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> has been campaign boilerplate, at least until recently. This surprising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> is partly a matter of pandering to anti-government paranoids in the
gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia movement</ENAMEX>; partly anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> opportunism; partly
explained, at least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> case, by the interests of business; but partly,
perhaps, principled.

            
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox of California</ENAMEX> led the push for an alternative; both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX>'s position. But it was left to a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-judge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> to throw out the law,
calling it "profoundly repugnant." Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> learn his lesson? Hardly. The
administration is appealing the decision to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
recently signed an immigration bill giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the power to exclude
anyone who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> "terrorist activity." This threatens to become a modern
version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">McCarran-Walter Act</ENAMEX>, which was used during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> to
exclude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lefty writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourth Amendment</ENAMEX> rights,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been no better. In his crime bill, passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, he went further
than any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would have dared to restrict habeas corpus, the
writ by which state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, including those on death row, can get their
cases reviewed by federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Under the immigration bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> directed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> to deport asylum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> without
giving them any opportunity to appear before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>. And in his most recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-terrorism</ENAMEX> proposal, which he tried to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in the wake of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> disaster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> requested vast new wiretapping powers for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. Once again, it was primarily a few liberty-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who
restrained him.

            The drug-testing
proposal may be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s most obnoxious gesture of all. In the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, there is at least a trade-off posited between individual rights and
competing public purposes, like the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In the case of drug
testing, however, the proposed warrantless blanket invasions of privacy serve
only a symbolic value. A scheduled drug test is easily beaten; you just need to
stay clean for a short time before the test. Then you can celebrate your
license by getting high. In answer to the objection that urine tests reveal
only very recent use of hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Reed</ENAMEX> says that before long,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drug-testing</ENAMEX> technology will have advanced from urine to hair tests, which may
reveal chemical traces for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to a year</TIMEX>. But here the insult to civil liberties
becomes staggering. The explicit purpose becomes finding out who among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">young</ENAMEX> has ever indulged in the kind of experiment that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> ticket have acknowledged participating in themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
made this purpose clear in his speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birmingham Southern College</ENAMEX>,
where he said the reason for the tests was to "to find those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and help them
before they're in trouble and it's too late."

            
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> simply has no conception of why
such an intrusion might be worrisome was evident from that speech, as it was
from his radio address, in which he compared his proposal to the requirement
that parolees take drug tests. Parolees are convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
applying for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s licenses aren't even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> of anything. It has been
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> limited his idea to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under-18s</TIMEX> in order to affront only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who cannot vote. The more likely reason, however, is that if the idea is
ultimately judged constitutional--a big if--this will only be because it
applies to those who do not have the full legal rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.

            On top of this sorry
civil-liberties record are the misuse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s own
original travel-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> investigation, and what has come to be known as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX>. No one has yet traced these abuses to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> himself. But
there is something to the argument that his cavalier attitude about individual
rights helped to create an atmosphere in which thuggish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his
administration could regard invasions of privacy very lightly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is hardly
better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>, and there are lots of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, who decry only those incursions that
perturb the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX>. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sets the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> may not be far off when some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> accuses a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of being a card-carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX>--and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> proudly admits it.

         
      
   
