
   
   
      
         
            Credit Check

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1984</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s re-election ads first crowed that it was "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,"
inflation was at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.6 percent</NUMEX>, unemployment at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX>. The Dow was at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,100</NUMEX>, interest on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> mortgage was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.5 percent</NUMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was
projecting a budget deficit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$174 billion</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1997</TIMEX>, inflation
stands at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.3 percent</NUMEX>, unemployment at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.8 percent</NUMEX>. The Dow hovers just under
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX>, interest on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> mortgage is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5 percent</NUMEX>, and the administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> a deficit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37 billion</NUMEX>. If that was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, this must be high
noon.

            In other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respects</ENAMEX>, too, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is in better economic shape now than during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. While <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the '80s</TIMEX> recovery brought a rise in social problems such as
homelessness and welfare, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> boom has been accompanied by a decline in
those same ills. Recent hints of an increase in real incomes suggest that
affluence may be more widely shared this time around. Faced with such brilliant
economic performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> tend to be as eager to deny any credit to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent president</ENAMEX> as they were to give him all the credit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> display the opposite inconsistency.

            Serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> tend to agree with the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> have less impact on the economy than most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> can screw things up--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> did when he
implemented wage and price controls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> did when he
failed to focus on the problem of surging inflation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. But when it comes
to producing the general conditions of prosperity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> have little
power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s main economic lever, the money supply, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>
of the autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> points out, gross
domestic product growth has been remarkably consistent over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 2.3 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, despite dramatic reversals in economic
policy.

            Nonetheless, presidential
policy does affect the health of the economy. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is supposed to be
insulated from politics, it is not completely immune. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> term
alternating with the presidential-election cycle means that a one-term
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> gets a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of his choosing for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just under 50 percent</NUMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidency</ENAMEX>, while a two-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> in control nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the time. A successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> reflects well on the president
who picked him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>, for instance, deserves considerable credit for choosing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Volcker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcker</ENAMEX> was committed to taming inflation even at
the cost of putting the economy into a recession just before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> election,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> was committing honorable suicide by picking him.

            
Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> can make it harder or easier for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> to do its job
through fiscal policy--taxes, spending, and deficits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents</ENAMEX> also steer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> and dollar policy, but have a less tangible impact on business and
consumer confidence. It may be ridiculous that our presidential elections are
virtual referenda on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the economy when so much is out of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s hands. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> ignored the condition of the economy in
choosing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, they would be even less realistic.

            
So, with all those cautions in mind, I ask
again: Who deserves credit? In a recent column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James K. Glassman</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> should get it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s tax cuts, Glassman
contends, fueled the current gush of tax revenues as well as a flourishing
entrepreneurial culture. This is pretty far-fetched. Taking into account both
tax cuts and tax increases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> didn't reduce the overall tax burden during
his presidency. Supply-side dogma notwithstanding, what has boosted tax
revenues beyond expectations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> are the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tax
increases , in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and 1993</TIMEX>. (And in fact, the economy has reacted
better to increases than to cuts. See "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best</ENAMEX>
Policy.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s large spending increases for defense and the growth in
entitlements without higher taxes created a budget deficit that inarguably hurt
the economy. Government borrowing left less capital for private investment,
which meant that growth was lower and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> were worse off than
otherwise--for which we're paying the price <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> deserves
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s good times is limited to his sometimes equivocal support for free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>, and his reappointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>. (Under pressure from
free-lunch <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, he declined to reappoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcker</ENAMEX> again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chose Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>, who's been just as good, though under less challenging
circumstances.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
Reischauer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX> makes a more interesting nomination:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>. Though to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> his name is still synonymous with
betrayal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is a minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> for exactly the reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX>
consider him a major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>. By raising taxes significantly, the budget deal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> signed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> challenged the expansion of the deficit for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. The deal's spending caps and pay-as-you-go rules also brought
discipline to domestic spending. The same year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> fell on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> by
breaking his "read my lips" pledge, he impaled himself again by reappointing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was a
fierce enemy of inflation who wouldn't prime the pump before an election to
help the incumbent (though that didn't stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushies</ENAMEX> from prodding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>
to loosen up).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> deserves as much credit as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and arguably
more. He, too, rehired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, and has had more respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s
independence than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reluctantly</ENAMEX>, but less reluctantly than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> focused on the need for deficit reduction. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> economic plan,
which passed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> votes, included a tax increase that was
smaller in real terms than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> agreed to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, but was equally
significant as a harbinger of changed direction. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> economic program
directly benefited the economy, bringing down interest rates and boosting the
stock market to record highs. Like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> deal, it was also a genuine act of
self-sacrifice on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s part. Raising taxes probably cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> election and might easily have cost him
re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.

            With prodding from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich Congress</ENAMEX> (which also deserves some credit), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has remained
faithful to the cause of deficit reduction. He has also aided the economy in
less obvious ways. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>, has been a
tremendously reassuring figure to Wall Street. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s help, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
managed to forestall a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> financial collapse in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, which posed an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underappreciated</ENAMEX> threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy's recovery, then in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has supported the extension of free trade. Unlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, he was in a position to deliver <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NAFTA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> by getting
enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to go along--though one might argue that the
benefits of free trade are primarily long-term, and don't have much to do with
our current opulence.

            The economy could be still
better. Real wages continue to grow slowly. To increase wages significantly
without inflation would require a return to pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> levels of real growth,
which hasn't happened. Just the same, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy is the healthiest
it's been in a quarter-century. And for his contributions to it, the incumbent
deserves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> cheers.

         
      
   
