
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Collapse</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX>, just before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Press Office</ENAMEX> invites
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in for a spin session. In keeping with the current mood in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the message this time--conveyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">National Security Adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Raines</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Policy Adviser Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>--was about bipartisanship and cooperation. But after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour of</TIMEX>
anodyne sentiments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> more pugnacious
than the others, couldn't take it any more. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About a year ago</TIMEX> there was a
debate about whether there would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>," he said,
jumping up from his chair. "We have covered a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground</ENAMEX> here. When everyone
makes the point that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is somewhat conceding the agenda, the fact
is ... [the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>] have conceded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s priorities. In fact, it
is his initiatives that are the center of agreement."

            It is
amazing how much has changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX>. The chief theme in analyses of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was trying
to catch a ride on the unstoppable conservative freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>. But history
appears to have changed directions again. From the comfortable perch of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX>
percent approval rating, the highest of his presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spent most of
his speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> proposing a variety of new government programs. These
were not merely small-bore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>-era programs. Many were substantial and
costly efforts in the areas of education and health-care reform. And now, it's
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who are scrambling to get on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> and other gloating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonites</ENAMEX> contend that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> brought about this transformation by reclaiming the "vital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did indeed move deftly and systematically to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> all their
familiar means of portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> as being incorrigibly leftist and
outside the mainstream. By pushing a harsh anti-crime bill, proposing his own
version of a balanced budget, and signing a welfare reform package very
different from his own original notion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deprived <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of what
they expected to be their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> best issues. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> got done
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repositioning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> had very little left to run on.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s co-option is not the whole story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conservatism</ENAMEX> has collapsed. It has
been a cliché since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of ideas. But
today, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> generates--with seeming ease--popular and plausible
proposals, like expanding college opportunity and extending health insurance to
uncovered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are openly admitting that their party has no
clue what it is in favor of. "It is clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> are paralyzed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ennui</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is floundering," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Bennett</ENAMEX> in the most
recent issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> . "What is missing is a focused,
appealing, and philosophically coherent national agenda." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would expect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, after making such a statement, to propose such an agenda. But the
former drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>'s notion of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> should say resembles nothing
so much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s farrago of demitasse ideas from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bennett</ENAMEX>
suggests focusing on such "targets of opportunity" as missile defense and
opposition to racial set-asides and partial-birth abortion. These are
poll-driven wedge issues, which are likely to have little effect on the lives
of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and which surely don't constitute a philosophical program.

            
It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two years ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had
enough consistent doctrine for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Aquinas</ENAMEX>. What happened? Essentially,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> had an unpleasant encounter with reality. They took a few steps
in the direction of a coherent philosophical program and came back looking like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English Patient</ENAMEX>. Somehow, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> managed to unite all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for a dramatic attack on the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This attack was
never as broad as it was made out to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> rhetoric, but even so, it
scared the hell out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. An entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, and not just a faction
within it, was threatening to violate the national consensus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
role. Moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who barely held onto their seats in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, will not
sign on again any time soon for an attack on programs that are popular with the
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. Nor are they ready to mount an assault on environmental and
consumer regulations.

            So if
attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is out, what else can <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> do? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>,
and others would have them embrace social and cultural issues. But this plan is
even less promising than renewed attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>. Moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> were able to find
points of agreement with more authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> on issues like
cutting taxes, curtailing welfare, and balancing the budget. But there's less
room for compromise on the broader agenda of social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, which
includes issues like school prayer and abortion. With a slender majority,
divided <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can't easily move in any direction. Their only alternative
is to cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on issues of national consensus, which might
persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> they are worthy of continuing to share power with him.

            While they play along, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fantasize about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> scandal huge enough to overturn the existing political dynamic.
Hoping for a deus ex machina is also not a program, let alone a
philosophy.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> not only lack ideas--they also lack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> gets
back to the point where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> will allow him to be seen in public (he
actually appeared to be leaning outside the picture frame behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>), it's hard to imagine him leading a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> again. And
despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s many failings, there is no one else with imagination or
energy waiting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>. The designated respondent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX>, provided some novelty value for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX>. But though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasant</ENAMEX> and a polished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, he's an intellectual lightweight--and he's
certainly not a potential party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            
Who else do the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have? It is amusing
to watch the "strange new respect" phenomenon engulf <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> wake up to the fact that he is not the conservative
ideologue he appears. There's no telling how far the liberalizing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> might
go with enough positive reinforcement. His most recent gambit--criticizing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for proposing excessive cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> managed-care fees--was an
attempt to outflank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the left . It's clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> is not the
fellow to address the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s problem of intellectual bankruptcy.

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the challenge
of dominance is to act more responsibly and less politically. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is
in a strong enough position now to take his own rhetoric on reforming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entitlements</ENAMEX> (which he added to his address at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>) seriously, and
to drop leftover junk ideas from the campaign like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Victims Rights Amendment</ENAMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Now
it's time for him to start acting like one.

         
      
   
