
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxes Within Boxes</ENAMEX>

            
               Boxes
Within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxes</ENAMEX>
            

            Reader discussion forums
such as 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" are one of the advantages of publishing on the Web. But
they also create a weird <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">anomaly</ENAMEX>. On the one hand, the writings of professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and others who appear in 
                  Slate
                at our request, and
get paid for it, are put through an editorial process more or less like that of
a traditional paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, which can take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or more
from manuscript to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>." On the other hand, any stranger anywhere in
the world can have his or her words posted on our site instantaneously and with
no editing at all (except very occasionally after the fact).

            Faced with this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradiction</ENAMEX>, we decided not to start rigorous editing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>. It remains
a place where 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can speak out, unmolested by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meddlesome</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> wielding software programs such as Semicolon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Killer TM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shut Up Already 98</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows TM</ENAMEX> and
Antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">AutoPurge Pro TM</ENAMEX> (which automatically erases any turn of
phrase analyzed to agree with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>--about anything).

            Instead,
we have been experimenting cautiously with the opposite approach: giving a few
trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> the same freedom to publish in 
                  Slate
                that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> enjoy. Our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> "fraytech" feature was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>."
To be honest, this decision was based less on philosophical insight than on the
fact that none of us wanted to be up every weeknight at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> or so, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> files his copy.

            More recently, we've added "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>"
(political scuttlebutt and speculation) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culturebox</ENAMEX>" (insights
and musings about culture, high and low). Both these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> are updated
with new material <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times a week, very approximately, on no set
schedule and at no particular time of day or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s laptop to

                  Slate
               , nonstop.

            Now we are
adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more fraytech features. Or rather, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> established

                  Slate
                features are evolving in accord with the Web imperatives of
frequency and speed:

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fool</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> column on business and finance, becomes
"Moneybox"--still
written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, but shorter takes, more frequent, and more timely. We hope to
continue our happy relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Motley Fool</ENAMEX> shortly with a new
feature. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX> has left the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fool</ENAMEX> to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>," our weekly
background briefing on some issue in the news, will become "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX>." An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explainer</ENAMEX> is journospeak for an article that, um, explains things (he
explained). Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explainer</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, not the article) will be standing by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekday</TIMEX> to explain things the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and television and even news Web
sites leave unclear. It might be the historical background of some current news
story. It might be a straightforward rundown of the facts and arguments in a
controversy that has been clouded by strong passions and flying sound bites. Or
it might be a snappy summary of some issue that would be clear enough if you
actually read the entire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-part <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX> series, which
you're not about to do, because life is short. That's fine! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explainer</ENAMEX> will read
it for you.

            Explainer
is fully capable of finding news stories confusing or unclear without
assistance but also welcomes suggestions from puzzled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. E-mail explainer@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any time</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day or night</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Explanation</ENAMEX> begins around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10</TIMEX>.

            
               Now With
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extra Spin</ENAMEX>
            

            There's
also been a change in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>" that we hope you'll approve of. It now comes
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-essays</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> on the order of his
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" feature: shrewd analysis of how an issue is
being framed by the contending interests and who is winning the frame game.
These essays are accessible directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Contents</ENAMEX> page or from the
relevant item in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>.

            
               Free
Fiction
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reply All</ENAMEX>," our
experimental novel-by<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-e</ENAMEX>-mail written by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, moves outside the subscription wall for a while, beginning
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. In other words, you can get it free. You can also download all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>
existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Acrobat</ENAMEX> file.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have become embroiled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
affair, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> tries to subpoena a manuscript the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> e-mailers are
desperate to keep unpublished. Enjoy the story so far--on us. But you may have
to subscribe to find out whodunit.

            
               Hard
Covers
            

            
               The
Accidental <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> , by 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contributor Eric Liu</ENAMEX>, has been
published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>. A "personal and poignant defense of assimilation,
written in the tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates, Jr.</ENAMEX>," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BarnesandNoble</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> Web site (whatever tradition that might
be--apart from the one of books on ethnicity that sell a lot of copies, to
which we hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>'s book does indeed belong). For selfish reasons of our own
(i.e., we get a small cut), we prefer you order the book from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. But it's the same price at both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.10</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
percent off the list price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX>. You can read some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>'s writing in

                  Slate
                on ethnicity and other topics by clicking here.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Tupperware Party</ENAMEX>
            

            What are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> for? They
are for buying what you're selling, among other things. With that thought in
mind, 
                  Slate
                announces our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Referral Program</ENAMEX>: Persuade a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to
subscribe to 
                  Slate
               , and we'll extend your own subscription for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. Just e-mail the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>'s name and, if possible, e-mail
address, to refer@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Send as many names as you wish, as often as you
wish, and get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> additional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of 
                  Slate
                for each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. We
will check to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by these names have really
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subscribed</ENAMEX>--but we won't check on whether they're really your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>,
or if you really persuaded them to sign up. Click here for more details
and to read the fine print.

            Meanwhile, is that computer
you got your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>--hoping to bring the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>
Age, for heaven's sake--sitting mockingly dark and silent in the den, unused
and unloved? What that computer needs is a subscription to 
                  Slate
               .
You, meanwhile, need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web®TV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>, the box that turns your television into an
Internet terminal. Fortunately, 
                  Slate
                has a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX>
offer: Buy a Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV®Plus</ENAMEX> (a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$285</NUMEX> value), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> will be entered in a
sweepstakes to win a fabulous <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> subscription to 
                  Slate
               . No,
wait. That's wrong: Buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> the 
                  Slate
                subscription for
just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>, and you get entered into a drawing for a Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV®Plus</ENAMEX>.

            See official rules for
details. No purchase necessary. Some restrictions apply. (We've always wanted
to say that.)

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
