
   
   
      
         
            The Conintern

            Essential to the self-image
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> is the notion that they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of an established
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgents</ENAMEX> against the dogmatic political correctness that
predominates on the left. Some recent gleanings, however, suggest that the
opposite is true. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> where humorless thought police work to enforce a
rigid ideological discipline isn't made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. It comprises
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            A vision
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conintern</ENAMEX>, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, emerges from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> pieces, both by
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative journalists</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist Jr.</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>. It appeared in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> is a staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, turned the idea down. The article portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norquist</ENAMEX> as a buffoonish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissar</ENAMEX> who has misplaced his principles to the extent of accepting money to
lobby on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seychelles</ENAMEX>. In passing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norquist</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> meetings, where
conservative-movement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>, congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>,
and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who are deemed loyal, from places like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , gather to hash out what
can only be called the party line.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> article, which appears in the current issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , is by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Real Anita Hill and</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seduction</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham</ENAMEX> . Accompanied by a kinky photograph of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, tied to a stake with his chest bared, it describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> became
persona non grata on the right by writing too sympathetically about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>. Brock, strangely enough, acquiesces in the popular
misconception that his book was sympathetic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s
book was quite vicious about her, attacking her in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarthyite</ENAMEX> vein and
casting her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commie</ENAMEX> symp rather than a sleaze.

            But as a
glimpse into the world of conservative journalism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s article is
revealing. Brock portrays a political subculture in which loyalty to the cause
means everything, truth very little. He recalls being told by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> well-known
conservative to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> when he made trouble for the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cause by
inconveniently pointing out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Aldrich</ENAMEX>'s book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unlimited Access</ENAMEX> ,
was a crock. Before long, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> was being disinvited to conservative
conferences and parties and denounced by his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> as a turncoat.

            
This kind of treatment has no parallel among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. A few left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Hentoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Hitchens, have caught flak for dissenting from the conventional liberal
position on abortion. But there is no liberal "movement" like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
conservative movement, and no such thing as a liberal-movement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in
the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX> functioned as a conservative <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It is instructive to
compare what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brock</ENAMEX> with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> (formerly of the
New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> and The 
               New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ) was treated
by his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> when it was announced that he was joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> was attacked by fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal journalists</ENAMEX>
for having compromised his journalistic independence by being too kind to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. No conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> would ever be accused by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> of
being too close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, or to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who get
in trouble with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Phillips</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lind</ENAMEX>, who are accused of disloyalty to conservatism .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingraham</ENAMEX> is a legendarily on-the-make young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative pundit</ENAMEX>, who may need
to prove her independence to media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> more than her loyalty to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conintern</ENAMEX>. Ingraham was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brocked</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> when she wrote on the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, should step aside as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> campaign-finance investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, promptly denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ingraham</ENAMEX> as a "so-called conservative." At the
conservative gathering known as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark Ages Weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norquist</ENAMEX> asked her what
she was trying to accomplish by criticizing fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> in the
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingraham</ENAMEX> would have to choose, he said, "whether to be with us or
against us." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norquist</ENAMEX> also let it be known that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingraham</ENAMEX> would no longer be
welcome at those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> sessions.

            Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> don't just have the inside track
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> strategy--they help devise it. Consider, for instance, the many
roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Fund</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
editorial page. Fund has doubled as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisory Group</ENAMEX>, a
small cluster of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX> nearly
left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>.
After accepting the job initially, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX> changed his mind, perhaps because he is
more helpful where he is. (He declined comment.) Fund's denunciations of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> apostates have the flavor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>-era attacks on Trotskyite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heretics</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> argued in her syndicated
column that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> should step aside as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, an editorial promptly
appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> charging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffington</ENAMEX> with "intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exhibitionism</ENAMEX>." This tone is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s own. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> has been known to send
notes to errant conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> describing their work as
"strategically counterproductive."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ' editorial page, directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tod Lindberg</ENAMEX>, functions
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> piece shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norquist</ENAMEX> can secure an
editorial supporting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, no matter how obscure the subject. The paper
includes a few liberal points of view for window dressing, but hardly any
dissenting conservative ones. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> carries <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffington</ENAMEX>'s
syndicated column, she has been censored when she has tried to write critically
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. Again, the liberal equivalent of this--the New York
Times refusing to run criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>--is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unthinkable</ENAMEX>.

            
Nor is there any liberal equivalent to the way
various conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>--from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novak</ENAMEX>'s
syndicated column and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX>'s radio show--all disseminate the same
message du jour . Before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election, the conservative propaganda
line generally reflected poll-tested talking points on issues like taxes or
welfare reform. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> falters, however, the line seems to be less about
issues where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> disagree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and more about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
selling out fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A month ago</TIMEX>, the word emanating from all the
above-mentioned orifices was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> was betraying his
party by co-sponsoring a health-care reform bill with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>,
it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, has allowed himself to
become a tool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> by opposing the renewal of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Favored</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Nation</ENAMEX> status for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. These attempts to stamp out free thinking suggest what
is really going on inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>: an effort to submerge the battle of
ideas.

            Of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">main Conintern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, the least reliable in its political coverage is the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , which regularly launches fusillades against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, almost always for departing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Faith</ENAMEX>. (For a
related article on conservative cultural correctness, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">But Is It Art</ENAMEX>
Criticism?" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> in this issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kristol</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, recognizes such attacks for the great publicity
stunts they are. But even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , it seems, has its limits.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podhoretz</ENAMEX> turned down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norquist</ENAMEX> proposal because he didn't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to be seen as carrying on
a vendetta against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. It's seen that way just the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norquist</ENAMEX> has
been spreading the word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, must
stop funding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> says he has had calls from the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politburo</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ledeen</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, who told him, "No one who believes what we believe should be attacking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover</ENAMEX>."

            Much of this kind of behavior can be traced back to what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Hofstadter</ENAMEX> famously described as the "paranoid style" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Right. Conspiratorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have a tendency toward what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hofstadter</ENAMEX>
called "the imitation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>." Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> wore the vestments
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> they despised, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Birch Society</ENAMEX> organized itself in
secret cells and front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> modeled on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>. Contemporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> believe that the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society
are part of a liberal conspiracy. They feel this gives them license to create
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterinstitutions</ENAMEX>, from magazines to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX>. But these
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>--are part of an ideological mission in a way that "liberal"
ones--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX>--are not.

            Exaggerated and crude claims
of liberal bias have become an excuse for poor journalistic standards, and for
shoddy intellectual ones as well. But the worst of it isn't the propaganda that
passes for conservative thought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. It's the deadly sense of enforced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conformity</ENAMEX>, the stale air that blows in from the stagnant ponds of the
Right.

         
      
   
