
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Home Delivery</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Home Delivery</ENAMEX>
            

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to go directly to

                  Slate
                Home Delivery instructions.)

            Imagine this: You wake up,
stumble out of bed, pour a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, and go to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>. There, fresh
and warm, are 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," a few of your other
favorite 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>, maybe even a non-
                  Slate
               
item or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> such as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that morning</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> news digest. No need
to boot up or log on. No need to read onscreen or wait for a printout. Why,
there's no need even to go outside and collect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. True home
delivery-- inside your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Sound good?

            It
occurred to us a while ago: Why can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leave their computers and their
printers on overnight, or whenever, and have their printouts waiting for them,
rather than vice versa? There are "push" technologies, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PointCast</ENAMEX> and
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>, which will download Web pages
automatically. But none of them takes the next step of printing the pages out.
Why not? Could it be that computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX> don't appreciate the widespread
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aversion</ENAMEX> to reading things on a screen? Whatever the reason, how hard would it
be to offer this service to 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>?

            As we do with all deep philosophical questions, we took
this one to the nearest software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX>, who happened to be

                  Slate
               's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Computer Guy Andrew Shuman</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX> gave his
usual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part answer: a) Very easy. No problem at all. b) Very difficult.
Would require many a moon. Need new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, much wampum. Accused of
self-contradiction, he sniffed: "To you it's a contradiction. To me it's a
paradox. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't tell the difference." And he added, "If you think
it's so easy, why don't you do it yourself?"

            So we did.
The process gave us new respect for software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>. We deeply regret any
harsh or impatient words we may have uttered to them (or even behind their
backs). Nevertheless, we have a solution. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuman</ENAMEX> wishes it known that this is
not an official 
                  Slate
                service, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> wishes it known
that we cannot supply support or advice on it. It's just a whimsy of

                  Slate
               's journalistic element. It hasn't been tested. It doesn't
work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and may not work on any configuration of equipment and services
other than those on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s home machine. Nevertheless, we think it's
pretty cool.

            
It's actually just an adaptation of some
software from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP Web PrintSmart</ENAMEX>. You can download the software free from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP</ENAMEX>'s Web site. (Although the site
implies the software is intended only for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP</ENAMEX> printers, it actually plays well
with others.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PrintSmart</ENAMEX> has various features, and you're welcome to piss away
as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">many hours</TIMEX> horsing around with it as we have. But for our purposes, it does
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things. First, at a time and frequency you determine (just once, once a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekday</TIMEX>), it dials your Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> (if
necessary), makes a connection, downloads the Web pages you have selected,
closes the connection, and hangs up. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it very cleverly reformats the
pages to look good and save paper when printed out. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, it does print them
out.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PrintSmart</ENAMEX> can be customized for 
                  Slate
                fairly easily. You can
instruct the program to search in various ways for pages linked to other pages.
By setting these parameters correctly, you can schedule an overnight printout
of any combination of 
                  Slate
                articles or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> you wish.
(You can add other Web sites, too.) And in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, if you wish, you can go
to a checklist of 
                  Slate
                pages, preview them, and choose other
articles to print out--all without dialing in again.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PrintSmart</ENAMEX> has some flaws, and for our purposes it's more
complicated than it ought to be. 
                  Slate
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP</ENAMEX> both have ambitions
for a simpler process, and you can expect to see some developments over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next few months</TIMEX>.

            We also should mention a
rival product put out by another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Canon</ENAMEX>. Called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WebRecord</ENAMEX>, it
has some advantages over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PrintSmart</ENAMEX>. For example, it formats printouts for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> columns a page, thus saving even more paper. But it doesn't have a
search mechanism, it doesn't have a scheduler--and it costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>. Nevertheless,
if you're into printing out, it's worth
investigating.

            For instructions on setting
up 
                  Slate
                Home Delivery using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP PrintSmart</ENAMEX>, .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
