
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reading Safire</ENAMEX>'s Mind 

            
               It's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> of
frustration, but I think I've finally got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> by the short and curlies. It's
a tangled Web that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">POTUS</ENAMEX> has been weaving around his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>. Now his
spin has spun out of control. What everybody thinks, and nobody can print, is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> got his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> to pony up, lest a pinched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> feel
the urge to sing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. No evidence, but no matter. I'll read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s mind
and baptize the story "hushgate." Who knows what didn't happen? If I'm guessing
right, there's another <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> in it for me. If not, bygones will soon go
bye-bye, and I'll still make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibi</ENAMEX>'s day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been squeezing the
settlements a bit too hard lately.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> might complain that this attempt at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> into his thinking is
grotesquely unjust. After all, I don't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> recognizes the
unfairness of the accusations he flings around with such abandon in his column.
I can't prove that he is motivated by the quest for fame and power rather than
the desire to get at the truth. I don't even truly believe that he sticks up
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud Party</ENAMEX> out of personal loyalty to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
rather than genuine conviction. But I could pass off all that malicious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">innuendo</ENAMEX> as fact, and still remain within the boundaries <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Safire</ENAMEX> sets for
himself in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice-weekly</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Essay"</ENAMEX> column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

            The least defensible of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s columns are his
intermittent efforts at "Reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's Mind</ENAMEX>." In the latest of these, which
appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> projected a view inside the criminal consciousness of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "Just when I should feel terrific about my
economic boom making possible my budget deal, I can feel the damn prosecutors
closing in," the column began. "My main vulnerability, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Kendall</ENAMEX> tells me,
is arranging for that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half million</NUMEX> in hush money to Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>." Even for
Safire, the passage, and the column, were extraordinary. Under cover of his
favorite literary device--temporarily being someone else--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> was accusing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of active involvement in an effort to obstruct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>--an
impeachable, indictable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>.

            This
charge couldn't have appeared anywhere else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . Absent some
kind of evidence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> on the national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who have been covering
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals can only say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are exploring the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might have had some
role in arranging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s post-employment benefits package. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX>'s
fellow opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> wouldn't dare leap to his conclusion. They might
argue, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX> did in an unusually good column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire's</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s version of events doesn't add up, and that there are
strong grounds for suspicion about the serendipitous help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> got. But
accusing someone, even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, of a crime without evidence crosses a
divide that is usually observed even in op-ed land--the line separating
plausible opinion from pure speculation.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> gets away with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sliming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">artfully</ENAMEX> exploiting his status as hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>, and other traditional op-ed page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> does
actual--and sometimes extensive--reporting. He has even been known to
use-- how shall we say it? --strong incentives to encourage highly placed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to leak to him. What he writes carries the implication that he knows,
thanks to his inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tipsters</ENAMEX>, that which will soon come to light. But, with
increasing frequency, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> has been abusing the privileges he grants
himself.

            Let's look closely at the
rest of that mind-reading column: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Easy to</ENAMEX> say now that the cover-up is always
worse than the crime," the interior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton/Safire</ENAMEX> monologue continues. "But
what were we going to do in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>? Let Web twist in the wind? Abandon him to
that sumbitch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, until he started talking about our use of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">father-in-law</ENAMEX> as a front, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> files in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>, about what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX> had been working on?

            "We
bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three solid years</TIMEX>, and a re-election, by getting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to take
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care of Web</ENAMEX>."

            The welter of innuendo here is so thick that one can hardly
peer through it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> is saying that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had committed a variety
of crimes that would, if they had been brought to light, have prevented his
re-election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>, he suggests, knew about all of them, and so had to be
kept quiet with bribes. But what crimes might <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> have kept to himself?
Only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> will have any idea in this paragraph. But those who
follow this stuff should recognize that, like the theory <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> arranged hush
money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s hints about what got hushed up are pure conjecture.
Later in the column, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> does some more thinking on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>:
"My stonewalling just has to work past the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX> elections. Then I can finish out
my term and pardon everybody including me on the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>'s inauguration."

            
The key to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s deeper purpose is his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuous</ENAMEX> use of terms like "cover-up," "stonewall," "hush money," "twist in
the wind," "hang tough," and "pardon." This is the lingo of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, an event
that remains at the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s consciousness. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> speechwriter
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1969 until 1973</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> managed to avoid being dragged into the scandal
that ruined the careers of almost everyone he worked with. But after he joined
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> took it as his mission to exculpate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and
his henchmen. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> story was still breaking, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> focused on
dirty tricks by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>, to try to demonstrate that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had done was
no worse than what previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> had done. In fact, he has been trying,
ever since, to prove that "they all do it."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> were represented in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Safire</ENAMEX>'s column by a series of associative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wordplays</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billygate</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waterquiddick</ENAMEX>," "peanutgate," "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Koreagate</ENAMEX>," and--most
significantly--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lancegate</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> won a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> for helping to force
the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert Lance</ENAMEX> in a scandal no one much
remembers. In his excellent book <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Memory</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Schudson well describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s efforts to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Watergateize</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> scandals. The interesting point that emerged subsequently
was that the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> wasn't just using the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> comparison to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bash</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. He was--and, weirdly enough, still is--writing principally as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> apologist aiming to trivialize <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> itself.

            Though he is a graceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and
has a sharp mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> is hitting with a corked bat. No one should be angrier
about this than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Labaton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> who have patiently pursued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals in a careful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s journalistic cheating undermines their professional work. Back
during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> a "congenital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>,"
his hyperbole overshadowed the fibs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> was accused of
telling. The weight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is such that unfairness anywhere in the
paper casts a shadow over legitimate stories that appear elsewhere.

            
               I know, I know. But the
old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s been at it going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>. Can't ask him to learn a new
trick.
            

         
      
   
