
   
   
      
         
            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is the Summer of Too Much Content</ENAMEX>

            
               Now Is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Much Content</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX> complains
implausibly that the press doesn't pay enough attention to itself. The enormous
attention devoted to the premiere of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of press criticism,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> , somewhat undermines the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s founding premise.
That subtlety shouldn't cause him too much distress, because the press's
fascination with itself is a bonanza for its self-proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX>. Do not
look for articles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brill</ENAMEX>'s Content exposing how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were
enslaved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX> (like the article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> issue exposing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s alleged enslavement by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>). No, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX>, he has
every reason to be.

            Far be it
from 
                  Slate
               , of course, to complain about a ludicrous excess of
publicity attending the arrival of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. We've been there too. And
we're embarrassed to say that the current issue of 
                  Slate
                does
nothing to alleviate the symptoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill Overkill</ENAMEX>. Brill, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX>, and the
contents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s Content have been at least touched upon during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few days</TIMEX> in the following 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"In Other Magazines"</ENAMEX> (of course), "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> ," "Pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX>," "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedfellow</ENAMEX>." Oh--and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Readme</ENAMEX>." Every aspect of the phenomenon has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summarized</ENAMEX>, analyzed, criticized. We feel this has been a useful trial run for
future 
                  Slate
                coverage of the outbreak of a major war.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brillorama</ENAMEX> is not
wildly consistent. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> of breaking the basic rules of journalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> accuses
him of cleverly obeying those rules while offending journalistic ethical values
all the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> disagree about whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s central
failure is boredom or sanctimoniousness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s big scoop is no big deal, while
around her we analyze it in detail (scroll past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brooks</ENAMEX>' posting to read
hers).

            Still, the
overall "take" of all our coverage is fairly negative. That is not intentional.
Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>'s Content will devote a future article to explaining why
it so often just seems to turn out that way. We have nothing against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
Content . In fact, we wish it well. And no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> should be judged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irrevocably</ENAMEX> based on its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue. Basically--let's be blunt--we'll do or
say whatever it takes to be on good terms with journalism's growliest attack
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. ( Good doggie! Down, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie wanna</ENAMEX> biscuit? ) And if it means
having all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who criticize him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> killed--why, consider it
done. It's just a small gesture from 
                  Slate
                to help the world's
leading press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> do his job of ensuring the highest standards of honesty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuracy</ENAMEX>, and freedom of thought in the press.

            
The truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s reputation as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">attack dog</ENAMEX>--cherished above all by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> himself--is not completely deserved.
At his previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lawyer</ENAMEX> , he more or less invented a
genre of article that might be called the puff piece in the form of a hatchet
job. A typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lawyer</ENAMEX> article might reveal that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Attorney X</ENAMEX> is a
mean, nasty, unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a bitch who'll do anything to win a case.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX>'s business would soar, as would his self-esteem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> 's famous exposés of top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' salaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s indignant
editorials about overlavish summer intern programs (accompanying complex charts
that compared the number of opera tickets and restaurant dinners offered by
various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>) ... all had the natural effect of increasing the excesses he
complained about.

            Overall, by the very
attention it devotes--the breathless prose, the endlessness of the articles,
the huge photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in suits standing in front of shelves of
books-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lawyer</ENAMEX> has made the law seem more important and even
glamorized it. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> will do the same for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> (where
we already suspect we might be glamorous). He will flatter us by the very
standards he accuses us of failing to meet, by turning our peccadilloes into
moral crises, by the very gloss on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> that's all about us, and
above all by giving us an excuse once a month to write about ourselves.

            So good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, and let us know if there's anything we can do. Some software,
perhaps? Fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX>? Straight cash? Nothing's too good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who's
gonna make us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> take a long look in the mirror.

            
               Behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enemy Lines</ENAMEX>
            

            Starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millionerds"</ENAMEX> column will join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>,
and other 
                  Slate
                features that post constantly but irregularly,
whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>(s) are struck with an insight or acquire a nice tidbit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">info</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> will be filing from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to three</NUMEX> times a week.
Check it out.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
