
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nefarious Plots</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nefarious Plots</ENAMEX>
            

            As 
                  Slate
               's
"Pundit
Central" points out, the consensus view of the commentariat is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is to be blamed for selling burial rights at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>
Cemetery to campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>--even though it turns out he never did
it--because it's just the sort of thing he might have done. Or not quite:
There's a perception , well founded or otherwise, that this is the sort
of thing he might do.

            Here is an important new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> press corps' perceptions game. Often in the past,
when chasing some alleged miscreant, the press has brushed aside the question
of what exactly is wrong with the explanation that the situation creates the
perception of impropriety. We thereby avoid the tiresome issue of whether
anything improper actually has occurred. (The trick works both ways: Actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miscreants</ENAMEX> confess to having created an appearance of impropriety, thus
sidestepping the little matter of impropriety itself.) Since the press itself
largely creates the perception with its coverage, justifying the coverage on
the basis of the perception is a convenient form of circular reasoning.

            Never before, though (to our
knowledge), has a public figure been found guilty of committing a perception
when the perception is demonstrably untrue. Until now there had to be at least
a possibility that the perception of impropriety might some day molt into hard
evidence of actual impropriety. In this case, that possibility doesn't exist.
Undoubtedly there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who will continue to insist, against all evidence,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sold entry to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>. But those who take the
isn't-this-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just</NUMEX>-typical line are doing so precisely because, although they
think it's typical, they accept that it isn't true. Apparently that doesn't
matter anymore--as long as it's typical, or arguably typical. So boo to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, no need to apologize, and no need to worry about being the conduit for
any faintly plausible bit of poison his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> may be dispensing.

            Like all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, we at

                  Slate
                have longed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when "might be true" is accepted as
the standard for our trade. Never in our most idealistic moments did we dare
hope for a standard of "might be true--even though it isn't." Like a starving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> standing before the bounty of ... oh, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> cafeteria (check
out the vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stir-fry</ENAMEX>), we hardly know where to begin (don't miss those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice Krispies</ENAMEX> squares!).

            Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sold the
national monuments! (Q: Who is buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant's Tomb</ENAMEX>? A: If you have to ask,
you can't afford it.) Could be true. After all, it would be typical of someone
who sold <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arlington Cemetery plots</ENAMEX>, which, though he may not have done it, is
nevertheless typical of the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who'd kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Foster</ENAMEX>, which he
didn't do either--but that doesn't matter because he's the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who does
the kind of thing that gets you accused of doing that kind of thing.

            Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> actually
poisoned his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. After all, he divorced her on her deathbed--or
something like that. We don't remember the details, exactly, but they certainly
created the perception that he did something like that, and anyone who could be
perceived to do something like that has created an atmosphere that makes
possible the perception that he could do something worse. So he has no one to
blame but himself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, this
is going to be fun.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> of
All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> reported some preliminary results from a poll it has been conducting
on its Internet site about
whom it should pick for its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>." An impressive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 million</NUMEX>
votes have been cast since the poll went up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. But bizarrely, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7 million</NUMEX>
of those votes were for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kemal Atat√ºrk.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atat√ºrk</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, which is no mean accomplishment (what have you done with your life?),
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> understandably suspect ballot-stuffing.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's mistake, we
think, was its stinting view of history. If you're going in for shameless
promotional gimmicks, why limit yourself to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>? 
                  Slate
               
hereby announces its intention to mark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> by anointing a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemal Atat√</ENAMEX>ºrk need not apply. In fact, although all other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> are welcome, 
                  Slate
               's software-development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--through
a simple iterative program--has already cast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8 million</NUMEX> votes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>.
(Could there be any other real answer?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> was a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, in honor
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> 
                  Slate
                has published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week</TIMEX>'s issue as of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 26</TIMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days early</TIMEX>. Our "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers"</ENAMEX> column will be
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> (but not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving Day</TIMEX>). Our normal schedule will resume on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
