
   
   
      
         
            Battered-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Syndrome</ENAMEX>

            Back when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> were conservative on the subject of child
abuse. That is, they were in favor of it. "We all got the belt <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> wrote in his autobiography, describing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s preferred form of
punishment. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> could always be counted upon to
defend the educational advantages of a good lashing, whether in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bina</ENAMEX>,
who acquainted her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with the salubrious effects of the strap on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, a sound whipping always meant good
values.

            Those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, it appears, are gone. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sling Blade</ENAMEX> --films
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> damaged by their abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>--nominated for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Picture</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss</ENAMEX> moving up the best-seller list,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> want to tell you: We were abused too. As adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alcoholics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of deadbeat dads, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> to battered-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> syndrome, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of every sort of paddling and walloping and thwacking, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
no longer ceding ground to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> when it comes to feeling the pain of a
dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.

            The latest example of this weird phenomenon is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-right-wing representative</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> who is set to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising practices. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX> fetish whose <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hypochondria</ENAMEX> prevents him from eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.) In a profile in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX>
recounted the story he has told before--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People</ENAMEX> , among other
places--of how his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-foot-8-inch</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">280-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, used to pummel the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Burton</ENAMEX> hit his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> for getting up to go to the bathroom
in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and hit him for wetting his bed if he didn't get up
to go. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> was an infant, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> beat him black and blue for crying
in a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. After his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> tried to leave him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Burton</ENAMEX> abducted
her. Charged with kidnapping, he was convicted and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.
When he got out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and came around to where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lived, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 14</TIMEX>, faced him down with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Burton</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> raised the subject of his experiences to underscore his support for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> to aid battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. Now he is deploying his pain in a legislatively
less specific way, to try to show that he is not the reactionary bogeyman most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think he is. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> doesn't wish to indicate any lack of sympathy for what
sounds like a truly wretched and brutal childhood. But if we are to draw a
lesson from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s story, it is not that he is a sympathetic and caring man
because of his experiences, but rather that he is working out an inherited
disposition to abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on a more ambitious level. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> who
advocated using nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. He doesn't
beat his own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--he just wants to kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>, is not the kind
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who wears his heart on his sleeve, so it came as something of a shock
when, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks ago</TIMEX>, he revealed his own wretched childhood to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a shipyard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in
Pascagoula, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, was an alcoholic who died in a drunken-driving accident in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. "That sort of problem does affect you. You are forced into problems
between your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. It makes you grow up maybe a little
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> said. But he added that his wasn't a dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. "After
I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 years old</TIMEX>, I don't think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> ever laid a hand on me."

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> must be satisfied with one abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
According to various profiles, his natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton McPherson</ENAMEX>, stayed out
late at the pool <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> soon after marrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> tried to wake him the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">next morning</TIMEX> to go to work, he
slugged her. The next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> she married, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Gingrich</ENAMEX>, was not physically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abusive</ENAMEX>, but he was cold and uncommunicative toward his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepchildren</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> has
compared him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Santini</ENAMEX>, the inflexible military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conroy</ENAMEX>'s novel. "It was a sort of classic broken home," he has said. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>,
age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>, married his high-school math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> against his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stepfather</ENAMEX>'s wishes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Gingrich</ENAMEX> not only refused to come to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX>, he wouldn't let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> attend, either.

            Moving to the back benches, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> finds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Nussle</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, dealing with his anger over an absent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. "I have a deadbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> I have never met," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nussle</ENAMEX> said on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
floor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, arguing for a provision to compel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to get tougher on
child-support collection or risk losing federal aid. "I don't want to have
anybody else go through it." On his side in support of the measure was another
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ensign</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, who told of his own father
abandoning his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensign</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to support <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by
working as a "change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>" in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>.

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> start talking about being neglected and abused, you can bet that
they're about to violate some sacrosanct conservative principle like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>'
rights or the need to shrink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "I'm a conservative," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nussle</ENAMEX> said,
apropos of the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support enforcement, "and when I hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' rights, I say, 'Hold it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, there is a duty here for the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> used the same phraseology when explaining his
willingness to intervene against domestic violence, despite the otherwise
highly constricted role he sees for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "I'm not advocating
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Brother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> trying to solve the problem," he
said. "But I'm not saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shouldn't have a role in trying to
get the job done." The exceptions to conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX> that these
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> carve out are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>-specific, narrowly tailored to their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">miseries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> is anti-abuse, but doesn't fret about missed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support
payments. Nussle, by contrast, wants to punish deadbeat dads, but not abusive
ones; he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Parental Rights and Responsibilities Act</ENAMEX>, which
says it's fine to smack the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> (the phrase used is "reasonable corporal
discipline").

            
These little contradictions aside, one wonders
why stodgy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caucasian Republicans</ENAMEX> are playing the victimology card at all. The
basic explanation: the powerful lure of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Kaminer</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recovery</ENAMEX>
Movement. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> didn't boast about being abused. They all
sounded like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
ran a TV ad in which he folksily asserted, "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> never had to whip me twice
for the same thing." By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> about how he
stood up to that same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> for slapping his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> around. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, a little
behind in the game, are trying to say, "We feel your pain too." They're finally
cottoning on to the political value of the confessional culture. With their
party intellectually adrift, the appeal of this style of content-free,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>-fied populism continues to grow for them.

            Or maybe there's a simpler
explanation. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> need professional help, but are afraid to be seen near
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Pouring their hearts out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> is the only
therapy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> can get.

         
      
   
