
   
   
      
         
            We Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like Your Altitude</ENAMEX>

            
               We Don't
Like Your Altitude
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of our goals at

                  Slate
                is to provide what we call "intelligent synthesis" of the
news of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. Through features such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" (see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s analysis of the dismissal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit), we
hope to provide a deeper understanding than a conventional news summary would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enable</ENAMEX>, but without the time-wasting encrustation of quotations and anecdotes
that clogs the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> story.

            We like to think that in our
small way, we're having some influence on the conventional media, too. For
example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX>, the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times ran this
headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plane's Altitude Blamed in Crash That Killed 33</ENAMEX>." There, in
remarkably few words, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> gets to the essence of a complicated
story. Altitude problems caused the crash! What more, after all, does one need
to know? Pedants may quibble that the problem was, more precisely, a lack of
altitude, but that is a small point. The larger conceptual breakthrough is the
Times ' discovery of the single factor--altitude, or the lack
thereof--that can explain all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crashes past and future. Solve the altitude
problem, and no one need fear boarding an airplane ever again.

            We who
write headlines as part of our jobs are used to being underappreciated for the
contribution we make to human betterment. We are ordinarily happy to labor in
anonymity: No one ever gets a byline for a headline, however brilliant. But
this is a special case. Some toiler on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> copy desk has completed
the great work begun by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright Brothers</ENAMEX>. They lifted humankind up; he or
she has figured out how to keep us there. It all depends on having the right
altitude. Surely a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> is called for, if not a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>.

            
               More for
Your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>
            

            We'll be
trying a few new editorial features <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. Watch out for them:

            As announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">International Papers</ENAMEX>" is now attached to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> e-mail
deliveries of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>." And starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX>, your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> will include our fruitcake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> talk shows, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>." To sign up (or to sign up again if you
were cut off during the sign-up process), click here.

            We invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude</ENAMEX>
Himmelfarb, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, to exchange e-mail for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> about whatever struck them as interesting in the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himmelfarb</ENAMEX> (who is married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Kristol</ENAMEX>, the neoconservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>)
tortured us by saying it sounded like a good conversation over the breakfast
table--which is just what we have in mind--but that she'd rather keep her own
views to her own breakfast table. Damn. But that did give us a name for this
experimental dialogue--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Breakfast Table"</ENAMEX>--and we did line up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnist Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>, who is no mean consolation prize, to share
cyberkrispies with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sullivan</ENAMEX> starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, April 8</TIMEX>. And we hope neither
the vigorously conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Himmelfarb</ENAMEX> nor the vigorously left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollitt</ENAMEX> is
offended at the notion that they are what used to be called "moral
equivalents."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," our frequently
updated column of gossip, speculation, scuttlebutt, and philosophical
reflection on politics, has been so popular that we're initiating "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>,"
a similar feature on, well, culture. We define culture broadly to include
almost anything except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, who is adequately covered, we hope, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
