
   
   
      
         
            JFK TKO

            It's hard to remember a book
that has benefited from as much bad publicity as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Dark</ENAMEX>
Side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A month</TIMEX> before it was published, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
ran a lengthy front-page account of how its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> had fallen for a set of
forged papers that supposedly detailed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> hush-money payment from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys to Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>. Subsequent stories in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> slammed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> for his gullibility in being seduced by
these documents (which are not mentioned in his book). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>
story, by rival investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Sam Anson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flayed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX> as a
greedy journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> who blackmails <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.

            Since the
book came out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the press has greeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s
sexual excess, his various connections to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, and other sometimes
hyperbolic charges with exaggerated derision. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> tries to have it both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> with a cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that says, "DEBUNKING JFK: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX> takes on
Camelot, but how believable is his new book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The inside story, like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , attacks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> for repeating old hat charges, and for producing
a farrago of implausible fantasies. On the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hersh</ENAMEX> endured a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> grilling that seemed like payback for the time and money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> had wasted
on a documentary it abandoned because of suspicions about the forged papers.
"Do you think you were blinded by the desire to tell a sordid tale<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" was the
kind of question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Lauer</ENAMEX> asked him. The most bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are those whom
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> must hesitate, in light of current knowledge, to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy Mafia</ENAMEX>.
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> and acolytes like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Sorensen</ENAMEX>
have lumped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>, taking the line that the book is paranoid
speculation. Sorensen, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX> portrays as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> toady, has been
especially nasty in denouncing it as "a pathetic collection of wild
stories."

            It comes as something of a surprise, then, to read The
Dark <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Side of Camelot</ENAMEX> and find that it is not a trashy conspiracy screed at
all. Investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are often difficult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX>, who is one
of the best, sounds less pleasant than most. His book, however, is not merely a
great read. Much of what's in it is also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) new; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) shocking; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) well
supported; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) worth knowing.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> flame keepers would have you believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX> passes off malicious
gossip as historical fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>-style. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> does hyperventilate from
time to time, but he still manages to present his case in roughly the way a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> should. He includes enough contrary
evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can disagree with his conclusions without doing their own
research elsewhere. Take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his bombshells, the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s secret
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> marriage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> married a divorcee named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durie Malcolm</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Beach</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> and that the marriage lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 15 minutes</TIMEX>. His chief
witness is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Spalding</ENAMEX>, a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s, who says he was asked to
remove the wedding documents from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Beach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> acknowledges
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spalding</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">79</TIMEX>, suffers from short-term memory impairment, and that he
couldn't find family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to confirm the story, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indirectly</ENAMEX> denies. While he buys it himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> doesn't portray his evidence
as better than it really is.

            
The same goes for his fascinating scoop about a
break-in at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Exner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1962</TIMEX>. Exner, who was
at various times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Giancana</ENAMEX>, was under heavy surveillance by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> because of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> ties.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files obtained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> monitoring her home saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> break in via the fire escape. Tracing the license <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plates</ENAMEX>, they determined
that the burglars were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.B. Hale</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> special agent
who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of security for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics Corp.</ENAMEX> Hersh links this to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s pursuit--and otherwise inexplicable award, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months later</TIMEX>--of a
contract to build a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5-billion</NUMEX> jet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>. He thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX>
blackmailed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> into giving it the contract. Once again, though, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">readily</ENAMEX> admits that his evidence falls short of proof. "During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the five years</TIMEX>
of research for this book, I tried unsuccessfully to find out how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamics</ENAMEX> learned of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Exner</ENAMEX>'s ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX>," he writes. "I was
unable to make contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy or Bobby Hale</ENAMEX> despite repeated efforts."

            I won't
bore you again about the skinny-dipping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and on the road, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s range of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">venereal diseases</ENAMEX>, his affair with a
suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>, or his narrow escape from being drawn into the
Profumo scandal. The approved journalistic technique is to retail all these
prurient nuggets while appearing to hold your nose. The press treats these
eye-popping revelations as if curiosity about them, rather than the deeds
themselves, were something to be ashamed of. Even if true, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> suggest,
such information is not historically "relevant." But it is obviously relevant
to any real understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> does not argue this point very well. In
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Imprisonment</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX> did a much better job of
connecting the family attitudes toward sexual conquest, the pursuit of power,
and the conduct of foreign policy. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> supplies the raw material that
substantiates that case as never before.

            The book has plenty of flaws. Of these, some of the most
telling are failures to square minor inconsistencies. For instance, Hersh
relates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> anecdote about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> having to prevent the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> from finding out for herself what she suspected was going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> swimming pool. Later in the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strenuous</ENAMEX> efforts to avoid catching <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">JFK</ENAMEX> in action. Another example is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s
failure to harmonize his various stories of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Kennedy Sr.</ENAMEX> helped steal
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> election for his son by paying off Giancana to help deliver the union
vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. When it comes to major foreign-policy events--the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Crisis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cuban Missile Crisis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hersh</ENAMEX> is out of his
depth. There is more to these episodes than his monochromatic tales of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> willing to take any risk, tell any falsehood, for the sake of
political advantage.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> is much better on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> in which the press protected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>. Trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> were at his beck
and call, ready to advise on policy and bury indiscretions. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> letter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy Library</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Bradlee</ENAMEX>--then of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and
later the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> not to pick the
unmannered rube <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> as his running mate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX> also helped out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> needed to put rumors about his secret marriage to rest. In cases where
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> wouldn't play ball, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX> could easily pick up the phone and
get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to kill a story. Of course, the press no longer plays this role on
behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. But something of the old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamic</ENAMEX> may persist in the hostile reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sy Hersh</ENAMEX>'s book.

         
      
   
