
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Evasion</ENAMEX>

            Kicking
off the fall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>-bashing was a report on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. It featured the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie Johnson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, insurance
executive who described his nightmarish battle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in this way:

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> came in my office <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX>. ... He said, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, you have to
realize that the only good advertising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> gets is
when they bring a big one down. And your name is a household word to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." I said, "Do you mean to tell me you can take me to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of law
and convict me of some wrongdoing on the basis of what you had?" He said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>,
I don't believe I can do that." He said, "I can get your name in the paper.
That's what I'm after."

            Now an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> might have said these things, but I doubt
it. Even power-drunk bullies tend not to declare their own maliciousness. Nor
does the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s account of his own actions ring true. Why would a powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman succumb</ENAMEX> to extortion, plead guilty to a criminal charge of tax
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evasion</ENAMEX>, and pay a fine he did not owe? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> also claims that he agreed to
plead guilty on the condition that his identity be kept secret. But criminal
charges can't be filed in secret. And if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> told him it was only
interested in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> score, why would it then make a promise of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confidentiality</ENAMEX>, and why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">would Johnson</ENAMEX> believe it? On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> ,
however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s version was presented as indisputable fact. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Kroft</ENAMEX>, stated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> had declined requests for an interview.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kroft</ENAMEX> did not explain is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> was not allowed to respond. To do so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> would need a
waiver from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> giving it permission to discuss his case. According to a
producer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> did not request a waiver. Nor did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> explain that
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11-million</NUMEX> judgment <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> won against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>--subsequently reversed on
appeal--was based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s disclosure of confidential information without
such a waiver. (The program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deceptively</ENAMEX> implied that the judgment was based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrongful</ENAMEX> prosecution.) I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> whether his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> would be
willing to grant a waiver so that I could hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s side of the story as
well. No way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> said.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">lopsided 60 Minutes</ENAMEX> report was but one episode in a wide-ranging
suspension of skepticism about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> misdeeds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX>,
which fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> its story, followed with hearings that were more show trial than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oversight</ENAMEX> investigation. Disgruntled current and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> testified
anonymously from behind a screen. There was no real effort to ascertain their
motives or the truth of the generalizations they offered. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
seeking a quick populist fix have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several weeks</TIMEX> vilifying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, sensing a
political hazard, have piled on with their own expressions of outrage and calls
for reform. But is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> really a rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>? Consider the weakness of the
main charges.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> commonly abuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> heard testimony from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were culled,
according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1,500</NUMEX> who have contacted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. There is no way of knowing how many of them have legitimate gripes.
But even if all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> were genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, it would not remotely approach the
kind of systematic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sadism</ENAMEX> alleged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Roth Jr.</ENAMEX> and his
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 200 million</NUMEX> tax returns filed each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and collection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who audit
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2 million</NUMEX> of them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen hundred</NUMEX> abject failures would mean an error
rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.00075 percent</NUMEX>. And that's not even per year--it's per ever.

            It's also
worth noting that the bipartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrey</ENAMEX>-Portman <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> commission recently
concluded that there was no systematic abuse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> spends
significant resources educating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> fairly, and the
commission found very few examples of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> abusing power," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> noted. This statement was signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Grassley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, among
others. In the hearings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grassley</ENAMEX> changed his tune. "It is the management
culture, mindless of the fact that they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," he said.
"If allowed to persist, such a mind-set often leads to arrogance,
unresponsiveness, disregard of one's rights, and the very kinds of things that
we have been hearing from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> uses revenue quotas: To the extent this
happened, it happened in response to pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>
was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of a statute that demanded "performance measures"
from all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the newly elected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
passed a budget bill that included a "compliance initiative" authorizing the
hiring of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Appropriations</ENAMEX> report stated, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is further instructed to report back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> ... with data on ...
a categorical accounting of revenue received as a result of these
investigations."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> persecutes the poor: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the disguised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> said on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> focuses on
the poor and ignores wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "because those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can bring in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> or a tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and fight this system." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s own
statistics, there has been a sharp decline in audits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> with incomes
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100,000</NUMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.8 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. For
those earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $25,000</NUMEX>, the figure rose from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8 percent</NUMEX>
over the same period. Sounds ominous. But this accusation contradicts the
previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are trying to meet quotas. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> put it in a ridiculous cover story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, needs "to feed
the insatiable demands of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for revenue and more efficiency," it would
be crazy to look to the poor as cash <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>.

            In fact,
there are more innocent--and more plausible--explanations for the changes in
audit rates. The number of low-income audits also nearly doubled after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>,
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> began categorizing nonfilers about whom it lacked information in
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000-and-</NUMEX>under category. It jumped again after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> demanded that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> prevent cheating on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who earn
less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> qualify for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> also points out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upper-income</ENAMEX> audits dropped in response to the closing down of tax shelters in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform Act</ENAMEX>.

            It's pretty obvious what conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are
trying to do here: develop a winning issue for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one recent</TIMEX>
memo, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Luntz</ENAMEX> wrote: "Rather than investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
which no one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> wants, we should be focusing our attention on a
Government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that has a negative impact on our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> lives. Consider
the benefit of public hearings that highlight <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>." That's what they've done. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luntz</ENAMEX> is now advising <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to
decry the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> at every opportunity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> may have come to doubt tax-cut
rhetoric, but they still don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who collect taxes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have been running
with the theme. "If you file a paper tax return, the odds are better than one
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> that you will be told you are wrong when you are right," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
warned in a speech playing off the hearings. This is, of course, nonsense. Only
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of returns get audited at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> recently called the agency
"intrusive, abusive, and out of control." Not a bad sound bite. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
isn't out of control. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are.

         
      
   
