
   
   
      
         
            Pundit Heaven

            
               Pundit
Heaven
            

            
               
                  Slate
                is proud
to announce the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>. Well, not exactly. What we have
added is a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Links</ENAMEX>, with links to the most recent columns by
nearly every major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opinionmeister</ENAMEX> currently available on the Web, ranging
alphabetically from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Baker</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, and ideologically from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivins</ENAMEX> to--oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Emmett Tyrrell Jr.</ENAMEX>, we suppose. The whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> is there, for example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, and so on. Along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, there are links to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
gossip columns--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> "Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Smith</ENAMEX>, and so on--as
well as to the op-ed pages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.

            Get to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Links</ENAMEX> by clicking here, or via our "Pundit
Central" page, where we give you a quick and (we hope) insightful and
entertaining roundup of what happened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> talk shows. And if you
don't want to trust us on this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Links</ENAMEX> will take you to the talk-show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcripts</ENAMEX>, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookmark Pundit Links</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Netscape</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Navigator users</ENAMEX>) or put it in
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Favorites folder</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> Online users) and
you'll never find yourself short of an opinion again.

            
               Having
Written, Continued
            

            Who said, "I don't like
writing, I like having written"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Readme</ENAMEX>" asserted it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> guffawed and credited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Parker</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>. Now
comes 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> (and occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>--see his dispatches on
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Life</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen Family</ENAMEX>") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX> with the following from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>: "I allow
you may have pleasure from writing, after it is over, if you have written well;
but you don't go willingly to it again."

            Any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>? Let us
know at read@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
