
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
            

            
               
                  Slate
                is
published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX> Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are concerned or even alarmed at the
thought of the world's largest software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> getting into the media
business. Can 
                  Slate
                tell it straight when it is owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>? Since we are about to ask our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to help us finance this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX> (see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX>"), and since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is in the headlines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, this
may be a good moment to tell you how we see this issue.

            First, as a practical
matter, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and a half
                  Slate
                has been coming out, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has not interfered in editorial decisions in any way. Nor has any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> higher-up complained about any 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> even after
the fact.

            In
theory, too, the alarm about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> owning media properties seems odd.
Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> with, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">empire</ENAMEX>) or other big media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The potential conflicts of interest are
far greater for a publication that is part of a traditional media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> than
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> owned by a software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> bumps up against the
various interests of its corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> many times in each issue, including
every time it reviews a book or a movie. By contrast, even lately with the
antitrust controversy, very little of what 
                  Slate
                publishes has
anything to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s other products and interests.

            There is legitimate concern about the concentration of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> in large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> of any sort. But the special concern about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> entering the field is hard to understand. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has been founding
new journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> (
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, etc.)--not buying up
existing ones. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s media adventures add to diversity and
competition among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, rather than reducing it. This makes the complaints
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> in particular about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> getting into the journalism
business especially puzzling. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who objects to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> getting
into journalism is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> with a secure job.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, of course, have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of experience and (in the case of Time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, if not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>) a reputation for integrity to protect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, as a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> on the block, has no journalistic reputation yet, either good or bad.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> will need to establish a reputation for integrity and hands-off
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> if it hopes to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to its media
properties. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would be stupidly shortsighted to destroy this
reputation before it is even established, in order to tilt the editorial
product more in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s favor. And even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s fiercest critics
rarely accuse this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of being stupid or shortsighted.

            
Of course it may not be necessary for a
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to interfere actively with the editorial content of media it
owns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> know which side their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is buttered on. In software
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, a chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' pay is in stock options, which
give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> an especially throbbing interest in the future prosperity of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>. Does this affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' ability to treat issues touching
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with the same lofty detachment they bring to issues that don't?

            Answer:
maybe. As a practical matter, once again, we at 
                  Slate
                think we
play it pretty straight, though others inevitably will disagree. We
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commissioned Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>'s attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as soon as we heard about his campaign against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Later, we ran a piece defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. More than once, in discussions of the
browser wars, we have provided links to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX>'s download page. There are other examples, and no doubt there are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterexamples</ENAMEX>. Root around the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Compost</ENAMEX>" and decide for yourself.

            In theory, as well, we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have an even stronger
self-interest than our corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in establishing
                  Slate
               's
reputation for journalistic integrity. We don't have to resist temptation
nearly as often as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of traditional media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. And some of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, by the way, also use stock as an incentive.

            Now, a
slight disclaimer. Despite all the completely compelling arguments offered in
the preceding paragraphs, it would be silly and dishonest to insist that

                  Slate
                does or can treat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> just as we would if it were not
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>. (And the same is true for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> working for any company
with varied interests.) The reality of ownership affects 
                  Slate
                in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of ways, we think.

            
First, we cannot actually forget that we work
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The most we can aspire to is to imagine successfully how we
would treat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> if we didn't work for it. But this is an artifice, and it
is not foolproof. There is the temptation to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s side, and the
contrary temptation to prove one's independence with ostentatious criticism.
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> get their ideas from their surroundings,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
probably looms larger in 
                  Slate
               's editorial landscape than it does
in that of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, the simplest and always tempting
solution to conflict-of-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> is to take a pass on some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>-related topics that you would otherwise treat. Although we do the
best we can--and we think our best is pretty good--it would be an amazing
coincidence if the result of all these opposing temptations and self-conscious
calculations was exactly the same quantity and slant of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> coverage as
if there was no connection.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,

                  Slate
                will never give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> the skeptical scrutiny it
requires as a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society (any more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , once again, will sufficiently scrutinize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>). We can come
pretty close to neutral reporting and analysis of news developments in features
like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" and "The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week/</TIMEX>The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>." At the other extreme, if we discover that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murdered Vince Foster</ENAMEX>, or a similar megascoop, journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bravado</ENAMEX> will easily
triumph over corporate loyalty. But in the middle ground--entrepreneurial and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analytical</ENAMEX> journalism--no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> can reasonably be expected to audit
itself. The standard to insist on is that the sins be of omission, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distortion</ENAMEX>. There will be no major investigations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               .

            The journalism reviews dote on episodes where some
newspaper runs an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-part series about how its own ink is filled with
cancer-causing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, or whatnot. However, what guarantees that powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> get skeptical scrutiny isn't a lot ofstagy self-mutilation. It's
diversity of voices. You can't trust a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to keep
an eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, but you can expect it to keep an eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, and youcan reasonably expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> to keep an eye
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. By creating new journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>--sometimes in
competition with established ones--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is adding to the total amount of
skeptical scrutiny going on.

            Or at
least at 
                  Slate
                that's what we're trying to do.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
