
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA Home Videos</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> made headlines twice
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The first wave of publicity was of a familiar and negative type.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Declassified</ENAMEX> documents revealed new details about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Operation Mongoose</ENAMEX>," the
campaign to murder and otherwise annoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>. Besides the infamous toxic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cigars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX> intended to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>'s beard fall out, the agency
developed a killer scuba suit and poison-injecting pens. None of it worked.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> wave of publicity was more novel and positive. It was about a video the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> released as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> concluded its criminal investigation into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>
Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> disaster. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX> film was intended to bolster the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s
conclusion that the explosion was not the result of a terrorist attack, by
explaining why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eyewitnesses</ENAMEX> might have mistaken the airplane's midair
disintegration for a missile attack.

            Here, then, were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> CIAs: the ineptly diabolical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> of old vs. the chastened, competent, and versatile one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langley</ENAMEX>, whose run of luck in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has resembled that of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX>, must be hoping for just such a contrast to form in the public
mind. But while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> certainly has changed for the better, it would be
premature to quit worrying about what it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to</NUMEX>. The new, user-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
gives pause in new ways.

            Watch the
docudrama-style video, and you'll understand why. At the beginning, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
great seal appears and dissolves. Spooky music is heard, of the type most often
used as background for cheesy shows about paranormal phenomena. An anonymous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX> recounts the facts of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1996</TIMEX> disaster, and says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> were especially concerned with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eyewitnesses</ENAMEX> who thought
they saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>. "At the request of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> looked
into this possibility," the narrator explains. On-screen is a windowless room
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, in a tie and vest, motions toward a display <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
The others, in shirtsleeves, look on attentively. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s conclusion: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eyewitnesses</ENAMEX> did not see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>," the narration continues. "What these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eyewitnesses</ENAMEX> saw was, in fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">747</ENAMEX> in various stages of crippled
flight." With animation, the film re-creates the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> think the
airplane disintegrated. It then reconciles this scenario with the testimony of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.

            
This account is probably the best explanation
for the inevitable discrepancies in the evidence about what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>--a subject with which I have no obsession. But the video is nonetheless a
bizarre artifact, on several levels. Consider the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> working on the case. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possibilities here. Either these
portrayals are unacknowledged dramatic simulations, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> spent a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and money documenting its own inner workings. The former alternative
suggests that old habits of deception die hard. The latter suggests that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s public-relations goals for the Flight 800 assignment were fully
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> into the investigation itself. In fact, both things are probably
true.

            The
strangest thing about the film is that it is supposed to dispel paranoid
theories--and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> made it. From the outset of the investigation, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has been saying, convincingly, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> hit was a near-impossibility.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> accept this. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Salinger</ENAMEX> proposed
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> down, he was widely assumed to be off his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rocker</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> video is directed, then, at the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> of conspiracy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> who do not accept the official explanation. In other words, it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> at the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world who would ever believe anything the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> said. At Flight 800 sites on the Web, as you would expect, the video has
merely added fuel to the fire. Getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to reassure paranoiacs is like

            More troublesome is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s unprecedented role as
purveyor of the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> line. Since its creation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> has always had a dual function. It is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, providing
background for policymakers, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> clandestine arm of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy.
This split is built into the structure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, which separates its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directorate</ENAMEX> of intelligence from its directorate of operations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> wants
the film to look like a product of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. Its slick production values,
however, suggest something of a debt to the operations directorate, which has
long experience at spreading disinformation abroad. Because this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>,
we'll never know for sure (or at least not for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>). But it is alarming,
to say the least, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> trained in lying abroad are now moonlighting at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>--even if they're telling the truth this time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice of America</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Free Europe</ENAMEX> are prohibited from broadcasting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
specifically because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> didn't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s propaganda resources
trained on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The (oft-violated) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> charter forbids it from spying on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. It fails to ban domestic propagandizing only because no one ever
envisioned such a role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.

            So why is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> doing this? The answer goes beyond the urge for self-promotion. Since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> fell apart, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has been increasingly desperate to
justify its continued existence. Though its side won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, it didn't
get much credit. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> has emphasized, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
wildly overestimated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> economy and missed the impending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
collapse. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Nicholson</ENAMEX> were running amok.
Morale is reportedly low, and career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have been resigning in droves.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> has been through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.

            
The latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Tenet</ENAMEX>, hopes to
protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> staff and its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3-billion</NUMEX> budget (a number only
recently declassified) by orienting it around new international
threats--narcotics trafficking, terrorism, and nuclear proliferation. There are
debates about whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> has an appropriate role in any of these areas.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> may be better suited to dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narcotics</ENAMEX> enforcement is primarily the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Enforcement</ENAMEX>
Administration. In calling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to help on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flight 800</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> was making
a peace overture in a bitter, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> rivalry. After seeing the video, it may
regret this gesture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Kallstrom</ENAMEX>, who directed the Flight 800
investigation, indicated at a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that he had some
misgivings about the film.

            You don't have to be
conspiracy nut to worry about a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> with high-tech espionage
capabilities and a criminal record looking around for something to do. The
friendly new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> may mean well, but it sort of makes you nostalgic for the
spooks from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the bad old days</TIMEX>. Right about now, they'd be sending <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> a box
of exploding berets.

         
      
   
