
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> vs. the <I>Times</I>

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX> now,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have debated how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> would exit the stage. Would he depart on a
negative note about his opponent or a positive one about himself? Would he
leave with anger or with humor? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several days</TIMEX>, the issue has been
settled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, it appears, will end his political career raging against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s spat with the gray
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lady</ENAMEX> went public on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 24</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> charged the paper
with ignoring a story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> who got invited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. "This is a disgrace," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> insisted. "I doubt if you even read it in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . They probably put it in the want ads. They don't put any
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Only anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> stories in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> repeated his attack for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five days</TIMEX>.
"We are not going to let the media steal this election," he told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. "This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, not the New York
Times ." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Visalia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, he added, "I know that with a
crowd this size, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> will write not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> showed
up, but the other papers will get it right."

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> "the
apologist for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and an arm of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>." In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> interview broadcast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> "might as well be part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. ... They
hammer us on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis. We make a major speech, they bury it back on
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> They put a front-page story that, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>
didn't get along together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX>." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was still at it,
referring to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> words of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 10th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX>, and quipping, "That's about
what I got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> today."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has reacted to this assault by
highhandedly quoting everything and explaining none of it, leaving its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
baffled as to why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> is so upset at the paper. In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s fury at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is hardly news to those who work at the paper.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Seelye</ENAMEX>, who has covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> since the beginning of his
campaign, the complaints date from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1995</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> first
protested that she had misunderstood the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s position on abortion. The
real bitterness, however, began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> played what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
billed as a major address about welfare on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> of the business section.
Since then, campaign honchos have peppered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
with constant phone calls and letters complaining about unfair treatment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> traveling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
caught a glimpse of the enmity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 9</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Warfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, staged a public confrontation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seelye</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, Warfield
told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> waiting to board the campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, had just come from an
appearance on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Gordon Liddy</ENAMEX>'s radio show. Why, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seelye</ENAMEX> asked, weren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> told about the appearance in advance? According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> present,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warfield</ENAMEX> snapped that it wouldn't make any difference because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
would get the story wrong anyway. Then, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warfield</ENAMEX> walked back to
the press section and grandly served <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seelye</ENAMEX> with a copy of a letter from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Buckley</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Rosenthal</ENAMEX>.

            That
letter, which has fallen into the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, protests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seelye</ENAMEX>'s coverage of
a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, had talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AWOL</ENAMEX> in the drug war. "Where has he been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>? How many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> started <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three million</NUMEX> have
started smoking while he was playing around with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking</ENAMEX> and all this stuff
finally in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seelye</ENAMEX>'s front-page story reported that "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of 'playing around' while the drug war raged out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> complains that the story "could lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to believe
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was talking about a very different kind of 'playing
around'--something he did not say, and something he would not say." The letter
continues: "Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, I have been pointing out to you a problem we see with
the accuracy and understanding of context revealed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kit</ENAMEX>'s reporting," going
on to assert that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seelye</ENAMEX> has misquoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> on numerous occasions and done so
in a manner that distorted the accuracy of her assertions and your
coverage."

            
No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> staff would be quoted by name for this
story, but speaking on background, a senior campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> elaborated upon
the complaint. "They've just done a miserable job throughout this campaign,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said. "The coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has been excessively bitchy from day
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, in addition to having a number of extraordinary factual problems." With
Seelye, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> says, the problem is "not being able to transcribe a tape
accurately." With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Nagourney</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> covering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> full time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, "the problem is an incredible focus on the
little picture as opposed to the big picture." As an example, the official
cites a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> story in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagourney</ENAMEX> lumped together <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s fall from a
platform in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, and his mistaken reference to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>
as "a rough stretch of politicking." Other than those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> episodes, the
official says, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> actually had a great week. The campaign's complaint extends
to unequal treatment--a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-part series on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s record, which the
official describes as "the softest portrait since they invented black
velvet"--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> perpetually underestimating the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
crowds. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> even gets better photographs," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> contends.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, who has direct responsibility for campaign coverage at the
Times , professes bewilderment at these complaints. "We don't make
editorial judgments based on disposition to be tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> or nice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>," he says. On the specifics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ran an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s note acknowledging that it shouldn't have truncated the "playing
around" quote. He points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ran its story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> who visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> the same day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of
not covering it. As for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-part series on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> says it is
the long-standing practice of the paper to do a lengthy series on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incumbent</ENAMEX>'s record. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> wins and runs again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, he will get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>-part
series too," he says.

            
"Ithink we have been tough on him," Seelye
says. This stems, however, not from any bias, she says, but from the campaign's
own internal problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s campaign has been especially "porous," with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
emulating the proverbial seafaring <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. This is true enough--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Sipple</ENAMEX> has trashed the campaign on the record. But there's
another point, too. Contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s charge that she misquotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Seelye</ENAMEX> routinely makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> look ridiculous by quoting him all too accurately,
depicting him in what one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> calls a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema verit√</ENAMEX>© " style.
Famous for going over and over her tape recordings on the campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seelye</ENAMEX> manages to get every <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> mumble, repetition, and verbal miscue down.
For instance, in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 26</TIMEX> story reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seelye</ENAMEX> writes:

            "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>,
he had a delightful time drawing out his vowels as he described financial
contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. "From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indoneeesia</ENAMEX>," he said. "Yeah. From
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INdiaaaaah</ENAMEX>. Some fellow named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> out there. He owes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in back taxes,
but he found <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> to give to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. And now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaaaawn</ENAMEX>. Gaaaaandhi, gone gone gone. They can't find him."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, she quoted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> in another story: "They've turned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> into something else, I
don't know what it is. It's the animal house! It's the animal house!" Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> would write, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> compared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to an
"animal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>," sparing the exclamation points, and making him sound at least
compos mentis.

            But though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unflattering</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seelye</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mametizing</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> can hardly be called unfair. It
is not as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> cleans up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s quotes; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> simply
observes the rules of syntax most of the time. Something similar may be
happening with the pictures. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has learned how to avoid
looking unpresidential. He no longer allows himself to be photographed wearing
too-short running shorts, and he avoids pulling faces in public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, who is
simply less photogenic, is an easier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> for picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>--who, like
their editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, have a strong bias against dullness. Take, for
instance, the two pictures shown above. The front-page picture the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
ran <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> presidential debate does make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> look like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decomposing</ENAMEX> monster. But unlike the picture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> the
same day, it captures the spirit of the event, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> grimly taking the
offensive and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> watching warily but standing aside from the attacks.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> sounds absurd when he alleges that the
paper that broke <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> and the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s commodities
trades has not been aggressive in pursuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals. All sorts of
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> scandals have been soft-pedaled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, including the
Times , because he is so far behind. It's true that coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
on the campaign trail has been somewhat softer than the coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, as
even other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> acknowledge. But the explanation is
institutional, not ideological. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, as many have complained,
overemphasizes the "horse race" aspect of politics. As a side effect of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have excessive respect for a well-run campaign. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> benefited from this phenomenon.) A cruder reality is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> need to have a relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.

            None of these factors,
though, is unique to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . So why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> singling it out? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> have the appearance of being an exercise in
populist demagogy. In one of his great cue-card reading remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> tried to
explain his recent attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> by saying, "I like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.
They don't like them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>." But this pat explanation doesn't entirely
make sense. Red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> for right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> doesn't help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> with the centrist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> he would need to turn around in order to make the miraculous happen. And
in fact, according to a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, the attacks are heartfelt on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s part. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has been going after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> over the
objections of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> who have been telling him there's no percentage in
picking fights with the press.

            But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is attacking the
Times because he is truly furious and not because he thinks it will help
him get elected, what is he so angry about? The answer, I think, is that there
has always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixonian</ENAMEX> streak in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, by which I mean a part of him
which feels shut out of the closed circle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. At the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> convention, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> blasted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> who never grew up, never did anything real, never sacrificed, never
suffered, and never learned." That phrase recalled an attack he made on the
press long ago, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, when he accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post of being in bed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX>. "There is a cultural and social
affinity between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGovernites</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said then. "They belong to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>: They can be found living
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cheek-by-jowl</ENAMEX> in the same exclusive chic neighborhoods, and hob-nobbing at the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>." The deeper story here isn't whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was wrongly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shunted</ENAMEX> onto <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">D19</NUMEX> when he ought to have been on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A1</TIMEX>. It's his feelings, as he
says goodbye to politics, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get to decide.

         
      
   
