
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> Only

            The debate about affirmative
action is usually cast as a fight between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who wish to abolish the
policy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who want to keep it. That is a misunderstanding. The
argument is actually between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who want to remodel affirmative
action and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who want to conceal it.

            Even
those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> deemed the most extreme on issues of race, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX>, do not favor doing away with affirmative action.
Rather, they propose to base it on the principle of economic disadvantage.
This, they contend, would bring similar results in terms of diversity, without
the evident unfairness. Critics also sometimes argue that race-based
affirmative action would be fine if it were limited to efforts at "recruitment"
and "training." They generally agree that affirmative action is acceptable as a
"remedy" for specific acts of past discrimination. Many who think that
affirmative action shouldn't be required by law favor it as a voluntary policy.
And, of course, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action practice it themselves.
Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action, for example, are heavily favored over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> with similar views in getting promoted by the conservative propaganda
machine.

            If group preferences are wrong in principle, as these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> maintain, none of their exceptions makes much sense. Consider the
"remedy for past discrimination" dodge. Say you're a highly qualified white man
denied a job by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birmingham Fire Department</ENAMEX>. Are you supposed to feel better
if you got turned down because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> once discriminated against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>? You yourself never practiced discrimination. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>-not-race
alternative is even less of an improvement. It actually heightens the injustice
of affirmative action by punishing some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for a historical wrong that they
not only didn't participate in, but that also never occurred. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is as
famous for economic opportunity and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> mobility as it is for its legacy of
racial oppression. Class-based affirmative action trades in a vexed solution to
a real problem for an even more vexed solution to an illusory problem.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX>,
on the other hand, spend less time defending affirmative action than they do
trying to make it innocuous and invisible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> clings to
the evasion enshrined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Powell</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bakke</ENAMEX> case: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rigid</ENAMEX>"
numerical quotas are unfair and discriminatory, while "flexible" goals are not.
Race should be a factor, but it must not be the factor. What's the real
difference? In either case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a protected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> win jobs, promotions,
and educational slots that would otherwise go to better-qualified white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
This is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">colorblindness</ENAMEX> of a sort: No one can identify specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of "factor"-style affirmative action, even though both would
exist as surely as they do under a policy of explicit quotas.

            
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> propose more euphemism as a
solution. In a recent issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fredrickson</ENAMEX> recommends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of affirmative action avoid the words
"racial preferences" and "reverse discrimination" in favor of the term
"equality of opportunity." This is like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>'s attempt to fight
inflation by banning it from his vocabulary.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
says he wants to "mend" affirmative action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX>, it turns out, say the
same thing. So, behind the vicious argument is actually something like shared
understanding that affirmative action is a toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, sometimes necessary,
that we've been using too freely. The dosage needs to be scaled back. But how?
Here's my proposal.

            Any kind of affirmative action means preferring some people
over others for reasons having nothing to do with their intrinsic
merit--however merit is measured. That is not something that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, or any
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, should take on lightly. But it remains justified in one
case--that of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>. The wrong done to slaves and their descendents
is unique in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX>, racism, and segregation have left a
black social deficit that is damaging, not just to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> but also to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> as a whole. Were this problem evaporating on its own, affirmative
action would not be necessary. The condition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> is improving, but there
is strong evidence--see, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando Patterson</ENAMEX>'s new book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ordeal of Integration</ENAMEX> --that affirmative action has played an essential role
in fostering both integration and the growth of the black middle class. If
affirmative action needs to be reformed, the way to fix it is to narrow it, to
cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> only.

            This was
the original idea of affirmative action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> executive
order, which first created preferences in federal contracting, applied only to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. So did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon B. Johnson</ENAMEX>'s better-known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> order. The justification
was spelled out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard University</ENAMEX> speech of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, written by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>. "You do not take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, has been
hobbled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, and liberate him, bring him to the starting line of a race,
and then say, 'You are free to compete with all the others,' and still justly
believe that you have been completely fair," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>,
however, the concept was stretched to cover other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who
were less hobbled at the starting line. The greatest expansion was under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, who, it has been suggested, saw affirmative action as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trojan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> to slaughter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> continued to push to qualify new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for government set-aside contracts and other forms of preference.

            
Expansion of affirmative action was an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instinctual</ENAMEX> response of liberalism, and not in the crude talk-radio sense that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> love big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." The New Deal political model for social
programs was to include the semideserving and undeserving along with the truly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deserving</ENAMEX>. A broad base of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> meant a broad base of political
support. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has responded to opposition to affirmative action in exactly
this way. His "mend it, don't end it" speech of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1995</TIMEX> emphasized that
affirmative action helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. He even listed
"gender" before "race" in defining the policy. Though this approach didn't stop
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, it has become policy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
explicit strategy for saving affirmative action is to rally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in its
defense. Thus new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX> regulations intended to make it
easier for white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to compete for loans.

            There is,
to be sure, a long history of discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>,
and so on. But the mistreatment of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> was far less
severe, and it has proven far more amenable to cure without radical
intervention. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, are by and
large following the classic patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> and ethnic assimilation. For
various reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are not.

            In their abstract mode, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> argue that any group
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> is unfair. Why should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who did not themselves discriminate against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> be punished for what their or someone else's ancestors did? The answer
is that it shouldn't be thought of as punishment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whites</ENAMEX> who never practiced
discrimination are nonetheless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of it.

            As a
thought-experiment, consider what it might mean to a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of reverse
discrimination if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> had always been equal. Imagine a law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">100</ENAMEX> places. Under affirmative action, a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> who ranks
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99 th</NUMEX> might well be denied admission while a black who ranks
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> would get in. But where would those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> have ranked
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> had not been enslaved and discriminated against? Under the
overmechanical assumptions of affirmative-action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> themselves (and
putting aside the racial IQ theories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and some others), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> would
move up the list, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> would move down.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. That
doesn't necessarily mean that in a world with no racial discrimination, present
or past, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> would be black. But the number would be
closer to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> than to the likely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s world. And in that
case, the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99 th</NUMEX> place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> wouldn't get in
anyway.

            In other words, if our goal
is to replicate a colorblind world, a world with some forms of racial
affirmative action comes closer than a world without it.

         
      
   
