
   
   
      
         
            How to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appear Thoughtful</ENAMEX>

            At the height of his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>
act over whether to vote for the balanced-budget amendment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX>,
the first-term <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, gave an interview to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . "I understand this will be one of the most important
votes I ever cast," he told the paper. "I'm taking an extraordinary amount of
time talking about it." Now, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> might have noted that he was
spending a lot of time thinking about the issue, perhaps, or
listening to the arguments on both sides. But this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torch</ENAMEX>,
remember--who, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a couple of months</TIMEX>, has distinguished himself as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> most in love with the sound of his own voice. When
you consider that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Byrd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Biden</ENAMEX>, that is
really something.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> might be a blowhard, but he isn't dumb. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>,
he seems to have figured out in a hurry how this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> thing works. "I didn't
get here by design," he told reporters at a press conference on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. He was referring to his role as the decision <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> on the balanced-budget
amendment, which is set to fail by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next week</TIMEX>. This claim of
guilelessness was instantaneously belied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that he and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> "undecideds" had the narrow defeat of the bill. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX>'s accomplishment was more than just manipulating the timing of his
announcement to make himself the center of media attention. He also showed how
easy it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to cultivate the appearance of thoughtfulness without
doing a minute's worth of actual thinking.

            The challenge of looking like a soul-searching statesman
was made harder by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX>'s previous record on the issue. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, he had voted in favor of the balanced-budget amendment, in the same
version he now opposes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different times. During his recent campaign, he
said in unequivocal terms that he was in favor of the amendment, donning his
record on the issue as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Kevlar</ENAMEX> shield against the charge that he was a
fiscally irresponsible liberal. So his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> order of business in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
was to begin to lay the groundwork for a flip-flop. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> didn't do
anything so dramatic as to say he might have been wrong in the past. Instead,
he reinterpreted his past position as semaphore. He wasn't really voting
to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> at the time. He was trying to send a "message" about
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal irresponsibility</TIMEX> to various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. (When I conked
you over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with that frying pan, I was merely indicating my
concern .) Never mind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> himself, being as
fiscally irresponsible as the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> send messages to
themselves all the time.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
step is the fun part: agonizing in public. The national grandmaster of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technique</ENAMEX> is still the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>. But in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, the great role model is , who held a national dialogue with himself in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> before finally choosing to cast the deciding vote in favor of the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> economic plan. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrey</ENAMEX> carries off indecision better than Torricelli
does, because with him, it's not an act. He is truly, paralytically ambivalent,
perpetually ruminating about whether he should run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> even while
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Torricelli was merely feigning indecision when
he gave interviews to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> before last saying how seriously he took the arguments on both sides, and
how impressed he was with the deep consideration of important issues that took
place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            
Step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is negotiating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who need
your vote. At this stage, you are the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in town. The president
invites you over to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> respond to your smallest
hint with servile alacrity. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Broder</ENAMEX>, calling for you on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>." And so
forth. Being the swing vote means you can ask for the moon and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>--but you
can't ask for pork if you want to be seen as a deep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. Demanding a bridge
as your price would be tacky, especially in exchange for killing off a
big-ticket fiscal-austerity measure. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six months</TIMEX> down the road, you can ask for
all the post <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> you want.) More dignified is to ask for some kind of
commission. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrey</ENAMEX> got a commission on entitlements in exchange for
his vote on the budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> had been expressing concern about the lack
of capital budgeting--the inability, under our system of federal accounting, to
spread out the costs of "investment" expenditure. Presto: After a conversation
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> made clear his intention on the vote,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> announced the formation of a capital-budget <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> to
examine this important issue. Click to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> explain what's wrong
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX>'s capital-budget idea.

            The final
step is coming up with a pretext for your decision. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
used the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> cuts to justify his flip-flop several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days earlier</TIMEX>, but that was just to bear the weight of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, even a
light one. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> took a different tack, objecting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
version of the amendment because it didn't contain any provision for the
above-mentioned capital budget, and proposing an amendment to the amendment to
provide for one, pending the report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torch Commission</ENAMEX>. The merits of that
issue aside, this was an absurd proposal in the context of debate about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balanced-budget</ENAMEX> amendment. Balanced budgets and capital budgets are
contradictory ideas. Being against the former because it doesn't provide for
the latter is like saying you don't like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because it doesn't have
wheels.

            After the amendment's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, refused
to accept this change, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> took the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorry</ENAMEX>, wish I could help" line. "I
need the gentleman from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> to explain to me how a generation unborn in
circumstances unforeseen will deal with renewed military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX>, a deep
recession, or the problem of declining economic competitiveness." Nice bit of
ask-notting, that "generation unborn in circumstances unforeseen." Reverse word
order will get you everywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. After his endless speech on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor in defense of our founding "ancestors," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> repaired to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> radio and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> to continue his monologue. "I have struggled with
this decision more than any ... I have ever made in my life," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> said.
Chins were stroked. Editorials were penned, hailing the decision. A strange new
mantle of respect descended on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Torricelli</ENAMEX>.

            Of course, truly thoughtful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> don't go in for this kind of rigmarole. Take the now-retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon of Illinois</ENAMEX>, who took a courageous position in support of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balanced-budget</ENAMEX> amendment and held to it consistently--even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote short, and wouldn't have succeeded in defeating the
amendment without the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Hatfield</ENAMEX>. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> was wrong
on the merits, but I never questioned his sincerity on the issue. Or take
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX>'s predecessor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> took the same position that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torricelli</ENAMEX> did on the balanced-budget amendment after actually thinking
about it, and without making a fuss.

            But quiet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contemplation</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX>'s métier. To quote again from the pre-decision
piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> :

            
               After a long discourse
on the ins and outs of his vote, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> drops a hint that when it
matters, he will not desert his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> needs to determine a proper
level of debt," he said, "and it's possible several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> could emerge to use
votes on this to force new creative talking."
            

            Or, more creatively yet,
maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> could just stop talking for a while.

         
      
   
