
   
   
      
         
            Losing It

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, at least, seems to
have wrestled with his conscience before opting to launch bitter attacks on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." That does not appear to be the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. "On <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inauguration Day</ENAMEX>, they're breaking the law and doing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> told an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX>,
referring to unspecified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days</TIMEX>
later, they're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. This must be the most disciplined set of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> in the world, because none of them has ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> once since they
joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>." The accusation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is filled
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> is a classic political smear--ugly, utterly unsubstantiated,
and almost certainly false.

            It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">understandable</ENAMEX>, of course, that conservative frustration levels should be
running high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. For a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that thought it was leading an unstoppable
revolution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years ago</TIMEX>, it can't be much fun to be saddled with an
old gray <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare</ENAMEX> of a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, or to be faced with the
possibility of losing control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to an opposition they believe to be
not just wrong, but on the wrong side of history. That said, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are acting like sore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> already, becoming unhinged--there's really no other
word for it--at the prospect of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> resurrection. Some--including, in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> himself--are drumming up scandal in such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biased</ENAMEX> and hypocritical way that they risk sacrificing both their credibility
and their dignity for the sake of a lost cause.

            The charges are flying fast and furious--misappropriated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, even "money laundering." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> ago
that a second <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> term could produce "something like we went through in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> era," adding, "I believe this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is one of the most
corrupt in recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history." Only the weaselly
qualifications-- something like ... one of ... recent --save this remark
from transparent falsehood (by leaving it meaningless). But the implicit
comparison to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> is a shoddy historical absurdity, coming from Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intellectual Standards</ENAMEX>.

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surrogates</ENAMEX> have focused on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new issues that purport
to embody the flawed ethics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. What these lines of attack
have in common is that for all the hysteria with which they are being
expressed, they have yielded little evidence of presidential misbehavior, let
alone deep problems of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>."

            
The most recent, and bitter accusation has to
do with campaign contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>. Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> again, speaking on
Meet 
               the 
               Press just after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

               Times broke the story that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> had given <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> in soft money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>: "This makes <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
look tiny," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> said. "I mean, this is a potential abuse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
system on behalf of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> in a way we have never seen in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s wording was sly as ever--what isn't a
"potential" abuse? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Reed</ENAMEX>, used the same weaselly
language when he issued a statement attacking the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s potentially
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> actions in squeezing money out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian Lippo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>,"
going on to ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "Why have you used <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> as a fund-raising tool to help secure illegal campaign contributions
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> himself then scored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for failing to
answer this and other when-did-you-stop-beating-your-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> questions. In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who have been trying very hard to unearth evidence that the
contributions were illegal, or that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Riady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>
has had an effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy, have so far come up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empty-handed</ENAMEX>.

            Of
course, it would be nice if we lived in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where the political parties
were not allowed to take <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half-a-million-dollar</NUMEX> contributions from anyone. Under
our current system of campaign finance, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> connection is
merely and sadly typical. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As recently as the last presidential election</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> faced a similar embarrassment when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kojima</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, gave them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> which, it turned out, he owed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> and
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support payments. Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> nor the press made nearly this
big a deal about it. Since contributions from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> residing here
legally are allowed, it's hard to see what--other than a whiff of yellow peril
in this case--distinguishes them from big donations by domestic interests.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> has been carrying on about "rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>" in a truly ugly way.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> did accept, and subsequently return, an apparently illegal
contribution in a separate instance, from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> who lacked
a green card. But then, returning funny money is par for the course in
presidential campaigns. Back during the primaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> accepted and returned
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27,000</NUMEX> in illegally bundled money from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AquaLeisure</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> has since pleaded guilty to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> felony charges in the case.

            The real difference between foreign and domestic soft money
seems to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> get better value in exchange. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">backers</ENAMEX> include the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer Daniels</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midland</ENAMEX>, the agribusiness
concern whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> recently pleaded guilty to price fixing, and the Gallo
wine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. In those instances, unlike in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> one, there is strong
evidence of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quid</NUMEX> pro quo, or at least mutual back-scratching. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has done
explicit and valuable favors for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, sponsoring the notorious
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol boondoggle</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADM</ENAMEX>, and helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallos</ENAMEX> (who have given various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
organizations <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>) with family-specific tax breaks
and regulatory fixes. For some reason, no one considers these to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>" issues. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> were ahead and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> behind, there's little doubt
that the details of these relationships would now be front-page news. But,
being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is so immune to such assaults that he can send out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Black</ENAMEX>--whose professional specialty is lobbying on behalf of corrupt
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> like the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferdinand Marcos</ENAMEX>--to spin the press on how
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>'s taking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> money demonstrates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
flawed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            The
campaign contributions are at least in the realm of the troublesome. The pardon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fuss</ENAMEX>, on other hand, is simply absurd. "Here's how to succeed in obstructing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> wrote in a recent column in the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>

               Times . "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) publicly disparage all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> as partisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">miscreants</ENAMEX>,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> now does; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) encourage co-conspirators to resist prosecutorial
pressure by arranging for hush money; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) hint at post-election pardons."
The only problem here is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) is an unsupported fantasy, and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) is
simply wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has done nothing to hint at pardons. He has never brought
the matter up publicly, and there's no evidence he's done so in private. When
asked, he's said he hasn't thought about it and won't discuss it.

            
In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> presidential debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comically</ENAMEX> demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> say "no comment" when asked about pardons,
which is more or less precisely what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has done. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> later changed his
position and demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> explicitly promise to rule out pardons if
re-elected. "He better make it very clear--no pardons, no pardons to anybody he
did business with who may be in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said on the eve of the final
debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> justified this turnaround by arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had
obviated his "no comment" with an answer (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks earlier</TIMEX>) on the
News <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX>.
            

            Here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> actually
said: "My position would be that their cases should be handled like others,
they should go through--there's a regular process for that, and I have regular
meetings on that, and I review those cases as they come up after there's an
evaluation done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>." In no significant way does that
comment differ from a "no comment." Of course, a no-pardon promise would be
meaningless; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could simply break it on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of office. And if
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is as bad as some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> contend, there's no reason for them
to think he would hesitate to do so. It might also be pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
supported the political pardons meted out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>, when he served as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s running mate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. Likewise in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, he applauded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame-duck pardons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar Weinberger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>
al.

            "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">power-hungry</ENAMEX> and so shameless they'll do anything to win," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said at a rally
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glendale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the debate (before leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in
the chant: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's Our Money, It's Our Money, It's Our Money</ENAMEX>"). It's hard to say
whether this is really true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. But in the closing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the
campaign, it stands as an apt description of his faltering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
