
   
   
      
         
            We Happy Few

            
               We Happy
Few
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 17,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had
signed up for 
                  Slate
                by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of this week</TIMEX>, a day or so after
we became a paid-access site. For reasons explained in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX>" last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, we're very pleased with that number. Thanks, and welcome to all our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. And to those of you who are reading this on our "front porch" (free
area): <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come on in</ENAMEX>! Click here to subscribe.

            Keep in mind that in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, you get what you pay for. The version of this column available only to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> is not the rather perfunctory sales pitch you see before you. It is
an extravaganza of witty jokes, brilliant political insights, the startling
confessions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who claim to have slept with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past week</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of whom say they also slept with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Special Prosecutor Ken Starr</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> simultaneously), the details of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s plans to incorporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rico</ENAMEX> into the next generation of its Internet browser, a sonnet in memory of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Bridges</ENAMEX>, a special offer for laundry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>, and a secret password
that will get you into the hidden pages of any sadomasochistic site on the Web
(with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">amazon</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX> will confirm that it's heaven on this side of the wall: The sun
always shines, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are beautiful and kind, there is <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice pudding</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>--and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>! So please do join us.

            
               A Quiet
Word to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subscribers</ENAMEX>
            

            If anyone
asks, please do us a favor and confirm the preposterous lies in the preceding
item. Feel free to substitute your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> or to embroider and
fabricate generally. We're all in this together now.

            

               Navigational Notes
            

            Those reading

                  Slate
                on Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4</ENAMEX> should be sure to take advantage of
the new "nav bar" that runs across the top of each page. By clicking on the
various section headings, you can get a drop-down list of their current
contents and go directly to any article or feature in 
                  Slate
               . We
will soon be adding this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> at the bottom of pages, too (in the optimistic
belief that even in fin de 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">siècle America</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will a]
finish reading an article and b] wish to read another). We will also be
providing the nav bar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Netscape Navigator 4</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a free
download of the latest version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Navigator</ENAMEX>.)

            If you're
already a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> to 
                  Slate
               , you don't need to subject yourself
to the vulgar sales pitch we impose on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> to slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Nor must you
remember that damned password and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> name. Just check the box that says,
"From now on, sign me in automatically" (right below the sign-in boxes). Next
time you come to 
                  Slate
               , you'll go directly to the table of
contents.

            
               Boycott
the Web
            

            You can
avoid the Web completely, if you want, by signing up for e-mail delivery.

                  Slate 
                  on 
                  Paper
               , e-mailed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each Friday</TIMEX>, is a
text-only compilation of most of what 
                  Slate
                has published during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. It is formatted for printing out on standard-size paper. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers" is also delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> via e-mail. These services are available to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> only. Click here to sign up for e-mail delivery. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> we purged our
delivery lists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who hadn't subscribed. If you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> and
your delivery was discontinued, please accept our apologies, and sign up
again.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX>'
Honor
            

            We hate to sound like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX>, but you really must accept <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> if you're going to subscribe to

                  Slate
               . If you don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> are, in the technical,
computer sense, you almost surely can ignore this warning. (But click here for an
explanation.) If you do know what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> are and have set your computer not to
accept them, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">password</ENAMEX>/sign-in process won't work for you. Look, our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>
are truly harmless. Honest. Yes, yes, that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansel</ENAMEX> and
Gretel, but did she supply a list of ingredients to prove it? We do. Click
here to read it. And please accept <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> so you can enjoy

                  Slate
               .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
