
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">God Bless Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            
               God
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bless Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
            

            
               
                  Slate
                had more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270,000</NUMEX> individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, or at least
browsers, who visited slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> at least once during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX>.

            As we have explained in
the past, we regard individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>--or, technically, "unique browsers"--as
the best measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>. It is not perfect: It treats a single,
brief drop-in and a dedicated daily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> exactly the same when counting; for
technical reasons, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> don't get counted; and it doesn't include the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX> who get 
                  Slate
                by e-mail or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more who are e-mailed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. But the other common measurements--pages
served, or "hits"--are even more defective. Just for the record, though, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, we reported serving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140,000</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>. That is now up to about
200,000.

            These
numbers have risen dramatically in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX>, and especially in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few weeks</TIMEX>. How to explain it? We like to think, of course, that it is due
to loyal 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> spreading the word about our splendid
editorial product. We also would like to--and do--credit our recent alliances
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Network</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hotmail</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fool</ENAMEX>. But
it just might be that recent developments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> have had something to
do with it, too.

            Like all responsible media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               
deplores the deplorable situation that forces us to discuss deplorable matters
such as alleged fellatio in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> rather than global warming or the
strategic balance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>. We deplore the tawdry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of events
itself--whether the deplorable scenario should turn out to be a president
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misbehaving</ENAMEX> and lying about it under oath, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> brought to a halt
by the fevered imaginings of an overexcitable young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Whatever happened
exactly, it is deplorable. And we deplore it.

            That said, we can't help
acknowledging that whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> serviced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, she
certainly has serviced us. Not just us but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>

               Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX>, and every other outlet of news, analysis, and
commentary in every medium. She also has serviced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, all of whom, of course, deplore the situation as much as we in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> deplore it. For that matter the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, though generally
disgusted (whether by the alleged activity or the process that made it a public
issue or both), has also gained considerable pleasure and excitement from this
admittedly deplorable episode.

            Let us all, therefore, take a
brief moment off from all this deploring to say: "Thank you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. Thank you,
thank you, thank you." And if there's anything we at 
                  Slate
                in
particular can ever do ... some software, perhaps?

            We now
return to our regularly scheduled deploring. (This site works best using
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deplorer TM</ENAMEX> .)

            
               True
Story
            

            So a guy
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from an oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> are
talking at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> reception. It's around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Someone asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>,
"How are the ratings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> (hint: now at

                  Slate
               ): Not so good. We could use another war.

            Defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>: So
could we.

            Oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>: So could we, as
long as it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>.

            Moral:
Oral sex saves lives! We don't need a war to give the media a boost after all.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, thank you again. What it all does for the oil and defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> is
less clear.

            
               "Readme"
Special
            

            The next <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX> column will
be available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days early</TIMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb. 18</TIMEX>. It will contain the details
of our plan to begin charging for access to 
                  Slate
                and a special
offer for early sign-ups.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
