
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign Reform</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of
campaign-finance reform deserve fairly high marks for realism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. Most
of the good government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Cause</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Citizen</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women Voters</ENAMEX> have long favored a comprehensive solution based on public
financing of congressional campaigns. With varying degrees of enthusiasm,
however, they all have come around to supporting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-loaf baked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sens.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Feingold</ENAMEX>; and even to rooting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the quarter</TIMEX>-loaf of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold Lite</ENAMEX>, the version now crumbling on the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            In one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> are still being wildly
optimistic. They are counting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to reverse its long-standing
doctrine on campaign regulation and freedom of speech. There are strong First
Amendment obstacles to various provisions in the bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is unlikely to
remove these, which means that even if reform does pass, it will accomplish far
less than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> intend.

            He who would wade into this swamp must first immerse
himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valeo</ENAMEX> , the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> case that made
campaign-finance reform a sadistically complicated and possibly hopeless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> was a review of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Watergate</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">campaign-finance</ENAMEX> reforms, which were supposed to cure many of the very problems
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> is supposed to cure. In general, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> upheld
restrictions on political contributions while rejecting limits on
political expenditures . The core issue was whether money equals speech.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> conceded that giving money to a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is a way of
expressing support. But it reasoned that the message "I support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X</ENAMEX>"
has little relation to the amount of money you give. However, when you spend
your money directly communicating the message "I support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X"</ENAMEX> (or "I
am candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>"), that spending is an exercise of free speech protected
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>.

            But this bright line in
principle between contributions and expenditures quickly gets fuzzy in
practice. When is spending to promote a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> really just an in-kind
contribution? If I want to spend my salary on an ad saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse D'Amato</ENAMEX>
is a distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesman</ENAMEX> and a much underrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>, I'm free to do so.
But what if I work out the text of my encomium with his campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>? The
court created a distinction between "independent" and "coordinated"
expenditures. Coordinated expenditures amount to an in-kind contribution, and
are subject to all the rules and limits.

            Even
"independent" expenditures are not free of all restrictions if they involve
"express advocacy" of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, as opposed to a discussion of the issues
that stops short of explicit endorsement. Under current law, such expenditures
must be publicly disclosed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> are forbidden to make
them (except through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX>, which raise money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and members
ostensibly on a voluntary basis and have their own set of financial limits).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, however, have become adept at devising ways to help
their favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that stop just short of "express advocacy."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feingold</ENAMEX> are valiantly attempting to
crack down on the major abuses that have sprouted in the cracks of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> ruling. The bill closes the soft-money loophole, which is the
worst abuse of the current system. Soft money is money donated to and spent by
the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, ostensibly for reasons other than direct support of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, but without limits on who may give or how much. Unfortunately, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that spending by a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> cannot
automatically be assumed to be "coordinated" with a senatorial campaign. The
effect of this decision was to establish that political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have the same
rights as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and other kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to make independent
expenditures in the vicinity of an election.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> says that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office holders</ENAMEX> and national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> leaders
can't solicit soft-money contributions to state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in order to evade the
limits on hard-money contributions--as they did so bountifully in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Some
smart <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who are doubtful about other parts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> think this kind of soft-money ban is also OK. But it will
surely be challenged.

            The reform-heads run into bigger trouble on the other two
issues: wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who spend gargantuan sums of their own money and
phony issue ads that are barely disguised campaign ads. On the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> point,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> tries to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Huffingtons</ENAMEX> of the world from
spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $50,000</NUMEX> of their own riches by forbidding political parties
from making "coordinated" expenditures on their behalf. The device is borrowed
from the rules for presidential elections, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> accept spending
limits in exchange for government subsidies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> said this was OK
because the limits were "voluntary." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> would forbid political
parties to aid their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> "voluntarily" accepted
the personal spending limit. This might well strike the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> as being more
like a stick than a carrot, making the choice not "voluntary" at all.

            The independent-expenditure
problem is the most serious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> attempts to rein in political
spending by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> through expanding the definition of
"express advocacy." In essence, the bill states that any mention of a candidate
by name within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days of Election Day</TIMEX> counts as express advocacy. This
standard would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> out of the two little old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> who, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX>'s favorite example, took out an ad in the newspaper on the eve of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>
election to protest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> contend that this redefinition is consistent with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> , what they really mean is that they hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will
be prepared to rethink <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> . Their theory is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will look
at the mess of recent elections, and decide that the line it drew <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ago in Buckley</ENAMEX> is unworkable. Well, it's a theory.

         
      
   
