
   
   
      
         
            This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time We Mean It</ENAMEX>

            
               This
Time <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Mean It</ENAMEX>
            

            Like a growing number of
journalistic Web sites (the Wall 
               Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , among others),

                  Slate
                will begin charging for access sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>.
The exact details and timetable are still being worked out, but we wanted to
let our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> know that this is coming. Yes, yes, we said we were going to do
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this a year ago</TIMEX> and blinked, but this time we really do mean it. Many things
have changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the Web in general, and
reading 
                  Slate
                in particular, has soared (see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
"Readme" for our
latest figures). We've had a chance to learn a lot about how to make

                  Slate
                better, and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, we hope, have had a chance to
learn the value of what we're doing. Also, frankly, thanks to sites like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have become comfortable with the idea of paying for
things on the Web.

            We have
maintained from the beginning of this adventure that ultimately, we would have
to count on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to bear some of the cost. It is important to us to
become self-sustaining--not out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s bottom line but
because that is the best long-term guarantee of editorial independence.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has adopted a completely hands-off policy toward

                  Slate
               's editorial content, for which we're grateful. But
obviously it's better not to be dependent on subsidies from any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> or
individual.

            One premise of 
                  Slate
                is that publishing on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> should make financial independence easier to achieve. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX>, of
course, is just one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s glories. We're working hard at

                  Slate
                to use hyperlinks, sound and video clips, e-mail, and other
technological marvels of the Internet to develop an exciting new form of
journalism. But sheer economy should not be sneered at. In fact, we believe
that making it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> like 
                  Slate
                to become
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-sustaining</ENAMEX> will be among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s great contributions to democracy.
Unlike traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, we have no costs for printing, paper, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">postage</ENAMEX>. We intend to share those savings with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>: 
                  Slate
               
will charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> far less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , The

               New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> do. But any realistic
business scenario requires that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> pay something . Like roughly
equivalent print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, and unlike some other Web sites,

                  Slate
                appeals to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that will never be broad enough to
sustain us on advertising alone. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Right now</TIMEX>, of course, there is almost no Web
site that is free because it is sustained by advertising. Sites are free
because they are subsidized, a situation that won't endure.)

            There is
evidence that, as the Web matures, the resistance to paying for content is
crumbling. Still, there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who continue to refuse, on some principle,
to even consider paying for Web content. This puzzles us. Take

                  Slate
               . ( Please. ) If your attitude is "
                  Slate
               
is boring and of no interest to me, and I refuse to pay for it," we can
understand that, if not agree with it. But if your attitude is "I really enjoy

                  Slate
               , think it's entertaining and useful, visit the site while
it's free, but refuse to contemplate paying for it," we're not just puzzled but
actually a bit hurt. Here we are, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple of dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, plus many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributors</ENAMEX>, all trying to put out the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> we can. If you like what
we're doing, please think of our feelings before you say you won't pay a few
bucks for it!

            

               FAQ
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Why should I give my
money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>? He can afford to support 
                  Slate
                without my
help.

            A: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> question. An answer
is, as above, that 
                  Slate
                doesn't want to be dependent on the
charity of any rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, even one as saintly and magnificent as our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is funding the start-up costs of 
                  Slate
                as a
business proposition and is happy to continue doing so as a business
proposition, but has no justification for asking its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> to subsidize
a permanently money-losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. Anyway, you don't expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> to
give you Windows free, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>, or Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> ... whoops! OK,
the analogy isn't perfect. But you get the idea.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slate publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers Weed</ENAMEX> will enter "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to
answer your questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> "going paid." The thread's already
active, so to make your own comments and ask any questions, click here.

            
               Speaking
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> ...
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>, our new advice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, has supplied an answer to the question
posed in this space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the question--but in brief, it
had to do with why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> had managed to discourage unwanted
pursuit by a gal named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>, when another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> had not.) Here is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>'s response:

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>,

            I think I can read your story
between the lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX> was originally attached to the first Bill, and he did
much for her. But then she found that he was making unseemly demands upon her,
including the demand to lie on his behalf. Therefore, she was conflicted,
having a love-hate relationship with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. She was reluctant to leave him
entirely, however, because her connection with him meant much to her
self-esteem. So, by a process known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> as transference, she
transferred her feelings, both positive and negative, to you, the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-most-important Bill in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. She both loves and hates your
entrepreneurial machismo.

            What are
you to do? You should make her an offer she can't refuse. Make her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
in one of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, at your standard magnificent salary. She will soon
find that relationship excessively demanding and transfer her attentions
elsewhere--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, perhaps.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: For more advice from
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Prudence,</ENAMEX> click here.

            
               We're
Dreaming of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lite Christmas</ENAMEX>
            

            Practically all the weekly
print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> take a week off over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, and last year

                  Slate
                did the same. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> we decided that it would better
serve our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to take advantage of the inherent flexibility of Web
publication by merely reducing the flow of articles, columns, and features over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas-New Year</TIMEX> period. So for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two weeks</TIMEX>, we will be publishing

                  Slate
                
               
                  Lite
               . There will still be plenty to read,
including new stuff on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days</TIMEX> (including "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>,"
except on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> themselves). And of course, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> of

                  Slate
                is at your fingertips in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>."

            And in case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Readme</ENAMEX> succumbs
to the holiday spirit and fails to appear for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX>, best holiday
wishes and thanks to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> from all of us at 
                  Slate
               .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
