
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Calling
All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poets</ENAMEX>
            

            Since 
                  Slate
               's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue, which included a poem by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Heaney</ENAMEX>, we have published only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">poems</ENAMEX> solicited by our poetry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>. That policy has helped to
establish 
                  Slate
                as a place to read and publish poetry. The policy
was also a necessity, since we didn't have a way to screen submissions. Now,
with a screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in place, we are pleased to announce that we are
accepting submissions of unsolicited poetry.

            Now listen closely. Poetry
submitted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> must be sent by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX> mail (i.e., stamped paper mail)
and accompanied by a self-addressed, stamped envelope. (No e-mail submissions,
please.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manuscripts</ENAMEX> should have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s name and address on each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> and
should be sent to 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poetry</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">236</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay State Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02215</NUMEX>. And don't forget the envelope!

            
               
                  Slate
               
publishes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poem</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. You can read it and also listen to it in the
voice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> (or, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is dead, in the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>).
Click here for this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s poem, and here for a complete list of and links to poems published in

                  Slate
               .

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate Week Off, Um, We Mean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Special Issue</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>, we
hear, is putting out a special issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, because of the historic
importance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s events involving oral sex in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. This
special issue will replace <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s regular issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . Here at

                  Slate
                we also are closing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week</TIMEX>'s issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but to be
honest it's simply because it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and we want <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> off.

            On <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought, though,
why be honest? We're not under oath or anything. And heck, even if we were
...

            So, we hereby declare this a

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate Special Issue: Oral Sex and Beyond: A Historic Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will He Survive</ENAMEX>? To recover from the weightiness of it
all, we will be posting 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lite</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28</TIMEX>. It's
not all that lite. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" will continue to be posted (and e-mailed)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"International Papers</ENAMEX>,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX>," "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>," "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Diary</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" will appear as
usual. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX>'s diarist will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX>),
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX> conversation (also beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>) will be
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Tarloff</ENAMEX>. And, of course, any important
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> in the news (war, for example, or a new semen stain) may well drag
us in off the shuffleboard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have vigorously
objected to the amount of attention the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> in general and

                  Slate
                in particular are devoting to the scandal we call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.
As a service to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, we have set up a special page
listing, and linking to, all 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Flytrap</ENAMEX> coverage.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrapophobes</ENAMEX> can use this page to learn which 
                  Slate
                articles
they may wish to avoid.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
