
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellfire</ENAMEX> and dalmations.

            
               Hellfire
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalmatians</ENAMEX>
            

            Doggonit! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> back, last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> warned the world not to believe all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> propaganda about
the charm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dalmatian puppies</ENAMEX>. Contrary to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatians</ENAMEX> --in either
its original cartoon format or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s real-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-and-real-dogs
remake--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dalmatians</ENAMEX> are not cute. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>
reported: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalmatians</ENAMEX> are high-strung. They're hyperactive. They bark too
much. They're bad with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. They shed constantly. They're hard to train.
... They are, in short, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lousy pets</ENAMEX>." Ignoring (or possibly, though it is hard
to imagine, unaware of) this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage counsel</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> went straight from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multiplex</ENAMEX> to the pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and brought home a spotted darling of their own.

            Now these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are
saying, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Macbeth</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out, damned Spot</ENAMEX>!" According to the New York
Times (building on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WABC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatians</ENAMEX> are being abandoned in droves. "Animal shelters say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have found the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs high-strung</ENAMEX>, willful and aggressive." Furthermore,
there are "health problems associated with overbreeding," including "deafness
and urinary tract problems." (These problems are manifest, in case you were
wondering, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> that result from overbreeding, not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> on
overbreeding duty.)

            Animal
rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are predicting another wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dalmatian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> when a new
TV series based on the movie begins airing. Please: Avoid taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> home
just because they seemed cute on the screen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> too, for that matter.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lamb</ENAMEX>
            

            As some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may have learned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate and America Online</ENAMEX> have come to an agreement on a new relationship.
Beginning soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> will be an "anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newsstand</ENAMEX>. (For more
details, check out the press release.) Just so there is no confusion about this, let us
be clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is not "taking over" or "swallowing up" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America Online</ENAMEX>. AOL
will continue to function as an independent online service. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> will
be free not to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> if they so desire. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, for its part, will retain
(and cherish!) its sibling relationships with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Network</ENAMEX> (MSN) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>. All will be peaceful and joyous. Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> does retain the right
to swallow up <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> at some future date.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shameless Promotions</ENAMEX>
            

            If you haven't yet tried
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slate Explorer</ENAMEX>, a new way to--well, to explore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, you can find out more
about it and get instructions on how to download the free software by clicking
here. If you haven't yet tried voting on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dialogues</ENAMEX>," click here to visit one of our newest ones--on harassment and freedom of
speech--and vote your brains out.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
