
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Symbol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX>, the
pudgy-faced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> among social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> for producing a big majority vote in favor of his
proposed ban on partial-birth abortions. Even pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have declared
themselves impressed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santorum</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> more votes than he did the last
time his bill came up, and that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">converts</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> (who emitted a stream of gobbledygook when asked to
explain his flip-flop).

            But it
may be worth noting that thanks to his victory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> will be responsible
for more, not fewer, abortions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Here's why: As the debate
heated up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> offered a compromise that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was
apparently willing to support. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>'s alternative would have gone far beyond
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santorum</ENAMEX> has proposed, banning abortions by any method once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is
"viable." The point of viability is now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 22 weeks</TIMEX> into a pregnancy
(and seems likely to be stalled there absent some huge scientific
breakthrough--see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist"</ENAMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santorum</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>'s proposal in favor of his
own narrower ban.

            Why would a believing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santorum</ENAMEX> attach a
higher priority to prohibiting a grotesque-seeming but relatively rare practice
than to curtailing--perhaps significantly--the number of abortions performed
nationally? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santorum</ENAMEX> himself has contended that partial-birth abortions are
never necessary--from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s point of view. If his partial-birth ban
becomes law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> could still get a late-term abortion using a different
method. But under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>'s proposal, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-term</TIMEX> abortions of all types would
become illegal, except in cases where there was a dire threat to the mother's
health. What's more, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> indicated that he would have signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>
alternative, which would have made it the law of the land. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has pledged
to veto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX>'s bill. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> preferred having an issue
with which to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to achieving a genuine victory. He hinted at this
reasoning at the press conference he held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> after the vote. "We've got
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> up for re-election," he told reporters. "I wouldn't want to be home
defending this vote anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

            That
choice is the essence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> draw upon symbols and
symbolic issues like partial-birth abortion, which often have little real-world
consequences. Few, though, can match <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> in the pursuit of political
symbolism to the detriment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. In his quest for wedge issues,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> has managed, in his short time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> look
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of principle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Warner</ENAMEX> like a deep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Manners</ENAMEX>.

            
Like many on the right who decry the role of
government, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> is largely a product of it. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martinsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W. Va.</ENAMEX>, where
he lived until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 7</TIMEX>, both his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans</ENAMEX>'
Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>. With the help of student loans, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> attended
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>, then got an MBA from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and a law degree
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>. He bought his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with the help of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
low-income-housing assistance program. His only exposure to life in the private
sector was a brief stint as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> (where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> included
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wrestling Federation</ENAMEX>). Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> can sound like a militia
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> when he gets busy denouncing big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>: "I've read the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.
Nowhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> does it say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will be here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years from now</TIMEX>,"
he said at a rally in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. "We can blow this. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can fail. This
government can take your freedom. I know you feel safe for now ... but don't
give up your freedoms. Don't give up your freedom." In the article in which
these comments were quoted, his tone of voice was described as an impassioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">whisper</ENAMEX>.

            After he
was elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santorum</ENAMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the so-called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group of Seven</ENAMEX>," a clique that prefigured the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gang</ENAMEX>'s chief issue was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Bank</ENAMEX> scandal and their goal, to force full
disclosure of the number of checks bounced by various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Their
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-biggest issue was opposition to congressional pay raises. While he tried
to incite the public about these totemic reform issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> immersed
himself in the far more subversive legal corruption of the campaign-finance
system. His biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> were the pharmaceutical and medical-insurance
industries, impressed with his implacable resistance to health-care reform. In
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, he has remained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in his doctrinaire
opposition to any kind of meaningful campaign-finance reform.

            Hepped up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>-training tapes, Santorum
announced his plans to run against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris Wofford</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The
winning campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> ran was notable for its uncalled-for personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nastiness</ENAMEX>. Responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wofford</ENAMEX>'s support for national service, Santorum
smirked, "Someone's going to pick up trash in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and sing 'Kumbayah' around
a campfire and you're going to give them <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of the benefits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fictitiously</ENAMEX> claimed that those enrolled in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX> received
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, then accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wofford</ENAMEX> of being dishonest. "I have never seen
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in my life who would stand up in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and tell
lies, absolute lies, the way he does," he fulminated.

            At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>,
Santorum became the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and made a name for treating
fainthearted older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> with the same boorishness and
arrogance he had displayed toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wofford</ENAMEX>. Shortly after being elected, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attacked Mark Hatfield</ENAMEX>, the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, for refusing to provide
the margin of victory in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote on the balanced-budget amendment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> proposed punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> by stripping him of his chairmanship of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appropriations Committee</ENAMEX>. That, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> reasoned, was how things worked in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. The effort was roundly defeated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Caucus</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX>'s personal unpleasantness and affinity
for injecting religion into politics have led many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> to cast him as a
sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX>'s voting record on many
issues is more in line with the moderate profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> is rarely on the losing side of any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80-20</NUMEX> vote
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Though he is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to the environmental movement, he is
relatively pro-union. He supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposed ban on permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX> and voted for an increase in the minimum wage.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> looks in vain, however,
for any thread of consistent belief. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX> is pro-life, but supports the
death penalty; he opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>, but favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX>; he wants to balance the
budget while providing more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>. Unlike some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrades</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, who are principled in their bullheaded way, he never
met a principle he wouldn't swap for a few more votes. As he cultivates the
impression that he is standing on his convictions in the partial-birth abortion
fight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX> is in reality doing just the opposite.

         
      
   
