
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department Settlement</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department Settlement</ENAMEX>
            

            In settlement of a dispute
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
                has agreed to discontinue
"bundling" its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back of the Book</ENAMEX> with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. We take this
opportunity to inform our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that they are under no obligation to read the
music or movie reviews, or to follow the gardening column, or to listen to the
poem, in order to consume the news and political analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subscribers</ENAMEX> to 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                who wish to receive a
culture-free edition, with all the reviews and other artsy-fartsy stuff sliced
out at no extra charge, can e-mail us at philistine@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and we'll be
happy to oblige.

            It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s position in this controversy that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of news analysis and
a review of culture are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fundamentally different products, and that

                  Slate
               's merging of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was a subtle effort to foist culture
on an unwilling political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>. It was 
                  Slate
               's position
that the typical 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> is highly educated, civic-minded,
intellectually curious, culturally sensitive--also brave, debonair, and
sweet-smelling--and that these admirable qualities are intertwined, leading
each of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to value a wide variety of 
                  Slate
                offerings.
"The so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'front' and 'back'</ENAMEX> parts of 
                  Slate
                are as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inseparable</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX> and Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>," declared

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publisher Rogers Weed</ENAMEX>. "And everybody knows you can't get
more inseparable than that."

            In such situations we like
to ask ourselves, what would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lakshmi Gopalkrishnan</ENAMEX> have done? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakshmi</ENAMEX> is

                  Slate
               's co-managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and, as it happens, her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is just
down the hall, so the easy thing would have been to go and ask her. But the
easy thing is not always the right thing. And our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of
combined experience as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> tell us that the
right thing is to speculate. We speculate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakshmi</ENAMEX> would have wanted
us to settle. So we settled.

            In
response to 
                  Slate
               's concessions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> personally
agreed to drop a demand that 
                  Slate
                review more mystery novels
and, in the language of the DOJ brief, "get rid of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> with all
deliberate speed."

            
               Fresh
Blood
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> joins

                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> as a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s first book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> , a description of his life at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon Brothers</ENAMEX>, is the
definitive account of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> on Wall Street. His most recent book, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Fever</ENAMEX> , is a highly idiosyncratic and entertaining account of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
election. The words "entertaining" and "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election" don't sit easily
together, but take our word for it. Or, better yet, buy
the book.

            For

                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> will be engaged in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearlong</TIMEX> project to update
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Whyte</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Organization Man</ENAMEX> , the classic book about the
business culture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. He will be filing dispatches <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>, from his
base in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> and elsewhere, and we hope they will add up to an
equally compelling portrait of the business culture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> column will appear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 28</TIMEX> (or thereabouts).

            
               Welcome
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX>
            

            A hearty
welcome--or "HWELLLLL-kum," as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> puts it--to our new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
Online. 
                  Slate
                is scheduled to take up residence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 27</TIMEX>,
as an anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s news-channel newsstand. Of course

                  Slate
                continues to be available on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSN</ENAMEX> and directly on the Web at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               And for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America Offline</ENAMEX> ...
            

            There is
yet another new way to read 
                  Slate
               , or at least a part of it. The

                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Briefing</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX> is open for business on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Download</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IE4</ENAMEX> here if you want.
Or--yes, fine, OK--download the latest version of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX> here.) The 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Briefing</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX> is an automatic
daily download of new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> from 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Briefing</ENAMEX> section
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"In Other</ENAMEX>
Magazines," etc.). If you've installed Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>, click here for more about (and
a chance to download) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>.

            
               And for
You Netscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> ...
            

            We love you too.

                  Slate
                and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> have agreed in principle for

                  Slate
                to join <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inbox Direct</ENAMEX> program, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delivers Web</ENAMEX> pages directly to your e-mail inbox. Coming soon.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
