
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Microsoft</ENAMEX>

            To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Top Management</ENAMEX>

            From:
Jacobwe

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
Unsolicited Advice

            I am one
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who has embarked on the experiment of working for a software
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. I probably speak for all of us when I say that it has been
interesting. Recently, it's been especially interesting. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months ago</TIMEX>,
everyone I met seemed to think that working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was a pretty cool
thing to do. Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> treat us like we work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s current legal and public-relations headaches leave me, personally, in
an awkward position. I've devoted a good chunk of my career as a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> to criticizing the mercenary culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: influence
peddlers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PACs</ENAMEX>, and so on. Suddenly, I find myself working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with
big political problems. My bluff has been called. With my own prosperity
possibly at stake, would I urge my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> to remain aloof from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bazaar</ENAMEX>?

            No one else seems to share my disquiet. Ironically, one of
the charges leveled against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> of late is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has sinned by
not playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> influence game forcefully enough. Only now,
the analysis goes, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill G.</ENAMEX> realizing his mistake in neglecting to hire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, dole out huge campaign contributions, and so on. The theme of a
recent front-page story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> was that the failure to
flex political muscle demonstrates an arrogance and stubbornness for which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is now paying the price.

            The charge
of lacking respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> blurs the issues. It confuses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the valid
observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> often has a haughty attitude in general; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the at
least arguable contention that it has run afoul of antitrust law; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the
plausible suggestion that hiring more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, etc., would be a smart thing
to do; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) the entirely absurd notion that refusing to pay tribute inside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> amounts to some kind of ethical failing. Sit out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
legalized-bribery game? Why, that's downright un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>!

            
As you know, it's a bit of a myth that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is only now noticing the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> filed suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20</TIMEX>, the government-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has hired no
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, in-house or on contract. The old roster is intact. It includes
such hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist Jr.</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>,
and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vin Weber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Downey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, who happens to
be one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norquist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX> have worked for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> for some time, as have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Deaver</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>, who do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>,
has been in operation since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1995</TIMEX>. Before that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had the help
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston Gates Ellis & Rouvelas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meeds</ENAMEX>--as it still does. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has lobbied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the executive
branch on all the issues that matter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>: Internet freedom, encryption
policy, immigration for high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the tax-deductibility of stock
options, extending the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX> tax credit, software piracy abroad, taxation
of Internet commerce, and so on.

            At the
same time, I'm sure you will agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is somewhat diffident about
playing politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> contributions to both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the last election cycle. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43,500</NUMEX>. I can't say whether
you have kept your political profile low for the right reason--maybe you were
just cheap, or lazy, or out of your depth on the other coast. But whatever the
cause, I would argue that your relative passivity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is something to
be proud of. You haven't tried to corrupt the democratic process by handing out
wads of cash. You have done less than any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> approaching your size to
underwrite the sleazy business of influence peddling. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> isn't
looking for favors from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, it resists paying a fee to
self-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> gets no credit for this stance. Mother
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> has a piece in its new issue blasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> for politicking in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, which gives you the distinction of being attacked both for lobbying
and not lobbying in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same month</TIMEX>.

            The practical issue is much harder than the ethical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
Sure, the world would be a better place if there was no corporate money in
politics, and no hired-gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, as it would if there were no land mines
or nuclear weapons. But can <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> disarm unilaterally? Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Public Integrity</ENAMEX>--the least compromising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of the
revolving door--was quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> suggesting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has to do what everyone else does. Other stories have pointed out
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> are hauling out the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> recently signed, among
others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> (who couldn't even give his own Internet address correctly on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> television) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">domestic-policy adviser</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as their salvation. How can you fail to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mount</ENAMEX> a defense?

            I can't in
good conscience argue that you shouldn't field a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Modern legislation and
regulation are technical and complex. Any big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> needs skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
can process the implications of proposed changes and argue for its interests. I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regretfully</ENAMEX> acknowledge that it may even make practical sense to have a few
hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norquist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber</ENAMEX> around--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of value only for
their connections to power, not for any knowledge or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>.

            
Don't get me wrong--I think that what these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do for a living is slimy. They're not all equally bad, but I have
trouble deciding who is worse. Is it the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norquist</ENAMEX>, who
defied subpoenas from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson Committee</ENAMEX> about his role laundering campaign
contributions for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> (he is contemptuous
of the law)? Or is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Watergate</ENAMEX> Class
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'74</NUMEX> who wants everyone to think of him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> even as he sells his
connections to anyone who can pay his fee?

            Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quandary</ENAMEX>: Is it worse for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> to exploit their personal relationships
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, or to sell the illusion that they are doing so?
After years of covering lobbying, my impression is that the business is about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> con. You never know for sure what you're getting, which,
unfortunately, is an argument for ponying up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX>-dollar
issues at stake. At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120,000</NUMEX> a year for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norquist</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160,000</NUMEX> a year for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX>, it's a cheap lottery ticket. And odd as it sounds, hiring influence
peddlers generates good will on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think
of themselves as underpaid, there's hostility toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> based on the
fact that he's got a lot of dough and doesn't share it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like them.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, in particular, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>-inclined
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that is never going to hire them when they're ready to go through the
revolving door. This is a pretty venal outlook, but it's built into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> operating system the way, say, Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> is said to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> into Windows. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> can easily separate
Windows and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> if it wants to, but nobody would claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> can
single-handedly re-create the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            There are, however, advantages to not being heavy hitters
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>. Refusing to pay an unjustified toll may be contemptuous of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, but it's respectful of democracy. In a way, I think it has already
helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s image. You've been slammed for not throwing your weight
around in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, but would certainly be criticized much more if you did throw it
around. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has been defensive about its low-key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> role when it
could legitimately be boasting about it.

            Of course it's hard to brag
about your reluctance to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> sleazeballs when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deaver</ENAMEX> on your payroll. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deaver</ENAMEX> isn't just an ordinary convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX>. He was
on the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>-- making a phone call from his limousine--as the
symbol of the influence-peddling excesses of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. I'm sure he experienced
a great deal of personal growth during his community service, but he's not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> to organize a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> blitz around the theme of restraint in playing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> game.

         
      
   
