
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ox</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ox</ENAMEX>
            

            It used to be, of course,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> were all for tough laws against sexual harassment and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> complained that such laws create a sexual reign of terror.
Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> were great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> for the appointment of independent
counsels or special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> condemned these
investigations as "witch hunts" or, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">la-di-da</ENAMEX> mode, as the "criminalization
of political differences." Now those roles are usually reversed.

            Let us be charitable and
assume that these conversions are a sincere response to the scandals
surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX>, unimpressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>, didn't previously realize just how corrupt and disgusting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> could be. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, until one of their own got caught up in them,
didn't appreciate how onerous and unfair these laws are. Certainly my friend
and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Rosen</ENAMEX> writes in total
good faith. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>--brilliantly fulfilling the ancient journalistic dictum "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sell</ENAMEX>
every piece <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times"--has argued in the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s troubles are due to
catastrophic defects in the sexual-harassment and special-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> laws (with
help from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s own misbehavior, he always is careful to add).

            This is
an extremely tempting argument for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX>. Reversing your
opinion on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> moderately important points of law is far less painful than
reversing your opinion on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--and possibly the last--ideologically
compatible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX>. But will it wash? Unfortunately, I don't
think so.

            Problem <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> business happened to become
public due to the interplay between sexual harassment (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit)
and the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, but there are many other ways it might have done
so. Irony-pumping narratives noting that "if not for" this or that, everything
would be different--a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' device--are like saying that if not
for a particular bus, you wouldn't be at work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> come along. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was as reckless as many now assume, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and others, it's a
miracle he got away with it this long. Changing the sexual-harrassment and
special-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> laws won't begin to guarantee that information like this
won't become public. No matter how you define the problem--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s possible
misbehavior, false accusations of misbehavior, or accurate public revelation of
behavior that ought to stay private--this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> doesn't solve it.

            
Problem 2 is sexual harrassment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> argues
that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> is telling the truth--and even if the statute of
limitations on sexual harrassment hadn't expired, leading her to sue on a more
exotic theory--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> behavior she describes does not amount to sexual
harrassment under the law. But, he notes, the law allows the case to proceed
anyway, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overgenerous</ENAMEX> discovery rules allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to find out
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, drag her into the case, and force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to commit
perjury by denying the affair.

            I defer
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> on whether the scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> describes, if it happened,
constitutes illegal sexual harrassment. But if it doesn't, the
sexual-harrassment laws need to be strengthened, not weakened. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> orders state troopers to summon a lowly state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> to a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>,
where he exposes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> to her and says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss it</ENAMEX>." Sexual-harrassment law
may be dangerously broad and vague, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> says, but if this is not
considered sexual harrassment, it surely ought to be--even if there is no quid
pro quo and even if he backs off and zips up when she declines. Is it really an
abusive invasion of privacy for the law to insist that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> not do
that?

            Problem 3 is the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> or special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>
(or independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> or special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> ...). The basic logic of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> is: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> should not be trusted to investigate itself.
Nothing in our experience since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was institutionalized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>--either abuses by individual special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> (of which there have been
some) or fair and honest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> investigations of administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> (of which there also have been some) undermines this basic logic. An
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is the only realistic way criminal behavior by those in
power can be credibly investigated and--equally important--the only way falsely
accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> can be credibly vindicated.

            There are
sundry complaints about the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> as that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> has
evolved. One is that the very appointment of a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is a
politically traumatic affair and implies guilt. Another is that independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counsels</ENAMEX>, once appointed, turn into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ahabs</ENAMEX>. Their charter, unlike normal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>', is to pursue a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> rather than a particular crime.
Their every incentive is to prosecute, since failure to prosecute suggests that
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> was needless. Their pursuit is not hampered by many of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> and policy restraints that cool the zeal of normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. (These
               Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
editorial page almost any random day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, although not during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX>.)

            
Some of these complaints are valid. But the
solution is not to give up on special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. The solution is to make the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> a permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, rather than appointing a new one
every time a scandal or alleged scandal comes along. Unless the political
culture changes drastically, there will always be one or more independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> investigating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and/or past
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administrations</ENAMEX>, anyway. Referring some matter to a permanent independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> would be far less fraught than appointing a new independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> and would carry less of a stigma. A permanent independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> could be held more easily to reasonable financial and
procedural guidelines. A permanent independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> would not
need to feel that its reputation depended on prosecuting and convicting
everyone it investigated.

            There
would still be an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ahab</ENAMEX> syndrome. In fact a permanent independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> would institutionalize the current de facto reality that special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> hold high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to a fussier standard of law-abiding
than what the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> faces. That's OK. Those who enforce the law on
the rest of us ought to be more law-abiding than the average. If the speed
limit is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55 mph</NUMEX>, off-duty highway cops should drive at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>, even if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62 or 63</TIMEX> is
close enough for the rest of us. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> have to keep glancing
over their shoulders to see if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> is chasing them with a harpoon, that
is no bad thing. It might even be a nice tradition for the permanent
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s office always to be run by someone from the opposing
party.

            We all have learned recently, for example, that even
outright lying under oath in a deposition for a civil case is the kind of thing
that an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> apparently does not often get prosecuted for (though
it's not clear why not--especially when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> in the case).
Even under a reformed independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> law, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would be more at
risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>--or at least of public exposure and humiliation--for this
transgression than the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>. Is that such a terrible thing?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some day</TIMEX> there will be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> again, and the Wall 
               Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
will rediscover all its objections to independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, will be glad the law is still around. And who knows? Sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harrassment</ENAMEX> isn't unknown among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, either.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
