
   
   
      
         
            Hackathalon

            
               The
Hackathlon
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commentator</ENAMEX>, is (we think) the original source of a profound insight on the
nature of journalism--indeed, on human nature. "The most important quality any
piece of writing can have," he says, "is doneness ." (A related remark is
attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX>: "I don't like writing. I like having
written.")

            It is in this spirit that

                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> kicks off its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackathlon</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathlon</ENAMEX> will be officiated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>, who apparently
feels there isn't enough bad writing in 
                  Slate
               . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>
self-proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> (insert earnest demurral here: Oh, no, they're actually
extremely talented, etc., etc., etc.) will compete in trying to produce a piece
in a hurry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> will vote on whose work comes closest to resembling a
respectable work of journalism. Since true hackability is fearless and
fungible, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> will be tested in a variety of journalistic
genres.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s hackathletes
are: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Specter</ENAMEX> of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna Rosin</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Wheatcroft</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> too numerous to mention. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathlon</ENAMEX> is a
world-class event: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gladwell</ENAMEX> will be filing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>; Rosin from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheatcroft from Bath</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shafer</ENAMEX>
will officiate from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX> Here are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shafer</ENAMEX>'s instructions to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>:

            "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each Saturday</TIMEX>, I will
e-mail each hack a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathlon</ENAMEX> topic, a cheat sheet (notes, quotes, and facts),
and the name of a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> whose style each hack is expected to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ape</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> will have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> to complete the assignment and e-mail me at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hack Central</ENAMEX>. If any hack takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer than two hours</TIMEX> to complete his/her
assignment, we will report this transgression on the page with his/her
copy.

            "The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> events: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Op-Ed</ENAMEX> (maximum length, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> words); a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town</ENAMEX>" (maximum length, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> words); the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> Words of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> profile; a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breaking News Story</ENAMEX>.

            "Don't write parody. As one
accomplished hack put it, the essence of hackery is 'adjusting to a minimum of
information to produce the maximum journalistic effect.' Actually, he went on a
little longer to fill the available space. I've taken the liberty of truncating
his remarks.

            "The collected hackwork will
be posted on 
                  Slate
                on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four successive Tuesdays</TIMEX>, beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> will be invited to vote for the best hackwork in each event. The
hack who collects the most votes will be declared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> and be invited to
return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to face <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX>. The cheat sheets will be published for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' inspection.

            "Prepare
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yourselves</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader</ENAMEX>
Survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round</ENAMEX> 2
            

            While the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> are hacking away, we've got homework for you as well. But it will take a
lot <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than two hours</TIMEX>. We'd be grateful if you took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> to fill out
our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> survey. It will be on our site for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>,
beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 7</TIMEX>. All the questions are easy: "What is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>?" "Who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX>?" "What is your
credit-card number?" That sort of thing. E-mail 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
will get the survey by e-mail. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 4,000</NUMEX> 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> answered our survey. They seemed to enjoy it, and it was extremely
helpful to us. Thanks.

            

               Correction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sort Of</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millionerds</ENAMEX>"
column, as originally posted, stated that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.J. Rodgers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cypress Semiconducter</ENAMEX>--despises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil Amelio</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>
Computer, because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amelio</ENAMEX>'s support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The article was
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 4</TIMEX>), and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> we had received half
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> e-mail messages from various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> establishing beyond question, with
supportive documentation, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelio</ENAMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. So, in keeping with our policy, the article was amended. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> did tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> that he despises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amelio</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amelio</ENAMEX> supported
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, so it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX>' mistake, not our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s, that we are
correcting.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
