
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX> Foretold

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s snap decision
to schedule an immediate debate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> represents an important opening
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX>, the main vehicle for campaign-finance
reform. But do not suppose that the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> has developed any sympathy
for a bill that would ban soft money, limit independent expenditures, and
tighten disclosure requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have a huge stake in the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, under which they out-raised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> in the last
election cycle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Incumbents</ENAMEX> have an even bigger edge over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX>. Thus, for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, to permit the playing field to be
leveled would be to go beyond good sportsmanship. It would be an act of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">self-immolation.</ENAMEX>

            But even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s motive
for offing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> remains as powerful as ever, carrying out the hit no
longer looks so simple. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>'s hearings have done what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">henchmen Don Nickles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX> feared they would do--they have
dramatized the general horror of the current system more than they have the
particular excesses of the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Simply dismissing reform as
unnecessary--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s approach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as a few months ago</TIMEX>--no longer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suffices</ENAMEX>. At the same time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> can't be too brazen. To
count on party discipline to reject <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feingold</ENAMEX> outright, or to use the
power of the gavel to prevent it from coming to the floor, would be to court a
public backlash and a revolt within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX>. That kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> can make a party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> look bad.

            So a
straightforward machine-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> massacre is out. Thanks to the baroque vestiges of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> procedure, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> still have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> at their
disposal: the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> pick, the poisoned umbrella tip, the exploding cigar, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> shark tank, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> buzz saw, quicksand, car bombs, a variety of
slow-acting toxins, the complete works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carol Oates</ENAMEX>, and their bare
hands. (Some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> are, of course, too barbaric to actually use.)
Here's the best current thinking about how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are likely to try
to snuff their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> universally expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> try attaching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more killer amendments . The idea here is a
booby trap. You add something offensive that doesn't alter the appearance of
the bill, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to support it while compelling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to vote
against it. The most probable amendment is one that expands on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX> decision. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, the court ruled that union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have
a right to demand a refund of the portion of their dues spent on politics.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> would "codify" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> , by requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to notify their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickles</ENAMEX> argues for what is known as a "hard
Beck
               " provision, which would go further, giving union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> a
chance to opt out permanently. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> considers this non-negotiable, as do
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. They argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> may spend money on politics
without offering a rebate to dissatisfied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
tack on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickles</ENAMEX> amendment, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> might even filibuster to block
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX>, which otherwise has their unanimous support.

            The
advantage of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beck</ENAMEX> -based amendment is that it would create a version of
the bill friendly to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> interests to counter what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> can argue is a
version beneficial to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. But assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> does not persuade any
of the bill's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Collins</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>--he would need all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> of his remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to win
the vote. The fate of reform will then rest with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> from strong
labor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer Abraham</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> loses on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX> , he may try other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> amendments,
such as one that would abolish the public financing of presidential campaigns
and get rid of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> tax checkoff that pays for it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s side
think the votes on these amendments will be decisive. If they can fend off the
Klingons, it will demonstrate a majority for genuine reform.

            
In that event, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> may try to undermine the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> in back-room negotiations . This would be more in the line of
judicial murder. For example, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> might agree to ban soft money--but
only in exchange for deregulating hard money. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConnell</ENAMEX> would like to end all
limits on direct contributions. Short of that, he would like to raise the limit
on total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> contributions by any individual from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000 to $75,000</NUMEX>.
Because both a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and his/her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> can give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, this would
mean that he or she could effectively contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> in an election
cycle--not unlimited money, but pretty close. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Wertheimer</ENAMEX> of Democracy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>,
a reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, notes other recondite anti-reform measures that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> might try
to sneak in. He might try to undo the ban on direct corporate and labor
contributions that has been in effect since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX> or undo soft-money
restrictions by leaving state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> free to dabble in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>.

            The
burden of resisting these feints will fall partly on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> but principally on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>--who, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> POW, survived torture in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> holds out for a strong bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> may have no
alternative to an old-fashioned filibuster . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> will probably need not just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> votes for victory (with the tie
to be broken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>) but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> votes to invoke "cloture" and break a
thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can remain in control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 20 years</TIMEX> if
they can defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX>. He has said he is ready to use any means
necessary. A truly diabolical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, he could read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Buchwald</ENAMEX> columns on the
floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> until even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> cries <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>.

            This kind of public execution of reform would look
terrible, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> might try to mitigate a filibuster by offering as a
substitute his own phony reform bill . Think of this as a "pod" or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">replicate</ENAMEX> version of campaign-finance reform. It might contain a grab bag of
changes tied to revelations about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, such as banning
contributions from domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, phone
solicitations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom</ENAMEX>.
But surely this wouldn't satisfy anyone. And one downside would be the implicit
admission that most of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> did in the last election wasn't
illegal.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>-Feingold gains
enough shame-leverage to pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, expect an attempt to kill it in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, who argues that we need more money in campaigns,
not less, expressed his die-hard opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. He
could use the complex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rules to smother the bill. If some sort of
momentum carries the idea through both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>, differences between the two
versions would still need to be ironed out in conference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> . This
would provide additional opportunities for sabotage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conferees</ENAMEX> appointed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> could insert a poison pill that would 1) move
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to vote against final passage or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) be bait for a presidential veto.
They could also implant a constitutional depth charge , by burying
something that violates the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> and would be likely to result in
the whole mess being thrown out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.

            And that's just the stuff
they've thought of so far . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain-Feingold</ENAMEX> may be a bill with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
lives. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> knows that there are many, many ways for it to die.

         
      
   
