
   
   
      
         
            Big-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tent Democrats</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> I noted that while
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are quarreling in a self-destructive way, like old-fashioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> appear to have learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s lesson about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submerging</ENAMEX> internal differences for the sake of victory. Can this be true?

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are doing less infighting, it isn't because they've reached some sort
of ideological consensus. On the main issues of domestic and economic policy,
the disagreements among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are greater than the gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> think balancing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> is a big mistake. Self-styled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> regard it as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
proudest accomplishment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> are still smarting over the fact that he
signed the welfare-reform bill. To centrists, it was a moral and political leap
forward. Labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> are intent on stopping trade liberalization. Globalizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> think it's curtains if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> doesn't get to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, the trade fight is getting pretty nasty. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> feel unappreciated for the role they played in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s re-election, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike left them in a truculent mood. But
even with its new militancy, labor seems to recognize that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-loaf of an
impure <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is vastly preferable to no loaf--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Others on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s left manifest an even more striking change in attitude. Take a look
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Majority</ENAMEX> , a recent collection of essays by left-wing economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">populists</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As recently as a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, many of these left <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
couldn't go a paragraph without denouncing the moderating tendencies of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership Council</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, most offer only a gentle tug in the
opposite direction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Starr</ENAMEX>, a sociology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> who was once
a harsh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrats</ENAMEX>, writes that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> won't fly without
both of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>." Building the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bridge</ENAMEX> , a collection put out earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX>-affiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Policy Institute</ENAMEX>, omits the usual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> tirades against the paleolibs. Note, however, that the motivation in both
cases is pragmatic agreement-to-disagree (what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Atwater</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, used to call "the big tent") rather than any genuine ideological
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convergence</ENAMEX>.

            
Part of the explanation for the warming trend
is that the most divisive issues of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and '80s</TIMEX> have faded. There's no
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fratricide</ENAMEX> on defense and foreign policy because after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
there's little to get fratricidal about. On cultural issues, many of the scabs
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> used to love to pick have healed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> offers a
wonderful example of how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> used to act. After the bruising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy-Carter</ENAMEX> convention fight in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Organization for Women</ENAMEX>
refused to endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>--over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>! That wouldn't happen
today, largely because the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights no longer divides either the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> or the larger society. (And that is because on this issue, among
others, the left has carried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>--despite the bromide that ideology has
ended because conservative ideas have won.)

            Of
course, there still are divisive social issues. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has done a
shrewd job of abandoning the losing issues while turning the rest to the
party's advantage. He surrendered on the death penalty, welfare, and civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberties</ENAMEX> while sticking with abortion, gun control, and affirmative action.
This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> offers something to centrist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> and something to the
party's interest-group <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>.

            But the chief reason for relative harmony is the object
lesson of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few</TIMEX> elections. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> of their
Yugoslav tendencies, and they have decided they'd better learn to live
together. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, they were more or less tricked into making common cause.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> touched all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s erogenous zones, wooing each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> into
the illusion that he loved it alone. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inauguration</ENAMEX>, each awoke to the
realization that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was a policy polygamist. Disappointed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s too-sweeping health-care-reform plan and his failure to cut spending,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DLC</ENAMEX> trashed him openly and, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, even considered breaking off from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Disenchanted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pursuit of free-trade expansion, labor
largely sat out the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> midterm.

            That
election taught all of them that there are things worse than partial victory.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> new and old found the
unifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of a common enemy. Whether you wanted charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
tradable pollution credits or higher pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> mandates, you
didn't want the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to abdicate all responsibility for education
and the environment. And with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> defending against an
anti-government assault wave, there was no need to settle on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
agenda. The question of what new programs to support would be a largely
theoretical exercise, at least for a while.

            
But as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Newt peril</ENAMEX> fades, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
differences are becoming clearer. The first thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> disagrees about is
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> recovered and won re-election. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> point to a poll by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>. It showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX> of those
who voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> did so because of his support for domestic
programs--his defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, education, and the environment.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 31 percent</NUMEX> of those who voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did so because of his "centrist"
positions--a balanced budget and welfare reform. New <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, on the other
hand, point to a post-election study by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Penn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won because of his centrism and his emphasis on
values issues. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> contends that "downscale" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> provided
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s margin of victory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> argues it was middle-income,
middle-of-the-road suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who swung the election.

            Each
analysis supports a political ideology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> to
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> can win future elections by identifying
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Those in the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> are threatened by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX> and technological change. They look to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to mitigate the
new economy's negative consequences. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> should thus support, and not in
any way privatize or drastically reform, the successful social-insurance
programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> that made it popular with downscale
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. Beyond that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> agenda should be to
extend new benefits like universal health care and child care.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrats</ENAMEX> disagree with all this. They
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> must identify with the moral and economic concerns of a
largely suburban middle class. For these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> offers more
promise than hazard. New <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> don't want any expensive new federal
programs, and they want to remake most of the old ones with market-based
ideas.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has developed a
rhetoric and a series of positions that span this divide. He supports
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>" and the "future" without specifying which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> or what future.
Initiatives like community policing and expanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>
appeal to all parties in the debate. But what happens after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? Many on
both sides anticipate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> will be a showdown,
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> representing the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> standing in for the
new. But it may not shake out that way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> might or might not emerge as a
serious challenger to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. The election could just as easily be a contest
among several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--all of them trying to emulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s flight on both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>. That was
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> tried to do after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. It worked well for a while, until it
didn't work at all.

         
      
   
