
   
   
      
         
            Spin Out

            For a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> an
hour to spin the press, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert S. Bennett</ENAMEX> sometimes does a remarkably clumsy
job of it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his more ham-handed efforts was made evident on the front
page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 2</TIMEX>, in an article about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the sexual-harassment suit filed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> working with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> acknowledge that they spent
several <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> questioning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who said he had an intimate
relationship with Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>," the dispatch noted. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, whom they declined
to identify, was flown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and put up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who
said he provided a sworn statement about her behavior."

            This
looked like low-rent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> and legal work for several reasons. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the
diaphanous curtain from behind which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wizard</ENAMEX> speaks. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> himself was
not the source of this "acknowledgement," he evidently authorized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> to dish it out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil A. Lewis</ENAMEX>, who has written
generously about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> in the past. If you're not going to conceal your
leaking better than that, why not take credit for the information directly?

            But more important and more disturbing, at least from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s point of view, is what the leak represented in terms of defense
strategy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, who had spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late Edition making veiled and not-so-veiled threats to dredge up Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' sexual history (threats from which he backed off later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>), was
pushing a counterproductive tactic even further. By threatening to blackmail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> managed to make his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> look guilty as hell,
enrage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> who had refrained from criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> until then, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incite</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, while doing nothing to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> back to the settlement table. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s only accomplishment was a
rather dubious one: getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to violate its own standards of
fairness by printing a nasty smear--an unspecified allegation from an unnamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuser</ENAMEX>, passed along by an anonymous, if easily identified, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> has done a fine job for any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, including former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar Weinberger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Clifford</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neanderthal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cincinnati Reds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marge Schott</ENAMEX>. But the display of bluster in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
and on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is the wrong lawyer
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is telling the truth to any
significant degree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should find a way to settle the case as quickly and
as quietly as possible, keeping intact as many shreds of dignity as he has
left. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wheeler-dealer</ENAMEX>, and a loudmouth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX> seems to be doing
just the opposite: dragging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> deeper into the lurid morass, while
accentuating the public spectacle of his disgrace.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, of course, must share credit for the
foolish effort to intimidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> noted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, he had talked with
his client before going on the air, and it's hard to imagine they didn't
discuss this approach to the suit. And in a larger sense, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> gets the
blame for hiring a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> known for playing hardball and winning ugly. Every
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> remarks on his early aptitude for pugilism. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>,
according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> paid him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> he
didn't get into a fight back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flatbush</ENAMEX>, the tough <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> neighborhood where
he and younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> grew up before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.
As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX> was an apprentice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Corcoran</ENAMEX> (a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tommy the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cork</ENAMEX>), a legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> who became the prototype of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>
as fixer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> has done well for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity clients</ENAMEX> in the past not by
convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>, but by waging media and lobbying battles on their behalf,
often with incredible chutzpah.

            His
paradigmatic success was his work on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> won the
battle against <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Walsh</ENAMEX> by turning the
case against the prosecution. He charged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
Brosnahan was a partisan <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> pursuing an old and sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and (ironic in
light of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s effort to dirty up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>) delving into irrelevant
aspects of his personal life. Disingenuously but effectively, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> claimed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> was trying to blackmail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX> into telling falsehoods about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> lobbied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--and lobbied key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> to lobby the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--for a pardon. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four and a half years</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> pardoned him, the supposedly deathly ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX> looks pretty
good.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s most conspicuous failure--his only conspicuous
failure, in fact--was his defense of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rostenkowski</ENAMEX>, who is now serving time for ripping off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Post Office</ENAMEX>
and gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. The problem was that in the midst of pre-indictment machinations
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> case, a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> came along in the shape of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who hired the much-touted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> when his reputation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> was
at its highest. As if on cue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">superlawyer</ENAMEX>'s stock began to drop. He agreed
to take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case without warning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosty</ENAMEX> and, pressed for time,
pressured his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> to accept a plea bargain that would have meant time in
prison. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>--who had already billed him for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>--in part because he believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> was responsible for damaging leaks
about what crimes he was willing to confess to.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lloyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cutler</ENAMEX>, a discreet, old-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s legal antithesis,
reportedly recommended him for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case because he felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
needed someone with better media skills and more political savvy than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX>, who represents the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX>-related matters. This now
looks like lousy advice. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> wasn't being taken terribly seriously.
By hiring an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, or by letting his regular lawyer
handle the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have sent a compelling signal that her story was
a fantasy. By hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> telegraphed the message that he was
taking the case very seriously indeed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> himself then proceeded to
elevate the suit by going on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live and Don Imus</ENAMEX>' show and
discussing the tawdry details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' claim.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> did make one highly successful move by
delaying the suit until after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election. But faced with the possibility
of a trial, he is falling back on his familiar tactics, and they aren't
working. Intimidating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX> might be an effective tactic in a normal
sexual-harassment case, one taking place out of the limelight. Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goliath</ENAMEX> is
trying to rub out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> in front of a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> warned darkly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> might get what she wants and be squashed
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, he sounded like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> he is.
Belatedly, he seems to have realized this. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, he went on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nightline</ENAMEX> , and maintained with a straight face that he never intended to
drag in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' sexual history.

            But spin won't help him
either. The press has been through an orgy of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>-beating over its dismissal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. This attitude was fueled in part by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s leaks and sound
bites about what a big-haired slut she was, and reversed by an influential
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lawyer</ENAMEX> . For the same reason
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Organization for Women</ENAMEX> can no longer give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the benefit
of the doubt in his sexual-harassment case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are now in
be-extra-fair-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula</ENAMEX> mode. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> won't get away with trashing her on the
record or off this time around.

         
      
   
