
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outrageous Fortune</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outrageous Fortune</ENAMEX>
               
            

            What a coincidence! The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
2 issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> magazine initiates a feature called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fortune 40</ENAMEX>."
It is, of all things, a list of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calculation</ENAMEX>, gave the most to charity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. No doubt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of
Fortune were completely unaware of a remarkably similar feature, the
"
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>," which this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> has been publishing at intervals
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> published an unbranded list of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25</NUMEX> a year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.)

            To be sure, the whole idea
of a list of the biggest givers originated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice chairman</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, which publishes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fortune</ENAMEX> . And of course it's a variant on
the venerable Fortune 500 list of biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> (via the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes 400</ENAMEX> list
of richest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Animal Husbandry Quarterly 375</ENAMEX> list of most prolific
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rodents</ENAMEX>, and so on). Still, we did get there first. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> couldn't
resist ripping us off, a bit of credit might have been nice.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> 's list is on the Web, but we're not even going to link to it. So
there. Our 
                  Slate
                60 list from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> plus a couple of interim
updates are here. Our 
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> will be out next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>.

            
               Hot
Mail
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of minidialogues</TIMEX> in
"E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>" are worth calling to your special attention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Cameron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">originator</ENAMEX> of
the statistic (publicized by virtue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>) that gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> have
an average life expectancy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 years</TIMEX>, defends and explains his calculation in
response to a 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> debunking it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> redebunks right back.

            And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Shepard</ENAMEX>, responds to a recent

                  Slate
                column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> criticizing an essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> in
Business 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Economy</ENAMEX>." Anyone who follows Krugman
at all will not be surprised to know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> responds, unrepentant (except
for having misspelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s name, which we guess is our fault too. Sorry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>). In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> have been going at it in e-mail since the
exchange we published, and it's pretty darned interesting. We're working on
persuading them to let us share the subsequent mail messages with you as
well.

            
               In
Defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> claims a few
cyberinches of this column, on a point of privilege, to defend his former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>'s
resignation as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , to run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, has occasioned the usual pokes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s nightly political
interview-cum-debate program. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just the past few days</TIMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Goodman</ENAMEX> characterized <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> shout show," and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd summarized Ferraro</ENAMEX>'s duties as "blathering <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>."

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six and a half years</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989-1995</TIMEX>), I am familiar
with the rap: It's uncivilized, it's just show biz, it's not serious, you all
talk at the same time, no one gets to finish a sentence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sununu</ENAMEX> makes me ill (and they hear
similar complaints, apparently, about the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of
political talk shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> is considered the ne'er-do-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>.
In my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire days</ENAMEX>, I was patronized even by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> deserves more respect. To start, it is honest in
a way the other shows are not. Virtually all the political talk shows require
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to adopt <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dishonest postures: agnosticism or omniscience.
On traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Q&A</ENAMEX> shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> must
pretend that they are neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> who have no opinion about the subject
at hand. This is not only dishonest, but it also limits their ability to frame
sharp questions and to pursue evasive answers. On opinion-spouting shows like
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> , by contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> (often the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>) are free to have a point of view. Indeed, they are required to
have, or to pretend to have, a passionate and fully informed viewpoint on every
subject that comes along. How many of those opining solemnly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
financial crisis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX> know (or care) squat about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>?

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> 's basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> is the tendentious question. As a host, you
needn't pretend to be impartial or pretend to be all-knowing. This is more
honest, and it's also more effective in getting at the truth. Or at least, that
is the premise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American jurisprudence</ENAMEX>, which uses the same model. (For
the neutral-interrogator approach, try <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.) One thing this method is not is
easy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Goodman</ENAMEX> smirks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX>
job was "no doubt profitable and not arduous as these things go." But it's a
heckuva lot more arduous to conduct, in effect, a nationally televised
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examination than to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> droning, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So Ms. A</ENAMEX>, what do
you have to say about what Mr. B just said<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            
Talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> often have had
formal training in how to avoid answering questions, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 3-year-old</TIMEX> knows
how to deliver a prepackaged sound bite. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guests</ENAMEX> are less likely to get away
with that on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> than on any other show. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> hosts
not only are freer to ask more pointed questions, but they're also free to
point out that a guest hasn't answered them, to follow up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three or four</NUMEX>
times, and ultimately either to extract an answer or to make vividly clear that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> is ducking.

            There is
not nearly as much shouting on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> as its reputation would
suggest. But the show does get cacophonous, sometimes to the point of making
the discussion unintelligible. That's not on purpose. It's the price of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> 's approach. The opposite approach has a price, too. Other
interview shows may retain a smoother veneer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socratic</ENAMEX> dialogue, but the
emphasis on maintaining a civilized atmosphere actually dulls the intellectual
rigor of the discussion. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who are regulars on the other shows
decline to appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , blaming the shouting. It's not the
shouting that scares them. It's having to face a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> who will puncture
their postures and snare their sound bites.

            For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> is a more
intellectually rigorous experience than the other shows--or, in a way, than
print punditry. Where else does a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> face one or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dedicated to
demolishing his or her arguments on the spot and making him or her look like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>? Not on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> , where opinions are flung into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mixmaster</ENAMEX> and issues race by like movie credits. Not in the sedate and
agreeable discussions on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> . And not in the pages
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , where you may opine away with nothing more
immediate to fear than a distant letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> or, at worst, a politely
dissenting op-ed piece.

            To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX>
can be aggravating. There's the strain of finding something to argue about in
every big news event, the artifice of dividing every controversy into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sides
labeled "left" and "right." There are the many points of argument and fact that
flit past undigested. And of course, there's the "overtalk" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>'
term for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talking at once). Like all these shows,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> often falls for spin, serves the establishment, legitimizes
phonies, and in general misses the point completely. But it's no worse than the
others, and in some ways it's better.

            Anyone wanna argue with
that?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
