
   
   
      
         
            Lying All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weisberg</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> was about to resign over reports that he had been
consorting with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>-an-hour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>. I was, of course, amazed. But then I
thought: "Why should anyone be surprised? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>-an-hour
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>." Things have changed since then. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has raised his prices.

            Now a
normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would be offended by what I've just written. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>' case,
though, I'm afraid he may use it as a blurb for the paperback edition of his
book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, Behind the Oval Office</ENAMEX> . The current version includes this blurb
from a brutal demolition job in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> : "He never stops. Somehow,
each shocking thing he does tops the shocking thing he did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, or last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' career has developed the curious quality of
a plea bargain in reverse. If you say he's guilty of a misdemeanor, he will try
to persuade you he's actually committed a felony.

            In reality, he's not fit to stand trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> discusses
right and wrong as if those concepts were as remote from his own experience as
lunar geology. "I wanted to address the values agenda <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>," he writes at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in the book. "First, though, we had to identify
through polls which values were important to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." Blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> often
have highly developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> of hearing and smell, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>' case, he does
not seem to have compensated for an attenuated moral sense with any other
heightened abilities--not intelligence, not political savvy, and certainly not
literary acumen. Despite being rotten to the core, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> demonstrates in
his book that he has nothing else to offer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> casts himself, of
course, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> back from calamity and got him
re-elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Most of the press fell for this hype during the campaign.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' own account undermines the myth. By claiming credit for absolutely
everything, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> leaves you wondering whether he deserves credit for anything
at all. To call his recollections "unreliable" would be a massive
understatement. There is hardly anything he says in the book that he does not
contradict at some other point in the book. Usually, the mutually contradictory
statements fall within a few pages of each other. Here are just a few subjects
where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> absolutely mystified about his views and his
role:

            
               Negative advertising:
On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> swears off it. "As <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Eileen</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, who is now
divorcing him] and my therapist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hauser</ENAMEX>, softened my rage and
brought me inner peace for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life, I decided to abandon
negative advertising as a métier." On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> boasts about an ad he had
produced for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, attacking an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> gubernatorial
primary: "Don't let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McRae</ENAMEX> build a wall around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> pages after that,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> brags about his script for an ad in the general election of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>.
It culminated in this assertion: "You can't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheffield Nelson</ENAMEX>."

            
               Foreign intervention:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noninvolvement</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> had been a central element in my advice," he writes
on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">253</NUMEX>. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a few</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> was taking credit for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s brave decision to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, he's
telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to bomb the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone Age</ENAMEX>. "I don't mean
the current stuff ... where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> sends in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>," he counsels. "I
mean an air strike that continues until they give up."

            
               Press leaks:
"Throughout my tenure at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, I never leaked information unless I
was told to," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> writes on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">171</NUMEX>. On the same page: "I called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> to give him background on the strategic
implications of the speech and he ran a story." The call wasn't authorized--in
fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> got in trouble for it, he says.

            
               Budget
cuts: On page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> cuts are your single
biggest weapon against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. They are hated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, old and
young." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, he writes: "I argued that as long as we lined up
with the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and just sniped at cuts in school lunches and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, we would get nowhere."

            This last contradiction is central, because it goes to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heart of Morris</ENAMEX>' claim to have got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> re-elected. The conventional
understanding at the time was that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
Stephanopoulos, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX>--who were arguing in favor of
fiercely resisting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> cuts in social spending, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> was telling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to distance himself from the intransigent congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.
According to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> at the time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> was desperately pushing for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> deal and making the kind of hilariously precise electoral promises for
which he was legendary: If he compromised with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would win by a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14-point</NUMEX> margin, take back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and so forth.

            In
reality, both plans were in play in the re-election effort: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>'
"triangulation" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes-Panetta</ENAMEX>-Stephanopoulos tactic of standing firmly
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, education, and the environment.
Both strategies were crucial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> recovered his lost popularity by
resisting domestic budget cuts, while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist</ENAMEX> "values" agenda helped to
solidify his electoral gains. In retrospect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> appears to have shrewdly
pitted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> as an exercise in the management style
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> called "creative tension." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> needed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> to help him shore up his
liberal base and prevent a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>-primary challenge. He used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> to help
him move to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> tries to take credit for both strategies. But if
there was a great political mind behind this synthesis, it was that of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> himself.

            
Getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> re-elected is only one of
the many, many accomplishments claimed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, who plays both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boswell</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> in his memoirs. You may not have known that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> who had
suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> who had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recommended James Carville</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> in that campaign. Through secret back
channels to other political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> tells us that he managed
relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. It was none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> who
played a pivotal role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dayton Peace Accords</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>: "Without those words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s that you passed to me, I would
never have been able to get it done.") And it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' ideas that kept
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on track even after his--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>'--downfall. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>: "We're
basically following your game plan. It's working well.")

            But, even
as he emulates the rooster that thinks the sun rises because it crows, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>
demonstrates how right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX> and the others were to be terrified about his
running amok in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> microinitiatives that didn't
quite make it were a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33-cent</NUMEX> postage stamp, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> going to your favorite
charity, and a plan to force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to meet new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-mugging</ENAMEX> standards for ATM
machines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' "small-bore" ideas, as he calls them, made the presidency
look somewhat ridiculous in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>. The ones that were killed in the
crib would have turned neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonism</ENAMEX> into a full-scale self-parody.

            Through it all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> maintains that what he was doing was
really very high-minded. "I don't spin anything," he writes huffily. "I put new
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> and ideas before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>." Even as we see him fighting to reduce
governing to the most trivial micro-pandering, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> asserts the primacy of
principle. "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> seem to think that the real story is never the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s idea, but always the motivation to improve his or her political
status," he writes. A few pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, of course, he's explaining why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
had to sign a welfare bill that no one liked in order to get re-elected (a veto
would have meant a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-point loss").

            By the end
of his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has cast himself as a modest egomaniac, a shy publicity
hound, a principled manipulator, a loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>, and a truthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>. He isn't
just confused, he's the dialectic incarnate. He aims for evil, but only manages
to look ridiculous.

         
      
   
