
   
   
      
         
            No Cigar

            
               No
Cigar
            

            You already know what that
headline refers to, don't you? But how do you know?

            In
"Readme" recently
we told of how a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> tried to evade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s absurd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Official</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Secrets Act</ENAMEX> by inviting 
                  Slate
                to publish an article by a former
spy making spectacular charges against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence services. The
idea was that once an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>--accessible in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>--had
told the tale, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> could report that we had reported it. We
ultimately declined this opportunity, reasoning that we could not honestly
maintain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> was merely "incidental," since the instant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldwide</ENAMEX> accessibility of 
                  Slate
                was, in fact, the whole point.
The story was picked up, though, by a more provincial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>--the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> --which could more credibly make that claim. And thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
papers were free to tell the tale.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week or so</TIMEX>, oddly, the same process has
happened in reverse. A story that almost no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> will report
directly has been widely reported anyhow, sort of, in part in the form of
reporting that the story has been reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. The story involves
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and a cigar, and allegedly is part of the
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s as-yet-unwritten report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The current status of
this story is extremely peculiar. It has been Topic A in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. There have
been jokes about it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX> and passing comments on the TV yack shows. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> have told it in some detail.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and other foreign presses have also reported it--on the Web as well
as on paper. Not a word, though, in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of record," the
Times . And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> buried a coy discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> coverage in the back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
a barely related article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> turning against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
(
                  Slate
                has been full of unilluminating references, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Diary</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BT</ENAMEX> again.)

            There is a real problem here,
which the Internet obviously makes much worse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> once
got widely mocked for an editorial justifying the publication of a damaging
rumor about a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> with the argument that while the rumor may not be
true, it is true there is a rumor. But actually, there's something to that
argument. On the one hand, a publication's standards of proof and taste should
not be hostage to the lesser standards of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. On the other
hand, a story can spread without the help of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment media</ENAMEX> to the
point where making no acknowledgment of its existence becomes a failure in your
basic duty to reflect reality.

            What does
seem unsatisfactory is the current netherworld where serious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> refer
to the story as if everyone knows it without ever telling it straight. Burying
the story as a way of sort of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-publishing it--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
approach--also seems silly. So if you don't know what the heck all this is
about the cigar, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX>." Of course, we're not saying it's true. We're just
saying it's true that it's a rumor.

            
               Lonely
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Depressed and Proud of It</ENAMEX>
            

            The lumber-byproduct media
have reported with glee a study out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Mellon University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> purporting
to show that spending time on the Internet tends to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> and
depressed. This contradicts the widespread view among cyberfolk (including,
apparently, the study's own disappointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> staring into
computer screens form a wonderful new type of electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
claim to have corrected for the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX>, depressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
more inclined to use the Internet to begin with, and a cyberwag quoted in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> has already made the requisite joke that maybe these people
are depressed by being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>.

            (The study is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> pages long.
To minimize the risk of loneliness and depression, read <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this nine</TIMEX>
page press release.)

            So how can we Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> explain away this finding? Well, try this. Perhaps Internet users
are more depressed because they are better informed. Perhaps their feelings of
increased loneliness are reflections of a deepened understanding of the human
condition. Let's face it: The world is a mess, life is basically futile, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are pretty dreadful and don't like you much anyhow. And you'd
never acquire all this superior insight if you didn't spend many, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">many hours</TIMEX> on
the Internet. So read 
                  Slate
               . A lot. And don't forget to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floss</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
