
   
   
      
         
            Politics and Culture

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slate Lite</ENAMEX>
            

            A little-known clause in the
First <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> gives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> the right to a week off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and
then, especially during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>. When 
                  Slate
                began publishing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, we thought we were a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, more or less. But
we have evolved into something much more ... more ... well, "dynamic" is the
approved term of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> self-hype. "Relentless" is how our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> (and perhaps even
a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>) might prefer to describe it. We now post new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> at all
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days a week</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>'s fatal car crash
occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after we shut down for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, we realized that a vital and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underrated</ENAMEX> press freedom--the freedom not to publish--does not apply to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzines</ENAMEX> or, at least, not to this one. (Many thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who wrote
in to thank us for not succumbing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di'n'Dodi</ENAMEX> hysteria. An undeserved
compliment is cherished all the more.)

            What is left of our weeks
off is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, when we publish less
material than usual. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer weeks</TIMEX> is now upon us. We have
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week</TIMEX>'s worth of material <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (post date <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23</TIMEX>) and will
resume our full publishing schedule a week from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 3</TIMEX>). In the
interim, though, we will continue to post and update "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Briefing</ENAMEX>" features such
as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin"; "Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" will continue (now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days a week</TIMEX>);
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" will appear; and features such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogues</ENAMEX>" will be updated often but irregularly, as
always. That should be enough to satisfy most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, we hope. And if you need
more, there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>' worth of our archive, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>," to poke around
in.

            Thanks
for cutting us a little slack.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Progress Report</ENAMEX>
            

            When 
                  Slate
               
became a paid-subscription site in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, we steeled ourselves for an
inevitable drop in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. We're delighted to report that it hasn't
happened. We had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any month</TIMEX> since we began
publishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Metrix</ENAMEX>, the leading Internet
audience measurement service, 
                  Slate
                had a "reach" of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.6</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.
Reach is defined as the percentage of the total World Wide Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that visited your site at least once during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX>. Out of a Web
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">audience Media Metrix</ENAMEX> estimates as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40.4 million</NUMEX>, a reach of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6</NUMEX> works out to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240,000</NUMEX> individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. That doesn't include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 10 percent</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, as best we can estimate. It also
doesn't include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> who read 
                  Slate
                exclusively through
e-mail delivery
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>.

            Paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> now number
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,000</NUMEX>--up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> we had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> we went paid.
That's an encouraging rate of growth. But how can we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times as many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> as we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>? Answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are coming to our "front
porch"--the small sample of 
                  Slate
               's contents that is made
available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonsubscribers</ENAMEX>--and they are taking advantage of our free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s trial
offer. Naturally, we hope these nibbles of 
                  Slate
               's splendors
will persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to purchase the full meal. And that appears to be
happening.

            Among
magazines on the Web, 
                  Slate
               's reach of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6</NUMEX> is lower than that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathfinder</ENAMEX> (the site shared by all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hotwired</ENAMEX>, and
higher than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> .
All these other sites except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> are free. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> has no Web site to speak of.

            
               Politics
and Culture
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>,

                  Slate
               's chief political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, looked around him a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> and saw nothing but squalor. This is not a reference to

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> hangs his laptop. Those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> actually are quite snazzy, in an ever-so-faintly seedy downtown sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, inciting no small amount of envy in those of us who labor in the bland
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">vineyards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX> No, what struck <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> as oppressively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squalid</ENAMEX> was the subject matter he was forced to contemplate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after week</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fleeting</ENAMEX>, age-inappropriate sexual liaisons in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>; the seep of
money into every cranny of the political system; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>. It
was more than a sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> could bear.

            "Where is
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">beauty?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> wailed. "Where is art? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> does not live by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">privatization</ENAMEX> alone." And he pleaded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take me</ENAMEX> away from here, to
a realm of high thoughts and charmed vistas, where I may contemplate matters
more lovely than special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and nuclear proliferation. Where aesthetic
considerations are paramount and base motives are unknown."

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>'s plea. And he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arise</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>, and put aside politics for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX>. Go forth and cover culture and
the arts. There, among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> and book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and artsy-fartsies
generally, you will find nothing but wholesomeness. Beauty is in their hearts
and beauty is on their minds. Dwell among them and let their purity wash away
the filth of politics with which you are encrusted after lo! these many columns
and articles on the subject."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> was pierced by
shafts of doubt. "Are you sure," he asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, "that the world of
culture is actually so wonderful and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who dwell therein are
actually so pure? If so, what will I write about? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodness</ENAMEX> and purity maketh
not much of a column. What will I impugn, if not motives<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            "Fear not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
replied. "You will think of something. And, come to think of it, the world of
culture may not be as pure as all that after all. There is squalor aplenty. But
at least it will be a different kind of squalor." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> decreed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> culture column should be called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Browser</ENAMEX>." And he decreed
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>'s first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browser</ENAMEX> column should post <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 23</TIMEX>.

            And it was
good. (Or it had better be.)

            
               Musical
Chairs
            

            
Meanwhile, though, who would cover politics while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> dwelt in the land of
the artsy-fartsies? Using several top executive search <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, as well as
experimental talent sorting software from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX>'s research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> here
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, we scientifically ranked everyone in the entire world on the
basis of their qualifications to cover <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics for an online
magazine. By a miraculous and money-saving coincidence, No. 1 turned out to be

                  Slate
                Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>, whose first "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bedfellow"</ENAMEX> column was posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. (And here's the latest.)

            

               Complainer
            

            

               
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Explainer</ENAMEX> is complaining about the quality of the questions he is
receiving. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explainer</ENAMEX> stands ready to explain items in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s news that are
confusing or vague or seemingly contradictory or otherwise inadequately
explained by the conventional media. But many of the questions he receives, he
says, are "tendentious." They don't really seek information or understanding.
Questions such as "Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX> such a jerk?" are essentially
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unanswerable</ENAMEX>. They begin from a debatable premise and go on to raise profound
metaphysical questions that are beyond the scope of this 
                  Slate
               
feature. Questions such as "How big a jerk is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>?" are no better.
The answer is inherently subjective. (Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe, in all sincerity,
that he is a very small jerk. Nor does the question allow for the possibility,
however slight, that he is not a jerk at all.) "Why doesn't my computer work?"
is another category of questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> is not prepared to answer. Questions
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> life and love should go to "Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>." But if there's something that truly puzzles you
in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explainer</ENAMEX> is eager to straighten you out.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
