
   
   
      
         
            Suffer the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>

            So we're going to have a
contest after all. Not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> honestly thinks a surprise is
likely there. The horse race that's been declared is for control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Nearly all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prognosticators</ENAMEX> failed to predict the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> triumph in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Now they are saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s coattails might just be long enough
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to ride back into power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> is
raising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> per week on the promise to liberate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from the reign
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, more creatively, are trying to frighten small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with the supposedly terrifying specter of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>."

            Well, it
could happen. But there's good reason to hope it doesn't, whether you are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, a progressive, or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The reasons to
be alarmed about the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> aren't those put forward by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>, who have been warning of a
return to the liberal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark Ages</TIMEX>, circa <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> almost certainly would not try to pass comprehensive
health-care reform, cut the defense budget in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, or raise taxes. As Barbour
might say, even a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> learns not to stick its nose in the campfire a second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            The real reason to worry about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> retaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
is that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> out of power, they have begun to reconsider their
approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--but they've only just begun. The danger is that instead
of returning to power as spirited reform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would govern
as a devious, dispirited version of their old selves. And paradoxically, they
will have a more productive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> if they don't win than if they do.
Assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is re-elected, a divided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would be
able to accomplish more of what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want than if they controlled both
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX>.

            The
political model for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration Democratic Congress</ENAMEX> wouldn't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>,
the corpulent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. It would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Waxman</ENAMEX>, the tiny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> model was New Deal liberalism: Raise
money through taxation to pay for ambitious federal programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waxman</ENAMEX> model,
deployed when he chaired the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy and Commerce</ENAMEX>, is
administrative liberalism: Try to accomplish the same social goals covertly
through regulation and mandates. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was still arguing
for nationalized health care, paid for by a payroll tax, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waxman</ENAMEX> was trying to
create universal coverage through the back door, by expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eligibility</ENAMEX> and requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to provide ever more extensive benefits. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mandates Waxman</ENAMEX> buried in various appropriation bills produced a malfunctioning
system that was resented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> of both parties as its costs escalated
and the number of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> continued to rise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s was a
legitimate alternative, democratically rejected; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waxman</ENAMEX>'s approach (which has
finally become <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s as well) was to quietly foist more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> on an
uncomprehending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>.

            
Blocked by the present political mood from
acting in a direct, sensible way to create government programs where they are
needed, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would be tempted to operate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waxman</ENAMEX>-style, in an inefficient,
subterranean way. Take welfare reform. The bill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> is
deficient principally because it would cut poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off even if they
couldn't find jobs. It could, however, be made into a reasonable scheme by
adding a public-sector jobs program that would offer employment in the last
resort for those who are willing to work but are (frankly) unemployable in the
private sector. But--afraid of spending for the underclass--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> might find it easier to tinker with regulations to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> from
cutting welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> off at the end of their supposed time limits. This
would undermine reform rather than fixing it. With a nominally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might be able to drum up bipartisan support
to pass a humane modification in the form of a jobs program.

            Why
should that be? We saw how it worked during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term. In his first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
were truculent and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obstructionist</ENAMEX>. It soon dawned on them that any
accomplishments benefited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in power. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kristol</ENAMEX>
argued in his famous health-care memo, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were politically better off
blocking everything than compromising. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>, with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the incentives have been reversed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> tried
ruling by non-negotiable demand and ended up with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional
candidates denying any knowledge of his existence. He and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> learned the
hard way that they were better off cooperating with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on things the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> wants, and trying to share the credit--hence the recent flurry of
legislation passed with bipartisan support: welfare reform, health-care
portability, and the minimum-wage increase. In fact, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
would probably mean less opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pass legislation of any
kind.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> retain a majority, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will be
denied their grander schemes. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might win a few more
increments of health-care reform, improvements in the welfare bill, the kind of
tax cut he wants, and maybe even some sort of entitlement reform. The balanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> will continue to get closer. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> recover a majority,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will have every incentive to block everything once again. And with
a superslim majority, instead of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-seat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will be even weaker.
There won't be any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-vote budget victories. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> would jeer from the
sidelines, demanding big tax cuts and no longer spelling out--as they admirably
did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--how such cuts would be paid for. Cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> partisanship
would bring out the worst in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, encouraging more symbolic
"therapeutic legislation" (see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flame Posies"</ENAMEX> column) and demagoguery intended to keep old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-hating frenzy.

            It is said
that suffering is good for the soul, and so it has been for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. When
I went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, he was saying all the right things
about how his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> had been lazy and undisciplined, throwing programs at
problems without worrying about results. He was touting his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Families First</ENAMEX>"
agenda, a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Democratic Contract With America</ENAMEX>, which he developed with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>. It includes sensible, small-scale proposals
such as requiring health-insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>-only policies. These
are modest steps, but not falsely modest ones, like some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>-inspired micro-ideas (e.g., school uniforms). Those aren't
incremental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--they're infinitesimal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s admirable evolution may be
interrupted if he runs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The prospect of a party primary
will drag him back to the left. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> has yet to bring around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of</TIMEX>
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obeys</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boniors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dingells</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
still aren't into small stuff. They've made clear that the balanced budget will
be the first thing out the window if they get their old chairs back. The next
thing to go would be the rules restraining the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> chairs,
perhaps the only truly good deed of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich Congress</ENAMEX>. For the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> victory would prove that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> was a meaningless blip, that there was
nothing wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> after all.

            They may have suffered, but
they haven't suffered enough.

         
      
   
