
   
   
      
         
            Strange Webfellows

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Magaziner</ENAMEX> is best known
as the chief structural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s biggest
boo-boo, its first-term attempt to pass comprehensive health-care reform.
Though he stayed on at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> after that debacle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magaziner</ENAMEX> hasn't
been much heard from since, and his actual responsibilities have been something
of a mystery. Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magaziner</ENAMEX> has been found--making policy for the Internet.
Webheads, already angry at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>, might
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regard Magaziner</ENAMEX>'s latest assignment as insult added to injury. But in fact,
the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> and the Internet--and especially of how
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> came to support the unconstitutional, unpopular law known as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>--is more complicated and interesting than that.

            Magaziner
has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last eight months</TIMEX> in charge of an interagency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> that is
trying to figure out how to expand international opportunities for online
business. I hold in my hands, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> in advance of its release, the task
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force's</ENAMEX> draft report. It contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> remarkable passage. Along with their
worries about intellectual-property protections, tariffs, and technical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standards, Magaziner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> write that they are concerned that "many
restrict access to certain types of content through the Internet. ... These
multiple interests may result in barriers for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> attempting to enter
certain national markets." The report proposes a statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy on
content restrictions: "Promote the use of industry ... self-regulation and
rating systems, and technical solutions to empower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to
resolve contentious access issues (e.g. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s access, pornography and
violence)." (The latest version removes the word "pornography" from this
sequence.)

            This white paper is notable for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is
that the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, who is known (fairly or otherwise) for his fondness for
heavy regulation, seems to be leaning in a more libertarian direction.
Congratulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira</ENAMEX>. But the more significant point is that the report
completely contradicts what has heretofore been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
position on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>, which was signed by the president
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, as most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reading this probably know, attempts to
regulate content through criminal penalties for those who violate standards of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decency</ENAMEX> (standards drawn so broadly that they might prohibit, for instance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedaris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Diary</ENAMEX>" from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>) with "any comment, request, suggestion,
proposal, image, or other communication that, in context, depicts or describes,
in terms patently offensive as measured by contemporary standards, sexual or
excretory activities or organs."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>--which it is now defending before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>--has
been a bit of a mystery. It turns out to have been a bit of an accident. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> was first proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Exon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Justice Department</ENAMEX> frowned. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1995</TIMEX>, then-acting
Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent Markus</ENAMEX> wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Leahy</ENAMEX> that among
other problems, the proposal was an attempt to "impose criminal sanctions on
the transmission of constitutionally protected speech." Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
who have general responsibility for Internet-related issues, tried to steer the
administration away from supporting the act.

            As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> headed toward overwhelming passage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, however, political
reality began to assert itself. With an election coming up, the last thing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonites</ENAMEX> wanted was to get on the wrong side of a potentially explosive
issue dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and pornography. "No way are you going to get
yourself in a position where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> isn't willing to go as far as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> in restricting child pornography on the Internet," one
senior administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> explained. Child pornography and obscenity are
illegal anyway, but that was a fine point the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> wasn't willing to
risk elucidating on the verge of a campaign.

            
So, part of the explanation is cowardice in the
face of potential demagoguery. Another part is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> was folded into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telecommunications</ENAMEX> bill, an acre of legislation that reorganizes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s economy. It was a bill in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had many
interests--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">v-</ENAMEX>chip, competition among local telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and so on.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> could not afford to antagonize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exon</ENAMEX> by opposing his pet
provision. Those inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> who were troubled by the
constitutional implications of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> rationalized their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> out by saying
that the law was sure to be overturned anyway--as indeed it was, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-0</ENAMEX>
decision that gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> a welcome opportunity to sound
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clintonites</ENAMEX> say the decision to appeal that ruling is essentially pro
forma ; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor general</ENAMEX> rarely chooses not to not defend the
constitutionality of a law the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has signed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> was almost one of
those rare occasions. In its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> brief, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
stipulated that the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comstock</ENAMEX> provision in the law, which restricts
the dissemination of information about abortion, was unconstitutional and would
not be enforced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, in particular, wanted to avoid an appeal by finding a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to settle with the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> in the suit. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s decision to take
the bill to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> was over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s objections." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> says he had
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> discussions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> about whether there might be an alternative way to
stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from gaining access to inappropriate material on the Internet.
"We couldn't really find a technical way of doing it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> says. Others in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> believe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> himself who prevailed against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and
got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> behind the act.

            In any case, political logic prevailed. Officially, the
decision was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor general</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Days III</ENAMEX>. He had
his own reasons for pursuing the case. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> made a legally sound but politically disastrous decision to appeal the
child-pornography conviction of a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> for having videotapes that
showed teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> with their clothes on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> agreed with the
brief <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> filed in that case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knox</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S .</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-0
to condemn his intervention, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> promptly disavowed his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor</ENAMEX>
general in public. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX>, who previously was thought to have a good shot at a
seat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, fell off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> short-list. Soon after deciding
to appeal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
Dellinger, will argue the case before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> seem certain
that the former constitutional-law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX> personally opposes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dellinger</ENAMEX>, who is still acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor general</ENAMEX> pending official
nomination and confirmation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, wasn't about to risk premature
termination of his career. He wouldn't comment. But privately, he may believe
what many in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> offer in defense of their indefensible
position: that a resounding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision against them will do more to
advance the cause of free expression than would leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX>
opinion unchallenged.

            If that is the
administration's strategy, it is foolhardy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> might not
cooperate in rejecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s public position and embracing its
secret desire. Furthermore, it's preposterous that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> re-elected on
rhetoric about building a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX> hasn't bothered
to work out a minimally consistent position on the Internet. The basic problem,
as I've argued before, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lack of respect for civil liberties,
exacerbated in this instance by a lack of understanding beyond the vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of what is at stake in the development of the Internet. But
a simple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> might be at hand. It can be expressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> words I thought
I'd never utter: Listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Magaziner</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
