
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> Revisionism

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weisberg</ENAMEX>

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX> issue of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> opened with the kind of editorial one is used to reading
in conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. Titled "It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> to Take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX>," it heaped
outrage on the recent decision by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> halting the
enforcement of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX>, passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, which bans
state-sponsored affirmative action. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henderson</ENAMEX>'s order as "an assault on popular will" and an act of "judicial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">usurpation</ENAMEX>." Growing more indignant by the paragraph, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> declared it
"time to ignite a popular outcry against unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and their efforts
to invalidate the results of elections."

            It all
made sense--unless you happened to have read an article in the previous issue
of the Standard about <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 215</ENAMEX>, the other big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ballot
initiative <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, which legalized the use of marijuana for medical
purposes. In that piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Walters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s deputy
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, argued that the will of the people
must be overridden. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> recommended that the federal government
invoke an obscure provision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Controlled Substances Act of 1917</ENAMEX> to revoke
the licenses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who dare to act on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 215</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug</ENAMEX>
Enforcement Administration ignore state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and "use its power" to
"move unilaterally" against pro-pot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> position, which has been seconded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, among others, actually violates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> core conservative
principles. One is federalism--the preference for state authority over federal.
We have all endured screeds from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> on how terrible it is for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to usurp power from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The other is the demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
defer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> peremptorily overrule state law, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
wants, the issue will end up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> will,
presumably, favor unelected federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> backing the decision of unelected
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> to overturn the popular will. In defending this scenario,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, and others have already used the same argument conservatives
denounce as elitist and patronizing in the case of the affirmative-action
initiative: that disingenuous wording misled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> about the measure's real
effect.

            Decrying a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s interference with the affirmative-action initiative is more in keeping
with general conservative complaints about "judicial activism"--but not in
keeping with much previous conservative huffery on affirmative action itself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> have often expressed the view that affirmative action is
unconstitutional. In other words, when democratically elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> act
pro affirmative action, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> should overrule them; when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> acts
anti affirmative action, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s will must be sacrosanct.

            
Before I get too high on my own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, I ought
to acknowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> aren't always paragons of intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX>, either. In the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> initiatives, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>
have been just as outcome-based as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, denouncing
federal meddling in the case of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX> while supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henderson</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX>.
And let's give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> a bit of credit. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> significant issue, the
line-item veto, they held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> on an old stance even though doing so meant
handing a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a knife to gore <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oxen</ENAMEX> (though they did
postpone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> as long as possible and are now contending that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
conception of it is too broad).

            But despite these caveats,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are still the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> when it comes to inconsistency. On
a broad range of issues, the tensions--to choose a nice word--between their
principles and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> have gone completely out of control.

            The basic reason for these,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>, tensions is that many "principles" of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> were developed
under political conditions that prevailed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and a liberal federal bench. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> don't seem to
have anticipated that this might change. They guessed that they would do better
with a "strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>," a weaker legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>, and a restrained
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> to come.

            This
meant, for instance, that they didn't just defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Meese</ENAMEX>, who were accused of wrongdoing. They opposed the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> (a k a independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>) in
categorical terms as a violation of the separation of powers. Before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>
election, congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> caused the law authorizing special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to expire. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> changed their
minds and decided to reauthorize the law. Today, the shoe having switched feet,
one no longer hears conservative worries about abuse of the independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have been busy protesting James
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX>'s attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater Special Prosecutor Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> as the
scandalously inappropriate undermining of an essential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of public
accountability. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Walsh</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, with greater venom and less justification. On
this point at least, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have been much more consistent, supporting the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> throughout, despite their own partisan objections
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arelated</ENAMEX> issue is presidential pardons. In the closing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of the presidential campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> made a big fuss about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
refusal to categorically rule out pardons for former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> caught up in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> said they would consider such
pardons grounds for impeachment. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame-duck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> was
following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s urging when he pardoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar Weinberger</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> others
indicted or convicted in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s investigation "an
outrageous <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX> political persecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>," and applauded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pardons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">At the time, Walsh</ENAMEX> was trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in
exactly the same way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> reportedly is trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX> to finger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have also evolved a bit on the issue of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege," the
doctrine that protects communications between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> invoked this right to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> documents about
toxic-waste disposal from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> did the same when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banking Committee</ENAMEX> got interested in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. In instances where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has asserted the privilege,
however, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who apologized for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> have been
scathing in their denunciations. For instance, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cited executive
privilege as a reason for holding back a memo from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX>
criticizing his drug policies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> asserted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had no
basis for refusing to divulge it.

            
Another case in point is the matter of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s powers as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> could be
counted upon to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> needed congressional
authorization for military action. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, invariably
maintained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Act</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> to assert its
constitutional power to declare war, was unconstitutional, and that military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> rested solely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers</ENAMEX>
Act didn't apply when he sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, or to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grenada</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>,
or when he bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> didn't ask permission to invade
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did ask for a resolution authorizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>--by far
the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX>--but only with the stipulation
that he would go ahead with or without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' OK.

            Since a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat</ENAMEX> has occupied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, it has been a different story. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> objections, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voted for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> declaring that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "should have sought" congressional support.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1995</TIMEX>, none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the secret
incursion into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> that prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Act</ENAMEX>--asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
must "obtain clear and unambiguous congressional backing" before sending troops
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. And after not being told in advance about a missile attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Armed Services Committee</ENAMEX> spoke of
reviving the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Act</ENAMEX>.

            Or, consider the issue of informing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> about "covert
actions." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Committee</ENAMEX> were always
complaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had failed to tell them it was
mining <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">harbors</ENAMEX>, arming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX>, and so on. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was trying to "micromanage" foreign policy, couldn't be trusted not to
leak vital secrets, and so on. Now, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who are apoplectic about
a much less compelling incident, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s failure to relay
its knowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> was secretly arming the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX> says this breach is so serious that he may hold up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lake</ENAMEX>'s
nomination to head the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have admitted their mistake; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outgoing CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Deutsch</ENAMEX> have both said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> should
have told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> sales, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
wasn't behind them. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Committee</ENAMEX> has concluded that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> broke no laws in this incident. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> affair,
no comparable gestures of contrition were forthcoming from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. And in
that case, laws were broken.

            No one expected a great deal
of intellectual consistency from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
wants to be the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of ideas" and looks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX> to articulate its guiding principles. To govern according to
well-defined precepts is a worthy aspiration. But so far, for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aspiration</ENAMEX> is all it is.

         
      
   
