
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> or Bust

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>
or Bust
            

            A final reminder: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effective</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>, at around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. PT</TIMEX>, 
                  Slate
                becomes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>-only site. Click here to sign up for a charter subscription. Each <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>
one-year charter subscription comes with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> free extra <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, a free

                  Slate
                umbrella or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft ® Encarta ® Virtual Globe</ENAMEX>, and a
guarantee that the rate will never go up for as long as you renew. And of
course (for a modest <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.95 surcharge</NUMEX>) our gratitude at having you along.

            As of this writing, two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> after we began accepting credit cards, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> have
signed up. In a world where a formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180,000-plus</NUMEX>
paying online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> after it started charging, and where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX>'s site is
considered a success at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>, we're pretty pleased that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> signed up before they even had to. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naturally</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> on a

                  Slate
                subscription doesn't start running until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>, even if
you signed up early.) Our goal is to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000 to 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> within
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first few months</TIMEX>.

            If you
haven't done so already, please sign up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.
(If you prefer the telephone, call [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">800</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">706-3330</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Operators</ENAMEX> are standing by.
Or they'd better be.)

            

               Testimonials
            

            
               
                  Slate
               's
decision to ask its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> (for a product valued by the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Internet Content Laboratory</ENAMEX> at "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,922.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and not
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> less") has produced a flood of comments, ranging from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drop</ENAMEX> dead, you
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">greedbags</ENAMEX>" to "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> reads 
                  Slate
                over my shoulder sometimes,
so here is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39.90</NUMEX>--can I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> umbrellas<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remarkably</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> have sent favorable comments
with their credit-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">info</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> e-mailed
us:

            

               
                  Slate
                is magnificent. Your "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> column is nothing
short of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talmudic</ENAMEX> in its commentary, and the ironic humor of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The</ENAMEX>
Spin" reminds me of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> folk tales my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> used to recite to me
back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>. I never could figure out why my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> knew so
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> folk tales. Life is full of mysteries. Perhaps 
                  Slate
               
will be able to solve some of them.

            Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> wrote:

            I recall a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> meeting
in which 
                  Slate
                was discussed extensively. The consensus among all
these establishment white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in dark suits was that you'll never make it. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> said: "This Internet thing is just a fad. Give me paper and ink
any day." But I--a progressive black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in a demure dashiki and sensible
pumps--insisted: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, technology is vital to our future. It will liberate the
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." Of course they wouldn't listen. Why am I always the lone
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visionary</ENAMEX>? Perhaps I can find some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul mates</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>."

            Although
not officially a present or former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has spent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. She wrote us:

            Like, thank God for

                  Slate
                when I was hustled over to that no-work job at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. Staring at a computer screen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>, pretending to be busy--it was

                  Slate
                or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solitaire</ENAMEX>, I tell you. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solitaire</ENAMEX>'s so f******
hard . Who made those rules, anyway? I'd far rather read those sexy
economics columns by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>. If he doesn't get that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> pretty soon, he
should drop by, and I'll give him a consolation prize.

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> wrote:

            Well, I wasn't going to
sign up. I've got some heavy expenses ahead of me. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX> bucks can buy a good
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s time. But I was deeply impressed
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of your "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" columns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. I sobbed-- sobbed! --with shame as I
read about what our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is doing to punish innovation and creativity in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And I loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s dig at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McNealy</ENAMEX>. We need to hear
more from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> of large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>-based software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that has
remained silent for too long. By the way, send me that umbrella <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASAP</ENAMEX>. I sure
could have used it in those hearings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> started
flapping his lips, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> really flew!

            Wouldn't you like to join
this typical cross-section of 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>? Sign up now,
and thanks again.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
