
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Browser

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Browser
            

            Whom
should we run into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>! They were out together celebrating the settlement of
their little tiff over that consent decree. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' guard <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> snarled as we
approached, and so did the crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arsonists</ENAMEX> who were
standing by, ready to set the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> on fire at the slightest hint of
danger. "Down, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higgins</ENAMEX>! Down, Ballmer!" said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, feeding them small bits of
his braised <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Myhrvold nacho salad</ENAMEX> and inviting us to pull up a pew. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> called
off her flamethrowers as well, and it was the beginning of a jolly <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>.
After a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Neukom Pale Ales</ENAMEX>, we couldn't resist asking them what they
thought of this latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> brouhaha. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> observed tartly, "Someone should
tell that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to keep his browser separate from his operating system." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>
guffawed, "Maybe someone should tell him to keep his browser out of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s operating systems." Gates stared at her briefly, clearly annoyed
at having had his metaphor appropriated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. But then he relaxed
and added with a philosophical chuckle, "Of course in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">browser</ENAMEX> and the operating system seem to be one integrated product."

            

               Clinternalia
            

            If ever
there was a moment for pack journalism and media overkill, this is it. For
those who are too excited by this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> story to even think about their
browsers, 
                  Slate
                offers plenty of grist. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, is filing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> dispatches from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> until further notice. "Chatterbox," our
on-again/off-again feature of short observations, gossip, and other tidbits, is
on again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>, a former senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and the
New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , will be filing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Our ongoing
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" about Internet gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> , between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frum</ENAMEX>, switches from
discussing the issue of libel on the Internet to the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>'s role
in starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal. A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tangled Web</ENAMEX>"
column by 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> traces the path of the story
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Drudge</ENAMEX>, to the Internet as a whole, to television--and only then to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. Speaking of papers, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">International Papers</ENAMEX>" will keep you abreast of how the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> around the world are treating the scandal. And for an elegant
summary and analysis of the latest developments, go to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin</ENAMEX>."

            
               Is Not!
Is Too!!
            

            Second only in urgency to
the question of whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should be impeached
for subornation of perjury is the question of whether a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">501</NUMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) charitable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> is legally permitted to engage in lobbying of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. In a
recent column about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> asserted that it
isn't. In "E-Mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> asserts that it
is too. Who's
right? By a fortunate coincidence, one of the world's living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> on this
deeply troubling topic is the live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Allen</ENAMEX>'s definitive memo is available
here.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> is
not the first 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> to appear in our pages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah</ENAMEX>
Needleman, author of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> gardening columns (and we hope many more) is married to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackathlete Hanna Rosin</ENAMEX> is married to 
                  Slate
               'ssenior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>. Suspicious minds may be thinking at this point that being
married to a 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> carries some kind of unfair advantage
in getting published in 
                  Slate
               . Absolutely not. If anything, the
opposite is true. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> are a dime <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX>. In choosing among the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, it is
only reasonable to give a modest preference to those who can bring along a good
gardening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, a gifted hack, or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">501</TIMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.

            
               Sign Up
to Sign Up
            

            As you
probably know by now, 
                  Slate
                will soon become a paid-subscription
site. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for my discussion of the whys and wherefores <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>.) In the next few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, we will be sending subscription information--including a special
early-bird offer--to 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> whose e-mail addresses we
have, through registration or e-mail delivery of 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
               
or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, and so on. If we don't have you in our records (or you're
not sure), and you'd like to receive subscription information (or you're not
sure!), just e-mail kinsley@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and we'll put you on the list. Or, of course,
you can still sign up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few weeks</TIMEX> of free e-mail delivery of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, and you can still register free (required for
posting in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>" and
some other 
                  Slate
                features). Needless to say, 
                  Slate
               
does not sell or share this information, or use it for ulterior purposes.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
