
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payback Time</ENAMEX>

            Back when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> owned
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> ran the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Nightingale</ENAMEX> of wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>. He called it a "tragedy" that
"politics" had entered the judicial-nomination system. Defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> commented, "When you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of this caliber, I think it's just
terrible to try and make an ideological battle out of it." When it came to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">executive-branch</ENAMEX> appointments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> was adamant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> defer to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s choices. On this basis, he stood up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bradford Reynolds</ENAMEX>,
rejected for the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>, shot down as head of the civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.

            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatch</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, and he's the one blocking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s choices--most recently the nomination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> to be
assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> for civil rights. Aware that he is vulnerable to a
charge of double standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> has his defense ready. He says he's not a
hypocrite, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> changed the rules. In a hearing before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recess</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Leahy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>, proposed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
nomination on to the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> without a recommendation, something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> had
wanted to do for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> responded that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goose</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> for the gander. "I argued for reporting the nominations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lucas</ENAMEX> without recommendations," he said. "But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leahy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> all voted no."

            There's no denying that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> changed the rules. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Carter</ENAMEX> explains in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Confirmation Mess</ENAMEX> , contested
appointments were relatively rare from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s through the 1970s</TIMEX>. But around
the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> rediscovered the more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">literal</ENAMEX>, pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> understanding of "advice and consent." (This in
itself is ironic: Usually it is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who insist on taking the words of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> literally and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who argue for a broader
interpretation.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Lefever</ENAMEX> to withdraw as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary of state</ENAMEX> for human rights because he gave no
indication of caring about human rights. (It didn't help matters when family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefever</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> were genetically inferior, or when Lefever
himself told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Percy</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> were part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
conspiracy.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, the judiciary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX> from moving up
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s position--which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX>
endorsed--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Jones University</ENAMEX>, which forbade (and continues to forbid)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interracial</ENAMEX> dating, should be allowed to keep its tax-exempt status. This was
followed by the rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tower</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense, and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> standard was that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deference</ENAMEX> could no longer be expected, at least for jobs involving civil and
human rights.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> contend they're just playing by
these rules. "A deeply satisfying and entirely valid reason for rejecting the
nomination is pay-back," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> wrote in a recent column on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. Others
made the same argument about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lani Guinier</ENAMEX>, who never even got a hearing for the
civil-rights job in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>; and about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Dellinger</ENAMEX>, who served for several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> as "acting" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitor general</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> wouldn't confirm
him.

            But in
fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has gone beyond tit for tat. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> always conjured up some
kind of pretext: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX> hadn't enforced the law; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> had no background in
civil-rights enforcement and hadn't declared some stuff at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s
case, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> says he's opposing a qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> simply to draw the
line on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> position he disagrees with. "I think it's time for us
to that are dividing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> and ripping us apart," he declared in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>.

            Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have done away with deference for
a whole range of posts that touch upon contentious social issues, not just
those involving civil rights. Before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> killed the
nomination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Foster</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon general</ENAMEX> because of his support for
legalized abortion. Now they are sitting on the nomination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Satcher</ENAMEX> for
the same reason. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> has also been holding up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of nominations for
federal judgeships. In these cases, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have taken the
implicit position that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> shares the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s views,
that is reason enough for rejection.

            Nothing
can stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> from changing the rules of the nomination process
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unilaterally</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. And there's no way to enforce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> are free to defer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on ambassadors
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>, but not on chairpersons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> and surgeons
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, if they so desire. It is also egregiously unfair to charge, as Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mikulski</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, and others have, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> are
guilty of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> racism because they have chosen to make a fuss in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s
case and not in others. But ability and good sense are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different things.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-deference stance is a foolish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, even for those who share his
politics.

            
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hatch</ENAMEX> standard is
that it won't work. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> take the position that they will not accept
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> who share the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s views on important issues, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX> will remain perpetually unfilled. In the case of civil-rights enforcement,
this might not bother <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, many of whom don't believe in the whole
concept. But keeping an important post vacant may actually undermine the
attempt to change the policy it represents. Civil-rights enforcement can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> more quietly from another desk. As long as it is, there won't be any
point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to answer for administration policies, or to the public. In the
case of judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>, there's a more serious problem of justice delayed
(which, as we know, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> denied) due to a shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> problem is less tangible. The more policy disputes are personified, the
more the confirmation process becomes a war of martyrs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dragon slayers</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uglier</ENAMEX> and more unproductive politics becomes. On top of the many sacrifices
public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> already must make--disclosure, lower pay, restrictions on what
they can do after they leave--they must increasingly bank on being gratuitously
ripped apart by a totally politicized confirmation process. This seems too much
to ask. Already, those who aspire to confirmation must express themselves in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">euphemisms</ENAMEX> and pretend to have no views.

            There's no reason why affirmative action, in particular,
needs to be fought out at this sublimated level. In recent decisions, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has both circumscribed preferential policies and made clear that
they can be limited or abolished by legislation. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> want to
try to proscribe race-conscious policies by democratic means, nobody's stopping
them (from trying, that is).

            The last issue is practical.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some day</TIMEX>, divided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will again be divided the other way. When that
happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will be bound to escalate the confirmation battle once more,
to settle their score with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>. And so on, and so on. The game of payback
never ends.

         
      
   
