
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liars</ENAMEX>

            
               Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Liars</ENAMEX>
            

            Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is
the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, we suppose, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> may be the more brazen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
"that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>" lie at least was a sincere attempt to keep us in the dark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
by contrast, seems to think he can mislead us about truths that are right in
front of our eyes. And maybe he can.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , for example, carried excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> explaining why he would not give
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX> an advance peek at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. "As you doubtless know,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> wrote, "this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> steadily has maintained the position that it would
not be appropriate to comment on the possibility that it would provide a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'report</ENAMEX>' to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>." Naturally it is impossible to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX> see the report
in advance if you have a steadily maintained position that you don't even
concede the "possibility" that such a report exists.

            That was on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A18</NUMEX> of the national edition. Meanwhile, on
Page A1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Report by Starr Against Clinton Expected Soon"</ENAMEX>) of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>,
the "possibility" of a " 'report' " from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was getting very different
treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "plans to deliver a report" quite soon, and he "intends to
alert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>" that very day that the report contains "credible
grounds for impeachment." The report "is expected to outline ... will almost
certainly say ... is likely to include ..." and so on. Says who? Say "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> of
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> familiar with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s plans" and so forth.

            Despite the coy labeling,
this information could come from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>: someone's imagination
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. And since the info has proved to be accurate, the first
option defies probability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has said he disapproves of leaks, but leaks
have gushered out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> before and since, and no one has been caught
and fired. So it's obvious that his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>" did not have a steadily maintained
position of not commenting on its then-forthcoming report. It was commenting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and still is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX> was, in short, a lie.

            The same
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> Times contained its usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> editorial calling for more
flamboyant abjection from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, adding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "correctly rejected" his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s request to see the report in advance. It failed to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
reason for rejecting the request was transparently false.

            
               How to
Avoid Flytrap
            

            E-mail continues to pour in
complaining about too much 
                  Slate
                coverage of the presidential
scandal. For 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who agree with this sentiment, we have
created a special page listing and linking to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> stories in

                  Slate
                they may wish to avoid. They may wish to make an exception
for our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unique versions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, supplied to us early in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> by free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Levine</ENAMEX>, has turned out to be wildly
inaccurate. In hindsight, probably, we should have suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
would not use the phrase "fiery loins." Oh well.

            At this writing, the actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> is not yet out on the Web. As soon as it is, though, we plan to run it
through a feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Word <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX>. AutoSummarize
reduces the bulk of any piece of prose by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 90 percent</NUMEX> while attempting to
retain the original essence.

            We'll also, of course, have
links to various locations where you can read the whole thing.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
