
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Tobacco Whores</ENAMEX>

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry McPherson</ENAMEX>
is a saintly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>. As a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon B. Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPherson</ENAMEX> was an
important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the civil-rights movement, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> were attacked in
Selma, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX> helped persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> to deploy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> to protect
them. Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, he tried to talk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> out of escalating the
war.

            Today
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry McPherson</ENAMEX> is a tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR Nabisco</ENAMEX>,
and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have been negotiating a global
settlement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX>'s heavily
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernhard, McPherson</ENAMEX> &
Hand is being paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $200,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> by the tobacco industry, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX> . As senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX> has also helped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit liberal heroes</ENAMEX> of a more recent vintage as cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> recently deployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-tongued former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>,
to work on the settlement alongside former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, who was already on the case. Other well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have also
joined the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> recently. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter Eskew</ENAMEX>, a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who has
worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Dodd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>, is giving media
advice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> involved in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$368-billion</NUMEX> settlement, with the help
of others at his Democratically inclined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bozell Sawyer Miller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>.

            It is hard to say precisely what all these big-name
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are doing on behalf of the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. According to a report
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>, who is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, recently
paid a lobbying call on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> to encourage him to either support the
agreement (which needs congressional approval) or soft-pedal his objections.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> declined to comment, as did her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Hickie</ENAMEX>, a
Verner, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liipfert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> conducting negotiations on
behalf of the industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX> also declined to comment, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eskew</ENAMEX>. None
of them has yet filed a lobbying disclosure form that might give additional
particulars. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPherson</ENAMEX> says that his own work involves advising the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and lobbying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to support the deal.

            Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX>'s
recently acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bauble</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, who is still covered by
post-government-employment restrictions on lobbying, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> is free to work
his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX> was the one who brought the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
in as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and who participated in some of the early negotiating sessions.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPherson</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> hasn't yet "done much talking" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>
because he has been too busy as special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> peace talks. But
that distraction hasn't stopped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> from lobbying on other issues.
According to a recent issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll Call</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> worked
together on a provision of the budget deal on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit of the Loom</ENAMEX>. With
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX> working the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> advising <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> succeeded in
striking out a provision supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that would have allowed
more apparel imports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>.

            To see
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former legislative colossi bury their ideological differences and
come together on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> underpants is either inspiring or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grotesque</ENAMEX>, depending on your perspective. But while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s agreement with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> is that he won't lobby for the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> is likely to
ply the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> for them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this autumn</TIMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX> argues that lobbying on behalf of the
tobacco settlement is not the same as working for the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> under
ordinary circumstances, something he suggests his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> would not have done. He
says the proposed deal serves the public interest by restricting cigarette
advertising and marketing, and by requiring the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to cough up
billions if youth smoking fails to decline dramatically. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacts it
in pretty much its current shape, I believe it will be the biggest step forward
in public health with regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> in history," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPherson</ENAMEX> says. "The
tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have had to come forward with an inconceivably large number
of major concessions--committing to change everything about the way they
advertise and market cigarettes."

            Berl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernhard</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> who is an old-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>--he
worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Muskie</ENAMEX> and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Commission on Civil Rights</ENAMEX>--offers a
similar defense of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. He says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX> agreed to take on
tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> only after being persuaded that they were ready to mend their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>, and that a global settlement would serve the common good. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernhard</ENAMEX> avers
that he has been amazed by the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> the tobacco industry has
agreed to pony up. "The amount of money is staggering," he says. "They have
gone way beyond where I thought they would go."

            In a deal like this, it's not unusual for both sides to
claim, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernhard</ENAMEX> do, that they're getting the short end of the
stick--that's all part of the negotiation. What is truly odd is lawyers
suggesting that cutting a lousy deal absolves them of blame for working for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">creeps</ENAMEX>. This defense is also preposterous. Like any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liipfert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are trying to get the best deal they can for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
The morality of their participation doesn't depend on how badly they do.

            McPherson
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernhard</ENAMEX> also stretch the bounds of credulity when they suggest that what
they're doing is OK because they're merely working on a settlement, not on
traditional tobacco-industry concerns such as preventing regulation. There's no
moral distinction here. You settle a case if you believe you'll be better off
doing so. And in any event, there's no reason to think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX>'s work
will be confined to the settlement. An <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23</TIMEX> statement announces that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> has been retained "to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> in light of the heightened legal and
regulatory activities surrounding tobacco products." I asked both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernhard</ENAMEX> and
McPherson whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> would in fact limit its work to the settlement. Both
answered in lawyerly fashion that the issue of work on other matters "hasn't
come up."

            
Finally, it is fallacious to suggest that
because society may benefit from a compromise with an evildoer, work on behalf
of the evildoer is justified. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are good--and they
are at least well connected--they will strike a better bargain for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> would otherwise have got. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> might make the
case that even tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have rights, and that the public interest
actually was served by getting these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> a better bargain. But they
didn't make that case, at least to me. They themselves appear to accept--or at
least to be unwilling to challenge--the widely held assumption that the public
interest lies in the worst possible deal for the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            The traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> entitles everyone to legal
representation--hardly cuts it here either. Working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> isn't
like defending an indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> in a death penalty appeal. It's more like
defending a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> is going to have decent-quality
representation whether or not any particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> decides to sully his hands.
And in this instance, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>" defense is even weaker because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eskew</ENAMEX>, and the others are working not just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, but as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> as well. Despite the best efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
influence-peddling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, there's still no constitutional right to lobbying
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>. If you can't find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> won't appoint <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for you.

            Former <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>, too, is working on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
involved in the settlement, and he deserves as much scorn as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. But somehow you expect that from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, whereas you don't
expect it from big-name national <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northerners</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>. The only thing you can say on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> is that, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy operators</ENAMEX> on both sides have sold out to the tobacco industry, they
alone seem to feel a bit embarrassed about it.

         
      
   
