
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>! Where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do You Want To Go Today</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hey,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>! Where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do You Want To Go Today</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>, the legendary
consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>, recently announced plans for a conference called "Appraising
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Strategies</ENAMEX>." In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> to extend a public invitation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> to
visit the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSS</ENAMEX> specializes in making
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want to appraise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s global strategies feel loved. Our
initial response was that we didn't wish to be used in that manner. But the OSS
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> liaison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> reasoned, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look, bud</ENAMEX>, do you know who you're dealing
with here?" And we took that to be a fair point.

            Plans are
well advanced to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>'s day at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> a delight. It will start with a
magnificent rainstorm, which will hit just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> emerges from the airport
terminal. (He never carries an umbrella. "Do you know how many microbes there
are on the typical umbrella handle?") As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host team</ENAMEX> will explain
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> in an all-cash offer. Other weather
patterns may be acquired in the future. No "global strategy" involved! The sole
purpose is to provide weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> with a more consistent meteorological
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interface</ENAMEX>. A wide variety of weather will continue to be offered free of
charge--to all registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>--because, well, that's just the kind of company
we are. Certain select weather patterns (e.g., sunshine) will be fee-based,
although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> of balmy weather will come bundled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> will be met and driven from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corvair</ENAMEX>. A gala luncheon in his honor at the company <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feature Microsoft Food Service</ENAMEX>'s justly famous high-nitrite hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and
unlimited <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Additives Bar</ENAMEX>. After lunch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> will be given a
sneak preview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 98</ENAMEX>, to be made out of safety glass. Then, Chief
Technology Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX> will give a demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bag TM</ENAMEX> , experimental software to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> from physical harm
when their computers crash. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> develop
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hernias</ENAMEX> or serious back problems from attempting to lift up their machines and
fling them across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Air Bag TM</ENAMEX> is an instantly
inflating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> that will pin the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to his or her seat until the computer
can safely reboot.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> already has called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to make air
bags mandatory on all new computers.

            But the undoubted highlight
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> will be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, which is scheduled to take
place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Throne Room</ENAMEX> of his new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The original plan called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>
to enter on his knees, fall prostrate, and apologize profusely for impugning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s motives. He would then be taken off and melted into software. But
all this changed when we told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>'s
mandatory-air-bags-for-computers idea. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mandatory?</ENAMEX>" he said. "Require
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to buy software? What a marketing concept! It fits in perfectly with our
global stra ... er, our vision for humanity. I like the way this man
thinks!"

            You see?
Why can't we all just get along?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
