
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno Divorce</ENAMEX>

            Even by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> has
suffered a wicked case of conventional-wisdom whiplash. After famously "taking
responsibility" for the botched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> raid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, she was lionized for
her refreshing readiness to be held accountable. Before long, however, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buck</ENAMEX>-stops-here cliché grew stale, and the story line changed. It became:
Because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s managerial incompetence and the disarray she presided over at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, a lot of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidians</ENAMEX> died unnecessarily.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version 2</ENAMEX> is at least as dubious as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Version 1</ENAMEX>.) Originally hailed as "the very
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, bar none," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Kondracke</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has more recently been called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s "worst major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
appointment" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> .

            The latest and most
dramatic turnabout has been on the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s "independence." The
approved view until recently was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> had made herself irrelevant--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> nonplayer--by being so intractable and prissy. Various articles
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and '96</TIMEX> included mutterings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> had no relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and that officials
would love nothing more than an excuse to replace her after the election. More
recently, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have insinuated--and the news media have
reflected--the view that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is not just a team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, but a political shill
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. This is because she refuses to appoint an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> in the campaign-finance scandal . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , in a
recent editorial, raised doubts about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s "loyalty to the public." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, went well beyond that, comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mitchell</ENAMEX>, who went to jail for obstruction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s comments are as offensive as usual, but even the
milder form is absurd. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> do play against type from time to time, but the
charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has suddenly become a docile tool of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> simply
doesn't wash. Her decision on the independent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> issue may be good or
bad--but it is legally defensible, and the evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has been swayed
by political factors doesn't amount to a prima facie case.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> point is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s
own background and personality. As state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dade County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>
acquired a reputation not just for integrity but for an almost fanatical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">probity</ENAMEX>. She asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to prosecute
her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> when the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Reno</ENAMEX> was arrested for drunken driving. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> was criticized for her management style, for her
sentimental notions about crime, and for her general mulishness. But until a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, no one ever accused her of bending the law.

            Even if she were a different sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, the case that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is acting politically in not appointing an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> would fall
apart over the issue of motivation . When calls first came for an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> might have been vulnerable to pressure.
She was, by all accounts, eager to stay on as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> in an
administration that was not at all eager to keep her. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some time</TIMEX> after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inauguration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might have got away with getting rid of her while he was
replacing others in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>.

            But political
circumstances have changed since then. The best thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> could possibly do to
guarantee her own job security is to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. If she
did, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could never get rid of her. If he tried, it would be treated like
a version of the infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Massacre</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> kept firing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who wouldn't fire special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archibald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX>.

            Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision not to appoint is correct on the
merits is another question, which won't be settled here. But it is pretty
clearly within the bounds of reasonableness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have been
imprecise, and often contradictory, on the question of why they think she must
appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Under the law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> is obliged
to do so if she comes across "specific and credible" evidence of criminal
wrongdoing by a high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> covered by the act. She also has the
discretionary powers to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> if she feels there would
be a "personal, financial, or political conflict of interest" if normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
Department procedures were followed.

            Though it is blindingly
obvious to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> that criminal acts were performed by high-level
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, they don't agree among themselves about which actions by
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> qualify. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, thinks it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s
fund-raising calls from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Cause</ENAMEX> thinks it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
coordination of soft-money expenditures from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, thinks it's letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> says that no accusation against either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
meets the "specific and credible" standard. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, she asserts in a lengthy
response to a request from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, was raising soft money, which is not covered
by the regulation that prohibits solicitations from government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The
coordination of soft-money expenditures that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was involved in, she says,
isn't illegal. I think this last interpretation is unfortunate, because it
opens the floodgates for unlimited contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and labor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, which is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Watergate</ENAMEX> election reforms were supposed to
prevent. But legally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is on pretty firm ground.

            That leaves the more vague--and
discretionary--language about "personal, financial, or political conflict of
interest." No one has suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has a financial or personal stake in
the latest scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> and others have made the case that she faces a
political conflict: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> presiding over
an investigation that is potentially embarrassing and damaging to the
administration. But the standard for appointing an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> can't be
that broad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys general</ENAMEX> face political conflicts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>--whether to
bring cases against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. Given a broad interpretation, the conflict-of-interest
provision would require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX>, if not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>, of independent counsels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>
has apparently construed this ambiguous provision in the only way one sensibly
can. It gives her a wider berth than the "specific and credible" language, but
it does not require her to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> every time someone in
the opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> detects the appearance of a political conflict.

            Paradoxically, caving in to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bolster Reno</ENAMEX>'s reputation for fearless independence. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>
had ordered up an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, not only would her job have been secure
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> (and maybe even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>) would be swooning
over her once again. Standing up to them, and doing what she evidently feels is
right, means being taken for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hack. To her great credit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has thus
far rejected the perception of independence in favor of the genuine
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
