
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Descending</ENAMEX>

            He was persecuted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tormented</ENAMEX>, and crucified. But at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>, he rose. That, at least, is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s apostles are saying about him, pointing to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s successful
trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> and his return to public visibility following the
congressional spring recess.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is
sounding like his old self again. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> he called for abolition of both the
capital-gains tax and the estate tax. (For more on the capital-gains debate,
see this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C. Goodman</ENAMEX>.) In an
hour-long speech to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOPAC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, he boasted about the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mongolia</ENAMEX>. Once again the historical pedant, he explained
why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign-finance scandal--which he previously called merely
"worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>"--is actually tantamount to the fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. In ancient
times, "sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and offering bribes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> became the easiest and
most profitable route to wealth and power for many local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>
said. "If it is proven that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Communists</ENAMEX> were trying to funnel money
into a presidential defense fund, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> model of foreign corruption
will indeed be raising its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system."

            Contrary to the media hype and rumors floating around
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> will probably not be deposed before the next election. To
get rid of him would require not just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few dozen</NUMEX> defections, but a majority
vote of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX>. There is still no fully plausible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, and sacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> would mean <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> running in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> on a
record of catastrophe rather than mere inaction. At the same time, the
precariousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s position is making him and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
act in weird, unpredictable ways. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s shakiness has turned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
into a strange and somewhat silly place.

            The most
obvious effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s insecurity is on his own behavior, which has
consisted lately of dramatic lurches, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to the left, then to the right.
Before his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s comeback strategy was to show that he was not
the radical-right ogre of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> direct mail. He made nice with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> and announced that he was dropping affirmative action as an
issue. He warmly received <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal actors</ENAMEX>, who came to
lobby on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baldwin</ENAMEX> had been
quoted calling him "evil," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> invited him and the other thespians back
for dinner, and declared that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> might not be such a bad thing after all.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> who were annoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s nice-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> act were truly outraged when
he suggested that one way to get a balanced-budget agreement might be to put
off tax cuts.

            
This gambit was based on what was at least a
plausible political calculation. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> could separate their tax cuts
in the public mind from the domestic budget cuts necessary to balance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> could no longer accuse them of throwing old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the
snow in order to save money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. The idea was also to do with
taxes what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had shrewdly done with welfare reform in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
holding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s feet to the fire by sending him a politically popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">stand-alone bill.</ENAMEX> But the result of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s suggestion was blind fury on the
right. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman hotheads</ENAMEX> elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> openly challenged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. In a short, shocking article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> "political road
kill." In the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> didn't have to stand for this kind of
insubordination. Faced with an episode of dissent back then, he stripped one
nonconformist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> of a choice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> assignment.

            Now,
however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> lacks the power to punish, and can do little more than suck
up to his conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. He apologized profusely for the
"misunderstanding" about his comments on tax cuts. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOPAC</ENAMEX> speech was filled
with right-wing red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, such as a proposed crackdown on the political
influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and a demand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> be brought
to heel. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9</TIMEX>, he surprised everyone by proposing a more aggressive tax
cut than any of his more conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, calling for an end to all
taxes on both capital gains and estates, changes that would cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. In keeping with conservative newspeak,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> referred to these as the taxes on "savings and job creation" and the
tax on "death benefits."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is not the only one behaving erratically. As he
moves to shore up his right-wing credentials, his more authentically
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are trying to establish their own credibility in the eyes
of moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to suggest that going after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> again
might not be such a hot idea was not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libertarian</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>. When he came out with his put-off-the-tax-cuts suggestion,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was actually endorsing a proposal by ultracon <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
DeLay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> has been taking sudden umbrage at accusations that he is a tool of
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> has been losing weight and restraining his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proclivity</ENAMEX> toward quasioffensive humor. (At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, he joked, "I'm happy to be black--I mean back," and chided journalists
about their preference for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX>.) Gossip swirls about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-way
rivalry among the top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who rank just below <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boehner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX>. The latest rumor has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> teaming up
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> and majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            All this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jockeying</ENAMEX> has forestalled any real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> agenda. Compared with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperactive 104 th Congress</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> has been a joke.
What little time it has actually been in session it has spent on issues like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who posted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtroom</ENAMEX>, and a congressional gold medal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> passed a resolution banning the use of federal funds for assisted
suicide. Of course, no federal funds go to assisted suicide. In a caucus
meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> reportedly said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who
complained he had no agenda "weren't smart enough to understand it."

            
The most damaging consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s
weakness is the difficulty of negotiating what might be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s proudest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>--an agreement to balance the budget. The paradox is that while a
deal would shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s position, he hasn't got enough power to negotiate
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> are quite close on the numbers,
those on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s right flank are likely to portray any agreement with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as a capitulation born of weakness. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> had the clout
to make a centrist budget compromise stick. Now such an agreement would
probably provoke open rebellion, divide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, and deprive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of a
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>.

            The result is a complex
stalemate. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> face the prospect of running in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> with a discredited,
unpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> who is nonetheless impossible to dethrone, and with no record
of accomplishment. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> sinks deeper into
scandal-related debt, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> can look forward to running without a
functional party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to support them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> vs. the destitute--it
could be a great race.

         
      
   
