
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Calumny</ENAMEX>

            The best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> story I've
heard recently comes from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter friend</ENAMEX> of mine who went to check up on
some local property records relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign-finance
investigation. Inside the municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the Recorder
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deeds</ENAMEX> was supposed to be located, she followed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Way</ENAMEX>" signs for
property records up to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> and down a series of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX>.
When she finally found what appeared to be the right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, she opened the
door. Inside were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, standing around a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber grill</ENAMEX> cooking
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>. This was at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> They didn't have any property records, they said, but
she was welcome to some barbecue.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, this kind of anecdote constitutes gallows humor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is so
badly run that the only real defense is to laugh about it. This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>, after his release from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, tried to give a contract to
lay sewer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rock Newman</ENAMEX>, a boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>. It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> court convicts as an important political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>; where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> works for the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a proportion that rises steadily
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> hemorrhages; where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> once said that the crime rate
wasn't so bad if you didn't count murder.

            It is also becoming known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where representative
government failed. In a provision of the recently passed budget bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
used its constitutional authority to strip power from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, and to vest it in the financial control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that was set up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
This effectively suspends, for a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least four years</TIMEX>, the limited
"home rule" granted to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. In a column last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Unfit for Home Rule</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> a
"debacle of democracy." Quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stuart Mill</ENAMEX>, he called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, who
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> term after his release from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, "unfit for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberty</ENAMEX>." Mincing words even less, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> wrote in his syndicated column
that congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dixiecrats</ENAMEX> did a far better job of running <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in the
1950s. "How can we proclaim as the goal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy the
'expansion of democracy,' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> wrote, "when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> is being ditched in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s nearly explicit
argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> doesn't work when most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> aren't white is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insupportable</ENAMEX> as well as offensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with a racial makeup
similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s, has no comparable problems. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, a largely
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that is far worse off than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX>, now appears to
be on the mend after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> replaced an ineffectual black<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-nationalist mayor</ENAMEX>
with a dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>. But the usual liberal explanations for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s
predicament--that the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is underfunded, and that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are
still partially disenfranchised--are hardly more compelling. When it comes to
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> spends more to less effect than any other
big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In other areas, like housing, it is notorious
for failing to tap federal funds for which it is eligible, through sheer
incompetence. And while amending the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> to give District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
voting representation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> might make them feel better, it would
probably do little to address their underlying problems.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> are wrong about democracy being at fault. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> are wrong
about the problem being too little money and too few rights. So what is
wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>? A better explanation begins with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> defects: a
less-than-viable governing structure, a sick political culture, and a tradition
of gutless journalism.

            
               Government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>. In his study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX> Without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suburbs</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rusk</ENAMEX> argues that the most important measure of urban
well-being is "elasticity," that is, whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s boundaries can expand to
encompass outlying areas. This isn't just a question of preserving the tax
base. It's a matter of preserving a middle-class interest in urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>--the school system, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, and so on. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, has "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> elasticity." But it is far worse off than those
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, because District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who move to the suburbs also move
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">out-of-state</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>. Suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> don't share even the
common umbrella of a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> lacks even the few powers
that other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> have to help retain a fast-disappearing middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. For instance, according to its home-rule charter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX>
government can't even require that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> live in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. This makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that has always suffered from a high degree
of racial and economic segregation, a virtual machine for concentrating
poverty.

            
               Political culture. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> works like this: Paternalism <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>
rebellion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebellion</ENAMEX> fails, or succeeds only in limited ways, which leads to
frustration and apathy. The cycle then repeats itself. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> limited voting rights to elect a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, only to take those
rights away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX> because of accusations of corruption and
financial mismanagement, and also because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. Sound
familiar? It took another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> for home rule to arrive. But the
civil-rights-movement politics that brought home rule never translated into the
more regular habits of good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Opportunistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, namely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>, kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> focused on the denial of their full rights--and the
threat that even the limited ones that had been granted would be taken away.
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overseers</ENAMEX> played into this <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> by ignoring home rule
whenever it suited them. For instance, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Shelby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>,
tried to foist the death penalty on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that didn't want it. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> threatened to override self-government for the sake of getting rid
of rent control. More recently, home rule has been effectively suspended for a
better reason--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has bankrupted itself. Bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has
the psychological quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> "acting out." In no other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is voting
for a corrupt and incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> an expression of protest against
condescending parental authority.

            

               Press failure. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dysfunctional</ENAMEX> political culture, the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> becomes paramount. If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> isn't holding its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> accountable, the press is the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> that can spur it to do so. Unfortunately, for most of the period of
home rule, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has been not just a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-paper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, but a cowardly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-paper <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Out of a misguided sense of white guilt, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'80s</TIMEX>, and much of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> a free ride.
It endorsed him in every mayoral contest until he got arrested for smoking
crack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has improved a bit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX>, but its
attitude has historically been to hold black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to a lower standard.
In a shrewd section on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in his new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Future Once Happened</ENAMEX>
Here , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Siegel</ENAMEX> suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> would have done well to have had a
pugnacious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s.

            None of this exculpates the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX>, who have elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times and may well elect
him again, though he now plays only the role of queen to control-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Brimmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. It does not excuse their bad judgment to point
out that there are white precedents for self-destructive democratic behavior.
In much the same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> re-elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> after his
release from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> supported their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curley</ENAMEX>, when he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curley</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> at playing
upon the social resentments of his disadvantaged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>, doing them a
great disservice while proclaiming himself their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>. In '90s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
as in '20s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who fall for this type of demagoguery are
ultimately the ones at fault. What it does not mean, however, is that
voting is at fault.

         
      
   
