
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Birthday</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>

            Next
month marks the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>, the
biggest and best known of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX>. The festivities began a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX> with a black-tie gala for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,700</NUMEX>, at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> spoke
on the topic of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courage</ENAMEX>." ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and I refused to accept the decline
of the West as our ineluctable destiny," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> declared, displaying her
usual modesty and sense of fun.) The revelries are to continue for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> full
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, with a traveling lecture series featuring such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, who will orate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> about "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>,
who will address the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Beach</ENAMEX> on the subject of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Character</ENAMEX>."
Another vast dinner in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> will cap the series and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85-million</NUMEX> fund-raising drive. To commemorate the occasion, the foundation
also has sponsored a gushing account of its first quarter-century, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Power</ENAMEX>
of Ideas , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Edwards</ENAMEX>. The book's title is incongruous, since the whole
point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> is that ideas alone have little power without
a big push.

            By all measures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> has much to celebrate. From
across the political spectrum, opinion appears to be unanimous that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> has been singularly effective in accomplishing its mission of
dragging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics to the right. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980</TIMEX> release of its
Mandate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership</ENAMEX> , a detailed program for the incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
administration that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> actually took seriously, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>
has played a central role in setting not only the broad conservative agenda but
also the details of legislation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX>' book delights in quoting envious
encomia from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy camp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Shuman</ENAMEX> of the left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for</ENAMEX>
Policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Studies</ENAMEX> credits Heritage with a bigger influence on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics
and policy than any other conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Marshall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Democratic Progressive Policy Institute</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> "wrote the book
on how to market and popularize political ideas." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , among
others, keeps up a steady drumbeat on this theme: Why doesn't the left have an
advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> as influential as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>? Well, why not?

            The most
obvious explanation is money. A right-wing "advocacy tank" like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> is
able to raise much more than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal counterparts</ENAMEX> for the same reason that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> out-raise <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> ones. Those who have a lot to
give--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>--give primarily in their own
self-interest. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, unlike political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>
can accept donations directly from corporate treasuries.) Self-interested money
goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that promote lower taxes and less regulation, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> topics
on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> is absolutely unflinching. To be sure, there is disinterested
conservative money, and self-interested liberal money, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> funds
that go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Policy Institute</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX> that opposes free-trade
agreements. But such exceptions don't change the rule. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX>, often cast as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal counterpart</ENAMEX>, could never dream of
raising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>.

            In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> isn't really <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>'s liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>. Though it has historically exhibited a modest liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slant</ENAMEX>--diminished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> thinks of itself as a scholarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> devoted to objective research into public policy. It would never
spend its money in an explicit effort to harm its political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>, because it
does not conceive of itself as taking a side and does not view politics as
ideological warfare. This is even more true of the big "liberal" foundations
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur</ENAMEX>. New Right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, on the other
hand, as exemplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>, are quite explicit about viewing politics as
combat. In the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Feulner</ENAMEX>, "We conduct warfare
in the battle of ideas." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> exerts a strong moderating influence, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feulner</ENAMEX> has been attacked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> for going "establishment"--wanting to
be prestigious and respected like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> instead of being powerful and
feared. This is the same fault Heritage attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> for in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. But even if it has settled down a bit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>
still retains an insurgent mindset. It views itself as the center of a radical
movement, even if it has become part of an entrenched <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
establishment.

            Because of its combat mentality, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> has never been a
place with very high standards. Like other conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX>, it loves the
lingo of academic life. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> are cluttered with endowed chairs,
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX>, and distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. The conceit here is that as a PC
Dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> has overcome the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX> have become
the refuge of thought and learning. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> in particular, this is a laugh.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX> frequently produce stimulating books and
studies and occasionally arrive at unexpected positions. Even the more dogmatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX> has cultivated a reputation for rigorous research and analysis
from a libertarian point of view. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>, however, is essentially a
propaganda <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>. There are exceptions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Butler</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brit</ENAMEX> who runs the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">domestic-policy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, has done solid work on enterprise zones, and took pains
to develop a conscientious conservative alternative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> health-care
plan. But on the whole, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> is focused on selling and promoting its views
rather than on developing thoughtful or nuanced ones. It spends <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> its
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget on marketing. It prides itself on producing reports
with concision and speed. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent innovation is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colored</ENAMEX> index card summarizing a conservative position in "short, punchy
sentences." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-president</ENAMEX> for information marketing,"
these cards have been "wildly successful" with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            Its
ethical standards are as lax as its intellectual ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> is a tax-exempt
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">501</NUMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, which means it is not supposed to lobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> notes that a disclaimer appears at the foot of all its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>.
"Nothing written here is to be construed as an attempt to aid or hinder the
passage of any bill before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>." This is an evident absurdity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>
exists to aid and hinder legislation before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and often boasts
about doing so. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> disclaimer immediately after he
finishes explaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feulner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Weyrich</ENAMEX> founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> because in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEI</ENAMEX> was taking its tax-exempt status too seriously. Having
been investigated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEI</ENAMEX> didn't focus on getting
its reports into the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> before the relevant votes.
For whatever reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal groups</ENAMEX> tend to be more punctilious about this.
Many are split between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">501</NUMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), to which contributions
are tax deductible, and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">501</NUMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>), which is simply not taxable itself, and
which has more latitude in lobbying. This reduces the amount liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> can
raise, enhancing their natural disadvantage.

            
At bottom, the big liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX> remain
temperamentally different from the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>. They have their vices, to
be sure. They can be ponderous, conventional, and gimmicky--and miraculously,
sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> at once. But you can't see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth-Century Fund</ENAMEX>
feeding policy popcorn to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. They'd be insulted by the
idea. It's hard to imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Policy Institute</ENAMEX> naming a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-president</ENAMEX> for information marketing." You can't conceive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX>
putting out a volume of self-serving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bluster</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> book. In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> did commission a history for its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">75 th</NUMEX> anniversary in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
It was serious, critical, and self-questioning in a way that is totally alien
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have become better in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
at suppressing their differences in favor of their common interests, they still
shy away instinctually from a united front of the kind that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> is.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> say they want to
learn from the most successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> on the right. But in reality,
they're more comfortable, and probably better off, wishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>
Foundation a happy birthday and admiring it from afar.

         
      
   
