
   
   
      
         
            Soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> Nonsense

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Soccer</ENAMEX>, when I was growing
up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, was a still an esoteric sport. To find matches, we of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menomenee Boys Club</ENAMEX> had to travel a long way from the genteel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Side of Chicago</ENAMEX>. Generally, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> came from ethnic enclaves in
the distant suburbs. On almost a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis, we were humiliated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukrainian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lithuanian</ENAMEX> extraction whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> had been playing
since just after birth. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, who surrounded the field, terrified our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> by abusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX> in thick Slavic accents. We believed they
locked their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sausage</ENAMEX> shed as punishment for missing shots.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> complexion of the game has changed. No longer a mere bridge between
limousine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and the once-captive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> has become as
mainstream as Little League <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the sport is now so populist that
in the opinion of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, it is "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> moms" who will determine the
outcome of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s election. According to a lead story in the New York
Times , published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> presidential debate, soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> have
become "the most sought-after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of the campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>." Following the
debate, the buzz on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> was all about this emergent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> had tried to woo it. The idea is that while most other demographic
segments are largely committed, soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> make up a volatile, and hence
crucial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX>.

            Who exactly, we must ask, are these soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> who hold
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s fate in their hands? "They can be found," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> correspondent
informs us, "shuttling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>, nervously pacing the
sidelines, juggling the demands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and career." Well naturally, but what
sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>? According to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is "a well-heeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-parent</ENAMEX> whose primary mission
in life is to do too much for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. She got on a waiting list early for
the right day-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, sent junior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montessori</ENAMEX>, started violin lessons at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>." According to the
Rocky 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> 
               News , however, soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is "financially
stressed." Opinion is similarly divided on her employment status. In the view
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> 
               Plain 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dealer</ENAMEX> , soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is a career
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has "temporarily taken up child rearing." According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo</ENAMEX> 
               News , however, she is "balancing the demands of work and
family." The consensus seems to be that soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> are some subset of
middle-class, white suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. They "care about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>" (as opposed,
presumably, to urban "rap moms" who do not), and they are incredibly busy. If
you can't find a soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> for your story, don't worry. Part of the shtick is
that she hasn't got time to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>.

            Nexis, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, allows us to trace the historical evolution of the term.
The first reference to a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>" that turns up is from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, and involves
the tawdry tale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ludlow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who absconded with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,150</NUMEX> raised for
the benefit of a local soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. There's very little more until a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>-type tragedy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, when a soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> got so stressed out
that she shot her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and then tried, unsuccessfully, to kill
herself. The application of the term to politics goes back only to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>,
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> described
herself as a soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>--and won. Credit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s coinage apparently
goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Castellanos</ENAMEX>, who made ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>
during the primaries and now works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>. (See a sample of his work in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s Varnish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remover</ENAMEX>.) "The working soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is the swing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> of this election,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castellanos</ENAMEX> told the Wall 
               Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , back before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> campaign signed him up full time. "And she is not going to trust a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who
argues for the need to own an assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. She'll trust a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who can feel
her pain."

            
If the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> moms" has rapidly become
part of the political lexicon, it may be because it is cleverly positioned at
the intersection of several different trends--the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> as a
middle-class pastime, the demanding lives of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the diversification
of the suburbs, the popularity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caravan</ENAMEX>, and so on. Yet there is
something intrinsically misleading about the category, and indeed about all
such categories. The outcome of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> congressional election was supposedly
determined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Angry White Male</ENAMEX>, who
loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> while hating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. What, one wonders,
happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Angry White Male</ENAMEX>? Did he die in a hunting accident? Did he go on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prozac</ENAMEX>? What about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Perot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, who are, by definition, the
largest swing-voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>? Why aren't they deciding the
election? The notion that there is a single demographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that determines
each election, then recedes back into the anonymity of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>, is
useful for political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. But as the impermanence of such
categories suggests, they are usually clichés that obscure as much as they
reveal.

            "The
soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s hula hoop," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Hickman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX> points out that married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in general tend to be very
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>, which somewhat undermines the argument that voting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'96</TIMEX> represents some sort of tectonic shift. But even in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> split <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40-40-20</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> respectively.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX>'s view, the soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> segment is either "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that's so small as
to be meaningless or so large that differences between them are more important
than similarities among them." Narrowly defined as married, college-educated,
suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with school-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> constitute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 4 percent</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>. Broadly defined as suburban white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with
school-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, they add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 11 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX>. But then, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman</ENAMEX>
points out, that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> covers both working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who live in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-bedroom <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ramblers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester County</ENAMEX> with inherited
wealth. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have little in common from election to
election.

            Of course both these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roseannes</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murphy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browns</ENAMEX>, you might say--are currently leaning heavily for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The gender
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gap</ENAMEX> has turned into a gorge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in all categories favoring
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26-point</NUMEX> margin, according to the most recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC/ Wall</ENAMEX> 
               Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> poll. Among soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX>--this is
actually a category in the poll--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is ahead by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> percentage points. If
the election were very close, such a bulge might make a difference. But as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX>
Molineaux of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart Research</ENAMEX> points out, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the gender gap has gotten to
the point where all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are trending <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer moms</ENAMEX>, bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX>,
you name it." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molineaux</ENAMEX> also points out that in polling, it is a truism that
higher up the socioeconomic ladder, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> tend to vote more differently from
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>. So it's hardly a surprise that soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> are somewhat more
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> than bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX>.

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mellman</ENAMEX>, points out that the big swing between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> triumph of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> was among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. And the same seems to
be true of the swing back toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Soccer moms</ENAMEX>, whoever
and however many they are, are less flighty--and thus less crucial to the
election--than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s conception of the
crucial swing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>, in other words, seems especially muddled and misleading.
But it doesn't matter much. By the next election season some other cliché will
have emerged, and we won't have soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> to kick around anymore.

         
      
   
