
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fictional Journalism for Dummies</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fictional Journalism for Dummies</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> have
both commissioned investigations into the question of whether they may have
jointly put out a false story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX>. It's hard to know what there is
to investigate. The story (reported and broadcast by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, with a version
published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) contained two hot allegations: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
used fatal nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> (sarin) on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> and
that the purpose was to kill a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defectors. Both were
almost instantly and pretty spectacularly discredited.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus Krohn of</ENAMEX>

                  Slate
                reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's story appeared, the story's
main cited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> published a memoir <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years ago</TIMEX> that describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX> raid
in detail--but mentions nothing about nerve gas or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defectors. This
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> subsequently explained that he had blocked the memory until it
suddenly resurfaced during his interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> (a little
detail both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> failed to note in their respective reports).
Other alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> now claim to have specifically denied the allegations.
Many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> have come forward to say the story is false. Various
implausible elements of the story have been noted. (For example, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> were exposed to fatal nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, why did none die?)

            But you
almost don't have to go beyond the story itself to strongly suspect it's false.
The signs of comic overreaching, at the very least, are right there. In these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when making up stories is so fashionable among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, many younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
                may wish to try it themselves.

                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Krohn</ENAMEX>, of course, is a trained professional, equipped
with the advanced journalistic tools of cynicism, suspicion, and heartlessness.
He is equally adept (as we all are in this profession, though we don't like to
brag about it) at making up stories and spotting those made up by others. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amateurs</ENAMEX>, though, can learn how to make up a pretty convincing story in the
comfort of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, using nothing more than a mild sense of mischief
and a decent word processor. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We recommend Word 97 for Windows</ENAMEX>.)

            Pending the results of all these investigations, we're not
saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> report was fabricated. But it is nevertheless a useful
illustration of a few techniques that need to be mastered by anyone wishing to
fabricate a news story:

            

               Bootstrap sourcing. Near the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> version, the story
says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> at the time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Moorer</ENAMEX>,
"confirmed the use of sarin in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laotian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>." Further down:
"Confirming the use of sarin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moorer</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> was 'by and large available.'
" And finally: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concludes Moorer</ENAMEX>: 'This is a much bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> than you
realize.' " Thus "available" is bootstrapped into "used" and "used" into "used
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX>," while "used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX> in this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>" sneaks through by
implication, all buttressed by the empty assertion that "this"--what?--is
bigger than you realize. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moorer</ENAMEX>'s subsequent denial that he meant to endorse
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sarin</ENAMEX>/defectors charge is not surprising (though the fact--which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN/ Time</ENAMEX> also failed to mention--that he is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> and not in top mental
condition is suggestive).

            
               Double
bootstrap sourcing; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of nothing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin Laird</ENAMEX>, is quoted as having "no specific recollection" of sarin
being used, but "I do not dispute what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moorer</ENAMEX> has to say on this matter."
If he has no recollection of the matter, he obviously is in no position to
dispute what anyone has to say about it. His statement to that effect has no
evidentiary value, but it is cited as implicit confirmation. (Elsewhere an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force 'ratpack</ENAMEX>' commando"--an impressive but unexplained label--is quoted as
saying, "I believed that these were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defectors." No surprise that he
turns out to have been far away and says he was only "speculating.")

            

               Heavy-handed seasoning with overheated quotes. This is a useful way to
distract the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s attention from gaps in logic and evidence, just as curry
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> were once used to make bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> palatable. "I just went 'oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'
and knew we were in for some really deep s___." Or, "It was a hairy situation
from the time we got there." As a bonus, those quoted seem to be endorsing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thesis</ENAMEX>, though that doesn't logically follow (and several of those quoted have
subsequently denied it).

            

               Pointless detail. " 'There were more defectors than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize,'
says an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX>.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOG</ENAMEX> is the acronym for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that
conducted the raid in question. But how does an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, whose
qualifications to opine on the subject are not offered, gain added credibility
by being "at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> after the event in question?

            

               Self-contradiction; fuzzy verb forms; anonymous quotes. "No definitive
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who went over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> is available, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moorer</ENAMEX>
indicated there were scores. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> put the number at close to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newsstand</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> that there were only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> known military defectors during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) In other words,
there is a definitive number, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. That number is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> "known" defectors. Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> believe there are unknown
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defectors</ENAMEX>? We are not told. But apparently "no definitive number ... is
available" only in the sense that the article doesn't accept the number that is
available--thus using its own doubts to lend validity to themselves.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>
"indicated." How? By sign language? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charades</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Semaphore?</ENAMEX> "Indicated" is a way
of implying he said it while indicating he must not have actually said it. (As,
it seems, he didn't.)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) "Another SOG
veteran" makes the highest bid of "close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>." Why would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> have any basis for knowing the total number of defectors in the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> war? Who is he, and why does he need to be anonymous? Never mind. He's
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>, isn't he?

            Using
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> simple techniques, you can fabricate a news story in the comfort of
your own home. No longer is there any need to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 cents</NUMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.95</NUMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--or even to turn on the television! Start with something
plausible--say, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> claiming to have had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--and work your way up to the outbreaks of major wars, visits by
extraterrestrials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who actually believe a browser shouldn't be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> into the operating system, and similar hard-to-believe phenomena.
You'll be a pro.

            
               Search
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>
            

            Some

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have complained, with justification, that our
search function did not successfully retrieve items from a few recently added
departments such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>." This is now fixed. Please try
again.

            
               Weekend
Papers
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> editions of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
will begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> e-mail will get the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> extra days automatically. Of course, they will also be available at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. If you're not signed up for e-mail delivery and would like to be,
click here.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independence Day</ENAMEX>
            

            By the magic of overworking
the production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>'s worth of 
                  Slate
                will be crammed
into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, so that we can all enjoy the traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patriotic</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday Friday</TIMEX>. A happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3</TIMEX> to all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
