
   
   
      
         
            Corporate-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX> NIMBYs

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Weisberg</ENAMEX>

            A great turn of phrase can
transform the political debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of labor, first
deployed the phrase "corporate welfare" in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> speech. The phrase was
brilliant political jujitsu, turning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' favorite issue against
them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> wanted to cut poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off the dole, but was ignoring the much
larger sums that go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in the form of tax breaks, direct subsidies,
and regulatory favoritism. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s slogan has been so successful that
it has created a new, bipartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX>--the
corporate-welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIMBY</ENAMEX>.

            Corporate-welfare NIMBYs are
those who want to slash corporate welfare, but not in their own back <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">yards</NUMEX>.
They are unalterably opposed to handouts for private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>--as long as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are in somebody else's state or district. They are outraged by
federal largess that goes to the undeserving--except when the undeserving
happen to include their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>.

            To see this double standard
in action, you don't even have to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> for very long. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX>, for
on something called the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Corporate Subsidy Reform Commission Act</ENAMEX>. This is a bill
to create a commission to propose cuts in corporate welfare. Like the
military-base-closing commission on which it is modeled, the corporate-welfare
commission would produce a hit list, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would then vote "yes" or "no"
on the whole package. Chairing the hearing was a fervent supporter of the idea,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Brownback</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>.

            Brownback, who succeeded to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s seat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, casts himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s most fervid enemy
of government waste. "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Pork</ENAMEX> has no place when we're so broke," he told a roomful
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28</TIMEX> press conference announcing the
corporate-welfare-commission bill. At the end of the event, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> surrounded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownback</ENAMEX> to ask whether he considered government ethanol
subsidies to be corporate welfare. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethanol</ENAMEX> is distilled from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX>, so the
subsidies benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> as well as the politically connected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniels Midland Co.</ENAMEX> There are few better examples of corporate welfare. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownback</ENAMEX> "made clear that wasn't what he meant," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who attended
the event. Brownback, by the way, cast the lone vote against the confirmation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Daley</ENAMEX> as commerce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownback</ENAMEX> insisted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> hadn't
made clear enough his hatred of corporate welfare.

            The chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bill is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Feingold</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>.
"Ending corporate welfare is not a luxury, it is a necessity," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feingold</ENAMEX> noted
in a press release. Would that include, say, federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dairy</ENAMEX> supports and
marketing orders for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> industry, which somehow escaped being scaled back
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1996 Farm Bill</ENAMEX>? "I told you he's for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> ," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feingold</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bottari</ENAMEX>. Feingold, who is up for re-election
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, carries a different tune when it comes to aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dependent cheese</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> do tend to mean different things
when they denounce corporate welfare. To <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, corporate welfare usually
means indirect subsidies in the form of tax breaks, like the ethanol tax credit
or the rule that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to depreciate some of their advertising costs as
capital. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> himself seldom complained about spending programs like the
Overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Investment Corp.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Export-Import Bank</ENAMEX>, which subsidize
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> exports.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, on the other
hand, corporate welfare generally refers only to spending. To close any of the
loopholes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> says cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> would mean raising taxes . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX> (of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>), who is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>'s
corporate-welfare-cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, takes the standard conservative line that
tax subsidies should be addressed separately, and only in context of a
tax-cutting bill that reduces rates. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are busy expanding
this form of corporate welfare. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX> slipped
into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s minimum-wage bill a new version of the huge tax break that
goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> operating out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>. The corporate-welfare queens who
Business.

            But the distinction between a
tax subsidy and a payment subsidy doesn't account for all the double standards.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> supported the old version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> tax subsidy. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will support subsidies for any form of agricultural production.
Perhaps the most absurd examples are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Coats</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsor</ENAMEX> of the corporate-welfare-commission bill--who voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to
stop a brave attempt by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> to get rid of the
so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Market Access</ENAMEX> Program. This handout for the rich is perhaps the
purest example of corporate welfare in the federal budget. It's a direct grant
to giant food and wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyson Foods</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell Soup</ENAMEX> to
pay for their advertising costs overseas.

            Another favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
cause is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX>, which exists to make loans to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> deem nonviable. Even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Forbes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--who, according to press reports, has been treated
as a nonperson by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> since he voted against the re-election of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>--bleats like a goat when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBA</ENAMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in his
Long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> is threatened. And then there are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>, who have the gall to sign on as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsors</ENAMEX> of the
corporate-welfare bill while holding out for ludicrous federal maritime
subsidies. Their interest is in protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyard</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quincy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            There are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of
corporate welfare who don't instinctively exempt their own oxen from being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gored</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is one (though it should be noted that the big federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boondoggles</ENAMEX> in retiree-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, not
corporate welfare). Kasich, who represents farm-free <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Columbus</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, is
another who practices what he preaches. But even these relatively honest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have let all the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> wriggle off the hook. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasich</ENAMEX>'s proposed
corporate-welfare package draws together a measly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.5 billion</NUMEX> in cuts over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Policy Institute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Shapiro</ENAMEX>, who invented the
concept of corporate welfare before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> gave it a name, has identified <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> worth.

            And slight as they are, most
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasich</ENAMEX>'s proposed cuts aren't really corporate welfare at all. They're
regular old spending that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> happen not to like, such as support for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> and highway demonstration projects in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasich</ENAMEX> isn't a corporate-welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIMBY</ENAMEX>. He's a
corporate-welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX>. But that's another story.

         
      
   
