
   
   
      
         
            Here's an Idea

            Talk to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, and you're likely to hear a lament about the
shortage of politically potent ideas. Looking toward the midterm election in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> have no rabble-rousing answer to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> promise of sweeping tax overhaul. Sure, they can point out that the
most familiar conservative proposal--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flat Tax</ENAMEX>--is a hoax. It would
produce a huge revenue shortfall for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and/or a big tax hike for
the middle class. But you can't beat a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> with no horse. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have on
their side populist ire against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>.
And filing your return on a postcard--or not having to file one at all--is a
pretty appealing notion.

            In fact,
there's a perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>'s tax reform. It's called tax
reform: good tax reform. The shared idea of both kinds of tax reform is
cleaning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Augean</ENAMEX> stables of the tax code. You make everyone's life simpler,
and you get lower rates by getting rid of loopholes and making the law neutral
among different kinds of income; you promote economic efficiency. Resources go
where the invisible hand directs them, not where they can get the most
favorable tax treatment. Under the reform championed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, which
passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, the corporate rate dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent to 34 percent</NUMEX>. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> brackets and a top rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> shrank into three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brackets</ENAMEX> and a top rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent</NUMEX>.

            But the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> tax reform has been gradually undone by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
intervening budget bills, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'90, '93</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX>. Preferences have crept back in,
shelters are returning (see 
                  Slate
               's do-it-yourself tax
shelter), and figuring out your taxes is more complicated than ever. Yet
for some reason, the only major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who has tried to latch onto the
issue is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>, who was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of tax reform in the
1980s (the original bill was known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley-Gephardt</ENAMEX>), has proposed to do it
again. He points out that higher tax rates for higher incomes aren't what make
the tax code complicated: You can get <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99 percent</NUMEX> of the flat tax's simplicity
without giving up the principle of progressivity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s version of tax
reform would make the code more progressive. A basic rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>
would cover <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> other rates, ranging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 34</NUMEX>
percent, would cover the rest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> would get rid of all deductions except
those for home-mortgage interest, charitable contributions, and state and local
taxes.

            
Some version of this idea ought to be a natural
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. As he made clear in an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, he's fishing around for a tax proposal to include in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> address. Unfortunately, the reports trickling out suggest
that he is likely to suggest some modest tinkering--a small tax rebate, paid
for by possible future budget surpluses, or more "targeted" incentives to
promote the right kind of investment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seems to have no interest in bold
and sweeping tax reform. Why not?

            The most
common explanations you hear are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Rubin</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the
interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> theory is based on political rivalry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> don't want to be accused of copyright infringement. Under the most
Machiavellian theory, the election of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> would be
bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, since he would have to run against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. This supposedly makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> want to avoid excessively good ideas until
after the midterm election. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> theory is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> has
persuaded everyone to let well enough alone. With the economy swimming along so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nicely</ENAMEX>, why meddle? The last theory, the most malignant, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
are too much in the thrall of interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and fat-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> campaign contributors
to assault their cherished tax preferences.

            None of these explanations fully adds up. In politics,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plagiarism</ENAMEX> is not only legal but also often effective. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>
were both for tax reform, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> would lose his best issue. "I thought of it
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>" is a pretty weak line in a debate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> argument may have a little
more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>. Tinkering with the tax code is always hazardous. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>
see the hood open, they all come running with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey wrenches</ENAMEX>--you never
know what may get "fixed." But that's a better argument against the grab bag of
breaks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is likely to propose (which will encourage special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pleading</ENAMEX>) than it is against sweeping reform. The power of moneyed interests
doesn't explain much, either. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> that benefit most from tax
loopholes--real estate, oil and gas, finance--give much more money to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, worried about the deduction for employer-paid
health care, cut much sway with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            A better
explanation for the failure to jump aboard tax reform is the wider political
predicament of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. In the present climate, it is nearly impossible to
spend money on new spending programs. But it is sometimes possible to disguise
spending programs as tax breaks. Of course, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> of government revenue lost
to an investment tax credit is a dollar added to the national debt as surely as
a dollar spent on food stamps. In fact, the cost is usually higher, since
indirect incentives tend to be less efficient than direct expenditures. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> tolerate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-by-incentive, so <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> rely on it. A clean
tax code would foreclose this dodge.

            
Since he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has
recognized the tax code as an excellent hiding place for social policy. If he
has any appreciation of the economic value of tax neutrality, or of the
political appeal of simplicity, he has never shown it. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposed not only higher rates on the rich and a new business tax to
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> training, but also augmented research and development credits, a
long-term capital-gains exclusion, and various other bounties intended to
support education and the environment. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> budget plan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indisputably</ENAMEX> strengthened the economy by reducing the budget deficit, it truly
undid tax reform. It turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four</TIMEX> rates into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and created a powerful bias in
favor of capital gains vs. ordinary income. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> drove <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
nails into the coffin: The bill he signed created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different capital-gains
rates, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of IRAs, and so on. (Many of these were actually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
initiatives, pushed by the very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> out there denouncing the complex
tax code and demanding a flat, no-loopholes system.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> obviously
isn't an economic purist. But you still have to wonder how such a smart policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wonk</ENAMEX> can fail to be bothered by the perversities and complications of the tax
code. The only other explanation is something we learned about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> during
all that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Whitewater</ENAMEX> business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> does the taxes.

         
      
   
