
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Umbrella Policy</ENAMEX>

            
               Umbrella
Policy
            

            Looking for a tasteful yet
exciting gift, suitable for all occasions? For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 20</TIMEX> bucks? Please consider
a gift subscription to 
                  Slate
               , available beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> will be impressed with your cleverness and sophistication (which
is, after all, the whole point of giving), and they will never suspect that so
much wonderful journalism was procured for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $19.95</NUMEX>. Click here for
more information or to send a gift subscription.

            Like a
regular 
                  Slate
                subscription, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX> gift subscription also
entitles the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> to an attractive 
                  Slate
               -logo umbrella.
This is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> value in and of itself, we allege. Why have we "bundled" an
umbrella with a subscription to 
                  Slate
               ? Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--some of them
wielding subpoenas--have asked us this question. The answer is simple: We do
not see the umbrella and the subscription to 
                  Slate
                online
magazine as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate products. The umbrella is fully integrated into

                  Slate
               . (Or possibly 
                  Slate
                is integrated into the
umbrella. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> or the other.) To bar us, as some have suggested, from including
the umbrella with 
                  Slate
                would effectively mean that anyone who
chooses to read 
                  Slate
                outdoors would risk serious water damage to
his or her computer.

            It is charged (by knee-jerk 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haters</ENAMEX> and
paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>) that by including a free umbrella with each
subscription to 
                  Slate
               , we are attempting to extend our current
dominant position in online poetry-read-aloud into the market for umbrellas,
thereby stifling innovation in this crucial field. Simple mathematics disposes
of this canard. If the umbrella is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> (which we say it is--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX> does not work here), and if a subscription to 
                  Slate
               
with a fully integrated umbrella is also <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX>, then it is obviously

                  Slate
               , not the umbrella, that is being given away free. And
nobody in his right mind would put at risk a monopoly as lucrative as the one
we have on 
                  Slate
               -logo umbrellas by trying to extend it into the
challenging market for online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>.

            To borrow
an image from our corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, we reserve the right to
integrate a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham sandwich</ENAMEX> into a subscription to 
                  Slate
                if we wish.
As a matter of fact, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham sandwich</ENAMEX> goes very well with some of

                  Slate
               's features. What could be nicer than sitting under an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">umbrella</ENAMEX>, munching a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham sandwich</ENAMEX>, and reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' latest
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millionerds"</ENAMEX> column or one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Yoffe</ENAMEX>'s dispatches from the world of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>? To forbid 
                  Slate
                to innovate by incorporating useful new
features in our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> would put us at an unfair disadvantage vis-à-vis other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webzines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , for example, is already full of baloney. (Oh, please.
Only joshing.)

            Afunny little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> was skulking
around 
                  Slate
                the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX>, hinting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s effort to force
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX> in every copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 98</ENAMEX> is just a
warm-up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s real goal, he revealed, is to "level the playing
field" by forcing us to include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> in every
edition of 
                  Slate
               . Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, has said that this
kind of suggestion is like requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> to include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cans of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> in
every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>. That analogy has stirred much discussion about its validity.
Our own view, if you're wondering, is that the analogy is brilliantly acute and
totally disposes of the issue in the minds of all honest and clear-thinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. But the uncomfortable truth is that 
                  Slate
                already
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incorporates Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> --in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> called
"In Other
Magazines." The result, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> would have predicted, is
a robustly competitive magazine market in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
actually, in some ways, surpass 
                  Slate
               . Circulation, revenue, ad
pages, and profitability are a few of the dimensions in which, quite frankly,
we are somewhat behind, although we lead in other important measures such as
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with 
                  Slate
               -logo umbrellas.

            
               "The
Fray" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enters the Fray</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of our most loyal and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enthusiastic Fraygrants</ENAMEX>--
                  Slate
               speak for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> who are
active in our discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>--goes under the nom de clavier
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Snodgrass</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>" is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX> and has been
regaling the Fray with tales of life in the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> revolution.
At last report he was more or less trapped in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, so he's had plenty of
time to spend at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. (Come to think of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> trapped by political
turmoil in distant lands are a great potential market for

                  Slate
               --provided they're trapped in a place with a working
computer and modem. They won't need umbrellas, of course. Circulation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>, please note.) Enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>, read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving</ENAMEX>'s dispatches, and maybe
send him a message of support. The thread is called "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Scene</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>'s posts begin at entry No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6718</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s resignation.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
