
   
   
      
         
            Now He Tells Us

            
               Now He
Tells Us
            

            So we
were reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>--online, of course--when
we came across a report of a speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>.
We're always interested in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> has to say because--well, obviously.
You would be too, would you not? Anyway, this speech was especially interesting
to us. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> :

            The computer genius
sketched out his rosy vision of a future world of technology-loving households
[... yeah, yeah ...] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in which computers enhance the learning
process [... sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> ...]. ... But he conceded that sometimes the
old ways are still the best. He prefers magazines the way they come in the
mail , he confessed, and he cannot read anything longer on his computer
screen than a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-page memo.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whoa</ENAMEX>. These words came as
quite a shock to those of us who have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> trying to
develop, on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> whose distinguishing
characteristic is that it does not come in the mail. Although we
disagree with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> about the best way to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, we do agree that
sometimes the old way is still the best. For example, we generally prefer
typewriters to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>, and we find that our sturdy abacus crashes less
often than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excel</ENAMEX>.

            Lesser
online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> might find it discouraging to learn that their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX>
prefers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that come in the mail. And there were tears, of course, even
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>--mainly from the software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>, a notoriously sensitive lot. But
ultimately we at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> invoked the true <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> and took this as a
challenge. A two-pronged challenge, actually. The first challenge was how to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevent Bill Gates</ENAMEX> from finding out that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> publishes an online
magazine. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> challenge was to misrepresent (or "spin," to use the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vernacular</ENAMEX>) his remarks to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part is easy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
as is so often the case with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, misquoted Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' speech. What he
actually said was that he prefers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that come in e-mail , and he
reads them on his specially designed computer screen that can display a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-page memo. He was referring, of course, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s free weekly e-mail
delivery. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to subscribe.)

            Part 1 is tougher. Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, it is frequently mentioned in the
press, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> connection is often noted. But we have assigned a
junior staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> to lurk near the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> family mailbox and, when no one is
looking, to go through the contents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Marker</ENAMEX> out all references to the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

            That'll
teach him to get his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> by mail.

            

               Fourplay
            

            If you've installed Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>, the new version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s browser, you might like to take a
peek at our new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table of Contents</ENAMEX>, designed especially to take advantage of the
advances in Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>. Among other features, it allows even the
smallest standard computer screen to display the entire contents of an issue of
Slate without scrolling. Make sure that you're running Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>,
then click here to take a
look. This is still a "beta," meaning that we're still tinkering with it, but
we think it's pretty close. If you run into any problems, e-mail help@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            And if
you haven't yet installed Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>, you can get a free download by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clicking</ENAMEX> here. Be
forewarned that the download takes quite a while via modem. You can also order
a CD. Or you can while away the time reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> on paper.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
