
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lurking Made Easy</ENAMEX>

            
               Lurking
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Made Easy</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lurking</ENAMEX>," in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Webspeak</ENAMEX>, means reading what others are saying in discussion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forums</ENAMEX> and chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> without joining in yourself. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>," 
                  Slate
               's
discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, we don't discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lurkers</ENAMEX>--though we'd rather have you join
in. "Fraygrants," as regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> call themselves, live all over the
world and conduct energetic discussions of everything under the sun. To give
you a taste, we've started a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Best of the</ENAMEX>
Fray." Written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, who calls himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fray Vader</ENAMEX> (and runs
it from his home somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>), it summarizes, quotes from, and links to
some of the livelier ongoing discussions. If you haven't yet entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>,
start with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best</ENAMEX> of to get the general idea, then go and lurk a bit, then jump
in.

            
               Krugman
Between Covers
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accidental Theorist</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Dispatches From the Dismal Science</ENAMEX> , a collection of essays by

                  Slate
               's economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>, will be published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>. Through the magic of publishing industry nonsense, though, copies
exist now. You can order it directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wwnorton</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> (or if that's
more w's than you can handle, call [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">800</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">233-4830</ENAMEX>), or you can buy it from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Or you could walk into a bookstore the
old-fashioned way and buy it with doubloons.

            Of course if you're a real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> you can get much of the book online without actually buying it. About
half the essays originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dismal Science"</ENAMEX> column for

                  Slate
                and are available in our archive, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Compost</ENAMEX>." And other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Krugmaniana</ENAMEX> are available on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s own Web
site. But we certainly don't want to discourage sales. So let us be clear
that the book contains a few excellent essays not available on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> and that
it is a delightful physical object in its own right.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
