
   
   
      
         
            It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Conspiracy</ENAMEX>

             

            You can just about imagine
the pitch meeting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX>'s clever new movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> .
It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>-meets-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> kind of deal. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just 11 days</TIMEX> before the
presidential election, a major scandal breaks. A young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> accuses the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of having molested her during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tour. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>
plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Brean</ENAMEX>, a jaded political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who is called out of
retirement to rescue the incumbent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brean</ENAMEX> isn't interested in whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s accusation is true or not. It's a story , which he needs to
smother with a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX>--a fake war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>. For help generating the
war, he flies to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> to recruit big-time movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Motss</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brilliantly</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>. In an early scene (PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> explains to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> that real
events work just like invented ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> are in the same
business.

            This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parody</ENAMEX>, of course, not explicit commentary. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brean</ENAMEX> wants to show off to
Motss, he flicks on his tiny cell phone and beams a message directly into the
earpiece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, who is in midsentence at a press
conference. The flack mouths the words (PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>) injected into his head. But despite being a satire, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wag</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> embodies an analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that is fairly typical of the
better class of political movie. The view is conspiratorial, not in the
strung-out, scandalized manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>'s JFK but in a cool,
ironic way. That a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> runs the show is just a fact of
life--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get excited about it are ridiculous. Connected to this hip
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> is an equally jaded belief that politics is merely the art of media
manipulation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> a compelling diet of music and images, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and the
producer agree, a docile and credulous public will go for just about
anything.

            Asimilar message comes through in almost every recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> movie. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> , the gimmick is a look-alike who becomes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> after the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has a stroke atop a bimbo. In this
scene (PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Kline</ENAMEX> preps with the coup
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plotters</ENAMEX> to fool his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>. The film takes its biggest wink in the scene
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>, playing himself in a cameo, tries to convince a skeptical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s appearance has changed slightly since his
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>. ("Do you think you're a little paranoid<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> asks him.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Robbins</ENAMEX> plays a right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk singer</ENAMEX> running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
with the help of a rogue ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. A frightening demagogue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> whips
crowds into a nationalistic frenzy with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> protest songs like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drugs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stink "</ENAMEX> (PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>). He subsequently wins the
election after staging a fake assassination attempt. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fellow Americans</ENAMEX>
is much cruder. We never understand why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Aykroyd</ENAMEX>) is trying
to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ex-presidents (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Lemmon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Garner</ENAMEX>) killed. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hate
each other's guts, but wind up as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> trying to escape their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> (PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>).

            There's a good excuse for all
this <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>--it's a great plot device. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent movie that presents
something resembling an accurate view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> , is cloying and tedious. This scene (PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>), in which an environmental interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> moves to
hire an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>, might have been based on an article from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX> . But the more usual conspiratorial refrain can't be
dismissed as a mere narrative technique. It expresses the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
understands <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
falls prey to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> because it's easy. If you don't have the patience to try
to understand politics or aren't really interested, conspiracy allows you to
seem sophisticated. It's a dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s way of seeming smart. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX> proposes an additional hypothesis. Much that happens in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
is attributable to conspiracies of a kind. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Producer X</ENAMEX> is
sleeping with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starlet Y</ENAMEX> really does explain why she gets a big part in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Director</ENAMEX>
Z's new movie. A film gets made, or doesn't, because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen</ENAMEX>'s rivalry with
Ovitz, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX>'s with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>. In portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> this way, those in
the movie business are depicting their political culture, not ours.

            
The other component of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s view of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is that politics is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of show business. "It's all a change
of wardrobe," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> opines in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> as he emerges
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. This notion seems to have taken deep root when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> used his acting skills as governing ones;
he was accused of confusing art and life, remembering scenes from the movies as
if they'd really happened. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s politics were conservative,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> couldn't believe he was legitimately popular. It had to be a trick.
The argument was that he'd brainwashed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> and mirrors,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artifice</ENAMEX> and stagecraft. The problem with the view that politics is merely the
effective manipulation of images is that it inflates a minor consideration into
the whole ballgame. It makes democracy irrelevant, while discounting the single
most important motivation in politics, which is conviction. But once again, you
can appreciate why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> sees <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> this way. Staging is one part of
politics the entertainment business understands. There's also a projection
factor. Belief plays a negligible part in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the movie industry do,
so they assume it's the same elsewhere.

            The opinion that conspiracy
and show business rule <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> exists in tension with an older,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">literal-minded Hollywood</ENAMEX> liberalism. The premise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> is a widowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> dating an environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>. They
fall in love, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is emboldened to do the right thing on crime
and global warming. The "right thing," of course, is to replace phony toughness
with gun control and demand a larger reduction in greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kline</ENAMEX> wins the affection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX> by
restoring funding for a homeless shelter. In almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> movies,
there's an impassioned speech echoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX>'s climactic filibuster in
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith Goes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> calls a
press conference to announce a full-employment program. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Roberts</ENAMEX> ,
the voice of decency is the worthy old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX>,
who declares that politics is about reality, not illusion.

            This contradiction results
in disorientation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capraesque</ENAMEX> idealism is in conflict with
the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>. Wanting to have it both ways fosters a tone of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incoherence</ENAMEX>. Wag the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> is the exception among these films in that
there's no voice of democratic decency attempting to shine through. Thanks
perhaps to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>, who wrote the screenplay, it doesn't have any
sentimental Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> speeches. It's funnier than most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> movies, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">darker</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
