
   
   
      
         
            It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> thing is easy: It wasn't to my taste, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> tended to
like it the way it was. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> holding a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX> celebration at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is playing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>. That may be
good strategy for an economy losing manufacturing jobs (a strategy honed for
decades by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>), but that's a fickle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> to keep happy. I say just
give up and put a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> in the middle of it. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>.

            I'm handling the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> thing so well. Mainly because, as with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capra</ENAMEX>, I
never saw the dark side, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met Life</ENAMEX> commercials side. Frankly, I cross
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off my list who say It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> is their favorite
movie.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> scandal is remarkable precisely because, in defense of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' behavior, so many other egregious examples of
editorial-advertiser coziness surface. I do think it stinks that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that their sports pages have to "cover," or that even the most
distinguished papers hold conferences, seminars, and festivals that then tend
to get "covered" more than events sponsored by others. It's a practice
indistinguishable except in degree from TV newscasts' doing "stories" that just
"happen" to tie in to the movies that preceded them. Don't get me started.

            Does this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> scare you? Personally, I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s resignation
speech. The slowest anybody has ever been allowed to speak on television, like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slow Talkers of America</ENAMEX>. We're gonna miss
that lovable old drunk. Now comes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who actually knows how to run a
government, and thinks the coolest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> thereof is the secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
