
   
   
      
         
            Why <i><ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX></i> Is Not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>

            Is anti-Semitism always <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>, or can it be something else? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX>
Foxman of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX> thinks it's always <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> disagrees. The case in point: A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">little more than a week ago</TIMEX>, Foxman
wrote a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> asking it never to rebroadcast portions of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> skit he said were offensive to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> first
agreed not to. But after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNL</ENAMEX> 's executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorne Michaels</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objected</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> put the matter "under review." The sketch in question
parodies a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS Christmas</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And So This Is Christmas</ENAMEX> . The
idea is to do a promotional spot for the forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> special "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And So</ENAMEX>
This Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> ." For those who didn't tune in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4</TIMEX>, it went like
this:

            Strains of bad klezmer music and a portentous voice-over give way to clips
of pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNL</ENAMEX> cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>) singing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> songs. The
female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> wear scanty clothing and make crude sexual gestures. The men
wear <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">yarmulkes</ENAMEX> and rap exaggeratedly or dry-hump their backup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>. The
songs range from the mildly amusing to the unfunny. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Bega"</ENAMEX> replaces
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica" with "Hanukkah</ENAMEX>" in his famous refrain, "A little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> in my
life." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Martin"</ENAMEX> does the same with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Vida Loca</ENAMEX>." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tori Amos"</ENAMEX> sings a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">torchy</ENAMEX> holiday ballad while nearly having sex with a piano leg. And divas
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Britney Spears</ENAMEX>" (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX>," and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Celine Dion</ENAMEX>" share their feelings about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> holiday. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spears</ENAMEX>" thinks
it's OK because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> have forgiven the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> for killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>.
"Dion" recalls that when she asked her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> was, her mother
said it was a holiday celebrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who own the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.

            It's those last <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two bits</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foxman</ENAMEX> wants pulled from circulation. Out of
context, this isn't crazy, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer epithet</ENAMEX> has justified
pogroms for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> and the international <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> banking and media conspiracy
theory is alive and being propagated. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foxman</ENAMEX> is wrong to think he needs to
defend his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNL</ENAMEX> , however tasteless they may
be. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being made fun of in this sketch are not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. They're pop
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> doesn't mean to suggest that your average pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> is not
an ignorant, self-promoting ditzbrain, of course. In the scene <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Foxman</ENAMEX> objects
to, however, the mockery is not aimed at pop stars in general. It targets a
specific kind of pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from a background so low-class she doesn't
know enough to hide her anti-Semitism. In other words, it's white-trash
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> who are being insulted, so it is the trailer-park pop-star
anti-defamation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foxman's</ENAMEX>, that should be demanding a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retraction</ENAMEX>.

            If you want to understand who exactly is being skewered in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spears</ENAMEX>" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dion</ENAMEX>," it helps to think of a scene in a better television comedy in which a
white-trash country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> makes a similarly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> remark. (This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>, by the way, is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s. It was sent to her by a

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> who insists on anonymity but who seems to be
possessed of an astonishing memory. Whether his memory is accurate cannot be
confirmed, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Tristar Television</ENAMEX>, which owns the tapes in question,
says it is unable to look the incident up.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox's</ENAMEX> correspondent
writes:

            

               With respect to current controversy over <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SNL</ENAMEX> /<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX>/Britney
Spears, you may recall an almost identical line from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Hartman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
Hartman , back in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Haggers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX> Place), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> and a country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, got her big break on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carson</ENAMEX>-like show. She
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> that everyone had been so nice to her in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> and rattled off a
bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> names. Then she added, "I can't believe they're the same people
who killed our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>." I'm not sure if it was controversial at the time in the
real world. It did kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta</ENAMEX>'s career on the show.

            

         
      
   
