
   
   
      
         
            Gems Amid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprawl</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whatup</ENAMEX>?:

            It may not be a good sign to start off an e-mail with a salutation from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lawrence</ENAMEX>, but what the heck? Scanning the trail of emails--ah, it's good
to be reminded of how stupid I am--I notice that no one seemed to have
mentioned that most movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> take place in real time. Maybe that's why
I liked the animated stuff so much. I didn't suffer booty fatigue or gluteal
nerve-damage after leaving the theater showing The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron Giant</ENAMEX> . There's a
resolute quality to all of this cinematic sprawl that hurts filmmakers. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topsy-Turvy</ENAMEX> is the best thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX> has ever done.
But the painstaking build to this payoff has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fleeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> in a
blind rage. It opens with a shot of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">usher</ENAMEX> carefully checking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> seat
in the corner of the frame. And sure enough, we see the usher go across the
whole row--the entire length of the frame.

            I didn't mean to suggest I had a better way of making The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> .
I don't think it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>'s job to tell filmmakers how to do theirs. (Though
a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> quoted a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of mine whining that I
didn't write enough "constructive criticism"--maybe I can start giving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX> marks in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> and playing well with others. And he wonders why
I left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Free Press</ENAMEX> ?) My point was that, by skirting the
issue, instead of making a movie about racism they may have made a racist
movie.

            Getting back to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best Man</ENAMEX> : It's not a great movie. But a lot of it
is funny, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Howard</ENAMEX> is better than anybody in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wood</ENAMEX> , which
felt sitcomish and broad to me. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> brought weight and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to the
picture--it's a genuine movie-star turn. (He'll be playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX> in a TV
movie soon.)

            I do think that the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godard</ENAMEX> has filtered into the current film
scene, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>. Maybe not intentionally, but it wouldn't be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case of
trickle-down tribute to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX> pays tribute to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godard</ENAMEX> quotes: "All you need to make a movie is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and a
gun."

            I hate to end my correspondence on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an up</TIMEX> note, but I had a better time at
movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> than I have in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who plays the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in
Election is nothing short of fabulous--I hope someone gave her props.
There are shards of movies that stick with me. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
Ravenous shows why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Carlyle</ENAMEX> deserves a film career. That freakish
doggie paddle he does before revealing himself is more unsettling than any of
the hokey vampire film that follows. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watching Matthew Broderick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> from
playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris Bueller</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Jones</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election</TIMEX> brings <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> important
thing to mind. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godard</ENAMEX> doesn't turn out to be the most influential filmmaker
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Hughes</ENAMEX> will. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty is staged
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hughes</ENAMEX> film. It must be the eve of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> if I'm thinking
back fondly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Breakfast Club</ENAMEX> .

            Don't you forget about me,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Elvis</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
