
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opening-Night</ENAMEX> Neurosis
            

            If you want to be, oh, a heretic and actually go out to the movies this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> instead of staying at home watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It's a Wonderful Life,</ENAMEX>
good luck finding a new--I mean, brand-spanking new--movie to watch. There
won't be any. Either there will be movies that have been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> at
least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> (and who wants to watch those on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>?) or movies that
opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (this list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX>, Any Given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow Falling</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cedars</ENAMEX> ). But unlike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other Friday</TIMEX> in movie history,
there will be no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> films opening on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 24</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> that might
have-- The Talented Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galaxy Quest</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titus</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ashes</ENAMEX> --will instead be opening on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, which in the case
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titus</ENAMEX> makes for a very odd combination.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> have explained that they aren't releasing their movies on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> because it is one of the slowest--if not the
slowest--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">moviegoing day of the year</TIMEX>, and they'd rather wait and let their films
debut with a splash on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. This sounds plausible, until you think about
what the decision to release the films a day late actually means. Since movies
always end their runs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thursdays</ENAMEX> (or occasionally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>) regardless of
when those runs start, it means that these movies will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fewer day in
which to make money. That's not a day the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> will be able to get back at
some point. Whenever their runs end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley , et al.</ENAMEX>, will have runs that
are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> shorter than they otherwise would have been.

            Now, the cost of showing those films for that extra day is negligible enough
that even if only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> show up, you'll make some money. And it isn't as
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> are going to be closed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX>. They're going to be
showing something . In fact, they'll be showing Any Given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX> , among other movies. So why would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> make a
decision to keep their films out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>?

            The answer has everything to do with the astonishing importance that films'
opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> have taken on in the mind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. If you open Galaxy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quest</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and it turns in numbers that are disappointing relative to
the opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> of other comparable films, then you end up looking like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loser</ENAMEX>, even though you could quite sensibly argue that this particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> is not like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other Friday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> now
operates under the conviction that if your films look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> after their opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>, they will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> in the mind of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. If you open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, though, then your per-screen average will
look better, your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> performance has a good chance of being impressive,
and you can't get dragged down by the inevitably weak <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            This makes no sense from a business perspective, since it's analogous to
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> shouldn't sell its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when it knows sales will be
slow, since that will hurt month-to-month comparisons. But the opening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>--which, to be fair, has always been disproportionately important in
shaping the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> handle films--is now of such importance that throwing
away the money that could have been made on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in order to make the weekend
look better somehow seems logical.

            The interesting part of all this is that there isn't really much evidence
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> really do pay attention to those "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The No. 1 film in America</ENAMEX>!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blurbs</ENAMEX> in the ads (let alone the "No. 1 comedy about androids in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>!"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blurbs</ENAMEX>). It's become a cliché that all anyone pays attention to anymore are
box-office grosses. But it seems likely that this is a cliché that is true of
the chattering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> but not true at all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who actually go to
movies. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> releasing The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> and
Toy Story 2 mixed it up because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toy Story 2</ENAMEX> claimed the top
position in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> gross by a slim margin, even though it was The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mile</ENAMEX> 's opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> behind The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> essentially
said, "They had their turn. They should give us a break," which was odd in two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. First, it seemed to assume that box-office position was some subjective
judgment. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, it assumed that finishing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> would really make a
difference to The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> 's eventual performance. If only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pixar</ENAMEX> had said: "OK, you finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Do you really feel better now?"

         
      
   
