
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indefensible Stanley Fish</ENAMEX>

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> fiction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Fish</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of arts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sciences</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-most-famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX>--is
indistinguishable from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris Zapp</ENAMEX>. Everyone knows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lodge</ENAMEX>'s trilogy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Changing Places, Small World</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nice Work</ENAMEX> , the
most popular campus novels since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kingsley Amis' Lucky Jim</ENAMEX> , was based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lodge</ENAMEX>'s good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. Zapp, a jetsetting, starfucking, and intellectually
luminous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deconstructionist</ENAMEX> whose charm lies in his gleeful disregard
for scholarly convention, aspires to become the highest-paid English professor
in the world. What's wrong with that? he asks.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, however, particularly the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> is the symbol of how the left is wrecking
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>'s sin, according to his journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, is
moral relativism. He is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>-response" criticism, which holds
that texts don't have intrinsic meaning--meaning is a byproduct of the
encounter between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> and text. He <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> campus speech codes, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> in political correctness. He defends the cultural-studies journal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Text</ENAMEX> and the field of "science studies," even after they were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humiliated</ENAMEX> through a brilliant prank by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sokal</ENAMEX>. And yes, he
is one of the highest-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> around. He currently gets
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$230,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX>. This, it is felt, does not
reflect an amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">brashness</ENAMEX>. It reflects a lack of principle.

            An implicit answer to these and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX> can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>'s
latest book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Trouble With Principle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University Press</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.95</NUMEX>) . It opens with a scene from a movie--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Peckinpah</ENAMEX>'s western
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild Bunch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outlaws Ernest Borgnine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Holden</ENAMEX> are
discussing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who has betrayed them by becoming a railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX>. Why
would their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> do a thing like that? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borgnine</ENAMEX> asks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> explains: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> gave his word to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX>. So what? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borgnine</ENAMEX> replies: "It isn't
giving your word that's important; it's who you give your word to."

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holden</ENAMEX> that a code of honor is worth at least
paying lip service to. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">combative Fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borgnine</ENAMEX>. "The trouble
with principle," he writes, "is, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, it does not exist, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, that
nowadays many bad things are done in its name." None of the ideals a liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> is supposed to be based on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> argues--fairness, impartiality,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reasonableness</ENAMEX>--is ever truly neutral or principled. They all mask a political
agenda. If all disputes over abstract ideals are, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> says, attempts to
exploit an elevated moral language for partisan advantage, then to hell with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and their faith in chimera such as free speech and scientific
objectivity! To hell with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and their absolute values! To hell with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and their cherished notion of tolerance, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who benefit
from it (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> and supremacists) would punch a liberal silly
if they found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in a dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>. The only beliefs that matter, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX>, are
the ones that matter directly to you. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stanley Fish</ENAMEX>, those are
"my convictions and commitments."

            Before you dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> as either a danger to democratic values or a
pugilistic idiot, you have to know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more things about him. First, he's a
remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>. As a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, he single-handedly dragged his
chosen specialty, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Milton</ENAMEX> studies, into the modern era. The field was mired
in a stale debate over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paradise Lost</ENAMEX> is flawed because it
contradicts itself--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX> is an appealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton</ENAMEX> appears
to side with God, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton</ENAMEX>'s contradictions to be a dramatization
of the theological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paradoxes</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX>, rather than mere literary error.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> is a political realist, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-in-the-clouds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>. He
is receiving such a princely sum from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX> not just
because he's famous--or notorious--but because he was the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the most well-thought-of (though controversial) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> academic
programs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s and '90s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humanities Center</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. His success as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>
rested on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> insights that are now commonplace: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, that the academic star
system could be used to create <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> with high-profile brand names, and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, that the longing of academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> to live in the same place
represents an administrative opportunity, not a headache. Fish built both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humanities Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> by hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity couples</ENAMEX> and
finding room for both, rather than wooing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> and
banishing the other to a lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, or condemning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to a
commuter marriage. That both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> are now falling apart can be chalked
up either to his considerable skill at maintaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> or to his cynical
lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with long-term stability.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, it is not as easy as it seems to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lump Fish</ENAMEX> with the progressives and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">utopianists</ENAMEX> who dominate the cultural and intellectual left. The Trouble
With Principle , with its typically Fishy mix of transgressiveness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">realism</ENAMEX>, demonstrates the distance between him and them. The book's best essay
by far is an attack on multiculturalism. In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multiculturalism</ENAMEX> is a logical impossibility. His brief goes like this: There
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of multiculturalism, "weak" (or "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutique</ENAMEX>") "multiculturalism"
and "strong multiculturalism." "Weak multiculturalism," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX>, is a watery
tolerance for cultural diversity. Weak multiculturalists hold that the
differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trivial, because there are certain central
values--tolerance, respecting the dignity of individual rights, etc--that
supersede everything else. Weak multiculturalists do not tolerate practices,
such as polygamy or female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circumcision</ENAMEX>, that offend those values. Strong
multiculturalists recognize that some differences are irreconcilable, but say
you must put up with them. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> argues, both multiculturalisms are
really uniculturalism. Weak multiculturalists simply impose their Western,
liberal values on everyone else. Strong multiculturalists, if they follow their
argument to its extremes, end up having to support some other culture whose
basic principles violate their own--thereby elevating the values of that
culture above their own.

            If there are no rules for living peacefully in an ethnically mixed society,
what do we do now? Why, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX>, we do what we have always done, since we
have never really practiced multiculturalism. We improvise. We engage in
something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> calls, borrowing the phrase from a philosopher named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>, "inspired adhoccery." We decide what to do on a case-by-case basis.
When it makes sense to offer a major in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> studies, we offer a major in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> studies. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> sacrifices become sufficiently offensive, we outlaw
them. This, he adds, is not a recommendation. It is how we do things already,
and the sooner we admit that, the better we'll get at it.

            This may be well and good for multiculturalism, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> has bigger targets
in mind. The most troubling essay in the book is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Mission Impossible</ENAMEX>."
Here Fish claims that there is no such thing as liberalism, since liberalism's
only way of dealing with those who don't agree with it is forcibly to exclude
them, mostly by calling them mad. It's an old argument, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> makes it new
by going back to the source--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Locke</ENAMEX>--and showing that in order to arrive at
the principle of separation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and state (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of liberal polity
), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> had to define religion as an internal process, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s war "upon
his own lusts and vices." In so doing, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> defines religion away,
or at least all religions with strong beliefs and problematic forms of public
worship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> does acknowledge that in some rare cases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> must be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suppressed</ENAMEX>, but, he says, that's not a problem--we'll know which ones to
suppress because they will be condemned "by the judgment of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>." Right
there, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> undoes his own argument, since "the judgment of all
mankind" requires a reigning consensus that doesn't exist. If it did, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>
wouldn't have had to invent liberalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX>, rather than practicing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tolerance</ENAMEX>, have by acts of intellectual (and real) violence elevated their own
ideas of what will and won't do to the status of that which is universally
right.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">philosophy Fish</ENAMEX> is practicing here bears some resemblance to pragmatism,
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> doctrine that has recently been revived and
wedded to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> postmodernism. Modern pragmatism is a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brew</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relativism</ENAMEX>--the idea that all truths are situational--and the optimistic belief
that things work themselves out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> is not an upbeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pragmatist</ENAMEX>. His vision of society is far darker, for instance, than that of the
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rorty</ENAMEX>, who holds that no idea is truly bad
as long as it leads to other ideas. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission Impossible</ENAMEX>" is the essay in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX>'s scariest side emerges in clear view. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> who is really
honest about the implausibility of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX>, is Hobbes:

            

               [B]ecause the equality of right and ability breeds "equality of hope in the
attaining of our Ends," and because each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> are naturally to be
preferred to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>'s, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> will inevitably "become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>," and in the
absence of a neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX> "they will endeavor to destroy or subdue one
another."

            

            And there Fish more or less stops. (Well, actually, he goes on to argue in a
similar fashion against the logical plausibility of free speech, academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>, and blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maddeningly</ENAMEX>, he leads us to the center of the
Hobbesian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">maze</ENAMEX>, then refuses to extricate us. If life is a war of all against
all, what guarantee do we have that adhoccery will work, no matter how
inspired? None, of course--at which point Fish generally cackles and says that
since he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatist</ENAMEX>, he believes that his ideas about the world are just
that, ideas without consequences. There is, he says, "no straight line from
these propositions to the solution of any real-life problem; they are of no
help and do no work except the non-directing work of telling you that you are
on your own."

            In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> isn't the unprincipled relativist he's accused of
being. He's something worse. He's a fatalist. But then, so were the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pre-Socratics</ENAMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavelli</ENAMEX>. Culturebox
certainly can't tell you whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> is right or wrong. On the other hand,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fish</ENAMEX> never claimed to be right. In fact, he once quipped that, now that
objectivity is dead, it is no longer necessary to be right. You just have to be
interesting. Which he is.

         
      
   
