
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Battle Against Selective Disclosure</ENAMEX>
            

            Sometimes a situation seems so obviously wrong that you can't believe it's
allowed to continue. Then someone--like, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange</ENAMEX>
Commission--comes along and says the situation won't be allowed to continue,
and a host of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> spring up to say, unbelievably, "Things are just fine
the way they are." To which the only reasonable response, of course, is to say,
"Who are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?"

            This is pretty much the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>'s battle against the selective
disclosure of significant financial and business information by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and large institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, who routinely get
looks inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and notifications of changes in future outlooks long
before everyone else does. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Levitt</ENAMEX> has been publicly on the
attack against selective disclosure for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 18 months</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> issued a remarkably measured proposal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation FD</ENAMEX>, that simply stated in
essence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would not release any "material information" privately.
Instead of applauding the regulation, Wall Street looks ready to fight it.

            From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> perspective, of course, this is hardly surprising. Investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>
and brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> built their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> around their access to information,
and their ability to get that information to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> before it reached
anyone else. And while in theory that information could be--and sometimes
is--the product of especially dedicated digging or sharp analysis, it's often
the product of a phone call to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief financial officer</ENAMEX>, or comes from a vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who lets slip that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX> is looking especially good. If
you give up selective disclosure, and create a truly free flow of information
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, then the possibility of making
easy profits (either by getting in before everyone hears the good news, or
getting out before everyone hears the bad) disappears.

            That's hardly an argument even Wall Street could use to defend itself. So
instead what you hear is the classic "this will lead to a general chill on
information" argument, which says that since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> don't want to put out
press releases all the time, they'll stop talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> at all, for fear
that they'll be breaking the law. And since markets function best when there's
more information, the market will work less well if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation FD</ENAMEX> is
ratified.

            The truth is, it's not clear that there would be any damage done at all if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> stopped having private conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. The privileged
position of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, after all, is a vestige of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when just about
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> had accounts with the major brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s world,
with the profusion of online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokerages</ENAMEX>, that's an unnecessary privilege. At
the same time, if you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' estimates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' quarterly
earnings, they tend to be quite similar, which suggests that they're the result
not of aggressive independent research but rather of company guidance. If
that's the case, then let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> give its guidance publicly, in a
conference call accessible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, broadcast on the Internet, and
transcribed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s Web site. The same should be the case with any
disclosure of material information.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulation FD</ENAMEX> will work, though, only if it's followed up with a loosening
of the rules on the kinds of public statements <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can make without fear
of running afoul of either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> or minority-shareholder lawsuits. Even
today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> continues to limit the kinds of forward-looking statements
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can make, out of a desire to protect individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--whom it
considers less serious and financially responsible--from potentially deceptive
statements. And the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to sue every company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who makes
a prediction that doesn't come true obviously keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> from making
predictions that would be of great use to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. Both of these phenomena
are legacies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX> laws passed when Wall Street was purely an
insider's game and individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> really were at a radical disadvantage
in terms of separating truth from lies. But protecting individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> has the ironic effect of perpetuating their informational disadvantage.
If we're going to have full disclosure, then we have to accept the risks that
go along with it. So let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> speak and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> listen and decide from
themselves, and cut out the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
