
   
   
      
         
            Who Killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> found that restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loyd Jowers</ENAMEX> was
involved in a conspiracy to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> Some claim that the
verdict proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX>--who was convicted of the assassination in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> and died in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--did not shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>. Others say that the
verdict was bogus. What is the gist of the story?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> was assassinated on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4, 1968</TIMEX>, while standing on the balcony of his
Memphis motel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> with a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> shot
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> he rented across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. A pair of binoculars and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>
with a single spent shell were recovered from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> stayed.
Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> and the binoculars were covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s fingerprints. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, a
racist and career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> who had escaped from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX>, was
arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> after the killing. At first he claimed innocence,
but later pleaded guilty and received a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">99-year</TIMEX> sentence. Soon afterward, he
recanted his confession, saying that he had transported the suspected murder
weapon to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> on behalf of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raoul</ENAMEX>," but did not shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King's family</ENAMEX> publicly reconciled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, endorsing his innocence
and positing a wider conspiracy to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>'s
Office reopened its investigation, but reaffirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s conviction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
Represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pepper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King family</ENAMEX> responded
by filing a wrongful death civil suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jowers</ENAMEX> for his role in the
alleged plot, which they claimed also involved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> armed forces,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> police, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>, who declared that their purpose was
to win a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s endorsement of their views, demanded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $100</NUMEX> in damages.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jowers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> didn't put up much of a fight: He never disputed that there
was a conspiracy, but simply denied that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> was knowingly a part of it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> were instructed to decide whether or not a conspiracy involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jowers</ENAMEX> and "others, including governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>" existed. But they did not
have to determine who was involved or what role each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> played. So,
the specifics of the alleged theory remain vague. Among the arguments presented
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX> could not have committed the crime : Some say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, who
dropped out of school in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> grade, was not smart enough to pull it
off. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> also presented ballistics evidence suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s gun
could not have fired the fatal shot. Although government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> did not
participate in the civil trial, they have long cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s record of successful
bank robberies and his above average IQ as evidence that he was capable of the
crime. They also say that while the ballistic information is inconclusive, it
does not rule <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> out.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loyd Jowers</ENAMEX> confessed : In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> television interview, Jowers
claimed that he had hired and assisted someone else in killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>. Jowers,
who owned the restaurant opposite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s motel (and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> below the room
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> rented), said he had hired the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> on behalf of an associate with
possible ties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>. He claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin shot King</ENAMEX> from his restaurant
and fled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jowers</ENAMEX> failed a lie detector test about the claims. He has since
changed his story multiple times and now denies any intentional involvement in
the assassination. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>'s investigation concluded that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jowers</ENAMEX> made his claims in hopes of snagging a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> deal.

               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> disliked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s anger
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> for his opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> and his activism for racial and
economic equality is well documented: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX> bugged his
hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and sent his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> a tape that suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> was having an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extramarital</ENAMEX> affair. (Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> did have such affairs.) While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX>
presented no definitive evidence establishing a government conspiracy, he did
claim to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in reserve who can prove the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s role. He has
not revealed most of their identities; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX>
implicated in the plot sued him for libel.

            

            In addition to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> investigation of the murder in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> found no evidence
of a government conspiracy. (It did leave open the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> was
involved in a low-level plot involving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and a racist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>
also appealed his conviction <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>--each time citing
new evidence--but the appeals were rejected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, at
the behest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> ordered an investigation
into the assassination. However, early reports indicate that it, too, is likely
to conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> fired the fatal shot.

         
      
   
