
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Terrible Thing</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> hijacked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> en route to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katmandu</ENAMEX> remained idle in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, while hijackers
issued demands. They threatened to blow up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, and its remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> does not release a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>--including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiri</ENAMEX> separatist movement jailed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
launched what they hope is their final assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX> and the estimated
lead with reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> story.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maulana Mansood Azhar</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> in
question, is believed to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the hijackers. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>, which also fronts the story, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report the identity of
the passenger stabbed to death for not obeying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>' orders to sit with
his head down and eyes closed: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rupin Katyal</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delhi</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> after their honeymoon. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> may be aboard the flight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Correspondents</ENAMEX> from the LAT
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> file from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> puts a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s
coverage on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A8</TIMEX>: easier access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>? They don't print the
known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s tragedy.

            A combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechens</ENAMEX> started to take the
Chechen capital piece by piece. This means the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> learned from its mistake in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994-96</TIMEX> war, when a mad dash for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surround</ENAMEX> and pounce on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> explain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
notes that the attack was delayed until after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s parliamentary
elections, in which the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> block made a strong showing. Deep in its
A-section, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports accusations that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> looted a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> near
the capital and murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Tens of thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> remain trapped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> is prohibiting
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> from traveling to the war arena without permission, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also emphasizes the dearth of non-official
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subhead</ENAMEX> reads "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troops Said</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advance</ENAMEX>" and the lead explains the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battle</ENAMEX> is "billed as" definitive.

            "Nothing terrible is going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caucasus</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>. This is an odd locution, not only in light of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">circumstance</ENAMEX>, but also because the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> word grozny is commonly
translated as "terrible" or "terrifying." (Although here, admittedly, he's
probably used a different <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> word for "terrible.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Terrible</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Grozny</ENAMEX>. It seems terrible things go on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX> almost by
definition.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> were forced to leave
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX> were classified as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> aliens
until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s surrender in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> at the time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo Rossi</ENAMEX>, was forced to testify before an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un-American</ENAMEX>
activities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> about his preferred form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>-approved
legislation calling for a formal presidential acknowledgment is currently bound
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> article in a series on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
life. Despite early ideological and professional tinkering, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s son
sought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freshman Council</ENAMEX> presidency at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and cowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> with
his precocious campaigning skills. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> did not seek a higher student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>,
perhaps because of the ribbing he took from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suitemate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, who declared that student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>." A peer remarks
that in their economics section, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "looked scared, and overmatched," but the
paper reports him as "blessedly free of any such fears."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 
               Magazine interviews computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> of the 1970s
to pin down responsibility for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Y2K</TIMEX> bug. The introductory paragraph asks
"who is to blame," so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> come across as sitting ducks. They discuss
their priorities at the time and cough up reasons why the problem was never
addressed. Not all hold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Quoth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortran Standards</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>: "We could have fixed that anytime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. The trouble is, it
would have affected all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' existing programs, and that wasn't
something they would have appreciated." Fortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>,
mollified by lattes and cell phones, have been far more understanding.

            
               Present <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> excluded: On the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX> &
Business" Section, market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gretchen Morgenson</ENAMEX> matches high-flying market
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capitalizations</ENAMEX> to equivalent Gross <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Products</ENAMEX>. The exercise illustrates
why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> believes "these stocks have become like major land
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>." Among those market caps and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GNPs</ENAMEX> compared: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$201</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion; Home Depot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$155 billion</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$593</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. The piece does not illustrate where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> fit in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Co.</ENAMEX>, with a market cap of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just over $8 billion</NUMEX>, matches up with
Phone.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Co.</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.5 billion</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.5 billion</NUMEX>), which publishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , together eclipse FreeMarkets
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX>, which are listed at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 billion</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
