
   
   
      
         
            The <i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX></i> Takes on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journalists</ENAMEX>

they've discovered a really neat argument against campaign finance reform. New
restrictions on special-interest money, they fret, would only enhance the power
of the press. An editorial published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Self-Love</ENAMEX>-in"
argues that the "pundit overlords" are sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> for just this reason. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> wants to help [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>] or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," the piece contends. "Then they will help the media become
the overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX> of what the political system spends its energies
on."

            It's always a pleasure to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> istas applying their special
brand of right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> analysis to politics. But I fear that they have not
been rigorous enough in exposing the press's hidden interests. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is
intentionally promoting the cause of campaign finance reform, it is doing so
despite the clear benefits it derives from the current system--and that it
stands to lose under a reformed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> arguments that support
this.

            Argument No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> would require that as a condition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> licenses, TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> be required to provide free airtime to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.
This would cost media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> some significant fraction of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the estimated $600</NUMEX>
million that will be spent on televised political advertising in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. And it
could run them even more, because mandated free airtime might preempt other
programming and/or non-political paid advertising. To a lesser degree,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> would also suffer under a reformed system,
especially one that restricted lucrative "independent expenditure" campaigns
that tend to buy all those full-page ads.

            Argument No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine says that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
anti-boring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. We thrive on conflict and corruption, and suffer amid
harmony and good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Just ask any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, Which would you rather
cover: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago City Council</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Performance Review</ENAMEX>? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are biased in favor of campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reform, it's not because it will do us any good personally but because
we're high-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mugwumps</ENAMEX> at heart.

            Argument No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: If it's true that campaign finance reform would give the
editorial pages such awesome power, it's darned impressive that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> alone is immune to this temptation. How admirable of them to
show this kind of selfless restraint and idealism when the rest of us are
disingenuously promoting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> interests. Unless, of course, it's the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> around.

         
      
   
