
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox Debates Ballot Box</ENAMEX>

            Chatterbox, who rarely disagrees with his 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">colleague Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, a k a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ballot Box</ENAMEX>," must dissent from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
view that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> look like a jerk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> rightly
points out, the key moment was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> proposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> that they both
agree to stop all television and radio advertising until the nomination is
decided, and instead debate twice a week for the duration of the campaign.
"That can get a lot of the money out of the presidential campaign and
accomplish one of the best reforms," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said. "What about it?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
contemptuous response was to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, "Sounds to me like you're having
trouble raising money," and to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s proposal a "ploy." In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
view, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> succeeded in making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "look like a complete ass."

            But to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s mind, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> who looked like the ass--or, to be
more specific, the hypocrite. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> has rightly pointed
out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s grandiose plan for campaign reform, which requires a
constitutional amendment, and which he trumpeted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> at a joint
appearance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, is far less practical than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s
campaign-reform plan. It is also less practical than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> portrays
himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who sees campaign reform as a far more urgent issue than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> does. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> proposes doing something about the problem right now , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> mocks it as a stunt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> can't have it both ways. If the political process is as corrupted by
cash as he says, then he can't refuse an offer like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s out of hand without
looking like a phony. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s motive was to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> look like a phony
didn't make it any less wrong for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to mock and reject <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s offer. Even
if it was a bluff, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> ought to have called it.

         
      
   
