
   
   
      
         
            Tough Sit

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the agreement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey</ENAMEX> struck <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Justice</ENAMEX> that's designed to ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> police stop
using race as a factor in making traffic stops. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with testimony from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s court
hearing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> in which an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> went to unusual
lengths to mislead his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> about what he was doing when
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nighttime</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> sessions, he downloaded onto portable tapes the
highly classified nuclear secrets to which he had access. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a new poll (undertaken with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>) indicating that, because
of the latest terrorism concerns, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> are less likely to
attend public gatherings on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year's Day</TIMEX>. The poll also
found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> of those asked thought it was at least somewhat
likely that an act of terrorism would occur somewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>. The story also reports that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> a federal grand jury
indicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for trying to smuggle
bombmaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, a development that is fronted at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and reefered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> nor
USAT front the racial profiling story.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> leads <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that under the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> profiling deal, the
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> will report to a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> who will have broad powers to
investigate virtually any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> function and who will track the cops' patterns
of arrests and traffic stops to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> are not being singled
out. Neither story really gets at the nuances involved in really doing this.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions for instance that under the agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>,
troopers are still allowed to make a race-based stop when they are pursuing a
specific criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>, but neither story says whether an all points
bulletin saying to be on the look out for say, a fleeing black or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latino</ENAMEX> is
specific enough. And neither addresses whether or not race-driven stops that
result in an arrest or conviction will/should be counted as racial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profiling</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's story does not include any negative reactions from cops,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's does, including a harsh one from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>'s black police
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>: "It's not the fault of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> when they stop minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> or put
them in jail. It's the fault of the minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> for committing the
crime."

            The LAT front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> is on the verge of adopting
its first new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> would use the precision
guidance technology already common in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> to deliver rounds that
explode in the air above <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy soldiers</ENAMEX>, thereby lessening their ability to
survive battlefield small arms fire by taking cover. There are question marks
however: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> is more than twice as heavy as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-16</ENAMEX> it would replace,
and it's not clear if its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex works</ENAMEX> are really combat-hardy. The LAT
waits until pretty deep into the story to raise another very realistic worry:
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> would wreak havoc in the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX>. And hey, given the
track record of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M-16</ENAMEX> and its ilk--what about in the hands of street
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>?

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pager</NUMEX> describes an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> experiment that intensifies the issues
surrounding the possibility of adding genes to human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryos</ENAMEX>. And the headline
makes the whole thing sound like science gone mad: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SCIENTISTS PLACE</ENAMEX> JELLYFISH
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GENES INTO MONKEYS</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX>, recovering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> made his first public appearance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX>. Appearing
alongside a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> called on all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> of the
world to "end the cycle of violence and the cycle of hatred."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> area of the economy that's
booming as a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y2K</ENAMEX>: the babysitting sector. In big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s
Eve rates of upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> an hour are common. Also pulling down premium
prices for the big <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>: pet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> and security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front returns to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
its more widely read pieces of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>--an airline nightmare story--to tell the
tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S Airways</ENAMEX>' MetroJet Flight 2762, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> to
Dulles that has the distinction of being <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s most delayed flight. The
scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">70-minute</TIMEX> hop, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , averages <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an hour</NUMEX> behind
schedule. It is late <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the time. The piece quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> of one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">night</ENAMEX>'s flight after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an 80-minute</TIMEX> runway stint followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX>-ordered
zigzag patterns over the ocean: "We hate it too."

         
      
   
