
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            This was one of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in the market that a couple
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>, perhaps even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, would have seemed inconceivable. (I
know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week these days</TIMEX> probably would have seemed inconceivable.) Despite
some really impressive news on the inflation front--the Consumer Price Index
rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a weaker-than-expected 0.1 percent</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> issued a study
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with the lowest unemployment rates showed no added
inflationary pressure--interest rates just kept rising, touching <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.4 percent</NUMEX> at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. Normally, those kinds of yields in the bond market would
pull money out of stocks. But at least when it came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouses</ENAMEX> of this
stock market, the big-cap tech names, no one even blinked. Y2K? Tax-selling
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the New Year</TIMEX>? High p/e ratios? It does not seem to matter. So down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg nog</ENAMEX> and give shares in some Internet highfliers as gifts. It'll be just
like when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> used to give us lottery tickets for our birthdays.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> is
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> for possible antitrust violations. I can hear the lawyers
talking now: 'Well, we could go after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>. But if we go after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>, even if
nothing comes of it, we'll probably get to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serena Altschul</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lopez</ENAMEX>.' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Reilly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief financial officer</ENAMEX> of
Linux software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corel</ENAMEX> , announced he was
resigning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Reilly</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> exec to
leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corel</ENAMEX> says they all left for 'personal
reasons.' As in, they were personally appalled at the direction the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was
taking, and could no longer work there in good conscience<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Pascal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX> , was being promoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chairwoman</ENAMEX>, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> has been in a slump and had only one hit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> . On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascal</ENAMEX> was visionary
enough to green-light <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Daddy</ENAMEX> . So
give her a corner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, too!"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> antismoking groups
issued a report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> telling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> that their economic problems
stemmed not from antismoking efforts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but from
cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' decisions to outsource
production and supply abroad. Surprisingly, the report did not add: 'Of
course, we do want you to go out of business. But we really aren't the ones who
are making that happen.' "

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMGI</ENAMEX> announced it was
spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$523 million</NUMEX> to acquire yesmail.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> , which
delivers targeted promotional messages to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
e-mail boxes. Ah, the promise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a billion dollars</NUMEX> for the online
equivalent of telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitors</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s stock soared
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> after the long-awaited <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 2000</ENAMEX> operating system was released
to manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. Now, given that Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
wasn't exactly a secret , it's not clear why anyone who bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> wouldn't have bought it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>. Of course, maybe they
just thought it was never going to appear. I guess it's easier to underpromise
and overdeliver when no one believes in you to begin with."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahir Cagri</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyber-star</ENAMEX> because of his wiggy home page featuring the dreaded
photo of him in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speedo</ENAMEX> and his inimitable slogan 'I
kiss you!' has gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> offers from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> to 'film his life
story.' Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascal</ENAMEX>, I think we've just found the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX>
vehicle!"

         
      
   
