
   
   
      
         
            Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> a Cineaste
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Roger</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX> didn't write for "actual moviegoers like herself"; she wrote
for ideal moviegoers like herself. She wouldn't praise a film she found
offensively treacly or that trafficked in positive stereotypes because
she thought it would ennoble the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> who saw only a handful
of pictures a year. She went to the opposite extreme--she even hated films like
To Kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mockingbird</ENAMEX> that arguably have done humanity good,
especially if they've been seen by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at an impressionable age. (The words
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boo Radley</ENAMEX>" are lodged in the back of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s mind who thinks about making
fun of some seeming weirdo on the block.) She could be a gleeful provocateur,
like one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ibsen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who lives to hurl sticks of dynamite into
"the damned, compact majority." And she loved to throw her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> off
balance by praising both the rare piece of populist entertainment she thought
was beautifully made or rooted in truth ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>! , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Heat of</ENAMEX>

               the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.T.</ENAMEX> ) and the foreign-made art film that could never
be seen by more than a sliver of moviegoers.

            When I called you the conscience of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>, I was being neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ironic</ENAMEX> nor, I hope, patronizing. Because of your stature and the size of the TV
audience you've built for film criticism, you've saddled yourself with what
seem like political responsibilities. I don't mean to suggest that your
response to The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> (or that damn <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jar Jar picture</ENAMEX>) isn't
genuine--only that you seem to be responding both for yourself and for
the unsophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moviegoer</ENAMEX> who will be better off seeing a movie in which a
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a mystical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healer</ENAMEX> wrongly executed than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which a black man
is, say, a drug pusher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gorily</ENAMEX> dispatched by some action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. You might be
right, but you're grading on a different curve than I am.

            Does that make me an elitist? I hope it makes me exactly the opposite. I'd
like to think that the "common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>"--whoever they might be--are as
capable of responding to works of complexity as I am. Maybe A Taste of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherry</ENAMEX> --although I was scratching my head over that one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.
Certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Kings</ENAMEX> or Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> or--duhhh-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bigger, Longer & Uncut</ENAMEX> . I'd also like to think they could see
The 
               Green <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mile</ENAMEX> and be moved and impressed by parts of it (as I
was) and still be able to say, when it's over: "There's something really creepy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that ..."

         
      
   
