
   
   
      
         
            Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Shrug</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> fighting
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, a story run above the fold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and on Page
A17 in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with
pieces on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> computer glitches--or rather the lack thereof--a story fronted by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (technically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story is part of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> package
serving as the top non-local lead).

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> labels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> a presidential
"campaign-style tour" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calls it "unexpected," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> relates that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had planned the trip months
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> decided to step down (this important detail
probably pushed the story off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's front page). As proof of this
prior scheduling, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that the engravings on the souvenir
hunting knives given by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX> bore the title "prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>" but not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." With not much else to report about the
presidential visit, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> stories wander in different directions: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gives behind-the-scenes details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s resignation
announcement and analyzes the legality of his immunity deal; the LAT
speculates on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX> presidential election; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports
on the status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX> siege. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think-tank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> tells the LAT
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s casualty rate exceeds that of both its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994-'96</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> campaign
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>'s ill-fated war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.

            The headline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> computer glitch asks, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Did It All Go</ENAMEX>
Right?" The answer: Good preparation in the developed world and a low reliance
on technology in the developing world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Firms, Overreacted to Y2K Fix, Critics Say"</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Vast Efforts to Fix Computers Defended</ENAMEX> [and It's
Not Over]") take a more provocative angle--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> spent too much to fix
the problem. But the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> can dig up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> between them--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and an anonymous Internet newsgroup <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>--willing to
argue this. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does lay out some plausible reasons why
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> may have overprepared: fear of litigation and the bureaucratic
imperative to simply upgrade software rather than fix it. The only major
computer foul-up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, was the temporary malfunction
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> satellite.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> abandons Y2K sobriety by devoting much of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section to the lighter side of millennial madness. There is an
amusing dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and a report on several memorable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">kisses</TIMEX>. Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manners</ENAMEX> announces, with tongue in cheek, that she will
begin to employ the phrase, "Oh, that's soooo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th century</TIMEX>." A computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> says of the anti-climactic changeover, "It's like coitus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interruptus</ENAMEX>. You know: Is that all there is?" Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> article
begins, "We realize that you are almost certainly reading
this article by candlelight ... and we regret that our experiments with
glow-in-the-dark ink have failed." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> both pan the millennial celebration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>,
blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s lack of a geographic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, of signature iconography, and
of community spirit. (To read 
                  Slate
               's dispatch from
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Square</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucas Miller</ENAMEX>, click here.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run fascinating accounts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s hijacking of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, as told by several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, who
identified themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> fighting for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> control of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>,
escaped on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX> after negotiating a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>; to read

                  Slate
               's briefing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> conflict, click
here.) The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few days</TIMEX> saw repeated emergency landings--one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> was made
without runway lights and with only a minute and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> left. Although
the hijackers slit the throat of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passenger in private, they did not
disclose this murder to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, who at times joked and conversed
with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX>. Near the end of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-day</TIMEX> odyssey the toilets were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overflowing</ENAMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventh day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> announced that in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>
every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> would be shot. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> hijacker, who called himself "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burger</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recited Urdu</ENAMEX> poetry, gave a passenger a birthday gift, and before escaping
ordered all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to say they had forgiven him.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" article details the apparent failure of "boot-camp" rehabilitation for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juvenile delinquents</ENAMEX>. Launched in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX> with much fanfare, these
paramilitary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> had expanded to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>
are routinely beaten and suffer recidivism rates higher than those of juveniles
in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> have dropped their
programs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> will likely follow.

            An article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describes the surrender in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> believe has murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six months</TIMEX>.
Question: Why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> repeatedly call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> a "mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>"
when he has yet to be tried? Are accusations against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> qualified with
words like "allegedly" only when the crime is prosecuted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>?

            In his inaugural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX>--recently
poached from that renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repository</ENAMEX> of writing talent,

                  Slate
               --notes that the much-heralded global economy of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 20th</TIMEX> (and now 21st) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> is really the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of its kind. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Global Economy</ENAMEX>, as he dubs it, occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> started laying telegraph cables beneath the ocean, blasting railroad
tunnels through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>, and linking the seas with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canals</ENAMEX>. A combination of
jingoism among political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> and insularity among the business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> who
spearheaded this new international commerce provoked a near-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year</TIMEX> reaction
against free trade and global communications. "The big economic question for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next century</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> concludes,

            

               is really political: Can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Global Economy</ENAMEX> build a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> that
reaches beyond the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who congregate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davos</ENAMEX>? If not, it will
eventually go the way of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

            

            (To read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               , click here.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dueling NYT</ENAMEX> headlines (from the Internet edition):

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Trying Time For Many Net Retailers</ENAMEX>"

            "A Very Big E-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Christmas</ENAMEX>"


This Just In--<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nuclear War Averted</ENAMEX>
            

            A lede from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> :

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">COLORADO SPRINGS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>--The new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> arrived well before dawn here
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Peterson Air Force Base</ENAMEX>, but there was more relief than celebration as
the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> time zones began passing from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> without nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conflagration</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
