
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comfort Cinema</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>:

            So much stuff to respond to, my keyboard is shaking. Of course, that could
just be the horrifying turbulence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. That and the fact that reading
all of this e-mail via a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE Airfone</ENAMEX> will cost me a down payment on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rog</ENAMEX>--the reason I brought up The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> had nothing to do with
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correctness</ENAMEX>. The fact is, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> had a
lot to prove. As my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, told me, it really was
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about</NUMEX> working twice as fast to go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as far. If <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> had any
bravery, it would have dealt with the fact that racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epithets</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">offhandedly</ENAMEX> tossed off by what were considered the best of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> during that
period. Green 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mile</ENAMEX> 's fear of the real world is the real political
correctness: Every white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the movie is a warm, decent sort who regrets
any motion that's vaguely menacing. Every racist in the movie is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caricature</ENAMEX>--even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Sinise</ENAMEX>, who compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that'll turn on you.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> had been forced to deal with his own incipient racism, that would have
made his "life sentence" seem fitting--he had to lose his mortality to gain
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> sight--and the movie would have a real wallop. But the fact is, no
studio is gonna pony up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> uncomfortable and
remind us of attitudes that still drift throughout this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. (I have a
cassette of censored cartoons from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, and the racism in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coal Black</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Sebben Dwarfs</ENAMEX> alone is enough to explain all of the anger in hip-hop.)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my concerns about moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is the open racism that still lives
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>; the joke I used to make is the only reason black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> date white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> is so they can get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, I discussed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> the strain of sacrificial black
mystics that runs throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s work, and put that stuff in my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star-Telegram</ENAMEX> review of the picture, then cut it for space reasons
myself. I'm sorry I did. As much as I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawshank Redemption</ENAMEX> , the
p.c.-minded ignoring of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgan Freeman</ENAMEX>'s race made the movie seem slightly
insane to me. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman</ENAMEX>--here's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who knows what it's like to suffer.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Roughly</NUMEX> a contemporary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poitier</ENAMEX>, he--like a bunch of other black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>--had
to watch as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poitier</ENAMEX> was treated like the only black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the planet. He had
to wait until most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> think about collecting a pension to watch his career
start. It creates a core of tension in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman</ENAMEX>'s work. (This residual anger can
be seen even in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>'s early acting--he's the only good thing in the
otherwise atrocious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jugs & Speed</ENAMEX> and there's a compelling
undercurrent of rancor in his work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickey & Boggs</ENAMEX> --before he
retired from the human race. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> I ever read, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> I
think, featured an interview with a very angry <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby</ENAMEX>, who sided with the black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX> with a thirst for payback. It was the first sense I got of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was as deeply compromised by success as any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>: You have to check out Praise . It's a remarkable piece of work
that hasn't been picked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> because there's no way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> could
be shoehorned into it. The seedy romance between a slacker and an agressive
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> covered with psoriasis--it's like her id is eating her up from the
inside--doesn't give anyone an easy out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacha Holder</ENAMEX>, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the
lead, has presence to burn--she never tips her hand. It's worth looking for.
Otherwise, it has been <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys Night Out in the American Cinematheque</ENAMEX>. The stuff
treating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seriously has come from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. And I hate saying that,
because it makes me look like some middlebrow reflex <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francophile</ENAMEX> or something.
Which I ain't.

         
      
   
