
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Revolution</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            Well, that message would have been the right place to stop. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Revelation of Saint John</ENAMEX>, anything else is going to be a bit of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anticlimax</ENAMEX>. But I'll take a stab at it anyway, and finish, in the spirit of the
family, and maybe even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>, not with a last word, but with a
last question. Are we at the End of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eschatology</ENAMEX>?

            Let me explain what I mean. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX> put
forward his famous thesis about how we were at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of History</ENAMEX>, only to see
History seem to resume with a vengeance, as you put it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>. But he
was obviously onto something. I would call it the end of revolution. It was
only a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years ago</TIMEX> that the modern idea of revolution developed:
that is, the idea that society, and perhaps even human nature, could be rapidly
altered and improved through concerted political action. It has its origin, as
much as anywhere, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rousseau</ENAMEX>. "The passing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of nature to the
civil society," he wrote, "produces a remarkable change in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>; it puts justice
as a rule of conduct in the place of instinct, and gives his actions the moral
quality they previously lacked." Here, in these remarkable words, is the seed
of modern radical politics, the promise that brute human nature and selfish
instinct can be overcome, given the proper political system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Revolutionaries</ENAMEX> believed in it, and talked of the "new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" (nu?). So did the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian Revolutionaries</ENAMEX>.

            This promise, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can be suddenly and purposefully redeemed and
lifted above their sinful natures, is a profoundly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian</ENAMEX> one. And it is no
accident that the idea of revolution arose at a moment when the terrible fires
of religious conflict had burnt out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thinkers</ENAMEX> had
largely concluded that forcibly imposing possible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> salvation on
doctrinal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> was not worth the enormous cost in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and toil that two
centuries of religious warfare had taken (the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Thirty Years' War</ENAMEX> alone reduced
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 25 percent</NUMEX>). It was called an age of
"anti-enthusiasm" (i.e. religious enthusiasm). But in this vacuum, a new form
of enthusiasm quickly emerged, along with a new, quasi-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eschatology</ENAMEX>,
in the idea of revolution. There would still be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, although a
purely terrestrial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. There would still be Final Things, and a direction to
history.

            But now, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX> that have seen far greater suffering than the
religious wars ever caused, in the pursuit of this new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jerusalem</ENAMEX> (what is
Wallenstein, next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>?), revolution, too, is at an end. The central and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> were very careful not to label what
they were doing a "revolution." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Revolutions</ENAMEX> don't work, wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pole Jacek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuron</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation</ENAMEX> , pointedly on the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution of 1789</ENAMEX>. Today, hardly
anyone outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pyongyang</ENAMEX> talks about using politics to change
human nature, or even suddenly and drastically to improve society. In that
sense, we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> now, and in another age of anti-enthusiasm.

            But will new enthusiasms arise once again, and if so, from where? Will there
be new promises of liberation, human fulfillment, and Final Things? Or are we,
therefore, at the End of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eschatology</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
