
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whores</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qualcomm Soars</ENAMEX>
            

            If there's one thing to hope for after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> leapt
over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4,000</NUMEX> (hardly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> after it crossed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX>), it's that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> from
now no one remembers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Piecyk</ENAMEX>'s name.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piecyk</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paine Webber telecom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> who this morning put a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-month</TIMEX>
price target of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>-a-share on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qualcomm</ENAMEX>, which closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$503</NUMEX> a
share. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piecyk</ENAMEX>'s call sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qualcomm</ENAMEX>'s stock back off to the races. It opened at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$560</NUMEX>, and ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$659</NUMEX>, which is a leap of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX>. That's
respectable by any standard, but it's especially remarkable when you consider
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qualcomm</ENAMEX>, before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, was already the best-performing stock in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX> 500 Index, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1,800 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. (It's now up better
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2,300 percent</NUMEX>.)

            I know, I know. These numbers are effectively gibberish, especially since I
could fill this column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> with stories about stocks making incredible
moves upward. So why does it matter or not matter whether in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> the mention of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Piecyk</ENAMEX>'s name will be greeted with anything other than "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who?</ENAMEX>"

            The simplest answer is that the success of calls like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piecyk's</ENAMEX>--success here
meaning just that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> buy on the news of your price target--leads to more
calls just like it. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Blodget</ENAMEX>, who was then at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIBC Oppenheimer</ENAMEX>, said
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s shares would hit <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> (he was right), it
catapulted him into national attention and, in some sense, probably got him his
new job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX>. And other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> noticed. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FreeMarkets</ENAMEX>, a hot
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business-to-business company</ENAMEX>, went public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that wasn't underwriting the deal initiated coverage on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the IPO
and set a price target of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> a share, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was going
public at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48</NUMEX> a share. It's become almost <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">de rigueur</TIMEX> , in fact, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> to make audacious calls. Otherwise they won't even be noticed.

            You can see the same phenomenon at work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' estimates of things
like that fabled Internet business-to-business market. For a while now, the
number everyone's been tossing around is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 trillion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. But that means
that if you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> and you cite that number, no one will notice you. So
now the numbers are getting ratcheted up, to the point where a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sachs</ENAMEX> study said the market could be as large as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 trillion</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, of
course, here I am mentioning the report.)

            The phenomenon of number creep is bad because we want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> to reach
conclusions they think are true, and not conclusions that they think are going
to get them on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>. (I realize this is incredibly naive, but there it is.) And
the truth is that there still isn't enough accountability for these kinds of
forecasts to make the rewards and punishments for success and failure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commensurate</ENAMEX>. But the phenomenon is also bad because these kinds of calls have
become market-moving events, which means that it's no longer irrational to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> as a result of them, at least if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>.

            According to a traditional definition of "information" about a stock (as in,
a stock's price reflects all the available information the market has about
it), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piecyk</ENAMEX>'s report was not new. Moreover, when you consider that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qualcomm</ENAMEX> was
already up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1,800 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, the appropriate question to ask is
probably: "Why are you just starting to cover this stock now?" But if we
broaden the definition of "information" to include everything that might affect
that stock's price, even in the short term, then the report has to be
considered new information, which means that it has to affect the stock price.
And that means that ignoring it is not necessarily rational, even if
there's nothing valuable about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piecyk</ENAMEX>'s analysis.

            The best thing for everyone, then, will be for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qualcomm</ENAMEX> to settle back in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next couple of months</TIMEX>, or even just rise slightly, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piecyk</ENAMEX>'s
forecast to be forgotten. In the long run, even in this stock market,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' stock prices will find their true level. But what has become
incredibly clear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> is that the signal-to-noise ratio in the stock market
is degenerating (with something like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piecyk</ENAMEX>'s report being noise), and that
means that it will take longer for those true levels to be reached.

         
      
   
