
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Times Blasts ... the L.A. Times</ENAMEX>!

            Chatterbox started reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-page investigation of itself well before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>. (If you don't
know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is talking about, click here and
here and
here.) 
He didn't finish until after the sun had set. Even granting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other minor tasks to complete <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, it does seem that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven hours</TIMEX>
is more time than any reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should have to spend reading about the
genesis of a single-topic edition of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Someone less familiar
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> ' tradition of
running stories at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately five</NUMEX> times their logical length might suspect
that publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shaw</ENAMEX>'s opus, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossing the Line</ENAMEX>," was a deliberate
scheme to hide news of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s misbehavior by burying it
inside a self-important and interminable narrative that almost no one would
have the patience to read. The thing came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>," and there was so
much throat-clearing that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>
was actually called, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Prelude</ENAMEX>." But in fact, the length was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> ' own daft way of saying that it
views the recent corruption of its editorial standards as a serious matter.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> wins bravery points for all but calling his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Downing</ENAMEX>, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Parks</ENAMEX>, a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liars</ENAMEX> who ought to be
sacked forthwith. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> never told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> until very late in the game that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> 's special issue celebrating the
opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> was going to share ad revenues with the new
downtown sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>. She kept this secret, she says, because she didn't want
to corrupt editorial processes. But it's much likelier, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> writes, that she
"didn't think it was a big deal" (the actual quote is from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Stanton</ENAMEX>, senior
heard about the revenue-sharing deal and revolted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> gave assurances that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> hadn't helped sell ads. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> shows, they had.
("That's us, that was us, that was us, that was us," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Lieweke</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>, paging through the issue with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> and
pointing out ads he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> helped to get.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> also told the angry
news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> that she was canceling the ad-revenue-sharing agreement with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> and sending it a check instead. But the check still hasn't been
sent, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> reports. (Perhaps it was sent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> read his
story.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, insists that at various planning
meetings, when the revenue-sharing arrangement was discussed or mentioned in
memos that were handed out, he was somehow not paying attention, or out of the
room talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, or something. He says that when he did find out
about it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, he was outraged, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>'s reporting shows his reaction
to have been weirdly muted. He didn't have the special issue canceled, even
though at that point most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> hadn't yet been printed; he didn't
even consider running a disclosure statement about the deal, which would have
been laughably easy to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> that he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity Barringer</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , who broke the
story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> deal in the national press, that it was "an inappropriate
arrangement, and we should not have done it," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barringer</ENAMEX>, who is a
scrupulously fair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> he never told her anything like
that.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> also deserves kudos for documenting his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s decline under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
Mirror <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Willes</ENAMEX> (who, interestingly, was still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> contract was signed). The horror stories include a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of an
ad-sales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> impersonating an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>; the ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> telling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> of a "'Millennium
Home contest,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of which would be 'profiled in a follow-up feature
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>' " that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> neither knew of nor would approve; and various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> being
corralled into planning profit-making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> conferences of various kinds
featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they wrote about. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s slide into ethically
questionable business practices predates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX>' arrival, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> makes clear that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willes</ENAMEX> has accelerated it.

            Chatterbox must fault <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX>, though, for offering only the sketchiest answer
to a question Chatterbox
raised when the story first broke: namely, what business justification was there for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> to enter into its
founding-partnership deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>? As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> pointed out
then, the dollar value of the newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concession</ENAMEX> and the ad placements and
the skybox inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>, which appear to be all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> gets out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>, is
well under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> ended up paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 million</NUMEX>
annually for the privilege. This is better than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>
that was previous reported, but it's still a bad financial deal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> reports
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> was demanding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million to $3 million</NUMEX> from its other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founding partners</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times suits felt very clever for having bid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> down. Of its annual
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 million</NUMEX> payment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX>
pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX> in cash; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> in free advertising; and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $300,000</NUMEX> in
profits from joint ventures. This last, which has come to symbolize in most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s minds the corruption of editorial standards implicit in the deal, was
viewed at the time (in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who negotiated the deal) as "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> for us to be able to make this deal during a time when cash was a problem."
Perhaps coincidentally, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times set about calculating how much it had netted off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>
issue, it found that after making extremely complex estimates regarding the use
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>' time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>'s agreed-upon <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> share was ...
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>. But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> was
swindling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>, it was only in the context of a larger deal in
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> had conned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A. Times</ENAMEX> .

            Perhaps that story should be assigned to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times ' business section. It could probably be explained quite exhaustively
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few hundred</NUMEX> words.

         
      
   
