
   
   
      
         
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fool Speaks</ENAMEX>, (Some) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> Listen
            

            The Internet has become such a central part of both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cultural landscape that it's easy to imagine that a real convergence
between the offline and online worlds has happened, particularly when it comes
to the media world. But the truth seems to be that for a lot of the offline
press, and for much of Wall Street, what happens on the Internet is still
either something of a mystery or, almost by definition, too sketchy to take
seriously.

            Take the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera Genomics</ENAMEX>, a biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that offers information
from its genetic databases to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. Since the close of trading on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s share price has risen from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">76 to 160</TIMEX>, or better than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s trading volume has skyrocketed as well. Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110,000</NUMEX> shares
traded on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16 th</NUMEX> , while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.69 million</NUMEX> changed hands on the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> , and the stock has had volume of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> shares or better
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> since then. (Well, technically, on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 rd only 997,000</NUMEX>
shares traded, but that's pretty close to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million</NUMEX>.) The stock leapt <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> points
on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> points on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> points on the
21st, fell back a little on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> nd , and then bounced further ahead
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two days</TIMEX>.

            Even by the standards of this wacky momentum-driven market, that's an
impressive and really surprising move, and it did not go unnoticed by either
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> or, eventually, by the financial press. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>,
for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> itself whether it knew of any reason for
the sudden spike in its stock, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> said, sensibly enough, that it
did not comment on its stock price. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three days later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> had to declare
an order imbalance at the open because there were too many buy orders and not
enough sell orders on the books. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> both ran pieces on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s ascent.

            The odd thing, though, is that no one has actually reported what happened.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloomberg, for instance,</ENAMEX> blithely attributed the run-up to "increased
enthusiasm for genetic information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and for incorporating genomic
research into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> development." As for why that enthusiasm suddenly hit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> with such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, and why it was so focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>, all Bloomberg
could offer was an article that appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, which included a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-line reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomberg</ENAMEX> quoted an analyst
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banc Boston Robertson Stephens</ENAMEX> who confidently said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New York</ENAMEX>
Times article would be the trigger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, came to the
story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> in a broader piece about a boom in biotech
stocks, a boom that, weirdly enough, it suggested began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 days ago</TIMEX>, on
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> .

            What everyone appears to have missed is that on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fool</ENAMEX>, an online
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2 million</NUMEX> unique <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> (and my
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>), announced that it would be adding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celera</ENAMEX> to its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule-Breaker</ENAMEX>
Portfolio" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five days</TIMEX>. (The Fools announce all their buys in advance
of actually making the purchase in order not to front-run the stock.) The very
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, volume in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celera</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> times higher than it had been on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, and the stock's dramatic rise was under way. It's probably true that
all the stock's rise can't be attributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fool</ENAMEX>'s influence, especially
since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> did announce an important acquisition on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>. But it's also
true that many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are now paying attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celera</ENAMEX> than were
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rule</ENAMEX>-Breaker buy, and that now includes lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have
never even visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fool</ENAMEX> site.

            Whether you think this is a good thing or a bad thing probably depends on
what you think of the Internet's impact on financial markets. I think a good
argument can be made that in this case, what you're looking at is not a
speculative bubble but rather an example of potentially valuable
information--not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rule-Breaker Portfolio</ENAMEX>'s decision to buy, but its
explanation of why it was buying--being disseminated to a much wider audience
than would once have had access to it. But the really interesting thing is the
almost complete obliviousness of the offline media to what actually happened,
and the forced nature of their explanations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s rise. You didn't even
to have to work hard to find out about the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> to the portfolio,
since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fool</ENAMEX> put out a news release announcing it. Call it willful blindness,
then. Apparently the Net still has a ways to go before the offline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> can
really take it seriously.

         
      
   
