
   
   
      
         
            Dumb and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumber</ENAMEX>!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liberal Media Bias Lives</ENAMEX>! Exhibit A: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Minority Growth Slips at Top</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Schools</ENAMEX>," read the headline on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randal C. Archibold</ENAMEX>. You could have been forgiven for
muttering, "Uh oh," and thinking here was another example of the project of
racial integration collapsing. But the alarmist headline was a Nixonian
trick--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixonian</ENAMEX> in the sense of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s notorious declaration, while
prices were soaring in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>, that "we have slowed the rise in the
rate of inflation." Prices were still rising. The rate at which prices were
rising was still rising. Only the rate at which that rate was rising wasn't
rising anymore.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> headline wasn't quite that deceptive, but it was close. It
turns out that minority enrollment isn't falling. It's increasing. It was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, and it's "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 21 percent</NUMEX>" now.
What's the problem, then? It seems, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archibold</ENAMEX> ominously notes, that "the pace
of growth has slowed." But should we really expect the minority share of
enrollments not just to keep growing but to keep growing at its initial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pace</ENAMEX> ? Even in the best of all possible civil-rights environments, the
rate of increase would have to slow down sometime, wouldn't it, as minority
admissions approached a fair, non-discriminatory level? ...

            It turns out there is a story buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Archibold</ENAMEX>'s piece, but it's
mostly a success story. Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are indeed accepted at private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, but even though "they can afford the steep tuition," their parents
"often choose other options, including parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and a move to the
suburbs" where the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> "have a better reputation." Isn't this
basically a heartening trend? Integrating the suburbs is arguably more
important than integrating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldston</ENAMEX>. At elite private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archibold</ENAMEX> tells
us, minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> fear cultural isolation. They also fear becoming the
"subject of speculation" as to whether they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of race
preferences. Yet the overall picture is positive: The private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are
becoming more integrated while the suburbs are becoming more integrated, too.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Private School Minority Enrollment Holds Steady Even as Qualified Students</ENAMEX>
Move to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suburbs"</ENAMEX> would have been a more accurate headline. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liberal Media Bias Lives</ENAMEX>! Exhibit B: Meanwhile, on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B3</TIMEX>, the
spread of half-baked faux-Dowdism continues with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kifner</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX>" section
story headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Menaces</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kifner</ENAMEX> writes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A decade</ENAMEX>
after the fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX> signaled the swift collapse of communism's
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evil Empire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph W. Giuliani</ENAMEX> is still darkly wary of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>
influence in the nooks and crannies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>." It seems the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> didn't
like it when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of transit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> decried "an
orgy of profit-making" by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> leader
said, "They're not going to rake it in if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> aren't running." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
argued that that "means taking jobs away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," and said it reflected a
"true misunderstanding of what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is all about. That comes from the
influence of Marxism, and if you need any better indication of it, it was said
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kifner</ENAMEX> implicitly ridicules this statement--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, he says, "has
discerned a sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> tinge"--but he never explains why it's ridiculous.
Are there no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marxists</ENAMEX> left after the fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall</ENAMEX>? Was the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>
and Marxism entirely bound up in the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Bloc</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> "C"
Communism? That's not what they taught me in my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>! Has Kifner
heard of the New Left? And isn't it true that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marxists</ENAMEX> have a vision of class
conflict that is at odds with a vision (embraced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>) that sees an
"orgy of profit-making" as a good thing because everyone has an interest in
capitalist prosperity? ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kifner</ENAMEX> doesn't even tell us whether the union
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s statement really was "said at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
apparently must be a wacky McCarthyist paranoid regardless of whether he's
telling the truth. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kifner</ENAMEX>'s piece makes sense only as an appeal to the
unexamined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-anti-Communist</ENAMEX>) biases of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. ... A couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kifner</ENAMEX>'s other examples do show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> has a tendency to view any
deploring of class disparities as "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> pays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> more
respect by recognizing that his philosophy has some meaning worth criticizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Kifner</ENAMEX> does by acting as if it is so dead and meaningless that anyone who
takes it seriously is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>. ...

            In the middle of his piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kifner</ENAMEX> veers off and makes fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> for
having "expanded his horizon to foreign affairs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>." It seems the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
lamented that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> had been "romanticized," and urged asylum for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elián González.</ENAMEX> And this was ridiculous because ... why, exactly?
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>? But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> didn't use the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describe Castro</ENAMEX> (though it surely would have been appropriate). He was adding
his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two cents</NUMEX> to a controversy in the news, and his position on asylum was
hardly outlandish. ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kifner</ENAMEX>'s smug, sneering piece wasn't labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Analysis</ENAMEX>." But that
wouldn't have saved it. ...

            [ So the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has a liberal bias. Isn't that an easy
target?--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ed</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> shoot the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in the barrel." Plus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
seems to be getting worse, playing to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> NPR demographic the same way
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC Nightly News</ENAMEX> plays to geriatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.]

         
      
   
