
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Speed Ahead</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with news that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and
her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>, arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> at a border crossing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>,
may be connected to a militant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front the story). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> she was driving and phone she was
carrying were linked to a "primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">member</ENAMEX>" of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that sponsors terrorism
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s top non-local story is the dismal
result of talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy secretary of state</ENAMEX> expressed displeasure
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s offensive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>'s refusal to budge on
modifications to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads
with the Dow's record high, its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. Why the boom? The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> panic
sell-off many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> predicted has failed to materialize. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Education</ENAMEX>'s decision not to renew <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools chancellor</ENAMEX>'s contract, citing his increasingly erratic behavior and
unwillingness to address recent allegations of widespread attendance fraud. An
accompanying article paints <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guiliani</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>, as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> behind his dismissal.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say that there is no link yet between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> arrests and
the earlier arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a carload of bomb
ingredients. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic League</ENAMEX>, the suspected terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, is
described as a now-defunct cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX>
arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also notes that the woman
listed her only asset as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> in a checking account, and claims her living
expenses, including significant international travel, are met by her wealthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT fronts the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie Meeks</ENAMEX>, who received a
presidential pardon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meeks</ENAMEX> was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seamen</ENAMEX> accused of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutiny</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> when they refused to resume loading <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition onto ships</ENAMEX> after
a deadly explosion at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Chicago</ENAMEX>. White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> were given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>'s leave
in the wake of the explosion; a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> investigation concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meeks</ENAMEX>
and the other "mutineers" were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of racial prejudice but did not overturn
the ruling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meeks</ENAMEX> was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pardoned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P.T</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnum</ENAMEX>, eat your heart out: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">High-</ENAMEX>flight tech stocks
continue to soar, but aging rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, another perennially overvalued
commodity, have hit the skids.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than half</NUMEX>
of the seats for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Buffett</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s concert--priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $1,000</NUMEX>
apiece--have sold. Another gala affair, featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sting</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Jones</ENAMEX>, was
canceled when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partiers</ENAMEX> balked at the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> tickets. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> blame
general Y2K dread for the sluggish sales. Filled with the spirit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> offers a more charitable explanation: Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> just aren't as
dumb as rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> think they are.

         
      
   
