
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A.'s Belated New Year</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>, although it's already afternoon there. We Southern
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> experienced a really bad case of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World</ENAMEX> syndrome when
new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> marched flashily around the globe before finally, timidly,
landing here. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insult</ENAMEX> was added to injury when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Purdum</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> took out after us for our lack of excitement, resuscitating the
"laid-back" stereotype that I thought had been shipped off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
or so ago, along with our laid-off aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Left out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdum</ENAMEX>'s
piece, because it vitiated his argument, was the fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> (and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>) do get excited <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose Parade</ENAMEX>, which lasts a lot longer than a fireworks show, and is
slightly less inexplicable than the diaphanously costumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> who cavorted
through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX> endorses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. Knock me over with an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>-mover,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buddy</ENAMEX>. This should solve her lingering case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.D.</ENAMEX> (electoral dysfunction).
But I can't think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more grating campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> joined on a single
ticket than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. As to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX>, I had the opportunity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to
watch both their speeches, and in each case, after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few moments</TIMEX>, I opted
instead to wash some long-neglected dishes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> are wrong to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is
suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fatigue. I already have a well-developed case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
fatigue. He was back to the blue suit, though; does that mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> has
taken another pay cut?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Re Clinton</ENAMEX>'s taste in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, I've covered this in my book, but, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he's supposed to be banging movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. I did see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> , and the show left me with one burning question that
hard-hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> failed to ask: If you're a borderline nobody who's been
given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> of nationwide airtime with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of Talk, what in hell is so
important that you have to leave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> early?

            As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, I say send him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> fight it
out. Speaking of borders, though, isn't the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> bombing conspiracy
being teased out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> reason enough to bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> finally and close
the damn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> border? Couldn't an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> have anchored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 hours</TIMEX> of
millennium coverage just as well and, at the end, just as tearfully?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
