
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Backlash Against the Backlash Against Irony</ENAMEX>

            The backlash against the backlash against irony has begun, and just in time.
Deriding irony is now a reflex not just among the serious, such as Jedediah
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of For Common Things , but among the ironic as well.
Take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinite Jest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster Wallace</ENAMEX>, who has called irony the
source of "a great despair and stasis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> culture." Or former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and wit-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX>-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hirschorn</ENAMEX>, who, agreeing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX> in a

                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dialogue</ENAMEX>," deemed irony "a
comfortable perch from which we can be unserious about the environment, not to
mention labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-world <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX>, ethnic conflict, wage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disparities</ENAMEX>, corporate malfeasance." When master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ironists</ENAMEX> feel the need to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disparage</ENAMEX>, non-ironically, the very instinct that animates them, you know that
we've all traveled too far down the path toward neurotic self-negation.

            Hence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s relief at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glimmers of a countertrend--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
articles and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie defending irony in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three weeks</TIMEX>. The first piece
was an unsigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18</TIMEX> editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , endorsing the
opinion of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Foreign Office</ENAMEX> who considers irony a
necessary virtue in a post-colonial world: It "suggests a certain modesty about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oneself</ENAMEX>, one's values, and one's aspirations. At least irony is unlikely to be
used to justify programmes of conquest or extermination." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> article was by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gates</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
claiming in somewhat overblown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsweekly</ENAMEX> fashion that irony and ironic
juxtapositions are "an inevitable response to the human condition. The original
ironic juxtaposition, after all, is the spirit plunked down into the material
world." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>,
who argues for irony on the charmingly loopy ground that it is a fin de
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">siècle condition</ENAMEX>, and that one corrective for the fin de siècle
condition is, historically, the election of non-ironic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, whose ranks
might include not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> but also the frightening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyes</ENAMEX>.

            What unites all of these articles is a certain earnestness: Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
are not joking (well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> sort of is). Irony, they say, is
good --good for foreign policy, good for the soul, even good for the
presidency. Which brings us to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man on the Moon</ENAMEX> , a movie celebrating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedian Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX>, whose performances were ironic in the deepest sense.
Sweet, gentle, and never sarcastic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaufman</ENAMEX> was a kind of holy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>. He refused
to wink at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> so as to let them know that his nonsense was a put-on.
Wrestling irate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>? Bashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>? Being an inept and
unfunny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> with no business on stage? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> refused to reassure you
that any of it was a joke. The movie has no such qualms, however. It is a
conventional celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biopic</ENAMEX>, lionizing its subject at every possible turn,
and congratulating itself for its insight. It winks nonstop. See? the
movie says, S ee how great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> was? See how stupid everyone else was,
because they didn't get it? See how smart we are, who do get it?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> is so insufferable it made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Culturebox</ENAMEX> wonder whether the
entire effort to defend irony nonironically, welcome though it is, is somehow
doomed to fail. Does the very effort to defend irony to those impervious to its
charms require you to trick it up as something it is not? After all, irony is
not for anything. It has no higher purpose. It is a perspective on the
world, one that takes advantage of distance and some weirdly skewed point of
view to see everyday things--pomposity, convention, higher purposes, and the
earnest advancement of points like this one--as ridiculous or sad or just
somehow other than what they usually seem. It's a lens that is morally
neutral, deployed for evil as easily as for good. (There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> who
argue that the ironic sensibility is morally preferable, because it makes you
aware of limitations, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would argue that what they really mean by
irony is the tragic vision of the world, not a particular trick of speech or
performance.) 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX> would have been horrified by the implication that he was better
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who failed to understand him, if only because that would have
made him so easy to skewer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on whose behalf <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gates</ENAMEX> is
pleading--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX>--would not be happy to know
that their particular slant on life expresses the universal human condition.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> gets a little closer to the heart of the matter when its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">editorialist</ENAMEX> writes, "Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, when hearing an ironic remark, may not
realize that it is meant in jest. ... those who realize that an ironic remark
has been made are instantly complicit, and they can enjoy the fact that there
are others who have missed the joke." In other words, irony is how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superior</ENAMEX>--presumably of class, certainly of intellect--get together and exclude
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>. It's funny, and it's fun, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, for one, couldn't live
without it. But it's neither virtuous nor defensible.

         
      
   
