
   
   
      
         
            The Old Old Things
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>:

            I am skeptical of historical analogies, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weimar Germany</ENAMEX> and
post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> never completed their "bourgeois revolutions" that led to
stability (look how well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> is doing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>). Nor is there an organized
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Russian Fascism</ENAMEX>" to step in and seize power. I do not think we can do anything
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, ghastly as is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> behavior. Whatever noises we make cannot
be backed up by effective actions, so that any rhetoric in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> may make us
look even more foolish. But this is not the place to deal with such complex
issues. Since I believe that "normal" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> politics is the politics of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">platitudes</ENAMEX> (and looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, perhaps we should not knock that), I am
going to pick up my theme of our democratic, domestic rhetoric and come back to
your turf, that of history, in a reverse manner. So ...

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> I mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Giddens</ENAMEX> as the house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>.
In thinking back, every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> in-house
intellectual. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur M. Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John P. Roche</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADA</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Caddell</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, who is sui
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generis</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> do not seem to have had any such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>,
perhaps because they distrust them. (But, then, who wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s flash
cards?)

            The function of the in-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> is to think up Big Ideas that are
to be imprinted into the historical period of the time (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Frontier</ENAMEX>, Great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>) or to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> or to combat other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger</ENAMEX> propagated the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> would have taken us out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> if he had lived. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Roche</ENAMEX> tried to pin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Caddell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fashioned Carter</ENAMEX>'s "malaise" speech, blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for the funk we were in
(recalling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brecht</ENAMEX> remark: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; the
government has to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>), and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>.

            The other week, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godfrey Hodgson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, wrote an essay in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian Weekly</ENAMEX> about an encounter in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> was rhapsodic
over dinner. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> do not understand, he complained, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
was creating a world society. The new politics, the new economics, the new
technology and the new immigration were coming together to change the tired old
rules of the game. There was more in the same poetic vein.

            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days ago</TIMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jim Lehrer NewsHour</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Brookhiser</ENAMEX>, who has
written a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Father</ENAMEX> , said that what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>
had done was to create "a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, 36 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lipset</ENAMEX> wrote a book about our founding called The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> . So new is obviously a tattered, tired old term. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nu</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nu</ENAMEX>.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two hundred years</TIMEX>. Is that a long time, historically speaking? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> I
became a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> on the New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> , then a large-format newspaper
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the paper was a quiet, courtly old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohn</ENAMEX>. He wrote the editorials; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Riesel</ENAMEX> and I wrote most of the paper. We
used pseudonyms to fill up the pages. I used <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Donne</ENAMEX>, until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>'s book
came out, and then shifted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Marvell</ENAMEX>.

            After we had put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> "to bed" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>, we would sit and
talk about history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bohn</ENAMEX> had been expelled as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX> because he was a socialist. He startled us
once by saying that his older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had fought in the American <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, and
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> had fought against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1815</TIMEX>! So that was three
degrees of separation. Your young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> will probably go to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2080</TIMEX> so for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 300 years</TIMEX>, that will be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six degrees</NUMEX> of separation.

            But history was always a living presence. I think of my late lamented friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Shub</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menshevik</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shub</ENAMEX>, who had set up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIAS</ENAMEX> (the
radio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, a major cold war
propaganda asset. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX> was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Witt Clinton High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'30s</NUMEX>, his history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> once remarked that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1917</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> had made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Revolution</ENAMEX> and was soon after overthrown by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX> shot up his hand and said: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> did not make the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
revolution. That had been made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cadets</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>) under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Lvov</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> did not come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, in the sealed train
across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> had refused to take a job in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>, but
did in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muliukov</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of war. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> reshuffle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. How do
you know all this, asked the startled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> told me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
replied. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> lived until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, and one could see him, as I did, walking
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> campus, where he was affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoover</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX>. History lives.)

            What impresses me, in fact, is that with all the blather about "the new,"
there is a hunger for history, and for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the old is more relevant
than the new. I was struck by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this a decade or so ago</TIMEX> when I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>,
then still under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> rule, where I had been invited to give a few
lectures to some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> institutes about technology. (At least the theory of
it.) After the sessions, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> eagerly escorted me around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and took
me to the towering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hradcany Castle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle</ENAMEX>, since he had once lived in
a small hovel in the wall underneath.) What they wanted to talk about was not
the future but the past, about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf II</ENAMEX>, who had ruled the Holy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Empire</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 16 th century</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,
before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>. And to show me the famous window of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defenestration of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>, the glorious day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1618</TIMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Thirty Years War</ENAMEX> when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> royal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> had been hurled from the window by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemian Diet</ENAMEX>--and being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>, had landed on a haystack below.

            And I think, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, where the bones of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazar</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> of the battle against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1389</TIMEX>, have become hallowed in
history and whose legends were written down by church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribes</ENAMEX> and canonized in
cycles of folk poetry. In commemoration of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">600 th</NUMEX> anniversary of
the great battle, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lazar</ENAMEX>'s bones were taken for a tour around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monastery</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> they lie in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ravinica</ENAMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>
the coffin is opened for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>, and his brown and withered hands peek
out from under the shroud. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Lenin</ENAMEX>'s embalmed body be around for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>?) I know that these are alleged bones, and emotional sentiments are
whipped up by the prayers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> and the nuns. But people
believe , or want to believe. That is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">icons</ENAMEX> have the power they
have.

            But since this will be the last round before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the century</TIMEX>, shall
we conclude with a discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>--but which one?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
