
   
   
      
         
            <i>Green <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mile</ENAMEX></i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">age</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Elvis</ENAMEX>,

            Regarding your ideas about other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> that The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> could
have explored: Yes, yours would be a better, braver, picture. The way pop
culture works, I think, is that the themes of small, cutting-edge pictures get
watered down over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> into large, cutting-board pictures, and we can see that
process happening here. I have no doubt that the film's portrait of race
relations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> is a fantasy (although no less a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fantasy</ENAMEX> than the sentimentalized view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lawrence</ENAMEX>
friendship in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Demme</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> ). Since all pictures are fantasies, some
more than most, I think it is useful to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">The Green Mile</ENAMEX> in terms
of what its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will see. Many of them will see not clichés and stereotypes
but an enormously good black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose fate they mourn. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uninformed</ENAMEX> and unsophisticated in terms of the actual conditions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> described to you, but that is the nature of a society's
memory.

            I had an interesting talk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Mayer</ENAMEX>, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking/Penguin</ENAMEX>, who has published just about everyone. I asked him
for the name of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> on his list. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>, he said. And then
he mused that he wouldn't call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in the same sense
but would call him a great storyteller in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> tradition (I am not using
quotation marks because I cannot claim to remember verbatim). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> is scorned
by those who do not read him, he said, but is underrated and sometimes very
good (he suggested I start with the short stories). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> recently, I went
to every bookstore I could find, and even in stores the size of a broom closet
in back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> (where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietors</ENAMEX> surely stocked no book they were not
certain they could sell), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-most-stocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. (The
most popular was Wodehouse!) These were book stalls catering to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>. I saw
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>. Why do they read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>? Because
they want to.

            No filmgoer attends a movie to "support" it. They choose a movie in the hope
that for a period of time they will be more entertained or interested or
happier than otherwise. Our job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> is to encourage them to choose films
that we think will be less a waste of their time than those they might choose
on their own. This is a relative and inexact process, but worth doing. If we do
not get up to our elbows in the real mix of real movies, real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, and
real motives for going to the movies, what function do we serve?

            In insular, media-obsessed, buzz-driven markets like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, I wonder
whether some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> on the make, don't position their
reviews primarily to position themselves. The real reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutionary</ENAMEX> was that she wrote for actual moviegoers like herself, and evoked
their needs and desires. No one who seriously believes Taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherry</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulysses' Gaze</ENAMEX> is a great movie believes that being able to enjoy a
movie is necessary to make that movie great. Oh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> of those movies
enjoy them, I suppose, but in a way so specialized and evolved that it has
nothing to do with moviegoing as it is generally understood.

            Many of the films on our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-best lists will play only in the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
I get e-mail from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moviegoers</ENAMEX> who complain that Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> Don't Cry , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mononoke</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Beauty
have not played in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topsy-Turvy</ENAMEX> certainly won't, and
probably not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnolia</ENAMEX> . Subtitled films and documentaries may not play in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Talbott</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker Films</ENAMEX> told me the average
subtitled film makes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> gross in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX> .

            Movies like The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> are progressive compared with the movies
most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> sees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most weekends</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> is an important and
worthy fact of popular culture--not sophisticated, not as hard-edged or
accurate or courageous as it could be, but more a part of the solution than a
part of the problem. Here is an obviously unprovable guess: For <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who see it, it will be the best movie they see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX>, even from
your point of view.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
