
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley Won't Go Soft</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' top non-local
story is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-commissioned report that holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> and leading member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>, primarily the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, responsible for failing to prevent or curtail the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> genocide of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX>. Everybody else stuffs the story. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead is the change of venue to upstate ordered in the trial of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
NYPD cops accused of murdering an unarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> talks, which
wrapped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on an encouraging note--an agreement to a new round in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in the new year</TIMEX> (possibly at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> safe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the talks, while the remaining
majors put them inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s first-ever lawsuit
against a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> for racial discrimination. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the newest trend among online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>--striking alliances with
traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. The latest example is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s deal between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> will provide a low-cost Internet-access service carrying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> brand, and will at its own site promote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, while
in return <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> will promote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. The paper ticks off the
spate of other similar arrangements struck recently--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best Buy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>,
Circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Shack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--and nutshells
the point: giving online concerns access to the still-huge number of offline
homes while jumpstarting the struggling Web presences of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , in its story on the trend,
coins a wonderful name for it: "bricks and clicks."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> depicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> report as striking in its institutional candor: Although
commissioned by the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-General</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>, the report
criticizes him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>, for failing to take
decisive action as the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> reported
back about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX>'s plans for ethnic attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tutsis</ENAMEX> and about
their accumulating weapons caches towards that end. The report also criticizes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX>--managed, points out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , by the world's
major powers and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>--for extracting most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> at the time when even more of them were most crucially needed.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the report's principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> said he got
scant help from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A U.S. State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> is quoted denying
this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s hotel suit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says, was announced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and
charges that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>-based but nationwide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> forced blacks
to pay more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> out of hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lounges</ENAMEX>. The paper quotes a source saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winston-Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> are among those
implicated.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts cover the joint appearance
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> at which they signed a pledge
stating that if they won their nominations, they would not accept their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>' soft money. But as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out, the agreement only goes
so far: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> supports public financing of congressional elections, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> does not. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> admitted at the pledge event that he had in the
past been influenced by donations, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said he had not.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> returns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to the place that made her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>. No, not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> carpet, but the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which covers her
testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at an evidentiary hearing for the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>
wiretapping trial. The point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s testimony was to try to establish
that one of her conversations was taped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> was warned that
doing so would be illegal, and also that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> became aware of this taping
from her own knowledge of what she had said and therefore her knowledge of it
was not dependent on an immunized source--what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> told her based
on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> told them--and hence is not inadmissible.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes inside with a new nationwide study of high-school disciplinary practices,
which, it says, shows that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two years</TIMEX> since "zero tolerance"
anti-violence policies were popularized, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> surveyed
have been expelled or suspended at a rate disproportionate to their numbers.
The story quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>'s reaction: that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-tolerance policies are
"arbitrary and capricious," resulting in wide racial disparities in discipline.
The only problem here, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't notice, is that mere
racial disproportionality shows nothing of the sort. You would need to show
that the racial breakouts of punishments are disproportionate, not to the
racial composition of the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, but to the racial composition of the
rule breakers .

            
               And strong letters to follow from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cinder Block Assn.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> contained this
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>' Note": "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Our Towns</ENAMEX> column on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5</TIMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>'
resistance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX>'s plan to add a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>, an ice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rink</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.8 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">14-acre</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX>. The column
commented that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX> 'is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Airstream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> where people
sit outside on cinder <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX>, whiling away the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> by taking aim with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> at upturned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buicks</ENAMEX>.' The reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Airstream</ENAMEX>, though jocular, was
unwarranted. The brand is a luxury recreational <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> often referred to as a
land <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX>. It should not have been associated with shabby surroundings."

         
      
   
