
   
   
      
         
            Is the <I><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX></I> Y2K-Compliant?

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> regrets its math,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of record reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on its front page. This is in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reefer</ENAMEX> to an amusing article confessing that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX> the issue number on the
upper left hand of the front page has been off by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>--a fact that was
discovered recently by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 year-old</TIMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Donovan</ENAMEX>. But the
mea culpa could just as
appropriately be applied to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s lead story by the
paper's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> prize-winning rewrite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert D. McFadden</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two thousand years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s
obscure birth in a dusty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Judea</ENAMEX>, the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> blah
blah blah ...

            

            Because 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are uncommonly sharp, they
will notice immediately that, quite apart from whether you accept <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>
as the turning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>--which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> does*--and quite
apart from whether you accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gregorian</ENAMEX> calendar's date for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s
birth--which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't,** but never mind-- it is not possible to add the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX>
to the number one and come up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> .

            This arithmetic error never would have happened had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Donovan</ENAMEX> edited
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFadden</ENAMEX>'s story.

            * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s rationale: Since,
retrospectively, we view <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1000</TIMEX> as marking the start of the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1900</TIMEX> as marking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of the last century</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of the new millennium and century</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">999-year</TIMEX> millennium
wasn't the stretch from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000 to 2000</TIMEX>, but from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year one to 1000</TIMEX>; and no one
who'd be affected by that is around anymore to complain.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">** Herod</ENAMEX>'s death is documented as
occurring in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>, which renders the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>'s birth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonsensical</ENAMEX>; either there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> was born at least
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years earlier</TIMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> calendar says.
            

         
      
   
