
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brush Up Your Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. <i>Please.</i>

            It was inevitable that--as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> would come to rival
Machiavelli as the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> in world literature
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> who want to lie, cheat, and scheme their way to the top. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers Grimm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. A. Milne</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Winnie the Pooh</ENAMEX> , dabble in
that line of work too, but their output is noncompetitive--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> book to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavelli's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s several each.) It is also fitting that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shakespeare in Charge: The Bard's Guide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading</ENAMEX> and
Succeeding on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Stage</ENAMEX> as a role model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal</ENAMEX>, as he is called, is widely acknowledged to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>'s most
Machiavellian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> as a jolly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX> who conquered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>--hurrah!--which is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurence Olivier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Branagh</ENAMEX> play
him in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> movie versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> . But read the play more closely
and you realize that the cheerfully successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> bears little resemblance to
the man <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> created. At best, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> was, as critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hazlitt</ENAMEX> wrote, "an amiable monster"--"that is, he was ready to
sacrifice his own life for the pleasure of destroying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of other
lives." At worst, he was a cold and cunning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> without a glimmer of
moral doubt, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> as happy to humiliate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, even execute them, as he
is to commit mass murder--all in the name of consolidating power.

            
               Just the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> should emulate! you may be thinking.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> agrees. The Shakespearean (as opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oliverian</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branaghian</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> embodies several telling bits of wisdom for he who would
develop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of a true-blue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Learn everything you can from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, but drop them the minute
they get in your way. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry IV</ENAMEX> , young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roustabout</ENAMEX> who
keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merry thieves</ENAMEX> led by the obese drunkard
Falstaff, who has been described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX> as the life force
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incarnate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falstaff</ENAMEX> teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal</ENAMEX> how to be a quick-witter punster and a master
of play; he also teaches him a commoner's skepticism of power and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pretensions</ENAMEX>. In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hal</ENAMEX> learns from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falstaff</ENAMEX> a street savvy that will make
him enormously popular later in life. As soon as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hal</ENAMEX> ascends to the throne,
however, he pretends not to know his old and embarrassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>:

            

               I know thee not, old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>: fall to thy prayers;
How ill white hairs become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jester</ENAMEX>!
I have long dream'd of such a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
So surfeit-swell'd, so old and so profane;
But, being awaked, I do despise my dream.

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Don't worry about whether you have a good reason to initiate a
hostile takeover; simply having the means to do so will suffice. Why does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> gather up an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and sail to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>? For no better reason than that he
suddenly came upon a way to pay for it. At the beginning of the play, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> offer to underwrite an invasion as a bribe to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">appropriating</ENAMEX> church lands. Upon receiving the proposal, he asks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s
bishops several times to give him a clear justification for the invasion, which
will necessarily entail the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> give him
long-winded answers that make no sense at all, at the end of which he asks
again, confused: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> I with right and conscience make this claim?" More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incomprehensible</ENAMEX> replies ensue. The scene ends without good reasons having ever
been offered, after which he goes ahead and invades anyway.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Threaten to loot, pillage, and rape the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> of your competitors
if they don't give up the fight as soon as you enter the field--and explain
that they have forced you to do so. Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s speech before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town of Harfleur</ENAMEX>, whose crime has been to hold out against a siege:

            

               What is't to me, when you yourselves are cause,
If your pure maidens fall into the hand
Of hot and forcing violation?
What rein can hold licentious wickedness
When down the hill he holds his fierce career?

            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. If a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> has committed a crime, however minor, make sure he
receives the maximum punishment in order to make an example of him. Just
before the great battle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agincourt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> is told that
Bardolph, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>, has been caught stealing a small statue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> from a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. For this act, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bardolph</ENAMEX> is to be hanged. Rather than
pardon the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> has him killed in order to show the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> that his
is an orderly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> that means them no real harm.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Take no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>. But if you do, kill them. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> hears at
Agincourt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have sent in reinforcements, he orders his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to
kill their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>--a terrifying act for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> facing the prospect of
imprisonment themselves. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> remarks: "'Tis expressly against the
law of arms: 'tis as arrant a piece of knavery, mark you now, as can be
offer't." Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> (who alludes to the incident only in passing) nor
history offers any justification for this gross violation of the laws of war:
"Was there, as it was later claimed, some sudden movement on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
cavalry which lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> to fear an attack from the rear? It is possible,
though no such attack took place," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Julius Norwich</ENAMEX> in his
forthcoming book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shakespeare's Kings: The Great Plays and the History of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1137-1485</TIMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norwich</ENAMEX>, who calls the command
"the darkest stain on [the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>'s] reputation," says that so many
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> refused to obey his order that "he was at last obligated to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">designate 200</ENAMEX> of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">archers</ENAMEX> specifically for the task."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Marry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> appropriate to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, and say anything you have
to to win her. In wooing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> he has just laid waste to, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, having never met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, calls
her an angel and claims to be in love with her. When, reasonably enough, she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objects</ENAMEX>, he subtly menaces her:

            

               No; it is not possible you should love the enemy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>: but, in loving me, you should love
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>; for I love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> so well that
I will not part with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> of it; I will have it
all mine: and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is mine and I am
yours, then yours is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and you are mine.

            

            To sum up, then: What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> really have to say to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> who
think that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> make good role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>--rather than, say, troubling,
interesting, morally questionable dramatizations of the effects of power?
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, what fools these mortals be!"

         
      
   
