
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DeParle Gets Half the Story</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jason DeParle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>'s radical welfare
reform are typically fair-minded and gripping. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> summing-up is no exception. But it also makes one
of the basic errors of welfare coverage, an error that might be called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leavers Fallacy</ENAMEX>.

            Specifically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeParle</ENAMEX> tends to judge the success of welfare reform by what
happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that were on welfare before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> reform
took effect, but who then left. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Jencks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Swingle</ENAMEX> point
out in the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Prospect</ENAMEX> , "[t]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hese families</ENAMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the story." The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> includes those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who would
have gone on welfare under the old system, but who now "no longer even apply
for welfare." These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">latter families</ENAMEX>, you'd think, would tend to be more
successful in the marketplace than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who now spend some time on the rolls.
To really judge welfare reform, then, you have to look at what happens to
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who would have been on welfare under the old system,
those who leave and those who never go on. Actually, you can't even stop there.
You have to look at what is happening to the overall society in which those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> live--at what's happening in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, to poor
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who might get welfare, but also to single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and non-poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who live in the same neighborhoods.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX>'s piece has good anecdotal reportage about specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who left
welfare for work and who still have big problems. From this he concludes that
welfare reform "may end up making less of a difference in the lives of the
poor, socially or economically, than much of the public imagined." But his
piece has very little evidence, and almost no statistical evidence, about what
has happened overall to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>'s poor, including those who "no longer even
apply for welfare"--the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the story.

            Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeParle</ENAMEX> points out that "a long list of things" remains present in the
lives of the poor, including "violent neighborhoods, absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, bare
cupboards, epidemics of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, the temptations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>." That's very
true. But are they getting better or worse? That is the issue, isn't it?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX> doesn't tell us. Are the neighborhoods more violent? Are fathers
taking more of an interest in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>? Are there fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> born
without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> present in the household? Are more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> being beaten up by
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>? Are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> doing better in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>? Is the culture of
drug-taking and drug-dealing becoming more or less entrenched? Are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> people
depressed? Hungry? Overall, how has the texture of ghetto life changed? Welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> said it would be change for the better. Were they right?

            Some of these things would not be difficult to report on; some would be very
difficult. That's why we give <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prizes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX> doesn't really seem to
try to come up with much. We learn a lot about the problems in the lives of the
handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> he has chosen as his case studies--but not only are they all
individual anecdotes, they are all "leavers," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were on welfare
before. The broader surveys <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX> offers are also all surveys of leavers. He
offers no economic surveys of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>--much less social
surveys of crime, marriage, and the like.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Jencks and Swingle article</ENAMEX> provides some of that necessary missing
information for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as a whole--as much as the existing statistics can
provide. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Prospect</ENAMEX> gives the piece a sleazily slanted
cover line (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Welfare Reform's Victims"</ENAMEX>), the article contains more positive
news than negative. "Employment among single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> has increased more than
almost anyone expected." Most single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are a little better off
economically, but a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> at the bottom "seem to be a little worse
off." The "rise of the single-parent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> may finally have been arrested,"
although this began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, so it's not clear that welfare reform can take the
credit. The most troubling statistic for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, the
proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> born out of wedlock doesn't seem to have improved
lately.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX>'s one stab at a general assessment of the social health of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>'s ghetto is rhetorically brilliant but ultimately unconvincing. He
tracks down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Love</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>, gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milwaukee Journal Sentinel</ENAMEX> an upbeat assessment of
the impact of reform on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> Sentinel clip got
passed around in pro-reform circles and wound up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> radio address.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeParle</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> is now "having doubts." Love is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>, and some of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>, who no longer receive guaranteed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> welfare checks, are
offering "excuses" for missing the rent. "So far, haven't seen a big
difference, one way or another," he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX>. It's a good shot at
welfare-reform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX>, but ultimately my suspicion is that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> may
be one of those kind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewees</ENAMEX> who winds up telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> what they want
to hear. (And aren't there other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> to talk to, like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>
whose pro-reform observations in the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> Sentinel piece
were actually stronger than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love's</ENAMEX>? What about local church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cops</ENAMEX>?)

            Some other beefs with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s piece:

            --Discussing one "leaver" survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeParle</ENAMEX> declares that "for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
the work has failed to translate into economic progress." These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, he
says, earn "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> less than they would have received by staying on welfare." But
he later admits this figure ignores "earned-income tax credits, which at these
levels typically total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $3,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>." Doesn't that mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are
actually <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,600</NUMEX> ahead? Isn't that the story?

            --DeParle refers to "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>'s growing homeless shelter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>," but
doesn't give any figures on how much it's growing. When I checked a couple of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the shelter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> had indeed increased, but only by a handful
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Is the problem now more severe? Are we talking about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeParle</ENAMEX>'s big concluding anecdote is the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Crawford</ENAMEX>, "a
39-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who went to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at a plastics <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>,
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> of desperation and chronic dependence on welfare." She's
still working, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeParle</ENAMEX> notes that even though "she earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $16,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," she "struggles to simply keep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on the table" to feed her
family. But wait a minute. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX> also notes that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>,
recently "found a job, as a hotel maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." Presumably he gets paid.
How much? And doesn't that money get added to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX> to help "feed her
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>"? Maybe it's not enough to make a big difference, but DeParle
doesn't even bother to tell us.

            Is there an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?

            
               
                  Coming soon
               
               : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kausfiles</ENAMEX>' 
               
                  Y2K
policy!
               
            

         
      
   
