
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cineastes</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Multiplexers</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Sarah</ENAMEX>,

            When I read a sentence about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> like "Wherever he goes, a treacly,
white-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> triumphalism seems to follow," I wonder what impulse causes you to
add the words "white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>" to the sentence. That's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part he can't help.
Would you write this sentence substituting "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>" or "black" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>"? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> embodies all he embodies. You don't like it, find another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>. To some degree every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> simply is what he is. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX>
ever put you in mind of treacly black-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> triumphalism? In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bone</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collector</ENAMEX> , for example? Or are both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in scripts you
don't like because as scripts they embody treacly triumphalism?

            But of course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>. Quite often I do, too. I think it is
important that as film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> we stay in touch with ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>--not to
reflect their values, because we must have our own, but to understand them.
Most of the ideological criticisms of The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> are by and for
sophisticated and subtle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>, writing for one another. The average
moviegoer with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> and a seat in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Abilene</ENAMEX> multiplex is likely to find himself
or herself subtly more complex, humane, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> after seeing that film than
before. It is reductive and stereotyped to a media cineaste, but perhaps the
best and most evolved movie that many of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX>.

            I agree with you, by the way, in feeling fed up to here with movies about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> being on the ropes. The most offensive example of that trend, of course,
was Fight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> , which I notice is very absent from most of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX>
best-film lists. Having recently returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>, where the extent of
the poverty was almost inconceivable to me, I now have even less sympathy for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathetic preppies</ENAMEX> who have to beat up each other to feel authentic. I am
thinking now of an e-mail from a twentysomething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiner</ENAMEX> who said that his
generation needed Fight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> because they have been denied a war like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> to test themselves in.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
