
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinematic Morals</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David,</ENAMEX>.

            As to whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX>, you and I, or anyone, should support a film
simply because it might do humanity some good, my argument is: All good films
do humanity some good, and no bad films do. So I will not give a movie a pass
because its heart is in the right place, and voted thumbs down on such as A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soldier's Story , Besieged</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Social Club</ENAMEX> (great
music, bad direction, terrible story sense, too much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ry Cooder</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jakob</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liar</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Other Sister</ENAMEX> .

            In writing approvingly about The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> , I was not endorsing it
for political reasons but for personal ones. Aware although I was of the
broadness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Coffey</ENAMEX> character, I genuinely liked the movie--found it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">absorbing</ENAMEX>, careful storytelling. Reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> indicate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>, by
and large, love it and are moved by it; it may emerge as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>'s biggest
hit.

            If I have "saddled myself with political responsibilities," it has not been
consciously, but I don't think that would be a bad thing for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> to do,
at least when a film makes it appropriate. My intense dislike for Very Bad
Things and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> reflected political or
moral outrage, among other things. And should have. Anyone who can find racism
in The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> but not fascism in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> is looking
through a very specialized filter.

            But I hope you don't believe I would praise or attack a movie I didn't
actually like/hate, just because of a political agenda. As for the "damn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar-Jar</ENAMEX> picture," that one is an excellent example of a film so quickly
dismissed by fast-draw gossip that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> (I am not including you) may
have been ashamed to say they liked it. It could have been the lost footage
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnificent Ambersons</ENAMEX> and if presented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX> in that
climate would have been shot down. It is always a little sad when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> tune
their strings with "Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> announced she was leaving the
times, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> headline said (quoting from memory) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liked</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hated Gummo</ENAMEX> ." As if, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'nuff</ENAMEX> said. My thought
was, So?
            

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jar-Jar</ENAMEX>, what was the matter with him? Didn't like his accent?
Thought his movements were too alien, or not alien enough? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aliens</ENAMEX> in movies are
routinely made understandable, likable, comprehensible. Or monsters. Can they
not also be goofy and very odd?

            Are the "common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>" capable of responding to works of complexity?
Sometimes. Depends on the work. But you cite Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX> as your examples, and I can only
observe that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> did disappointingly at the box office, the second only
fairly well, and while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> made piles of money, my own guess,
having attended a public screening, is that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> did not respond to it with
complexity but embraced its vulgarity while the irony whizzed right
overhead.

            Some of the reviews of that film were hilarious in the way they praised it
for accomplishments that had no remote connection, I suspect, to the way it was
seen, perceived, enjoyed, and understood by most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. They liked the
dirty jokes, the homophobia, and racism and the shit jokes, period. The
function of that material as liberating irony and reverse criticism, etc., was
limited to an elite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. I believe I was too hard on
the movie in my original review, and doubled back a little in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a later</TIMEX> TV
program on animation, but the notion that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience members</ENAMEX> picked up in
its complexities strikes me as optimistic.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> 's cheerfully blatant racism was praised as satirical
anti-racism by some of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who found racism in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mile</ENAMEX> , a film its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> intended to be anti-racist. My best guess is: A
large majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX> processed the racism on
its primary level and missed the irony, and a large majority of the audience
for The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Mile</ENAMEX> will see no racism, and if their attitudes are
influenced by the movie, it will make them less racist, not more. The critical
discussion of the racial content of those two movies has been too clever by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.

            Best,
R

         
      
   
