
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium's Most Intriguing People</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>,

            I suspect some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may be wondering what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
Lazar are doing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>. I can only assure them that, in our
family, the breakfast table really is like this. OK, not always. In fact, not
often. But sometimes.

            Your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1½-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> was sick and kept us up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half the night</TIMEX> (nothing
serious, luckily, and now he's tearing around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> like usual), so if this
were a real breakfast table, my conversation would not be rising very far above
occasional groans, grunts, and frantic gestures towards the coffee pot. This
being the case, I'm not sure how coherently I'll be able to respond to your
interesting thoughts about the living presence of history. But I'll try.

            So: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speaking of the Defenestration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> (how's that for a conversation
opener?), one of the funniest things about it is that one of the surviving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>--who fell on a dung-heap, not a haystack--was subsequently knighted,
and given the title <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freiherr von Hohenfall</ENAMEX>, which translates roughly as "Lord
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highjump</ENAMEX>."

            But more seriously, you suggest we talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>. What has
interested me, as a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s coverage of the
subject so far, has been how relatively little attention has been paid to the
history of the planet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1000 and 2000</TIMEX>. I expected far more in the way of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhibitions</ENAMEX>, TV shows, special editions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, polls commissioned on
"who were the most significant figures of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 1,000 years</TIMEX>," and so on,
particularly given the enormous interest in history that is demonstrated by
things like the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">History Channel</ENAMEX> (history as a living presence,
in the living room). All right, there were the special issues of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> . But not as much else as I would have thought.

            I suspect one reason is that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand years</TIMEX> is just too long a period of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. There is too much to consider. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second millennium</TIMEX> in
fact contains nearly everything we think of as "history," for even if we
arbitrarily define "history" as stopping in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, something like <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99.9 percent</NUMEX>
of all available historical source material dates from after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1000</TIMEX>. I
would bet that all the extant written material from all human civilizations for
everything before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.D. 1000</ENAMEX> could probably fit on a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DVD</ENAMEX> disk. It is
already possible to buy a single CD-ROM containing all the written material
available from classical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. This is the reason why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine series never really worked, and tended to veer off into
interesting digressions at best, and postmodern silliness at worst.

            The difficulty of even generalizing about such a long period is probably the
same reason we are seeing very few predictions about what life is going to be
like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 3000</TIMEX>. How can we even guess at such a thing? Making
predictions about the world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2100</TIMEX> is a very uncertain business, as you
stressed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, but it's fun, and you have at least a chance of being
right (and if some of your predictions involve the lengthening of the human
life span, and you hit the mark there, you may even still be around to see how
you did on the others). But the world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX>? Even most science fiction is
still set within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of centuries</TIMEX>.

            Another reason for the lack of attention, closer to my own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, is that
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> no longer have a simple story to tell about the history of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>--a single "meta-narrative," to use our jargon. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, and for the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> as well, the story
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> was the story of the Triumph of the West. If you had taken a
poll of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> about the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>,
I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> would have come at or close to the top, as an emblematic
figure of this triumph. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the picture is much more murky, the triumph
much more dubious. I suppose "political correctness" has some role in this loss
of focus. However, in my current grumpy and groggy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, I'm in absolutely no
mood to discuss political correctness. And anyway, more fundamental than
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correctness</ENAMEX> is surely the fact that the West has not exactly
distinguished itself in this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last century of the millennium</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was a child
of the West. So were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>. The horror of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> was a Western
horror. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> have a certain claim to being called honorary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westerners</ENAMEX>, given who their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were. And now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> is coming to an
end with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> army leveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grozny</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.

            Talk to you later,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
