
   
   
      
         
            Why "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paycheck Protection" Is</ENAMEX> Bunk

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has been saying that he doesn't support comprehensive
campaign reform without "paycheck protection." In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> debate earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  Here's my worry with your [campaign reform] plan: It's going to
hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> is really the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party and the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. And my worry is, is that you do nothing
about what's called "paycheck protection." We do nothing about saying to labor,
you can't take a laboring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s money and spend it in the way you see
fit.
               

            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> made clearer than, perhaps, he meant to, his primary concern about
political spending by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> isn't that it rips off union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>; it's that it
usually goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. But let's assume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had made a principled argument
rather than a partisan one: Is it wrong for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to spend union dues on
politics without first getting the consent of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Geoghegan</ENAMEX>, a labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Secret Lives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens</ENAMEX> , told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Of</ENAMEX>
course not. "What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't understand in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," he explained, is
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> exist for political action." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> can't get
benefits from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>, he said, they try to get them from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, for example, was "collectively bargained at the national level." The
irony, he pointed out, is that the vast majority of working <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, who
aren't dues-paying union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, get a free ride whenever labor gets a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> passed that expands government benefits for union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and non-members
alike. You might call it paycheck protection in reverse. (To read a

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geoghegan</ENAMEX> elaborating on this argument, click
here.)

            But what if a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> happens to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, and doesn't
like seeing his dues spent to help elect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> or to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>?
This question was raised in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Beck</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, who sued his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> because it was using his dues to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elect Hubert Humphrey</ENAMEX> (who lost, incidentally, even though labor was a much
bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics than it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
ruled that union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> could demand a refund when their dues were used for
political purposes against their wishes. But the decision didn't make it easy
in any practical sense for union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to get their money back, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Labor Relations Board</ENAMEX> dragged its heels for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> on the
matter. In practice, usually the only way a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> could really get his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX> to stop using his dues for political purposes was by quitting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>.

            Paycheck protection became a big conservative rallying cry after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
election, because labor's unexpectedly strong clout scared <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to
death. Now some form of paycheck protection has been adopted in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> (where it was later struck down
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ballot initiative on paycheck protection
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> failed, slowing the movement's momentum; no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> adopted paycheck
protection in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> has a paycheck-protection measure on the ballot
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            It's instructive to examine one reason why paycheck protection failed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> neutralized the business community by threatening to
sponsor a similar measure requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> ' permission before engaging in political activities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moreno</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> to the ballot initiative, explained to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Corn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> that "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gentleman</ENAMEX>'s agreement was worked out"
with the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to lie low. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX>, naturally, have tried
to argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> don't merit the same rights bestowed on
union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> by paycheck-protection measures. (Isn't it touching how
much more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> care about working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than they do about Wall
Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>?) Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Fund of the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's
editorial page making the case in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IntellectualCapital</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paycheck Protection</ENAMEX> argue that it is not balanced unless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> are also given the right to vote on whether or not a corporation
can make political expenditures. Once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has spoken
definitively on this. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First National Bank of Boston</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellotti</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> it noted: "The critical distinction here is that no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholder</ENAMEX> has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'compelled</ENAMEX>' to contribute anything. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholder</ENAMEX> invests in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> of
his own volition and is free to withdraw his investment at any time and for any
reason." In most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> can be required to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> or pay
union dues as a condition of employment.
               

            

            But the point isn't whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who own stocks live more comfortable and
independent lives than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>; clearly, they do. The point
is whether the same inconvenient principles of direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> that are used
to inhibit labor should be used to inhibit capital. Clearly, they should--if
not by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, then by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislative branch</ENAMEX>, which (rightly) has a
bit more leeway to decide how to achieve social justice.

            As it happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> says he supports both paycheck protection
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder</ENAMEX> protection." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Nehring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of national
campaigns for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>, a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that's pushing paycheck protection
very aggressively--and whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX>, has discussed the issue
extensively with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>--says what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s for isn't really paycheck
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nehring</ENAMEX> says it's mainly a codification of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
decision, and wouldn't put much more burden on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to prove they've got
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' permission to spend money on political causes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nickles</ENAMEX> attached to a campaign-finance bill a paycheck-protection amendment
that purported to require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to get members
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> to sign off on political spending. But corporations
enjoyed a huge loophole: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> had to do so only if they were
assessed special "dues or fees." (If the loophole hadn't been there, you can be
sure Fortune 500 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would have been out in force lobbying against it.)
The amendment failed, as did the overall bill; and when the bill came up for a
vote again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, no similar amendment was offered. This suggests that
paycheck protection will likely live on more as a rhetorical excuse for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of campaign reform than as an actual cause.

         
      
   
