
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Willennium Bug</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with a poll (of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">622</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>) purporting to show that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are unlikely to change their behavior or take special precautions
because of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>. But the story does add that most also believe in the likelihood
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more millennial terrorist attacks against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. The Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the cancellation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s
biggest private <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> celebration, which the paper takes as indicative
of a nationwide veer away from partying and toward cocooning on the big <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s recitation of failed events suggests a more down-to-earth
explanation: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Sedaka</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Wilson</ENAMEX> is stupid.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.7 percent</NUMEX> rise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> to a new all-time-high close, leaving that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tech</ENAMEX>-dominated market up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 84 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. The WP fronts the
financial whoopee. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> puts it on its business front (as does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ) and leads instead with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to take the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward prosecuting former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> in connection with recent allegations that he took, but did not at
the time report, contributions from an arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> and an oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>,
the paper reminds, started off the whole controversy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> by
acknowledging that while in power he kept secret bank accounts, but thus far
has refused to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. The WP fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
stuffs him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says no broad index of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stocks has ever risen as much
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a calendar year</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of its stocks are up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX>
percent since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qualcomm</ENAMEX>, is up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,444</NUMEX> percent
since then. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is so taken with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> that it waits until the
10th paragraph before noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> and other major indexes also set
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> gets right into the little summary
paragraph it runs at the top of its front-page financial news box.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-leads a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s decision to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> in
jail without bail pending his trial on charges of unauthorized handling of
secret nuclear weapons data. The other papers put the story inside, with all
the coverage explaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s reasoning: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> were out, he might be
able to transfer to a foreign power the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> highly sensitive data tapes he
admits making but that are currently missing. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> said however that if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> passes a polygraph test on the tapes, he could reapply for bail.) But none
of the stories mentions the real reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> wanted no bail: their
hope that the prospect of sitting in stir for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to several years</TIMEX> would make
the never-before-jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> break down and confess to the big hole in their
case: who he gave data to. By the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Lee</ENAMEX> story says that he is
prohibited from speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when they visit him in jail.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> would love to know what authority there is for this in the law,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason DeParle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> continues, in his usual off-lead space,
his tireless search for the failure of welfare reform. The dateline is the usual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>, home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> welfare-to-work
program. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s tack: Well, even if many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are getting off welfare
and on payrolls, their lives aren't "truly transformed." The story spends most
of its time playing out the examples of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who are supposed to
somehow stand proxy for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>. The story defends this
method with the remark that the notion that welfare reform is not "epochal ...
cannot be proved with charts and graphs." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> DeParle dwells on are
poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for irresponsibility as a lifestyle: At every turn there are
unexpected pregnancies, out of wedlock fatherless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and
abusive-cum-substance-abusive-cum-mooching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>. And yet the most obvious
takeaway from all this, from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> welfare-to-work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, is pushed
down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 4,000</NUMEX> words in and then glossed over quickly: "We're in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few years</TIMEX> of a new system after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> of welfare." (For more on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeParle</ENAMEX>'s piece, 
click here.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> effort--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">765</NUMEX> words explaining the meaning of the 20th
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>--is a textbook specimen of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>'s game. As if to prove he has
emerged utterly unscathed from his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doonesbury scathing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> manages
to shoehorn in quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frost</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Spender</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers is guessing somebody got the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anthology of Modern Poetry</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Balfour</ENAMEX>. But the real con is the lead, which is an
anecdote <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Kubizek</ENAMEX>, a childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>. There's
a long unattributed quote and an unsourced reference to a photograph. Now,
given all the express attribution in the piece, the effect here is one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s deep, deep knowledge: Who knew from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> Kubizek? But is there any
doubt that this anecdote and that photograph also come from a book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s
desk? So why not source them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
