
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp Makes</ENAMEX> Medical History
            

            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>? Let's get one thing straight: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> loves
big grosses, everything else is just a passing fling. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> doesn't have to
have a dip in the GDP to consider flaky presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. At what we
kept being told is the best of times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> are being
taken semi-seriously. What we flirted with during the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> was far worse.
And maybe our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX> should have
suggested taking the keys to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX> away from the apparatchiks before the
place was stripped bare.

            OK, I've tried. I've really tried to concentrate on this trivial stuff, but
the real news is--again!--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> does a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Craig</ENAMEX>
commercial, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> debated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> whether this was damaging to her
dignity. I beg to differ: Her dignity could be damaged only by doing
commercials for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that sells sinks. Then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> 's reporting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's reporting is
to be believed (and why not?), she joins the list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s life
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>) who've gotten cosmetic surgery long after
everyone knows what they look like. Timing, gals, is everything. This is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> medical history in which cosmetic surgery was reported
to have been caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Goodman</ENAMEX>. What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> both great and funny is
our stubborn belief in the redeemability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, which is the flip side of
our disdain for history. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> ever wants to be taken seriously ...," said
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mademoiselle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>. Let's start one premise
back: If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mademoiselle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> wants to be taken seriously
... No, wait: If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> wants to be taken seriously ... uh oh, I see where this
leads.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>

            
               Photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Table of</ENAMEX>
Contents by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Korotayev</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
