
   
   
      
         
            Y2OK

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with the
millennial coming, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the resignation (just after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> papers closed) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. The chronological milestone dominates
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts. The former runs a huge "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>" at
its top, while the latter goes for "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/1/00</NUMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead communicates the vast, unprecedented scope of the revel,
noting besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> bash attended by perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, an "around-the-world series of golden moments" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Americas</ENAMEX>. The overriding theme of the coverage is the
symbolic enthrallment of the planet from east to west and mercifully, the sheer
glitchlessness of it all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 billion</NUMEX> spent worldwide
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> seems to have done the trick, although it would be just as plausible to
wonder now if most of the spending was ever really necessary. The LAT
includes an "extra" front page that briefly notes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> bus ticketing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foul-ups</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> trial summonses gone awry but which declares above it
all in large pitch type "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millennial Mildness</ENAMEX>."

            So taken are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> with millennial matters and the other pressing
stories, that none makes room on their front for the news that all the major
indexes ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year/century/millennium</TIMEX> in nosebleed territory.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s surprise departure from the world scene leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> as acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and also the likely full-time successor
after the presidential elections that must take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within three months</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, said the new millennium required new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and
he appealed for forgiveness on his way out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> responded by signing an order
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> immunity from prosecution. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> that, according to the
coverage, saw <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> jointly shepherding
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> participated in a little
transition ceremony that centered on the handover of the suitcase that is used
to monitor a nuclear war.

            The other big story, which everybody fronts, is the peaceful resolution of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> hijacking crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> traded safe passage for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> militants and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> hijackers for the safety of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plane's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150 or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. It appears from the coverage that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>,
which controlled the overall situation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> sitting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, was
instrumental in forging the deal.

            There is some surprisingly wonderful stuff in the millennial coverage. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>'s celebration dryly mentions "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>"
getting "belted" twice in a minute by a reveler and then hit again by another.
Of course, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> speak this means the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> writing the story. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> biographical sketches solicited from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and many of
them fascinate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s favorite: "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> they were blacklisted; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> they worked for civil
rights and painted an <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">orange Day</ENAMEX>-Glo peace sign in our front window to
publicize their opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>. They embarrassed the hell out of
me, and I swore I would grow up to be normal. But what's written in one's DNA
cannot be denied. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years later</TIMEX>, I am a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> bisexual
priestess of eco-feminist witchcraft."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> takes the occasion to fess up to a mistake in the way the
paper has been counting its issues. Seems that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 1898</TIMEX>, the paper
has been giving itself credit for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> numbers more than it actually published.
The mistake, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> tells us, was discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. By a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> but, yes, with the help of a computer.

            The papers report inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Harrison</ENAMEX> will recover from his stab
wounds and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who inflicted them was charged with attempted murder
and scheduled for psychiatric evaluation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trivia Question</ENAMEX>: Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison</ENAMEX> alive but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> dead? Answer: because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, a wack job
can't get a handgun.

            There's no sign yet of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are going to call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> just
entered. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> favors "the noughties" or the "uh-ohs," but a letter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> proposes another idea that merits consideration:
"the e-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
