
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Et Tu</ENAMEX>, <I>TNR</I>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-orgy</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>-bashing in this space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> made kausfiles seem like
the organ of some irritable neoconservative rebelling against the dominance of
sentimental liberalism--someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilton Kramer</ENAMEX>, maybe, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Horowitz</ENAMEX>,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> disclosure: I used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Peretz</ENAMEX>, consider
him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and still eagerly read his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> . In
fact, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 27</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> just arrived ... wait a minute, what's
this? Can it be ... a really dumb liberal article in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that's supposed
to avoid reflexive anti-right politics, that sees itself as the puncturer of
leftish cant?

            I'm referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim VandeHei</ENAMEX>'s article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bottom of the Barrel"</ENAMEX> (overline: "Where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is
finding its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>."). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VandeHei</ENAMEX>'s thesis is that these are such "desperate
times" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> that they are sifting through the dregs, dragging
in "desperation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>" from the ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VandeHei</ENAMEX>'s evidence?
tried to recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff "Skunk" Baxter</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guitarist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doobie Brothers</ENAMEX>,
to run in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. He also talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Hemmings</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> surfing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Backlund</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro wrestler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble Willingham</ENAMEX>, a television
and movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, and others "from the lower rungs of the celebrity food
chain."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VandeHei</ENAMEX> is probably right to think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are in deep, deep
trouble in their fight to retain control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. But his piece doesn't do
anything to prove it. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VandeHei</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baxter</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemmings Davis</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX>," in fact they aren't running. (The districts
they were considering would be safely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> even in a better year for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.) More important, even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VandeHei</ENAMEX> eventually admits they wouldn't be
particularly unqualified: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baxter</ENAMEX>, he notes, is a "defense maven" who has
"written for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence Review</ENAMEX> " and "chairs a ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>
defense advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Weldon</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemmings</ENAMEX> is a former
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>. How are they the "bottom of the barrel"?

            It's pretty clear that we're supposed to laugh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>--well, because they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. It's not as if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have
never nominated minor TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cooter</ENAMEX>" Jones
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dukes of Hazzard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Congressional</ENAMEX>
District? And which party was it again whose local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> wanted to run <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
Springer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VandeHei</ENAMEX> gives the game away when he complains
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> is also trying to recruit such obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">low-lifes</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Putnam</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. Can you believe it? Running a
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>! That's really scraping the bottom!

            Why didn't any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> stop and think: Hold on. State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX>
have been running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> since the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>. That's
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX> come from! Because there's no payoff in being merciful to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. I've been at too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> lately with too many
respectable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who seem to think the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>" is
enough to bring any argument to a snorting, chuckling halt. Add to that the
press's non-ideological, but still unattractive, contempt for likely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>,
and you get an atmosphere in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> GOPs are fair game for cheap
shots.

            
               Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty</ENAMEX>: Please don't complain to your new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Beinart</ENAMEX>, about the amateurish
VandeHei piece. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beinart</ENAMEX>'s just started. And there'll be so many other important
things to talk to him about in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming months</TIMEX>!

         
      
   
