
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bradley Debates: Talk to the Hand</ENAMEX>

            In their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> televised debates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> both
showed substantial improvement since their previous
encounter in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has calmed down. While
still hyperactive, he seemed much less desperate and hysterical than in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> was much more keyed up. He's no longer practicing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> in the middle of a food fight.

            You got a sense of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has recalibrated his approach in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> events, a dull, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90-minute</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> special that kept <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX> up until after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 a.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> finally made
an effort to seize the offensive on health care, asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> repeatedly, "Who
would you leave out?" In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> just kept repeating his ineffectual and
inaccurate answer that his plan would leave no one out.

            But it was during the much feistier encounter on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet The Press</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>--the most contentious of the primary debates so far--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
finally came into his own. He performed a sort of political jujitsu I have
never really seen from him before, waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to charge at him, and then
turning the assault back on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attacker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> used this technique to
devastating effect, and he did so repeatedly through the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour-long</TIMEX> broadcast. 


            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s best moment came in response to a series of questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Russert about campaign finance reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> a compact: that
they both agree to a moratorium on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> ads and that they debate twice a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> for the rest of the campaign. In a long exchange, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> grabbed this
weapon out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s hand and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>-whipped him with it. Here are some
highlights:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : We
don't have to wait for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> to be picked. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, I'll make you
this offer right now. If you will agree, I will stop running all television and
radio commercials until this nomination is decided. That can get a lot of the
money out of the presidential campaign and accomplish one of the best reforms.
What about it?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: Sounds to me like you're
having trouble raising money.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: No, uh, as a matter of fact, I'm
not ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: I mean this is a
ridiculous proposal. You know, the way you communicate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is
when you talk to them. I love to talk to them in town meetings--that's my
favorite place. I've been doing that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. But I also love to talk to
them over television in their living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. ...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: [turning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX>] OK, here's
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of the proposal. ... Let's debate twice a week from now until
the nomination is decided and just go face-to-face about the issues and get rid
of all these television and radio commercials. Why not do that?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: You know something? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> that I was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> you ignored me. You pretended I didn't
exist. Suddenly I start to do better and you want to debate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. It's
ridiculous. We're having debates. ... The point is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, and I don't know if you
get this, but a political campaign is not just a performance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--which
is what this is--but it is rather a dialogue...

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> :
Look, we could call this the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet The Press</ENAMEX> agreement. We could have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> debates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single week</TIMEX> and get rid of all the television and radio
commercials. I'm willing to do it right now if you'll shake on it  [extends
hand].

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, that's good. I like that
hand [talks to the hand]. But the answer is noooo . I mean, why should I
agree now? I'm not interested in tactics, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Al.</ENAMEX> ... And that was a very
interesting ploy on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: Look, I'm ready to agree right
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: It was nothing but a ploy

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debates</ENAMEX> aren't ploys.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: That "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come</ENAMEX> here, shake my
hand"--that's nothing but a ploy.

            I've quoted this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> at length because I think it represents a pivotal
moment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaign. I'm not sure whether the effect fully comes
across in written form, but on television <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> look like a
complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ass</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks it was the
other way around; click here for
his take. For more on the debate, see "Pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> gave him an opening, by acting like a fast-talking used car
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> in a plaid blazer--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, I'll make you this offer right now." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
responded by snipping off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">huckster</ENAMEX>'s polyester necktie, saying in effect,
Do you have so little respect for me as to think I'd fall for something that
stupid ? While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> waited with his hand dangling in midair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
disdainfully critiqued and dismissed his whole approach to politics. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was equally effective in neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
assaults on other topics. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> what steps they
would consider to ensure long-term solvency for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>,
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> tried to rule out the option of raising the retirement age.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> then criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> for having voted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point to
consider raising it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> responded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had
itself discussed this option. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> responded that he hadn't ever discussed
it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: You didn't discuss it in all
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> forums out there?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: I certainly didn't.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: No one ever did, right? No one
ever did? Give me a break.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, I voted against raising the
retirement age.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>: Give me a break. But the point
is that at the same time you criticize me for wanting discussion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States Senate</ENAMEX> on the variety of possibilities--the exact thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> is talking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>--you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> are out doing the same thing.

            What made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s response on this point especially devastating was his
accompanying hand gesture, undoubtedly unconscious but perilously close to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> for "pull it a little harder." Throughout the entire debate,
grown-up compelled to contend with an obnoxious punk.  He would fight back if
necessary--but only after making clear that doing so was beneath him. What
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> showed, I think, is that he has found a way around the diabolical
box that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has tried to put him in. He has figured out a way to defend
himself without climbing into the mud-wrestling pit. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> rolled around
in the muck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> did no more than take off his jacket and roll up his
sleeves.

            At various points in the broadcast, you could hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> chuckling and
sighing while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was saying something he disagreed with. But these
expressions of contempt have nothing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
sneering gestures all seemed rehearsed and theatrical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, on the other
hand, came across as straightforward and real, his authenticity underscored by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s plasticity.

            In sum, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> may want to reconsider his request for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice-weekly</TIMEX> debates. A
few more like this morning's and he'll be kaput.

         
      
   
