
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Report Card</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> directed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Council on Environmental Quality</ENAMEX> to make a study of "probable changes in
the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, natural resources, and environment through the end of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>." The result, issued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, was Global <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> , remembered (perhaps a little
unfairly) as the definitive expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carteresque</ENAMEX> malaise about the future.
Copies of this report, which made a huge splash at the time and sold more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 million</NUMEX> copies, are amazingly hard to come by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>
library no longer has a complete set, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEQ</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>
it was inconceivable that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> report would be retrievable there. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, said its last copy
disappeared from the shelves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Moore</ENAMEX>, an
anti-doomsaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libertarian Cato Institute</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months earlier</TIMEX> a research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> he'd asked to find a copy came
back empty-handed. Internet searches turned up no used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area where you could buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> .

            Eventually, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was able to procure a copy of the summary
volume that was reissued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Locks Press</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> then
conferred with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Bailey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the anti-doomsaying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX> Report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>: Revisiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">True State</ENAMEX> of the
Planet , which was funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Competitive Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEI</ENAMEX> can all be fairly described as having an
ideological animus against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fretful</ENAMEX> liberalism of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Global</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> , but then much the same can be
said of the liberal establishment's attitude toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEI</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> didn't always buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX>'s analyses, he
guessed--correctly, it turned out--that they'd prove quite knowledgeable and
rigorous on the facts. (Besides, nobody seemed to be around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at the World
Bank.)

            The general outlook projected in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Global</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> is neatly summarized at the
beginning:

            
               If present trends continue, the
world in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> will be more crowded, more polluted, less  stable ecologically,
and more vulnerable to disruption than the world we live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> [i.e.,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>] . Serious stresses involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, resources, and environment are clearly visible ahead. Despite
greater material output, the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be poorer in many ways than
they are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
            

            
               For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of the
desperately poor, the outlook for food and other necessities of life will be no
better. For many it will be worse. Barring revolutionary advances in
technology, life for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on earth will be more precarious in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> than
it is now--unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the world act decisively to alter current
trends.
            

            Not exactly an invitation to break out the party hats on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX>. How
close to the truth is it?

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.)  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Population</ENAMEX>. 
               Global <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> predicts that the world
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> will grow from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.35 billion</NUMEX> (according to
"medium-growth projections") in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  Comment:
               
The world population hit <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past autumn</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> pointed out that this means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global 2000</ENAMEX> is off by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 6 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> attributed the error to an
overestimation of the total world fertility rate, which (his book documents)
has nearly halved since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global 2000</ENAMEX> got this one pretty close to
correct, however, and believes that, with the least developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> seeing
very little decline in total fertility rate since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>, world
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> remains worth worrying about.

            
               
                  Grade:
               

               Correct.
            

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.)  Food shortages. 
               Global <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> says the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, adjusted
for inflation, will double <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1975 and 2000</TIMEX>. Despite huge projected
increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> production, per capita <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> consumption in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, and the less-developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> "will scarcely improve or
will actually decline below present inadequate levels. "

            
               
                  Comment
               
               
: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> both said
this isn't true. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s now exporting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> pointed out. "As is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> added. Overall, world food prices have
"more than halved" since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> said. According to an index of food
prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX>'s book, food prices in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> were up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, but
down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">113 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>. Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> says, world food prices are "back
below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990</TIMEX> price."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> said the total number of calories
consumed is "substantially up" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, but he
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">admitted Africa</ENAMEX> remains "a basket case."

            
               
                  Grade:
               

               Mostly Incorrect.
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.) Energy.  According to
Global <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1975-2000</TIMEX>, "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s remaining petroleum resources  per capita can be expected to decline by
at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>." The price of energy will rise <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 150 percent</NUMEX>,
factoring out inflation, during this same period.

                   
               
                  Comment:
                Everybody agreed this is wrong.
Although the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> has spiked lately, last time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> checked it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per barrel, which (factoring out inflation
and taxes) was less than it was in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> (when oil prices were lower
than they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Global</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> 's
benchmark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year of 1975</TIMEX>).

                   
               
                  Grade:
                
               Incorrect.
            

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.)  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deforestation</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1975</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the Third World will lose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of its remaining forest
cover.

            
               
                  Comment:
               
Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> claimed to know much about this, but
both cited an essay in an earlier edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> 's book that said tropical
deforestation rates were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 8 percent</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. Assuming the same
rate of tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deforestation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global 2000</ENAMEX> would be off by a factor of at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> continues to
worry that the rainforest is disappearing, but agrees the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> figure is
probably too high.

            
               
                  Grade:
               

               Incorrect.
            

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.)  Climate change. Global warming
will alter the world's climate "significantly" by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2050</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  Comment
               
               
: Obviously nobody knows, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> both grudgingly admitted that the
evidence for global warming has grown since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  Grade:
               

               Essentially correct.
            

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.)  Growing income disparities between
wealthy and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. GNP is projected to increase everywhere,
especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> will average <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $11,000</NUMEX> in per-capita
GNP (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1975 dollars</NUMEX>), while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, will all remain
below <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> in per-capita GNP (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1975 dollars</NUMEX>). Overall, the per-capita GNP gap
between industrialized and Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> will grow from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> to
"<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $7,900</NUMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. 
            

            
               
                  Comment:
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> agreed this all sounded about right.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s
attention to a chart that seemed to support this in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> report called
Entering
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st Century</TIMEX> (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> in the introduction, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions in Development Thinking</ENAMEX>").
                  

                  
               
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Grade: Correct.</ENAMEX> 
               
            

            Granting that
the above sampling is hardly scientific, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes that
Global 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> 's pessimism is overstated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 50 percent</NUMEX> of
the time, and justified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 50 percent</NUMEX> of the time. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> right, which is about par for the course when it
comes to predicting the future (to test this proposition, flip a coin several
times). Another, perhaps less parochial, way to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global 2000</ENAMEX> is
to observe that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> is proving to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX> as disastrous
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> predicted it would be. This is either good news or bad news,
depending on your temperament.

         
      
   
