
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> to Judgment

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the early returns from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s parliamentary
elections, surprising because they show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist</ENAMEX> and reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>,
including a brand-new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, have made gains that
significantly cut into the power long wielded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> election at the top of
its world-wide news box. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> puts it deep inside, leading instead with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s search for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> accomplices of an alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX>
terrorist caught on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> trying to cross into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bomb</ENAMEX>-kit in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. The story describes a federal law enforcement
establishment both practicing and urging heightened anti-terrorist awareness
heading into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>, a topic that is fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , reefered
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and carried inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say high up that the election results
figure to be a boost to the presidential ambitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> doesn't mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">17th</NUMEX> paragraph. Everybody
agrees that the election is something of a referendum on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin-Putin</ENAMEX>
aggressive stance against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> that strongly support it
did best. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reminds of the volatility of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> politics when it
points out that all this comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was nearly impeached
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> for starting a war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front the death toll in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>
from flooding and mudslides. The high estimate: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> killed and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> left
homeless.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front the biggest news from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s televised joint appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to agree to stop all television and radio
commercials and debate regularly instead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> down, refusing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shake Gore</ENAMEX>'s extended hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say, calling the idea "ridiculous." (The
debate was also covered in 
                  Slate
               's "Pundit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Ballot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>.")

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section front points to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX>-related panic point few
have discussed before now: a possible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX>-driven gas
crunch that could, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s words, "make lines at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> machines and
supermarket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">checkouts</ENAMEX> seem tame by comparison." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> can stock up on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
food, batteries, and cash over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, the story notes, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cannot
store gasoline except in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, which means any rush to pump will take
place mostly on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30th and 31st</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside serves up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dispatches from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> front: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has ruled that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> budget--that's right the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 88</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>, a budget spent almost entirely on combating a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that no longer
exists--should remain secret; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon Mobil</ENAMEX> says that for the
recent merger that created his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> required the
production of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 31.2 million</NUMEX> pieces of paper.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> business section cites a fact that puts much Internet hype
into perspective while powerfully explaining the rationale of the recent spate
of "clicks and mortar" business deals: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> is expected to report nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$143 billion</NUMEX> in domestic revenue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 1999</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 7 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> retail market and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times all Internet sales combined.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> now own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> debt. This is double the percentage, says the paper, of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>.
The reason: the flight of capital from slumping economies like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s combined
with the drawdown of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> debt. The USAT front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snapshot</ENAMEX>"
presents a simple comparison between the cost of the federal debt per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX> and now:<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,800</NUMEX>. Interesting, but a little too simple: It's not
(apparently) adjusted for inflation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> weighs in with its story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>
fiasco. The piece, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>, will fill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> pages, complete with sidebars and graphics. In the
preparation of the piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> had his own computer account that was not
accessible by even senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at the paper. And when the
piece was completed, the negatives of it, ordinarily faxed to the printing
plant several blocks away in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, were hand-carried there instead.
The result of all this security is that even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Parks</ENAMEX>
will have to wait for the thud in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driveway</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> before he can read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">opus de</ENAMEX> oops. (It will become available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s web site as of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m. PT</TIMEX>.) Hmmm...wasn't this whole imbroglio about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s tendency to keep
too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> in the dark?

         
      
   
