
   
   
      
         
            Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley-McCain Handshake</ENAMEX>

             At their joint
appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Claremont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> seemed to be
saying much the same thing about campaign finance reform. Both see the present
system as murderous to democracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> said at the event what he has often
said before: that reform is required in order to "give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> back to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, using somewhat stronger language,
described big money a "plague," an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> "eating away at the core of our
democracy" and as "a great stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> that comes between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>." As the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> also explained in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> forum
taped before their "handshake," they both support an outright ban on soft
money--the huge, unregulated contributions funneled into the general election
by way of the political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> don't fully agree about campaign finance reform. Some
of their differences are subtle ones grounded in their respective political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orientations</ENAMEX>. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> thinks that special-interest
money works primarily to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from passing useful new laws,
like health-care reform and regulation of handguns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
thinks that special-interest money causes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to waste money on
unnecessary programs and prevents it from cutting ones it should get rid
of.

            Other distinctions visible <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> point up temperamental differences between
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, who is more of a risk-taker, feels so strongly about soft
money that he has promised not to accept it should he become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> no
matter what his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> does. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, more cautious by nature, has
declined to take a pledge of unilateral disarmament. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is also more
categorical about his moral indictment, saying at the press conference
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s event that special-interest money corrupts everyone in
politics, himself included. Money, he said, buys access, and "access is
influence." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, by contrast, said no decision he had ever made was
influenced by money, merely that he resented the suspicion--the appearance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impropriety</ENAMEX>--that is unavoidable under the present system.

            But when it comes to what sort of reform is necessary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
actually have big disagreements that they didn't illuminate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Basically it
comes down to this: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s idea of campaign finance reform is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> . He wants to eliminate the role of private money from
politics once and for all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s approach, on the other hand, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incremental</ENAMEX> . He will be satisfied with reducing the role and power of
special-interest money in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> believes that the entire system of financing campaigns needs to be
overhauled. To do this, he thinks, will require not only banning soft money and
providing free TV air time to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, but also full public financing of
congressional elections and a constitutional amendment to overturn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vs. Valeo</ENAMEX> , the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision that defines spending as speech.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Claremont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> employed the metaphor he also uses in his book: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX> in
politics is similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>," he writes. "Just when you
think you've got them blocked, they find another way to get in. Only
hermetically sealing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> off will work." We need to amend the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> and provide full public financing, he writes, because "anything
less means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> can still be corrupted."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> agrees with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> about how harmful special-interest money is. But
his own solution is much more modest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> doesn't think it will be possible
to eliminate the influence of private money from politics, or that doing so
would even be desirable. He wants to stamp out the most pernicious abuses--the
enormous contributions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
And he hopes to level the playing field for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> by
providing free airtime for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> does not favor public
financing for congressional campaigns and doesn't think it's necessary to amend
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> to get meaningful reform.

            I'd give a lot of credit to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> for trying to explain
this complex problem and make it into a major issue in the campaign. But I
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s less ambitious, piecemeal approach makes much more sense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Bradley</ENAMEX>'s comprehensive one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s desire to solve the problem once
and for all is understandable, but his approach is dangerous. Amending the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> should always be a last resort. And in this case, the alternatives
haven't been exhausted. It's not clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valeo</ENAMEX> prevents
genuine reform--or that even if it does, the corruption of the current system
is severe enough to warrant tinkering with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>. And in practical
terms, what's the point of even discussing a constitutional amendment--which
requires a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> vote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> as well as ratification by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--if you don't have a majority to pass a simple bill?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s sweeping proposals also cut against the nature and history of the
problem. Political reform in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has never taken the form of systemic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reengineering</ENAMEX>. Instead, it has always been a frustrating but productive
process, one in which rising expectations and public outrage lead to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ameliorative</ENAMEX> legislation and higher ethical standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> ought to
understand this, not only because he's well-versed in the history of political
reform--there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> on the subject in his book--but because the challenge
of campaign finance reform is so similar to that of tax reform, which was his
own greatest legislative accomplishment as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>. Passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, tax
reform was undone over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following decade</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Watergate</ENAMEX>
campaign finance reforms were unmade in a very similar way--smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> opened loopholes. The loopholes expanded, and eventually got to the
point where a fresh set of reforms was needed. Just like campaign finance
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
