
   
   
      
         
            Does Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Plan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cover Gnashed Teeth</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear David</ENAMEX>,

            At the end of this series, and of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>. It can
either be prosaic or dramatic. If it is just the spasm of sex or the
drunkenness of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>, and then the drab <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after, there is no meaning to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>. But what if ...

            Y2K is the perfect metaphor for one outcome. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>, the
whir of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>, the lights in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> go out, because we have
reached the limits of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> zeroes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 and 0</NUMEX> and then chaos. The computers flop.
All the stock options lapse. We all become cavemen and cavewomen, and the
Hobbesian world erupts in all its grim fury. All the world is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, with
the leer of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> hovering overhead.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> is itself mundane. It probably will not happen. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> zeroes will
emerge, and the computers will go whirring on endlessly. But what if beyond the
Y2K come the real portents of drama?

            The curtain rises. We call it eschatology --the transforming moment,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of days</TIMEX>. That has been one of the most enduring and powerful themes in
Western history.

            We see it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the frightening pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Revelation</ENAMEX>, the last
pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Testament</ENAMEX>. The trumpets sound. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> seals are broken. The
beasts come up from the seas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Four</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Horsemen of the Apocalypse</ENAMEX> begin their
grim ride, the last being the pale <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and pale rider, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX>, with a mantle
dyed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. And behind it the word of God. (As the fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">thundered: In the fiery furnaces of Hell</ENAMEX>, there is wailing and gnashing of
teeth. But I don't have any teeth, cried an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Teeth will be provided,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> answered.) And, then, a new heaven and a new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. The new
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> comes down from heaven.

            Revelation subsided for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>. But then in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cistercian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiore</ENAMEX>, developed a powerful and
original theology (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> books, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expositio</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Apocalypsim</ENAMEX> ),
which put eschatology into history . (As the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernst Bloch</ENAMEX> said:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to set a date for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of God, for the communist
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kingdom</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX> prophesized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three ages</TIMEX>--the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>, the age of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX>, and the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spirit</ENAMEX>, a new age of spirituality in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> hierarchy would be abolished and the infidels brought back into the
fold--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> and the lambs, so to speak, lying down together in peace. (How
do you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> and the lambs in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> once
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikita Khrushchev</ENAMEX> in wonder at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>. By changing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, la <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">femme</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikita</ENAMEX> replied.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX> was adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spiritual Franciscans</ENAMEX>
as their prophet, but few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franciscans</ENAMEX> with their
begging bowls, unless it is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> market. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joachim</ENAMEX> did have an echo
in poetry, since his prophecies inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeats</ENAMEX>' "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Second Coming</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poetry</ENAMEX> also came into eschatology in the movies, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> found a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liking for Blake</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton</ENAMEX> in the spirited lines: "Bring me my bow of
burning gold/ <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bring me my Arrows of Desire</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bring me my Spear</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> clouds
unfold!/ Bring me my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chariot</ENAMEX> of fire!" And ending, of course, that he will not
cease from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Fight</ENAMEX> until "we have built <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s green and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pleasant Land</ENAMEX>."

            In the bowels of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX> was creating a
new political eschatology, the "leap," as he said, from "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom of</ENAMEX>
Necessity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>." The drama is spelled out in that
lumbering bible, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Das Kapital</ENAMEX> , where in the deepening crises of
capitalism, and the sharpening knives of the class struggle, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of days</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrives</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> put it in the penultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of Volume I, when the
capitalist "integument" bursts asunder, and the new society, nurtured in the
womb of the old, steps forth as social labor, cooperative labor, communal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harmony</ENAMEX> (the transit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>) in a mutual embrace.

            All this was given concrete historical reality in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1917</TIMEX> with the holy
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Russian Revolution</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln Steffens</ENAMEX> came
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and marveled: I have seen the future, and it works. It was
a phrase repeated over and over by esteemed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.G. Wells</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice Webb</ENAMEX>, until in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, the mantra stopped. And amid the
detritus, one could find a scrawled phrase by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in an earlier novel
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Littel</ENAMEX>, Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> improbably named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robespierre</ENAMEX>
Pravdin: I have seen the future, and it needs work.

            So, off we go, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heigh ho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heigh ho</ENAMEX>, as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> cartoon, singing the
words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>: the new politics, the new economics,
the new technology (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nu</ENAMEX>, nu), all insured by comprehensive health
insurance with prescription drugs, spectacles, and false teeth for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> (as
promised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nye Bevan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, when he set up the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> comprehensive
health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>).

            But, hey, where is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>? Oh. That. That was the spasm of sex and
the drunkenness of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>. That was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before. And this is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
after.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dad</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
