
   
   
      
         
            Proust, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts, and Snow Days</ENAMEX>
            

            Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>

            A snow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>? It was a beautiful thing if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, as I did: They canceled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> if there was too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> on the
ground, leaving you a day to sled, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink cocoa</ENAMEX>, or profiteer by shoveling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">driveways</ENAMEX>. I imagine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> there weren't too many snow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, or
there wouldn't be any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at all. But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that are snow-prone, but not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snow-drenched</ENAMEX>, they were a lovely treat. Anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> made me a little
misty-eyed for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>calamity like that. But I should have left that a private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reverie</ENAMEX>.

            I totally agree re <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>. I especially loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> on the sheer walls
of the famed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera House</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> woke up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 a.m.</TIMEX> and we happened to catch it
live on that dreaded "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> TV." It was great.

            I'm trying to read between the lines of your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. You hated 'em,
but you also seem wistful for the pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Who knows? Maybe you'd like it
now without the squeegee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>-Zone: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant</ENAMEX>. (Somehow, I
think not.)

            Maybe it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 miles</NUMEX> distance, but am I wrong not to be too incensed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">scandal?</ENAMEX>" Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> 
               Times shouldn't
have split revenues with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> do a lot with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>
all the time. In the magazine world, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> are given heads-up about
upcoming issues and allowed to place ads in those issues. That, I realize, is a
far cry from what happened with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , but it's telling about the
intimacy between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>.

            I actually find the listing of names a perfectly fine gimmick. When I wrote
for small, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, one of the tricks of the trade was to get as many
local names into a story as possible. You could argue that this was shameless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pandering</ENAMEX>--I bristled at it at the time--but with some distance I can see the
merits: It gave a thrill for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who, unlike us, don't see their names in
print. Where's the harm? I admit, though, the misspelling thing is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hysterical</ENAMEX>.

            You handling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> thing OK? I have to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> thing is
making me wistful, too. (Maybe that's what triggered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proustian</ENAMEX> snow days
reaction?) Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> was always a lot darker than most people
thought--and the richer for it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanuts</ENAMEX>, with its neurosis, unrequited love,
and melancholy was newsprint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>. Funny and sad, too. Like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>,
I haven't read it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. It was one of those things, though,
you'd assumed would be there the way you assumed that, well, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>"
was the future.

            See you.
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
