
   
   
      
         
            Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Trading</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the heightening of security measures in the wake of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s arrest of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> trying to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> with the makings of
several large bombs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> off-leads anti-terrorism and goes instead with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s tech-led stock surge--apparently off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s decision not to
raise interest rates for now, a development the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts at the top of its front-page
business and finance news box. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's headline <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> a stunner: "NASDAQ
UP <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PERCENT FOR YEAR</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> stuffs the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">financials</ENAMEX> but leads with the likelihood that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications</ENAMEX>
Commission will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> to become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bell</ENAMEX> to enter the
long-distance market. This would mean, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , that for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> break-up, phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> will be
able to get local and long-distance phone service from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The
paper views this as auguring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s approval of long-distance provision by
the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> as well. Upshot: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">L</ENAMEX>-D <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX>
will have powerful new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> who already have service relationships with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tens</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead emphasizes the anti-terror moves being made by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead limns the
intensifying concern occurring across the full spectrum of the federal
government, reporting, for instance, on an anti-terrorism meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX>. Both stories note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> has just reassigned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 300</NUMEX> extra
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to remote spots along the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> borders.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead also promotes the significance of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> border arrest, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>, of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> trying to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> did not have
adequate identification, and later a false <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> passport was found in his
jacket. And, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-sniffing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> were called in
to go over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--one for detecting plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>, the other black
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">powder</ENAMEX>--they each alerted to the same portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, suggesting the
residue of explosives there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> its lead to this arrest,
and headlines it "2ND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALGERIAN ARRESTED ON U.S. BORDER</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead
saves the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> arrest until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few paragraphs</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a
story about it inside.)

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top-fronter reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have
established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> that channel large contributions to several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
campaigns in a way that circumvents limits on contributions to individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The so-called victory funds are, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , being used for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> races in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say the funds are "probably
legal" because, despite being incorporated and administered by national party
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, they create only an informal tie between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> or the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> on the one hand and the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> on the other
(whereas a formal tie would be illegal, given the amounts involved). And yes,
the paper explains, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>--to the
tune of "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gripe</ENAMEX>: Although the story makes it
clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have established victory funds as well, the headline
only mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story cites unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to sketch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s post-presidential plans: living half-time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, where he will
oversee a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arkansas</ENAMEX>, a public policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>, and a public-sector fellowship program for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. In
addition, says the story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> intends to earn large sums of money making
speeches at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $125,000</NUMEX> a pop.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cuomo</ENAMEX>'s announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will take
direct control of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX> earmarked for services for the homeless in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> cannot be trusted to
distribute them fairly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> responded, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, by accusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo</ENAMEX> of playing politics with the homeless programs and, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
by noting political ties between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hizzonner</ENAMEX>'s likely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's money front report
that a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall St.</ENAMEX> investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> was indicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> on charges
that he provided illegal tips about pending bank <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mergers</ENAMEX> to his still-at-large
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mistress</ENAMEX>, described variously as a stripper, an adult-film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>.
The story also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's front-page business and financial news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">box</ENAMEX>, although in the summary there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is spared any reference to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that newly declassified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> testimony shows that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX> that she thought federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> into the
possible theft of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear technology by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> had focused prematurely on
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, which has run many
front-page stories in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> did indeed steal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
nuclear secrets, often detailing suspicious behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, puts this one
inside. Incidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Scheer</ENAMEX> noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has yet to write about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
critique of the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> document making the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            A front-page WSJ story documents something pretty interesting about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> on military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>: Although their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student bodies</ENAMEX> are more racially
diverse and poorer than those in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society</ENAMEX>, their test scores are very
good. In fact, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">base schools</ENAMEX>' scores in the national <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>-grade
writing exam were No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And the rate of matriculation is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
percent, compared to the national rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 percent</NUMEX>. One hidden variable the
story suggests is partially responsible: The military commands tend to support
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in disciplinary wrangles with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes you wonder about the quality of thought behind many of
those anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> lawsuits that came tumbling forth right after the
antitrust trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s finding of facts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that one hastily filed
suit says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is a generic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> and another says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
principal location is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
