
   
   
      
         
            No Relation No. 7
            

            In the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7 th</NUMEX> installment of the ongoing No Relation series--which
sorts out newsmakers with confusingly similar names--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> takes on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gessens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glennys</ENAMEX>, as well as the many variations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaczynskis</ENAMEX>:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masha Gessen</ENAMEX> is the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itogi</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
affiliate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . Her reports on the turmoil in post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> have appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science</ENAMEX>
Monitor , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>), and

                  Slate
                (click here to read her assessment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> and here for one of her
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches from Hell"</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s extreme north). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, she authored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>
Again: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Russian Intelligentsia After Communism and edited Half a</ENAMEX>
Revolution , a collection of contemporary stories by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gessen</ENAMEX> has filed occasional reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, which is
where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misha Glenny</ENAMEX> gained notoriety. Glenny was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Europe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> before and during the wars in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Croatia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herzegovina</ENAMEX>. His
long-term perspective on the region landed him frequently on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>, as well as in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX> . After
writing a book on the roots of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> wars, he is now working as an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> book--a history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Balkan</ENAMEX> nationalism--will
be published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Glenny</ENAMEX> , is
well-known for his translations of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> works. Most of his
translations--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel--are of literature,
but he also translated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s autobiography, Against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Grain</ENAMEX> .

            The name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kaczynski</ENAMEX> is, of course, most closely associated with the
Unabomber, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX> , who is serving a life term in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaczynski</ENAMEX> is appealing his sentence, maintaining his confession was not
voluntary--a claim that will be heard by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Circuit Court of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kozinski</ENAMEX>, who has also
participated in 
                  Slate
               's "Breakfast
Table ." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurist</ENAMEX> should not be confused with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>
Kuczynski , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, formerly of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Observer</ENAMEX> . She ruffled feathers most recently with her unflattering
assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s Talk , charging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> with selling out
to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miramax</ENAMEX> films.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryszard Kapuscinski</ENAMEX> , too, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. But he is best-known for
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> book, The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Soccer War</ENAMEX> , which chronicles the horrors he witnessed
covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> revolutions and coups for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polish Press Agency</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1958</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerzy Kosinski</ENAMEX> , another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, won wide praise for
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Painted Bird</ENAMEX> , a fictionalized version of his experiences as a child
during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> (he was separated from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and traveled alone
through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to escape the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX>). He is also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of
Chance , which won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Book Award</ENAMEX>, and Being There , which
was turned into a movie starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Sellers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley MacLaine</ENAMEX>. He
committed suicide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.

            
               Previously in this series, the
Explainer tackled the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cohens</ENAMEX>
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephens</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richards</ENAMEX>), the

               Rays 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeths</ENAMEX>), the 
               Hirschfelds
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>), the 
               Strausses
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert and R. Peter</ENAMEX>), the 
               Broders
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>), and the Moores
               

               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michaels</ENAMEX>).
            

            Have you noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the news with confusingly similar names? Send
your suggestions to Explainer
               .
            

         
      
   
