
   
   
      
         
            Matchbook-Cover Issues Primer

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">BORED AND CONFUSED BY THE ISSUES IN THIS TIME OF PROSPERITY AND</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIDESPREAD POLITICAL APATHY</ENAMEX>???
            

            YOU'RE NOT ALONE!!!

            If you're like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> , you have little time during this
busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday season</TIMEX> to sort out what positions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> should take. Fortunately, there's an easy
solution! 
               Just observe whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> of secretly favoring , or whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> accuses
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> of secretly favoring !
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">THAT WILL BE WHAT WISE GOVERNANCE DICTATES</ENAMEX>! IT'S THAT SIMPLE!!!
            

            In most presidential elections , you get lots of
ideologically different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> vying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>

               nomination . This can be very confusing . In this election,
you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who are ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>! For all their
populist posturing, 
                  both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> way" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
(formerly known as "neoliberals") who can be counted on to favor a
non-doctrinaire, moderately liberal style of governing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FUNDAMENTALLY</ENAMEX>, IT REALLY DOESN'T MATTER WHICH <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ONE GETS THE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NOMINATION</ENAMEX>!!!
            

            Deep down, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> both know they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interchangeable</ENAMEX>, and find it deeply unsettling. So they lash out
at one another by each accusing the other of favoring politically
unpopular, but programmatically wise policy positions: to raise
taxes if circumstances warrant it; to raise the retirement age for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits; to consider school vouchers on an experimental
basis; and so on. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EACH ONE OF THESE IS A POLICY WELL WORTH</ENAMEX>
CONSIDERING!!!
            

            Next time you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> debate, try <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s unique
method for determining the right positions on the issues: look to
see what each accuses the other of secretly wanting! Then say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, sue
me, I want that, too!" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">YOU WON'T BE SORRY</ENAMEX>!!!
            

            Void where prohibited by law.

         
      
   
