
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidency: Easy to Putin</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s word from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will, in presenting his final budget plan to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, ask for tax cuts and credits worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX>. But both
stories are quickly forced into speculation mode because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> didn't
give out any crunchable details. The top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times states that the election chances of acting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> are excellent in part because of a bill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> signed on
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> in office that requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to garner the signatures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, an accomplishment the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says will be much easier
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>--now in control of considerable resources as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--than
for any potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> stuffs taxes and runs
a story inside that also suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s election inevitability but never
mentions the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>-vote requirement; the paper leads instead with a story
that only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also fronts--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> talks scheduled this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT fronts a story suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> preparedness could prove
to be a huge boon to the economy. The idea put forth is that under the rubric
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> replaced computer systems wholesale and in the process
they gained not just freedom from the millennial bug but also the ability to
perform a wide array of new tasks. And the productivity thus gained will pay
off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Or so the story says, quoting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in support along the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, before swerving abruptly to a "to be sure" <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">11th</NUMEX> paragraph that says Y2K
preparedness "posed an enormous distraction, soaking up time and money that
might have been plowed into projects with a more immediate payoff," and that
"much of the investment went to inoculate older technology against the computer
bug rather than to embrace the newest processes that could revolutionize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> work is done." If the point of the piece was to say that the money spent is
now looking like a tough call, then this idea should have been brought up
higher and developed. If the point is that despite such comments the
preparedness is a boon, then they should have been brought up higher and
answered. What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does instead makes for a disorienting
neither-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>-nor-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX> story.

            The papers visit with some Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimists</ENAMEX> post-non-disaster. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> finds a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> storage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month last year</TIMEX> sold <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> packets instead of the usual <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> and also spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> contingency measures for himself and his
family; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is now worried that the non-happening could mean his just-past
best year might be followed by his worst ever. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> presents
the author of Time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bomb</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> , who hands a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> (= the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>) a free copy. The author expresses few regrets for whatever role he
played in getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, and government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to avoid
breakdowns. But then, his book, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , has sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX>-million
copies.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> surprise by fronting the death of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of naval operations <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmo Zumwalt Jr.</ENAMEX>--an anti-bureaucratic admiral who
tried to open up his starched white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> to flexible thinking and minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sailors</ENAMEX>, but who was best known for having ordered the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Agent Orange</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, a decision which he came to believe caused the death of his own son
and the brain dysfunction of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> play it
inside (although it seems a bit cockeyed that the latter puts it below a
gigantic story-with-pictures about a certain fellating fatso).

            There are apparently unstated limits to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot Property</ENAMEX>"
counts as newsworthy about its glitzy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s column, for
instance, in reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Allen</ENAMEX> had bought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian Slater</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, was
only too glad to tick off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' credits but didn't mention another
residential fact the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have in common--they've both done time.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> ran, under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Must</ENAMEX>
Remember This," a selection of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>'s signal sports events.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incredibly</ENAMEX>, only one of the cited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keepers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Thomson</ENAMEX>'s home
run--occurred before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. This foreshortening of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> forced the
elimination of such undeniably epochal events as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Owens</ENAMEX>' performance in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Bannister</ENAMEX>'s breaking of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four-minute mile</NUMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colts</ENAMEX>' sudden death championship win. The likely explanation is worrisome even
if (like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>) you don't follow sports: boomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> who can't seem
to shake boomer sensibilities when they come to work.

            The headline over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story about former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ways and Means</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">major domo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> says he's back "showing a softer side," but you be
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. In commenting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s marital troubles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosty</ENAMEX> is quoted
saying, "Thank God, all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are dead."

         
      
   
