
   
   
      
         
            Why Are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan Fighting</ENAMEX>?
            

             The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> hijackers that commandeered
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> are reportedly demanding the release of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> imprisoned by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> stories suggest that the
hijacking, but few explain the dispute. What's the gist of the conflict?

            The controversy began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX> withdrew from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
subcontinent, creating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> (predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
(predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>)--out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcontinent</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">territories</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hindu ruler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, a territory about twice the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, agreed to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> objected and went to war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> claiming that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kashmir</ENAMEX>'s majority <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> would prefer to join it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> brokered a peace agreement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, dividing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>
along a cease-fire line that has roughly held until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> controls
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the land and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three quarters</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Free</ENAMEX>") <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jammu</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> became semi-autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> within the controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.
The cease-fire agreement called for a plebiscite to decide the governance. It
has never been held, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> does not recognize either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s claim to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. 

            The cease-fire has been marked by periodic fighting--including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>
invasion of a portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> that it still claims. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>,
various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> escalated the conflict
by demanding independence for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. They backed their
demands with kidnappings and bombings throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jammu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
responded by sending more armed forces to the region. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> expanded, too,
receiving political support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manpower</ENAMEX> and money from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hostilities</ENAMEX> approached all-out war between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>'
armies traded shots over the cease-fire line.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maulana Masood Azhar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cleric</ENAMEX> whose freedom the
hijackers are demanding, was an early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmiri</ENAMEX> independence
movement. He was arrested by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> for fomenting revolution. The Harkat
ul-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mujahedeen</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azhar headed</ENAMEX>, is considered a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and is one of the most violent and extreme rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, it kidnapped--and likely killed--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> in a failed effort
to win <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azhar</ENAMEX>'s freedom.

            Next question?

         
      
   
