
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Tanks</ENAMEX> for Nothing

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
onset in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> peace talks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> puts the talks above the fold but goes
instead with the continued <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechnya</ENAMEX> fighting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> leads all describe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> starting with a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk Shara</ENAMEX> spoke. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s remarks were
brief and cordial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree, but then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shara</ENAMEX> used his remarks to tick
off at some length a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s grievances against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The papers make
it clear that this soured the mood and created considerable awkwardness. Both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> make this point high up, while USAT
holds it for the penultimate paragraph. But, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , by the end of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> of three-way talks, the atmosphere seemed much
improved.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> armored column's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">penetration into Grozny</ENAMEX> was met with strong resistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, relying on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> on the scene, say the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX>
battle left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> dead, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> noting that the
total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian KIA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechnya</ENAMEX> fighting before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s battle
was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>. The LAT dispatch is more noncommittal about the battle, leaving
the clear impression that it had no eyes on the battlefield. Indeed, the
caption on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s front-page illustrated reefer to the battle story inside
reads "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">RUSSIANS ROLL IN.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch stating that the
Chechens have "repulsed" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">long-standing</ENAMEX> position with its announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that it will require
special safety seats for small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> traveling in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airliners</ENAMEX>. The story
doesn't mention who will pay for these seats, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, but
it does say that under the new policy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will probably be buying a
separate ticket for their toddlers, something they can avoid now by holding
them. The story saves for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10th</NUMEX> paragraph the total number of unrestrained
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> who've been killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crashes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.

            Everybody reports inside that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> official
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> testified before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The papers report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> denied that he had any part in channeling money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> '96 campaign but that he did admit to receiving
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> in "gift money" from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Riady</ENAMEX>, a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> with ties to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. The WP observes the hearing was poorly attended: out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> were present.

            Following up its report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on a federal investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>'s
possible restraint of trade, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that major music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, have talked with federal antitrust officials
about settling allegations that they have illegally discouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> from
discounting CDs.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story details the extent of domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> production in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. According to information supplied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
drug policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, marijuana has become the No. 1 cash <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> in poor areas of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, while "speed" manufacturing is on the
upswing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> released a summary of his medical records
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, which indicate he's in "outstanding overall health for a 51-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." The only real risk factor revealed is that his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> is borderline
high--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">231</NUMEX>. Meanwhile, here are some of the questions from the WSJ online
edition's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> questionnaire that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> "declined to answer": "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
single figure has had the greatest influence on the development of your own
political thinking?" "If you had to rely upon a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as your foremost
economic policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, who would it be?" "If you had to rely upon a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as your foremost foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, who would it be?" "What
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> do you most admire? Why?" "What is your favorite
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>?" "Which book that you've read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> has been most
important?" "What book (excepting the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>) that you've ever read has been
most important to you? Why?" "What is the best movie you've seen in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>?" "What is the best movie you've ever seen?"

         
      
   
