
   
   
      
         
            Run of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium Stories</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with (and the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> tops its front-page world-wide
news box with) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s wide-ranging law enforcement action on the trail of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist group</ENAMEX> implicated in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-smuggling arrest in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, action that netted a number of arrests in
different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> who had
recently traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report in addition that the feds are
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> recently arrested trying to come into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> caught in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> are both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> of a known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX>
terrorist. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> off-leads the story, going instead with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s final preparations for its giant millennial celebration.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , which through the miracle of extended newsstand dating becomes
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> to appear with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 time</TIMEX>-hack, gives its front
over to an essay, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Century</ENAMEX>," which spends most of its time reviewing
this one, predictably arcing over the likes of McCarthyism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> but then swerving into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. Not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gorman</ENAMEX>, who we learn was killed in a freakish
motorcycle accident; what we don't learn is who he was. And in the God-said<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-ha</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, the wires report the death of the world's oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, at age
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>, who therefore missed by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mere hours</TIMEX> the superhuman hat trick of drawing
breath in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three centuries</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> arrest was accomplished by "a
black-clad antiterrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX>," while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> involved feds giving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chase</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> drawn. Both papers imply that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> arrest was helped
along by an informant. The coverage says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-smuggling plan
reflected sophistication, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes "a major slip-up"
occurred when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, although registered under an alias
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, used his real address.

            The coverage makes it clear that beyond anything specifically tied to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, the cops were doing a bit of street sweeping. The WP
quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> referring to probable "preemptive arrests," and saying that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> would "nail [those arrested] for anything they can, just to get them
off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>."

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story reports that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> on the Wen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ho Lee</ENAMEX> case are now looking into the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> passed nuclear
secrets not to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, but to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. The story points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> has long
done consulting work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> and has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> who
still live on the island.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> detect hordes of non-hoards. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> telling of increased traffic in bottled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
batteries, candles, etc., but nothing out of control. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
that the extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$255</NUMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> added to the money supply
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> is just sitting there in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> salutes "the most
distinctive of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> inventions, a society based on the values of
political freedom, economic opportunity, individual worth and equal justice."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts forth a gigantic effort to assess the entire 2nd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>,
with sprawling essays on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX>'s history, and on its concepts of liberty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, hate, ingenuity, fear, beauty, thought, and mystery. The effort on
history says, "The best invention of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> is widely considered to be
the printing press, which is obvious and right. The rest of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> are:
glass lenses, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>, the clock pendulum, electrification, the birth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, refrigeration, anesthesia, indoor plumbing, and antibiotics. The
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">overrated</ENAMEX> invention of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX>." The section also
assesses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">worst year</TIMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1347</TIMEX> (bubonic plague comes to the
Continent) and its best as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1789</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> takes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, the factory system is born, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> is invented, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> writes two
piano sonatas, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> writes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> preludes).

            On the LAT op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> states, "Eventually almost
everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will be working directly or indirectly for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI-Worldcom</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> or AT&T." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that contrary to
other holidays, where status in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is measured by the
number/quality of party invites and the relative coolness of one's vacation
plans, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> are the ones who
will be working. Suddenly, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> feels very important.

         
      
   
