
   
   
      
         
            Religion <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX>

            One happy development <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new millennium</TIMEX> is apparently about to bring is the
formal death of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> are "blue-eyed devils" who
were specially bred in the laboratory of an evil black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> with the
suspiciously <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-sounding name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yacub</ENAMEX>. This good news comes in an article by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Magida</ENAMEX> posted on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beliefnet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beliefnet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is an interesting new
religion-oriented Web site founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Waldman</ENAMEX>,* a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> . According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> is
planning to announce in a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX> must merge
with plain-vanilla <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, and in the process embrace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koran</ENAMEX>'s teachings on
racial equality, which apparently preclude the mad-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> theory. (For a
helpful explication of the other cultlike aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX>, click
here.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX> is already pretty small--according to
Prof. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulayman Nyang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard University</ENAMEX>, it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 20,000 to 50,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. It is dwarfed by the following of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elijah Muhammed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warith Deen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX>, a mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">imam</ENAMEX> who rejected the "blue-eyed devils"
doctrines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>, and who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah Blank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News that he's "almost a fanatical supporter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government."

            Hoping to encourage what may be a nascent trend toward rationalism,
Chatterbox hereby challenges other religions to step forward and discard
outdated doctrines, such as, oh, papal infallibility, or Judaism's silly
prejudice against crabcakes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lobster Thermidor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> are invited to
nominate religious doctrines they'd like to see jettisoned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>.
Please provide documentation that the objectionable practice you are citing
isn't made up.

            * personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, as are several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who write or
edit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beliefnet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>; none of them wish to be associated in any way with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s belief that God doesn't actually exist.
            

         
      
   
