
   
   
      
         
            What's a But For?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with a story on everybody's front: "A divided [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to create a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> inspection system for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
with the promise to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> that sanctions against his country
[imposed after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf war</ENAMEX>] could be suspended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a year</TIMEX> and
eventually lifted if he cooperates," as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> puts it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
may never accept the plan. Both Times <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">es</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
has been restocking its supplies of prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lists these
as chemical and biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and components of atomic bombs. All papers
report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
Council abstained from voting, which might weaken the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>'s position and
the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s compliance; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> were the two
permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> that supported the measure. Except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story,
which explains <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> said it would cancel diplomatic relations and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> contracts
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> supported the resolution, there's not much on the
reason for the abstentions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's lead is local: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> will soon get
uglier, as a federal appeals court resurrected plans to replace the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deteriorating Woodrow Wilson Memorial Bridge</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-</NUMEX>lane one that should
alleviate congestion.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead
is also local. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George E. Pataki</ENAMEX> and bipartisan legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> agreed
"to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s cigarette tax by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">55 cents</NUMEX> a pack in an ambitious effort
to provide health care coverage for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as one million</NUMEX> uninsured New
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yorkers</ENAMEX>." The agreement is part of a larger plan, expected to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750 million</NUMEX>
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three and a half years</TIMEX>, to expand coverage. Passage of related
legislation, to be introduced possibly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, is highly likely.

            The focus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's front piece on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore-Bradley</ENAMEX> debate is
clear by its headline, "... Debate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers on Health Care</ENAMEX>." The WP waits till about half-way through its piece before
indicating that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopefuls</ENAMEX> discussed anything else: It reports
that both agreed stricter gun control is needed, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> claimed his
plan was more serious than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece, reefered to on its front, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front piece
touch on many more of the issues discussed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gives the impression that the debate was heated. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , while noting
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> showed "a new persistence and aggressiveness" and that health care
was a contentious issue, said the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> "agreed more than they
disagreed." The LAT similarly calls the debate "mostly ... decorous." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thinks Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health plan is too expensive; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s won't
reach enough currently uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has the
most detail on the education issue, reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> of
insufficient commitment to federal action on education. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have
poll statistics related to how any of these issues rank on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' list of
concerns.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, mainly electricity-generating ones, to cut in half their
emissions of nitrous oxides that contribute to Eastern seaboard smog at the
request of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> who asked for help meeting national smog standards.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> estimates the order would raise the cost of electricity by one percent
but that costs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are still expected to decline "because of
deregulation of the industry"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> should be more clear about what the final relative cost
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> might be. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are
denouncing the mandate.

            News that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Ressam</ENAMEX> was seized at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
border because he was carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> is on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> fronts.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cites an anonymous law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in
making the claim that possible links between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> militant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX> are being pursued, and quotes an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, saying "this was not a run-of-the-mill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> ...
This was serious." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also mentions the possible connection, though both
papers note a definite link to bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> has not been established. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes no mention of bin
Laden and credits an anonymous government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> with the quote, "There's
nothing mysterious at all about what was in [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX>'s] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>," though it also
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are worried that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> could be part of an
international terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> recently warned that it
had "credible information" about "terrorist attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>
[timed] around the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1 millennium</TIMEX> celebrations." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>) of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> were arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> for plotting such attacks.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is "strongly considering making
a request for government reimbursement of" most or all of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> owe in unpaid legal bills associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
investigations--which have already cost the public <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$47 million</NUMEX>. To be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reimbursed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> would have to prove that he would not have needed
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> "but for the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute." This is the so-called "but
for" clause. So if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can show he wouldn't have been prosecuted by a
regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, he'll get the money.

         
      
   
