
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential debates--both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s face-off
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>'s joint appearance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> . Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s remark in a debate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ</ENAMEX> "changed [his] heart" and a new
poll friendly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>.

            Sitting <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> apart on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
carry on the most spirited back-and-forth of the presidential campaign. Unlike
most debates, however, this one has a hands-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>, who
peppers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with his special brand of heavy-hitting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinpoint</ENAMEX>-accurate questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> is especially tough on the entitlement
issue: He shows both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> a government report, signed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Cabinet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>, which concludes that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2035</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> will either have
to raise taxes or cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> benefits. But neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> will commit to doing either, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX>'s insistence that there
is no free lunch. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--wearing a dark blue blazer rather than his trademark
"earth tones"--calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX>'s notion "elite opinion" and then reasserts his
commitment to the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.)

            Jumping on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> promises that he too will forgo soft money
in the general election if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s campaign-finance pledge in

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin" and "Ballot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> also pledges to renounce all TV and radio advertising in the
primary campaign if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will go along and challenges the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> debates per week as a substitute for the forgone ads. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> dismisses
both proposals as "ridiculous."

            Late in the program Russert catches <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> flatfooted. Asked if he would
"admit that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> fund-raising apparatus was overly
aggressive, perhaps unethical," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> says:

            

               I'm not going to use those words. I think, obviously, if we had to do it
over again, the point is do you learn from your mistakes, and I certainly have.
I strongly support--

               RUSSERT: What was the big mistake that was made, if you learned from it?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GORE</ENAMEX>: Oh, I think, um, pushing the limits, um, all this was reviewed and,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>, charges were brought. But I think it was a mistake nonetheless.

            

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> (the only pundit show taped after
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> opines that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign-finance ploy
worked and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> looked haughty, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>
thinks that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> came across as he always does--like a nervous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nellie</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> notes that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightline</ENAMEX> debate, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> mentioned the name of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s popular incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agree
that there are still few substantive differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) calls the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> candidates <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Diet Coke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diet Pepsi</ENAMEX>,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) says deciding which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to vote for is
like "trying to choose between <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> milk." (To read "Ballot
Box" on both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> debates, click here; to
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s dissent, click here.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> ruminate on the appropriateness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s remark in his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> presidential debate that his favorite political philosopher is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>,
because he changed my heart." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) think
it unseemly to wear one's religion on one's sleeve, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> sees
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby-</ENAMEX>boomer selfishness in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s transformation of a political question into a
personal one. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ) see little wrong with a simple declaration of faith.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> trots out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN/Gallup/ USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> poll indicating that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> win some early
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">primaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> may switch to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> likely will not
switch to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. The poll also shows that campaign-finance reform is low on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' lists of election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>; asked about this on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> blames the wording of the questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX> (both
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) say that the poll doesn't matter: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">campaign-finance</ENAMEX> issue is merely a prop for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s better selling points--his
biography and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Et Cetera</ENAMEX>: In an interview on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> says that if he could do it over again, he would have used the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> as a bully pulpit, appearing on television to
counter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>.

            

               Being, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nothingness</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX>
               
            

            

               [ <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> ] is also a commentary on the culture. The recurring theme
is too much and too little self-esteem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> has too much, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>
has too little. There is a kind of mild metaphysic involved. In one of the
strips, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> is jumping rope and says, "Suddenly it struck me
that it all seemed futile." Well, what doesn't?

               

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX>, on the legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>'s cartoon strip ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> )

               

            

            
               
Last Word
            

            

               It immediately communicated a certain reverence, which is to be welcomed.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> was not a political philosopher, he was the source of philosophy,
the source of goodness, the source of contemplation. So there is a formal
objection to his being named as such.

               

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s remark that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> had
"changed [his] heart" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> )

               

               
Now, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>, I assume he's for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Test-Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>, blessed are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacemakers</ENAMEX>. And I assume he's pro-Earned
Income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, blessed are the poor.

               

                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>, on the same topic ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> )

               

            

         
      
   
