
   
   
      
         
            Is That All There Is?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Harry</ENAMEX>,

            I feel a strange mix of emotions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this new millennium</TIMEX>. Like a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, I suspect, I have a guilty secret: I wish something bad had happened.
Not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapture</ENAMEX>. Not even a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Deadly Act</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorism</ENAMEX>. But a little glitch would
have been nice--kind of like a snow day when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> (I'm assuming you
haven't been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> your whole life)--something to put a little dent in the
manic optimism of the moment. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few hours</TIMEX> without the power, or having the ATM
jam would have been a useful cautionary note at a time when everyone feels like
they deserve an IPO of their own.

            I see from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> are already extremely
defensive, insisting that the problem wasn't hyped and that their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX>
price tag was worth it. I have my doubts. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year's Day</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> raised a
question that's already become cliché <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> later: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> wasn't a problem
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that spent a lot (e.g. us) and in those that spent little but
still have a lot of computers (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, I gather), then didn't we get ripped off?
I still haven't heard a good answer

            For all my wishing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>disaster, I also felt much more moved by the
celebration than I thought I would. Watching the rolling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> across the globe
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> was strangely riveting--not least of all because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>
felt compelled to pull a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX> telethon and anchor the whole thing
himself. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> he was babbling so much, I expected him to point to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tote</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed McMahon</ENAMEX> how much we'd raised. Still, the effect of seeing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Y2K date</TIMEX> roll across the globe brought out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kumbaya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> in me. I feel
the same way sometimes--I'm not kidding--watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Weather Channel</ENAMEX> seeing a
storm form over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast of Africa</ENAMEX> and then roll east into a hurricaine.
The same cloud pattern some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malawi</ENAMEX> tribesman gazed at eventually dumped water
on a shriner at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biloxi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX> We are the world.

            You think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had a good time, or what? Standing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX>, reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s words, with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of about a gazillion and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> production behind him? Raised in a liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, it infuriated
me as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> got to leave his signature on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> plaque left
on the moon. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> that got us there, and here was Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Un-American Activities</ENAMEX> getting to leave his name on the moon after just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in office. I imagine there are gazillions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> for whom
it's incredibly painful that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> got to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to usher in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third Millennium</ENAMEX>. Did you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King</ENAMEX> column in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ? He
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told him he owns the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> letter to the
music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, the one where he threatens to punch out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> for criticizing
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s piano recital. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the letter, according
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>. Weird ...

            I see in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposing a modest but still
sizable tax cut for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Can there be any doubt how this Kabuki ritual
will play out yet again? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubs</ENAMEX> will push for bigger cuts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX> will accuse them of endangering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. The public
will back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will bluster, losing popular support, but
then they'll finally cave to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and infuriate their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>. They're like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wile E. Coyote</ENAMEX> going off the cliff every time.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, I'm emceeing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Dinner</ENAMEX> that you
hosted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bigshots in a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ball room</ENAMEX>, done up in
black tie. You're a comedy God. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Spinal Tap</ENAMEX> on DVD yet?) I do
occasional stand up: Got any tips? I've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> to come up with a bevy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Hastert</ENAMEX> jokes and I'm getting edgy. As <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">millennial anxiety</ENAMEX> goes, it's
pretty small stuff, but I could still use a few tips.

            Talk to you later.
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
