
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Rifkin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spurious Suit Against Monsanto</ENAMEX>
            

            At this point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> in life-sciences giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX> have to be
wondering what else can go wrong. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s prospective merger
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX> unraveled in acrimony over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and strategy
questions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s agribusiness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, which it had once planned to make
the center of its operations, became the target of serious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
to genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>. Even as the major stock indices
continued to rise briskly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>'s shares have languished. And this past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> has seen bad news on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different fronts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Tuesday</TIMEX>, a class-action
lawsuit orchestrated by environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gadfly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Rifkin</ENAMEX> was filed against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> reacted to news of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX>'s planned merger
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia & Upjohn</ENAMEX> by sending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s shares down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
percent.

            I've written enough here about the vices of mergers, and those vices are
well-documented enough, to make any extended comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto/Pharmacia</ENAMEX>
deal superfluous. There's no good reason to think that this deal will work, and
it smacks of a move made--by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>--to preempt other,
perhaps hostile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX>. So the Street's reaction to the deal was sensible.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> interesting element of that reaction, though, was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> were
frustrated that, as part of the deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX> will be spinning off just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
percent of its agribusiness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. That unit is now generally acknowledged to be
a drain on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock price, and so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> have been
hoping for a full spin-off. But in the wake of this deal, tax considerations
make anything more than a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> spinoff next to impossible to pull
off.

            In the long run, that may actually be a good thing. Given the ongoing uproar
over genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>, an uproar that has played an important role in
issue between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, agribusiness certainly seems to be
a short-term loser. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of all the soybean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crops</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are already genetically modified varieties, and the
possibilities of using genetic modification to increase crop yields and protect
against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>, to say nothing of creating vitamin-enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX>, are so
wide-ranging that it seems difficult to imagine they will be dismissed out of
hand.

            Of course, that's exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Rifkin</ENAMEX> would like to do. The lawsuit
filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> on behalf of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
organic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> was a haphazard and scattershot collection of charges that might
have been designed to demonstrate the excesses to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> legal system
can be driven. The lawsuit accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX> of introducing products without
testing them sufficiently for safety, misleading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> about these products,
and monopolizing the patents and sale of these unsafe products. In other words,
it's a class-action unsafe-product, fraud, antitrust lawsuit. The damages being
asked for are "unspecified," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rifkin</ENAMEX> has said they could amount to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>. How he reached that figure remains unclear.

            The suit is exactly what it appears to be: a publicity stunt. To begin with,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX> hasn't violated any law by selling genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX>, and in
fact its products have been certified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> (which, needless to say, does
not certify "normal" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX>). And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can't be accused of selling unsafe
products because there's no evidence that the products are unsafe. That's why
the suit just says they should have tested more. The fraud charge seems equally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spurious</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monsanto</ENAMEX> has been straightforward about its testing procedures.
And as for the antitrust charge, the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novartis, DuPont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>, and
AstraZeneca are all named in the suit as "co-conspirators" (though not actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>) makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> charge a bit hard to believe. Perhaps we could
next sue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX> for monopolizing the
auto market.

            Obviously, there are important issues about genetically-modified agriculture
that have yet to be resolved. And just as obviously, the major agribusiness
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have hurt themselves by obstinately opposing things like labeling of
genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> (which is now required in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.U.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>). But class-action lawsuits are not useful ways of determining public
policy. (Perhaps the most ridiculous aspect of this whole farce is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rifkin</ENAMEX>'s use
of the word "populist" to describe the suit.) They are, though, very useful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> of fomenting ill-considered controversies. And in that sense, I suppose,
the suit is already a great success.

         
      
   
