
   
   
      
         
            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Intentions and Cracked Premises</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jim</ENAMEX>,

            Idealism sweet as ether boils off the pages of the book that we've been
assigned to read and discuss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Rosen</ENAMEX>'s history of and argument for
"public journalism," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Are Journalists For</ENAMEX>? I've survived its
narcotizing effect and hope that you're more enthusiastic about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX>'s ideas
than I am so we can enjoy a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fisted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>.

            For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> arriving late to the debate over public journalism, we should
define it and sketch its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> history--not that that will be easy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
journalism as propounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> is so broad and vague, so infused with good
intentions and cracked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>, that it melts at first touch.

            Something horrible has happened to public life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> believes. He doesn't
blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> for the disaster. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. Or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. Or even our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">campaign-finance</ENAMEX> system or handguns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> finds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> culpable for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s cynical politics, our public alienation, our adversarial culture, as
well as the violence perpetrated by terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>. Our
crime? We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> have failed to promote and enhance "democracy"
as imaged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dewey</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>.

            I'm not kidding. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are Journalists For</ENAMEX>? is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deweyan</ENAMEX> call to arms
to rebuild democracy! Never mind the old clichés about telling truth to power
or writing the first draft of history. Instead of hiding behind objective
reporting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> should foster "conversation" and "dialogue" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> to empower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in the democratic process. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> has been much pilloried by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> for his diagnosis and
prescription, most notably by editorial-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howell Raines</ENAMEX> of the New
But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wichita</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norfolk</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere have lit their candles from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> and
subscribed to his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-step cure, which holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> should:

            

               "Approach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> as potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in public affairs, rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>. ..."

               "Help the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> act upon, rather than just learn about, its
problems. ..."

               "Improve the climate of public discussion. ..."

               "Help make public life go well, so that it earns its claim on our
attention. ..."

            

            Wicked mush, don't you think? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, a story wouldn't necessarily be
bad journalism if it hit on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX>'s cylinders. But it wouldn't
necessarily be good if it did, would it?

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming days</TIMEX> I want to examine some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>, such as his
idea that a declining interest in the news can be linked to journalism as
currently practiced. But I'm running out of space and smelling salts and must
turn this enterprise over to you.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
