
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jenny Craig World Tour</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>

            D'you catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>? I've had this
reaction before, but I couldn't help but have it again: What was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
thinking? Of all the sex options open to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, this was a helluva
pick. This, I realize, is not exactly a stunning insight, but since the Jenny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Tour</ENAMEX> has begun, I couldn't help feeling it. I also couldn't help
but feel pity for the gal. She's got a bazillion dollars in legal bills thanks
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarlet Letter Special Counsel</ENAMEX>, and she has to do this humiliating
weight gig with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Craig</ENAMEX> in order to pay off the bills. (I believed her when
she said that this was the most tasteful of the offers she got.) By the way, my
favorite line from the scandal, which I think reduces the whole thing to one
sentence, is the line from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in which he said to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>--I'm not making
this up--"You can always say you were bringing me <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>."

            I see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is getting ready to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, the cuban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy/political</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, go back to his native land. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
reports that they're going to cut a deal in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> comes here and
picks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> up. I fear this whole thing will get even more bizarre. Won't
anti-Castro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Florida</ENAMEX> try to hide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>? Then we'll have months
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where's Elian?</ENAMEX>" I don't have particularly strong feelings about
where he belongs. Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> have any real role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s life? What
kind of home is he in now? (I've got doubts about any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that invites camera
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> in to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore-Bradley</ENAMEX> race, I see, is heating up with each tossing out charges
that the other one is a mere tinkerer and not bold enough. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is
exactly a poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for radical change, it seems to me. It's only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
and I'm already tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s pedantic tone and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
you-voted-for-vouchers-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-years-ago tone.

            Anything interesting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>?

         
      
   
