
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etymology</ENAMEX> of "Y2K"

            Y2K was born on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 12, 1995</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:31 p.m.</TIMEX> It was delivered in the
middle of an otherwise unintelligible e-mail, a contribution to an Internet
discussion group of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX> exploring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> bug long before
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were surfing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>.

            The efficiency of the term is undeniable--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>" for "year," the number "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>,"
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>" for "thousand" (from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> "kilo")--and it eventually caught on.
But its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> remained unidentified until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just over a year ago</TIMEX>, when someone
performed the equivalent of a computer paternity test by searching the
discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s archives for the term's first use.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the phrase is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Eddy</ENAMEX>, who's now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> consulting business (click
here to visit his Web page). "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were calling it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Date Change</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faddle</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Faulty Date Logic</ENAMEX>]," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddy</ENAMEX> says. "There were
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>. [Y2K] just came off my fingertips."

            But what made Y2K flourish while its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings withered</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> put in a
call to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.B. Master</ENAMEX>, who runs a naming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Master-McNeil</ENAMEX> (great
name!). Master, who has helped name products for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsystems</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3Com</ENAMEX>, performed her own "linguistic analysis" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y2K</ENAMEX> and
promptly listed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> reasons why the term holds such appeal.

            For starters, she said, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> is efficient, since it uses <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just three</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>; similarly structured acronyms such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> are a
staple <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it's gratifyingly symmetrical, with the two
consonants hugging that number in the middle. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the whole tradition of
combining letters and numbers is a venerated techie convention (think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R2D2</TIMEX> and
C3P0). The date-glitch issue has obvious technical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>; thus there is
a strong connection between the term's appearance and its meaning.

            But none of that explains why we're not using, say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2M</TIMEX>--which simply
replaces the consonant representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> term for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> with the one
for "mille," its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>. Y2K, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masters</ENAMEX> pointed out, is rhythmically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superior</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> is analyzed as poetry, one sees a satisfying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternation</ENAMEX> of
long and short syllables: a diphthong (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>), followed by a monothong (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), and a
final, concluding diphthong (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>). By contrast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2M</TIMEX> ends with a redundant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monothong</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX> praised Y2K for its superior sound production, noting that
the term features an elegant plosive progression, moving from soft (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>) to hard
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to hardest (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>). Y2M retreats lamely with a soft "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.</ENAMEX>"

            Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masters</ENAMEX> lauded the term for the way its articulation produces a
satisfying movement to the inside of the mouth. The term begins with a labial
sound: the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>" being formed with the lips. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2</ENAMEX>" is alveolar; it is produced
at the middle of the mouth when the tongue touches the roof. Finally, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>"
is velar, forming in the back of the mouth. That progression sets Y2K far apart
from its competition. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masters</ENAMEX> said, she could think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> other
word that featured such an exquisitely pleasing articulatory progression in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mouth</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
