
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dot-Com Mania Is More Selective Than You Think</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the basic truisms about investing that's very easy to forget,
especially in the middle of the kind of bull market we're in, is that it isn't
a stock market, but rather a market of stocks. In other words, even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are generally feeling bullish, that bullishness is not uniform. It
does not lead them to forget about distinctions among stocks. Even during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX> tulip mania, after all, there were some bulbs that seemed priceless and
others that you could buy.

            In the most general terms, we all recognize this. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, for instance,
the cliché became that everyone wanted to buy tech stocks and couldn't deal
with the large cyclical or commodity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcoa</ENAMEX> was up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">119 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, more than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> stock, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> were a little more discerning than "tech good, no tech bad." But as a
broad generalization, the cliché was accurate enough.

            The problem comes when the cliché is taken to mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are so
blindly rushing after stocks of a certain kind that they're not paying any
attention at all to the differences among all those stocks. This is a problem
because if it's true, it means that the market can't be doing what it is meant
to do: channel capital to those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will use it most productively
and away from those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will not. And it's a problem because if it's
false ... well, it's just always a problem when a conclusion is false.

            In this case, that's precisely what that conclusion is. Perhaps the most
remarkable thing about this market is that even in a time of seeming universal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buoyancy</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> was up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80-plus percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and you could not seem
to go wrong as an investor if you were buying anything with a .<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> at the end
of its name or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B2B</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business-to-business</ENAMEX>) label attached to its business
model, there are lots of tech stocks that are not doing especially well. More
to the point, there are lots of tech stocks that have done really well and then
been severely punished, and on any given day what you're most likely to see is
not a move upward or downward in which everyone's participating, but a
surprising mix of moves.

            Take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> opened up a blistering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> points, then
quickly tumbled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> points before rallying yet again (it's currently
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up 15</NUMEX> points). Even as some of the tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwarts</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
(both of which I own) were in free-fall, Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouses</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> were up
strong on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. And even as some of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">B2B</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JDS Uniphase, Foundry</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redback</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> you probably haven't heard of but which now sport <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> plus market caps)--were zooming, others were headed in the opposite
direction.

            On a deeper level, there are now a host of Internet stocks that no longer
participate in .<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> mania. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IVillage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marketwatch</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MP3</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koop</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wit Capital</ENAMEX>: All of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were once darlings of the
market and now see their stocks trade in very narrow ranges not much above--and
in some cases below--the prices at which they went public. You could say this
is just a case of market sentiment shifting. But it'd be more accurate to see
it as what it is: a collective verdict on the long-term profit possibilities of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Which is, after all, what market sentiment ultimately
means.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> overreact, in both directions. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> do become
hot and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> huge inflows of capital based mainly on trend-following. But
that kind of indistinct investing doesn't last too long, which is why the idea
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> "don't care about profits" is a misreading. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
didn't care about profits, they wouldn't distinguish as carefully as they
ultimately do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between one</NUMEX> unprofitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and another. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> (and
this is a good thing), everyone doesn't win. Even if those everyones have .<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
at the ends of their names.

         
      
   
