
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Letterman</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX>-Compliant?

            Among the questions unexplored in the reams of news copy commemorating the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century's end</TIMEX> is the likely fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boomer Irony</ENAMEX>. Chatterbox
agrees with Jedediah
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX> that there's too much of it (though he hasn't bothered to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdy</ENAMEX>'s book; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> feels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McGowan</ENAMEX> covered
the subject pretty comprehensively in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-page article* published in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monthly</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why David Letterman Is</ENAMEX>
Bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>"). But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>--who is, after all, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boomer</ENAMEX>--is not willing
entirely to give up the habit of discoursing ironically. It is therefore
with some apprehension that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> views the coming of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a new century</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boomer Irony</ENAMEX> is, after all, a distinctly fin de siècle phenomenon.
Here is how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britannica</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> defines fin de siècle :

            

               
                  of, relating to, characteristic of, or resembling the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-19 th -century</TIMEX> literary and artistic climate of sophistication,
escapism, extreme aestheticism, world-weariness, and fashionable despair. When
used in reference to literature, the term essentially describes the movement
inaugurated by the 
                  Decadent 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> called

                  Aestheticism 
                  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> during this
period.
               

            

            Sound familiar? (To sample some bona fide fin de siècle art and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">poetry,</ENAMEX> click here.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual indiscretions (not to mention his casual perjury about
them) make him a very fin de siècle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, though as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policymaker</ENAMEX>
he's clearly superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McKinley</ENAMEX>. Should history repeat itself, we
should expect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to elect a humorless, no-nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is not so fin de siècle as to contemplate that
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would take office as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> did--succeeding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> who
dies in office.) This speaks well for the chances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore**</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, and poorly for those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smirky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> is a
hard case, being conventionally brave and forthright but also kind of a cutup;
his crack about propping up a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan à la Weekend</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie</ENAMEX>'s was very fin de siècle .) However, to give an appropriate
nod to the underdogs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> also speaks well for the chances of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> (none of whom has an ironic or decadent bone
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can see). You begin to see the cause for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX>.

            * edited by Chatterbox
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">** Though Gore</ENAMEX> does have an ironic, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Boomerish</ENAMEX> sense of humor, he
shows so little of it to the public that he might as well not have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
            

         
      
   
