
   
   
      
         
            Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So Silent Night</ENAMEX>

            The front pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are splashed with violence and
bloodshed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast</ENAMEX> mounted a coup d'etat, ousting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Konan Bedie</ENAMEX> and suspending
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s constitution, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>. "I will take care of
everybody. You should not be worried," announced retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Guei</ENAMEX>, who
claimed to be in charge. Meanwhile, army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> alike pillaged
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abidjan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' motives are still unclear-- some
seem to be after back pay, while others said they specifically wanted to topple
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedie</ENAMEX>. Bedie may be under house arrest or may have taken refuge at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>-- no one's sure yet. The papers describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory Coast</ENAMEX>
as a former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">oasis</ENAMEX> of stability in war-torn <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front the hijacking of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> flight bound from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katmandu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">189</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> abroad (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reefers the story).
Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> seized it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> has touched down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> claim to
have killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, but so far they've released only one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>, along
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The papers tentatively identify
the hijackers as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX>, but don't give any background on their history or
goals. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> has long sought freedom from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> rule. Many
moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sikhs</ENAMEX> seek autonomy; more extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> want independence, and have
long used violent means to pursue it.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> tentatively speculates
that the hijacking is related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> tug-of-war over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>
but doesn't say how. The LAT mentions the possibility that the
hijackers are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiris</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are too quick
to broadcast warnings about terrorist threats to the public. By erring "on the
side of overexposure," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> may be encouraging mass <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>. As
evidence for this nationwide hysteria, the story quotes a gun shop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> who's been unloading an unusually high number of gas masks and
bulletproof <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vests</ENAMEX> (if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> are a reliable indicator of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s mood, then <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> is moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>). The story also says
that disclosure of the threats generates intense media coverage, which in turn
means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist groups</ENAMEX> get exactly what they're after--national
publicity. The tell-all policy is a reaction to the explosion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> Flight
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> was condemned for sharing some threats
with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> but not with the public. Many of the points in the story
were stated in an op-ed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> written by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>-nik.
These arguments seem to have migrated a little too quickly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and from the op-ed page to the front page.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front pager reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have issued an
arrest warrant for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abdelmajed Dahoumane</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Ressam</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> for trying to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state while carrying
ingredients for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> motel where they'd stayed
said their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> stank of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rotten eggs</ENAMEX>--more evidence that they may have been
brewing up bombs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hijackers</ENAMEX> from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> independence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ressam</ENAMEX> is linked hijacked an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air France</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>. They were foiled when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-terrorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX> stormed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> as it was parked and killed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that very little of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$206 billion</NUMEX>
settlement between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is being used for anti-smoking
programs. Instead, the money is being used for sundry bread-and-butter
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>: new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX>, tax cuts, boot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, school construction. The suit,
of course, was filed expressly to fund anti-smoking efforts.

            Front-page reports in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that millennial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> was peaceful, if a bit sparsely attended--many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> stayed away from fear of violence. Meanwhile, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basilica</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> was thronged with worshippers. Perhaps they
came for the e-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> produced "pilgrim cards"
embedded with microchips, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can swipe to reserve seats at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>,
on tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
