
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rationalist's Guide to New Year's Sentimentality</ENAMEX>

            Having read all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Op-Eds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> articles mocking millennial emotions
as so much numerological bunk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> is well aware that this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> is, strictly speaking, meaningless. She knows that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> arrives at
least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,005 years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> was actually born; that due to an error in
calculation stemming from medieval ignorance of the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX> doesn't start till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>; that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gregorian</ENAMEX> calendar is filled
with arbitrary adjustments and slippages; and so forth.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> also knows that when she raises her glass at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:59:50 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, she'll feel a wave of excited anxiety. She suspects
you'll feel it too. She does not believe that the obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">culprits</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>,
terrorism, the usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s hype that makes you feel that everyone else is
having a better time than you--are entirely responsible. Like most of the rest
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> won't be flying or driving or congregating
downtown or eating at some ludicrously overpriced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s extravaganza.
She'll be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, standing beside her loved ones, etc. And when
New <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s arrives and she experiences that brief sense of being overwhelmed by
something she can't explain, she'll be tempted to dismiss it, as she does every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, as sentimental and superstitious.

            But is it? What is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s, anyway, if not a reminder that time
has passed, which is to say that death has drawn that much closer? New <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> is just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s to a higher degree. For lack of a better reference
point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has spent her entire life dividing it into before the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX> and after. New <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> is the moment this personal temporal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX> arrives, for what it's worth.

            It's actually not unreasonable to feel awe on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, even if
you don't believe that it is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2000th</NUMEX> anniversary of the birth of the era of
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>. The great religions are a product of the same sense of awe. They
were invented in large part to help us deal with the terrifying fact that time
propels us toward our own destruction. The revolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX> was that it
transformed time from cyclical to historical--a history belonging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> by God--so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> could think of a future beyond mortality.
Christianity posited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shining moments, one in the past and one in the
future, when human time meets up with eternal time. Those are, of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s appearance and return. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> believed that the
passing of time led them inexorably to a horrible fate; their God was created
partly to guarantee that the fullness of time would be good, rather than evil.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Hindus</ENAMEX> banished time altogether by calling it unreal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> had a word for a moment in time that seemed to stand apart from
other moments. They called it a kairos --<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an auspicious moment</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">le</ENAMEX>
moment <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juste</ENAMEX> . The existential philosopher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Heidegger</ENAMEX> translated the
concept into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> word <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augenblick</ENAMEX> , an instant that occurs in the
blink of an eye. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidegger</ENAMEX>, this is an interval in which the world opens up
and we are allowed perceive it differently, to grasp it more authentically.
Maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve 2000</TIMEX> is one such blink of the eye, an opening in time
which forces us to grapple with time--and death. Enjoy it if you can.

         
      
   
