
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Yardeni</ENAMEX>

            "If I'm wrong about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>, I'll just check into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Betty Ford Clinic</ENAMEX> for
delusional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, publicly state that I'm on industrial-strength <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>,
and then ask for forgiveness," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Yardeni</ENAMEX> joked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past September</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>,
who is chief global <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank Securities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (he
previously held the same job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.J. Lawrence, Prudential Securities</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hutton</ENAMEX>), was the most respectable of all the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomsayers</ENAMEX>, his credibility
greatly enhanced by an accurate record of boldly optimistic financial forecasts
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. (Never mind that he wrongly predicted a recession following
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> stock-market crash and that he failed to see the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-91</TIMEX> recession
coming.) For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> was quoted regularly in the
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and appeared regularly on the tube predicting that computer
glitches in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2000</TIMEX> would cause the worst global recession since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past fall</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> downgraded his prediction from a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-month</TIMEX> or longer
recession" to a "very intense recession" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> that would bring the Dow
down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX>, but he continued to put the likelihood of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K-</ENAMEX>computer-glitch
recession at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>, up from his initial, more cautious prediction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
percent.

            Now it appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> was not just wrong, but spectacularly wrong. But
if you go to his Web site
and listen to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> conference call (scroll down to the pink area and click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meltup or Meltdown?</ENAMEX>"), you won't learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> is in rehab, or that he's
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-depressants</ENAMEX>, or even that he's asking forgiveness. Rather, you'll hear
the opening strains of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> movement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Symphony</ENAMEX>,
followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s somewhat brusque acknowledgment that things don't appear
to have gone as badly as he'd planned. If <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few additional days</TIMEX> go by and no
widespread computer failures present themselves, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>,
"you'll be able to read my lips. I'll just say, 'I was wrong.' " Attempting to
be gracious, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> added, "I have no problems" with the growing likelihood
that Y2K will end up being "a non-event." But "in retrospect, I certainly don't
regret that I did my small bit to raise awareness" of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem. (Come
again? Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> can argue they raised awareness and thereby
prevented problems, but financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> can't; they just predict
what's going to happen to markets.) Switching back to reluctant mea
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">culpa</ENAMEX> mode, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> continued,

            

               
                  I may have spent too much time trying to be a contrarian here. ...
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translates: "I'm sorry."] But I think that one aspect of
my job is to do some contrary thinking every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>. [ Chatterbox
translates: "I'm not sorry."] I guess I could just tell you what
you already know, just kind of regurgitate the consensus view.
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translates: "I'm glad ."]

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't mean to kick a prominent Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> when he's
down. Rather, he recites these details to raise a larger question: Do purveyors
of extreme predictions ever pay a price when their predictions prove wrong?
Commenting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s Y2K Chicken Little stance a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter Eric Reguly</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Cooper</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief economist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nesbitt Burns</ENAMEX> (and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reguly</ENAMEX>, "no slouch in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-promotion</ENAMEX> department herself"), said, "It's a good gamble on his part. As
long as there is some Y2K disruption anywhere, he can claim to be right." In
fact, there appears to have been no significant Y2K disruption anywhere,
but allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> to make a bold prediction of his own: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX> will still
be eagerly sought after by financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookers</ENAMEX>, because in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardeni</ENAMEX>'s particular market niche it's better to be vivid than to be right.

         
      
   
