
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creeping Rodhamism</ENAMEX>!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paranoid</ENAMEX>'s Corner: There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> angle to the previous,
epic-length kausfiles item on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s decision
to promote food-stamp receipt. It's this: Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s new emphasis on
food stamps an attempt to create an issue for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> to use against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has been accused of making it
too hard to get the stamps? ... I'm not saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> suddenly ordered
a way to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s campaign. The repackaging of food stamps as "critical
work supports" (rather than welfare handouts) has been pushed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> by
influential liberal antipoverty "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>" such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell Primus</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Budget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Priorities</ENAMEX>. Plenty of career <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
undoubtedly agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primus</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primus</ENAMEX> hasn't won many battles with the
triangulating, welfare-reforming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> lately. Why did the administration
suddenly now agree to give him a victory by taking a "food stamps are good for
you" line? What tipped the balance? Maybe they were spooked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primus</ENAMEX>'
statistical calculations showing some deterioration in the income of the bottom
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, even though those
numbers have been looking a lot better recently. Maybe ... If you believe
that, you probably believe it was also just a coincidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Development</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cuomo</ENAMEX>'s press release promoting a fairly dry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> study of the homeless happened to mention an advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s estimate
that "in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> per year to jail someone,
compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $12,500</NUMEX> to provide affordable housing and a variety of
supportive services." This after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> announced a controversial homeless
policy that involved police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> rousting homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, with some going
to jail. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> already noted the leftward drift of the waning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in a recent column. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX> blames both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s campaign and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s need for liberal primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. But food stamps are more clearly an
issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s race than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s. ...

            
               Not that there's anything wrong with losing money: Isn't the current
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>) issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> a little ... thin ? It's
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, after all. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Up-market</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are supposed to be chock full o' ads.
But I counted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 29</NUMEX> pages that looked paid-for. ... Maybe they're making it
all back on their Web site!

            
               More on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Journalist Dan Moldea</ENAMEX>, who worked on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>'s
investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, e-mailed to note that I didn't talk to him before I
wrote my recent item
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> sex scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moldea</ENAMEX> has a point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> can
find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moldea</ENAMEX>'s side of the story here, on his Web site. ... It's fancier than
The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's!

         
      
   
