
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Y2K Heist</ENAMEX>
            

            First things first: What's a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">snow day"</ENAMEX>? Yes, I did spend all my life in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>, except for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two nauseating years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Speaking of
which, my television viewing (aided by a big satellite dish that allows me to
see stuff without hearing all the babble <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> TV throws on top to "explain"
what you're seeing) convinced me that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>'s celebration beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Apple</ENAMEX>'s
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> mile. I still don't understand all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> in diaphanous
approximations of no national costume that cavorted through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> all
day. In the good old, pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> days, they would have been mugged and left
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">carrion before noon</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ran a long takeout regarding the putative Y2K
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gyp</ENAMEX>. One "information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>" was quoted as saying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> industry had been
had. This leads me to one conclusion: The vast, exciting run-up in the stock
market, yanked along by the (here's a journalistic cliché ripe for the
executing) "tech-heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>," may not have been irrational exuberance at all;
it may just have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' reaction to the tech industry's
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred-billion-dollar</NUMEX> holdup of the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to "fix the bug."

            Speaking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , said paper, still smarting from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX> scandal, in which it published a special issue of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
magazine on the opening of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> and split the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s profits with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>, published a special section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in which it printed in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-point type the names of all the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>" of its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millennium</ENAMEX> registry."
These were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who paid good money to get special commemorative editions of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s papers, and to get their names printed in that special
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, chastened by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shaw</ENAMEX>'s long exposé of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX>
scandal, claims to have learned its lesson, but that kind of learniing is
supposed to keep you from getting promoted to the next grade. Also, at the
bottom of the front page of the special section: "We regret any typographical
errors." So don't ask for your money back if they misprinted your name.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX>, incidentally, for "naming rights" to the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>. You'd think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> could get them to pay at least a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to get their name off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s scandal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
