
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reality Bites Value America</ENAMEX>
            

            Whatever the Internet will become, one of the things it's been in the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years</TIMEX> is a consumer's paradise, at least from a price perspective. In
their hunger to acquire new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> have engaged in good
old-fashioned price wars and have more generally made Net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> so
accustomed to sizable discounts that paying anything close to retail feels like
you're being robbed.

            The question, of course, has always been whether these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> were
actually ever going to be able to make money when their business often seemed,
as venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gurley</ENAMEX> so smartly put it, to be the equivalent of
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who visited their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> a dollar in exchange for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">95 cents</NUMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX>, we're starting to see signs that, in fact, a lot of these
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> are not only not going to be able to make money. They may
not even be able to stay in business for much longer.

            The most telling such sign was the announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX>
that it was going to slash its work force by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47 percent</NUMEX>, slim down its product
offerings, leave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> it now occupies, and make meaningful
cuts in its ad spending. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX> also announced that its revenue for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> will fall <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent to 9 percent</NUMEX> short of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' estimates
and that it will lose significantly more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> had expected in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX> has been this one-stop shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, where you could buy
everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to printers to appliances to computers. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computers</ENAMEX> like
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on which I'm writing this column, actually, bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> for a
very nice price.) It now plans to focus on selling computers and consumer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electronics</ENAMEX>, which on the one hand is a natural strategy for targeting Web
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and, on the other hand, is a strategy that everyone else in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has
already figured out and embraced. So the idea that the new approach is going to
rescue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> seems rather dubious.

            What's interesting about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX> story, though, is that it
represents an unusual intrusion of the things we've gotten used to about
offline business into the online world. Up to this point, with rare exceptions,
business on the Internet has seemed to exist in this fairy-tale realm where no
one ever gets fired, where expenses are irrelevant, and where all losses are
tolerated as simply necessary investments in the future. By eliminating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX>, cutting the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> it uses by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>, and admitting that
it's running through its capital much faster than originally planned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is essentially demonstrating what we all knew, but just weren't sure
when it would come true: Eventually, you have to earn a profit or else you'll
go under.

            Now, there are limits to the value, so to speak, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX> as a
cautionary tale. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, the site was never that popular, and even
now is only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">90th</NUMEX> most popular Web shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>. More important, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s everything-including-the-kitchen-sink strategy was ill-conceived,
especially for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that had no real brand name. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> to branch
out from books into CDs and then videos and then consumer electronics means one
thing. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX> to start by offering everything is another. And,
finally, there are Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, most notably--who are not just
running a business on hope, smoke, and mirrors; who have thought seriously
about their cost <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>; and understand things like return on invested
capital. That doesn't mean they will succeed, but it means they have a much
better chance than most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> out there.

            Even so, what's happening to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX> does have implications for the
Net as a whole, especially when so many Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> dumped <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX>
of dollars into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pre-Christmas</TIMEX> advertising with, by all accounts, very little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">payoff</ENAMEX> (relative to investment). And perhaps the most important thing to think
about is that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value America</ENAMEX> goes under, it increasingly looks like it will
do just that: go under and disappear. In other words, no one is going to come
along and acquire it, because ultimately there's really nothing there to
acquire. The conventional wisdom has been that eventually we'd see
consolidation in Net retailing through mergers and acquisitions. It's starting
to seem more likely that we'll see consolidation through failure.

         
      
   
