
   
   
      
         
            Signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligent Life</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>: I'd never accuse you of consciously formulating your reviews in
accordance with a political agenda. My fear, based on lifelong respect for your
writing and the early corruption of my morals by Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolls</ENAMEX> , is that the immense responsibility you've assumed could get in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of your having irresponsible fun. It would be OK if you hated South
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bigger</ENAMEX>, Longer 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Uncut</ENAMEX> ; what worried me was that you said
you felt guilty for having laughed. By the way, I missed the racism in that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>--unless it was the depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> as having crudely bisected
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eggheads</ENAMEX>. As for homophobia: I saw, on the contrary, a sophisticated gay/camp
worldview being slipped in through the back door. So to speak.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> is a more difficult case. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> clearly thought they
were satirizing fascism; you think they ended up celebrating it. My view is
closer to yours, but it's a tricky line. Some of the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> burrow so
deeply into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' twisted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">psyches</ENAMEX> that they risk making a case for
"the dark side." (A seminal masterpiece, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> , goes about
as deep as you can--and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think too deep.) A smart, twentysomething
former 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> tried to explain to me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that the
point of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> spends the whole movie punching
himself in the face. To him (and many others), this ironically brutal
confession of impotence sums up the messy, unresolved feelings of his
generation. I'm skeptical--I think the film's ironies are more opportunistic
than insightful. But I find it so much harder to dismiss than The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mile</ENAMEX> , which doesn't ever risk making the case for its evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldview</ENAMEX>--and so illuminates nothing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah: Lovely</ENAMEX> case for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sixth Sense</ENAMEX> , which had me bawling at the
end although it cheated like mad and I could smell the greasepaint on those
ghosts. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>-and-soul riff accounts for why the world through the prism of
movies seemed to open up toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this year</TIMEX>--to seem so fluid that
even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Destroyer</ENAMEX> had an out-of-body experience.

            By the way, I'm not your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>; I'm just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who camps here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-round</TIMEX>. I
admit I felt a little territorial when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movie Club</ENAMEX> started; now I'll be
lonely when the rest of you leave. I began on a note of hope for movies; I end
feeling hopeful about criticism.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jar Jar</ENAMEX> must die.

         
      
   
