
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Smirkology</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX>

            This just in (via e-mail) regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s smirk from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Carolina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Shelton Reed</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-edits Southern Cultures</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  The phenomenon has an easy explanation. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southerners</ENAMEX>. Southerners smile more than other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray L. Birdwhistell</ENAMEX>
has studied this, and discussed the misunderstandings that result.
               

               You're probably too young to recall that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> smiled all the time,
too. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Au</ENAMEX> contraire : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> cast his first-ever ballot for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> primary.] This spooked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, who feared
that he knew something they didn't. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> doesn't grin much is
eloquent testimony to the fact that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Alban</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and (at best)
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Marlette</ENAMEX> calls a faux <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bubba</ENAMEX>. And my theory is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> bites
his lip to keep from smiling.
               

            

            Chatterbox, who during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> immersion in the science of
nonverbal communication never came across the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birdwhistell</ENAMEX>, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
for more information about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birdwhistell</ENAMEX>'s work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> replied:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Birdwhistell</ENAMEX> was an anthropologist, late of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annenberg School</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, who pioneered what he called "kinesics," the
study of non-verbal communication. Unfortunately, he died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years ago</TIMEX> and I don't remember where I saw the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> about smiling, but I wrote it up for a book my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I did
called 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1001 Things Everyone Should Know About the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
                  . 
                  (It's No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">163</NUMEX>.)
               

               Here's my summary: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smiling</ENAMEX> appears to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> custom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birdwhistell</ENAMEX> found smiling among middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> most common in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>, and, last, western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. ... Such differences can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misunderstood</ENAMEX>: "In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> an unsmiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> might be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">queried</ENAMEX> as to whether he was 'angry about something,' while in another, the
smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> might be asked, 'What's funny?'"

            

            Chatterbox was unable to get his hands quickly on a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birdwhistell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">magnum opus, Kinesics and Context: Essays on Body Motion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communication</ENAMEX> , but he had no difficulty believing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birdwhistell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thesis</ENAMEX>, as summarized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had the kind of unctuous smile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with many southern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would say: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case</ENAMEX> closed.*
But, as has been widely noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s smile is a kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-grimace. This
leaves two possibilities:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s compulsion to smile is essentially southern, but the smile
itself is corrupted by other influences (a few possibilities were cited in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s previous
item) that transform it into a smirk;

            

            

               
                  or
               

            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s compulsion to smirk bears no relation to the southern
compulsion to smile , but is wholly the result of other phenomena.

            

            If the first possibility were correct, that would be good news for
the southern credentials of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush Sr.</ENAMEX>, since (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-Span</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Lamb</ENAMEX>
observed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> piece quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s
earlier
item) the smirk was clearly passed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> (acquiring some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exaggeration</ENAMEX> in the process). It will be remembered that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush Sr.</ENAMEX> was
never taken seriously by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>; he was criticized as being
"all hat and no cattle"--a transplanted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preppie</ENAMEX> who tried too hard.
But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birdwhistell</ENAMEX> theory explains (even in part) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s smirk, it
must perforce also explain (in part) the milder version worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sr.</ENAMEX>

            
               However, if the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> possibility were correct, then both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush Sr.</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>' southern identities would have to be called
into question. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> leans toward this latter interpretation, because he
can't recall ever seeing any true southerner smirk, not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivins</ENAMEX>; hers is a different kind of smile altogether. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birdwhistell</ENAMEX>, in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">travels</ENAMEX>, had been looking not for smiles but for smirks ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> strongly suspects he would have found lots of them on the
smile-barren <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>, especially in the vicinity of its prep schools
and Ivy League <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> . Here's a thought experiment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summon</ENAMEX> up a
mental image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali McGraw</ENAMEX>, the smirkiest performer in the history of the
movies. (If you need a little help, click here.) Now try to imagine her speaking with a southern accent.
Can't be done, can it?

            * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is well aware that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> resist attempts to classify
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> as southern, or western, or anything other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lone Star</ENAMEX>. For the
purposes of this discussion, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX>'s premise that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> are southerners.
            

         
      
   
