
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX> in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the upcoming caucuses in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and primary in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Issue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is predictions for the upcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are excited by the close presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>, especially in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> ) notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> raised about twice as much money as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last quarter</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is spending it furiously in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> are less sanguine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> can topple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, but many note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s fund raising, while well behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s clip, has increased substantially. Moreover, his lead in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> polls seems to be holding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> ) argue that no matter how well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> does in
the early primaries, the party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> will never let such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>
become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> argues that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> to win
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s nominations, independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> (that is, those not affiliated
with a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>) would have to become decisive, which is very unlikely in
the primaries. (For an opposing view, click here.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Oreskes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> matter at all: They represent a tiny fraction of nominating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>, and the value of their traditional spoils--such as early press
coverage--has diminished as other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have moved their primaries closer to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.  

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> muse on what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX> will bring. On
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, says that the successful
conquest of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> glitch bodes well for future technological hurdles.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX> hopes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX> brings greater
religious faith than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s ability to
overcome the political trauma of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> gives him hope that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> will be
just as "resilient" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian Doris Kearns Goodwin</ENAMEX> opines that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX> will provide more opportunity to help the poor. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> predicts that politics will
continue to be yoked to the whim of current events. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> predicts that
the globalization of society will render ideological differences obsolete in
the developed world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.J. Dionne</ENAMEX> predicts that the economic boom of the '90s
will lead to a period of social reform, much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded Age</ENAMEX> of the late 19th
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Era</ENAMEX>.

            

               Caressing the Hand that Feeds Him
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Morton</ENAMEX>, who ends each Late Edition show with a pithy
television essay on culture and politics, pokes fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> at the fatuous
use of millennial themes to sell products--from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Millennium Barbie</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M & M's</ENAMEX>, the "official candy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>," and so on.
After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> finishes and Late Edition host <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> Blitzer
signs off, there is a moment for station identification. That's right, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Parody</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MARK SHIELDS</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>, what were the great catastrophes of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOB NOVAK</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>, this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It could be bloody
totalitarian murderous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>, or
it just could be the intrusive, well-meaning socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> all over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scandinavia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. But this has been the blight of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>: too much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. And the hope of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX> is that
government will ease off. But looking around the world, I'm not that
optimistic. ... I would say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has done much more harm than good over
the world. And the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is [not responsible for] the social
engineering that we find--which was by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>, on a smaller level is
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>--[is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">preposterous</ENAMEX>].

            

               Last Word
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TONY SNOW</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ): When you get to heaven, who's going
to speak <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, you or God?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">REV. BILLY GRAHAM</ENAMEX>: When I get there, I'm sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is going to say
that he will welcome me. But I think that he's going to say: Well done, our
good and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful servant</ENAMEX>. Or he may say: You're in the wrong place.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SNOW</ENAMEX>: You really worry that you may be told you're in the wrong place?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRAHAM</ENAMEX>: Yes, because I have not--I'm not a righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> put me up
on a pedestal that I don't belong in my personal life. And they think that I'm
better than I am. I'm not the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think I am. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> and
magazines and television have made me out to be a saint. I'm not. I'm not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>. And I feel that very much.

         
      
   
