
   
   
      
         
            What's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Status</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Marriage</ENAMEX>?
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vermont Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> are entitled to
the same "benefits and protections" as heterosexual married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. Earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>'s high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> determined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was not required to
grant marriage licenses to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>. Why the different results? And
what legal effect will the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> decision have on the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>?

            Like virtually all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> have "equal protection"
clauses in their constitutions that guarantee all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> the same treatment
under the law. (These clauses are similar to the equal protection provision of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">U.S. Constitution</ENAMEX>'s 14th <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX>, which was used to secure civil rights
for racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.) In both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, gay couples
sued, asserting that the ban on same-sex marriage deprived them of equal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>: They argued that it blocked their access to the same rights and
obligations that heterosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> are granted through marriage, including
health and pension benefits, inheritance rights, joint decision-making power,
and shared parental and financial responsibilities.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled that, indeed, denial of same-sex
marriage amounted to discrimination on the basis of sex and sexual orientation.
Unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could demonstrate to lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> that it had a valid interest
in denying gay marriages, continued discrimination would be unconstitutional. A
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had failed to meet this requirement,
which seemed to pave the way for gay marriage. The state appealed, but before
the case reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> again, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> passed a constitutional
amendment exempting marriage from the equal protection clause. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court had no choice but to throw out the gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>' claims to marriage
licenses.

            With reasoning similar to that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vermont Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court determined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> "was constitutionally required to extend
to same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> the common benefits and protections that flow from marriage
under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> law." (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vermonters</ENAMEX> have not passed an amendment like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>'s
exempting marriage from the equal protection clause, although they could.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vermont Supreme Court</ENAMEX> left it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to decide whether to extend
these rights to gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> through state-recognized marriage or a new category
of domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> recognizes gay marriages, the national ramifications will be
immediate because all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> recognize marriages performed in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
Gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> would travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> to get married, and then upon returning
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, demand that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. 

            Anticipating this strategy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marriage Act</ENAMEX>" in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, declaring that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would not be compelled to recognize same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unions</ENAMEX>
performed elsewhere. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> decision, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have passed
preemptive laws saying they would not accept gay marriages from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> will have to decide whether these laws are constitutional. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> requires each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to give "full faith and credit ... to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public Acts, Records</ENAMEX>, and judicial Proceedings of every other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has held that this "full faith and credit" provision covers
divorce--otherwise, you might have to get re-divorced from your former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>
if you moved to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.  If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> extends the provision to
cover marriage, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Defense of Marriage Act</ENAMEX>--as well as the state laws
barring same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>--would quite likely be deemed unconstitutional. If not,
the issue would be left to each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to decide.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vermont</ENAMEX> declines to recognize gay marriage, it will have to define a new
category of domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> that provides precisely the same state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protections</ENAMEX> and benefits as marriage. But this domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> would not
necessarily yield rights for gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or from the federal
government. Many federal benefits and responsibilities depend on the "marriage"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classification</ENAMEX>, which has a privileged constitutional status that domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX> does not. Marriage is considered so fundamental a right, in fact,
that it cannot be withdrawn from any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>--even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>.

            Although the wording of constitutional equal protection clauses varies from
state to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>'s interpretation is not a binding precedent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
often look to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> for guidance on how to rule in similar
circumstances. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> ruling provides a basis for the argument that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">U.S. Constitution</ENAMEX>'s equal protection clause should be interpreted to
guarantee marriage rights for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> nationally. So, regardless of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX>'s course of action, gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> will use the ruling in
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> battles.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Slate readers</ENAMEX> for suggesting this
topic.
            

            Next question?

         
      
   
