
   
   
      
         
            Why <i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX></i> Comes but Once a Year
            

            
               It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> aired on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>--one of its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 1999</TIMEX> broadcasts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a few years ago</TIMEX>, the movie seemed to be shown on a
different channel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every day</TIMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX>. What
changed?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> copyright law determines who may distribute, display, or reproduce a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, a book, a drawing--essentially anything "fixed in a permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>," as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> like to say. Works not covered by copyrights--including ones with
copyrights that have expired and those that never secured this protection--are
said to be in the "public domain." These works, like the near-ancient Sherlock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> stories and some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX>'s silent films, can be reproduced,
broadcast, and sold freely.

            
               It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> entered the public domain by accident. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>,
when the movie was filmed, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> copyright protection lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 years</TIMEX> and could
be renewed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 28 years</TIMEX> by filing some paperwork and paying a nominal
fee. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic Pictures</ENAMEX>, the original copyright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> , neglected to renew the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> copyright in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. So, the
film entered the public domain. Though a box-office flop on release, it became
immensely popular on television thanks to repeated showings: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations</ENAMEX>
programmed it heavily during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>, paying no royalties to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> sold the movie on tape.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> regained control of the lucrative property in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> by flexing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling that determined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> of a
copyright to a story from which a movie was made had certain property rights
over the movie itself. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> still owned the copyrighted story behind
It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> and had also purchased exclusive rights to the
movie's copyrighted music, it was able to essentially yank the movie out of the
public domain: It claimed that since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> relied on these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">copyrighted</ENAMEX> works, the film could no longer be shown without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s
blessing. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technically</ENAMEX>, the film itself is not copyrighted. One could
hypothetically replace the music, rearrange the footage, and sell or show the
new product--but no one has done this.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>* signed a "long-term"
deal granting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> exclusive rights to broadcast the movie, and the network
typically does so between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and three</NUMEX> times a year.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX> won't re-enter the public domain for quite a while.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has repeatedly expanded copyright protections and made them effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retroactively</ENAMEX>. Most recently, at the behest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> and other large media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> with soon-to-expire copyrights, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> added <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> to all
existing copyright claims. They now stand at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95 years</TIMEX> for copyrights held by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. (The copyright protection for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
lasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> beyond their deaths.) Thus, showings of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX>
will remain limited well into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>.

            *In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>'s parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spelling Entertainment</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>), sold the rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>'s film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> to Artisan
Entertainment.

            Next question?

         
      
   
