
   
   
      
         
            Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s charge in an interview with the paper
that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> would endanger the economic expansion and risk
"blundering into another recession" because he would take the entire projected
surplus over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 10 years</TIMEX> and "just blow it" on health-care reform. The
paper has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s charge makes it obvious he lacks
confidence in his own agenda. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> also fronts campaign jousting by the two
but goes instead with a momentous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> decision: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> that
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to work at home will be held responsible for federal health and
safety violations that occur at the home work site. The stance, explains the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , would mean that even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> just occasionally takes work
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with him to attend to a sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are still required to make
sure that he/she has ergonomically correct furniture and proper lighting and
ventilation in the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story, adding in details about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but leads with the onset in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-moderated
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> talks, which is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead and which is
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fronted</ENAMEX> elsewhere. The same picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farouk Shara</ENAMEX> walking together
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX> all the fronts that carry photos.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> report that the meetings hit a snag quickly when an
anticipated face-to-face between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shara</ENAMEX> didn't come off. Both also
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will not attend every session but will be available to
return whenever circumstances warrant. So serious are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> about
breaking with their past tendencies to leak at such talks, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, that
they've promised to eschew cell phone calls.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts and the others report inside that acting
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> has fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> from her
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>'s post. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> treat the move as
only cosmetic, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her tight little circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family</ENAMEX>" retaining the power over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX> widely thought to
have brought him into his present circumstance. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> s quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> from an interview in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> paper
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> did not want to resign but was pushed out by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> of this
inner circle including his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" front reports an apparent consequence of not much
bang for the TV advertising bucks spent by dot-coms over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas holiday</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dot</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">com advertisers</ENAMEX> are starting to bail out of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> ad placements. Into
the breach, says the paper, may step <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, which has never advertised
during the big game.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story inside about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> is thrilled that it came through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> unscathed even
though it was probably one of the last developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to take the problem
seriously. But the story doesn't prove that doing nothing was the way to go;
actually, it explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> took quite a few precautions, but almost all
at the very last minute. So further reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> experience is not
likely to show that preparedness was a waste but rather perhaps that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">optimal</ENAMEX> strategy included a healthy dose of procrastination.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's lead editorial
defending the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> preparedness effort both mention a great feel-good solution
for anybody who went a touch too wacknoid with the tuna and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spam</ENAMEX> inventories:
Give it to places that feed the poor. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> doesn't ask much from its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, but is asking now: Please do this.

            With the economy at full throttle, it would be easy to forget that not
everybody has been able to make the trip. Thank goodness the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> helps remember the neediest. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Journal front recounts
the sad saga of a onetime <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>-a-year <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, who risked it
all--his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, his trips
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>--to join an Internet startup. But he found himself under a more
demanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> than he was used to and got fired before he got a chance to
exercise any stock options. To economize, he had to cancel his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s annual
vacation and his son's guitar lessons. He's now working for an internet outfit
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> plus stock options.

            The LAT business front reports that when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> re-launched its Web
site over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, it found it had inadvertently featured something
new--sex books. As a result of downloading a database of titles from a
third-party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> was suddenly able to offer
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best of Gay Adult Videos</ENAMEX> (got 'em) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Couple's Guide to</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best Erotic Videos</ENAMEX> (need 'em).

         
      
   
