
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plane Truth</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with late developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Airlines</ENAMEX> hostage
crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> sent an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to meet with the hijackers, an
indication that they were looking for ways to end the crisis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the speedy trial, conviction, and sentencing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> spiritual movement, banned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 22</TIMEX> as "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> on the society." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead documents increased <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> sales toward the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year's end</TIMEX>. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> tops its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World-Wide"</ENAMEX> column with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s most aggressive
attempt yet to seize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grozny</ENAMEX>, a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-leads.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hijackers</ENAMEX> set a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:40 p.m.</TIMEX> deadline (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:10 a.m. PT</TIMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> to respond to
demands, namely the release of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kashmiri</ENAMEX> separatist and religious leader
imprisoned there since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that finger-pointing among the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> has
begun before the crisis's resolution. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> have accused each
other of orchestrating the whole thing; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> does not recognize, wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> out of its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> mediation
in. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> did not want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">help</ENAMEX>. Eventually, the hijackers agreed to leave
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> checked up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and persuaded the hijackers to release a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diabetic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have delivered food to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, but
conditions are worsening. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that there were still 161
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> counts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with a
conservative "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 150</NUMEX>."

            The nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> trial--that is, artifice--betrays the
government's intolerance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of its ruling party who belong to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>: All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> accused were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
reports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> sentences range from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Chang</ENAMEX>, a police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ministry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who helped organize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>-person silent
demonstration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April, to seven years</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yao Jie</ENAMEX>, the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, who was charged as an accomplice. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> were officially accused of
using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to undermine law, contributing to the deaths of some
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were taught to avoid modern medicine, and obtaining and
dispersing information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s crackdown on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            Y2K fears have contributed to an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> sales, a trend that gun
industry marketing has to some extent encouraged, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>
Combat sells a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Millennium Protector .45 Automatic</ENAMEX> for self-defense, against
whom or what it is unclear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authorities</ENAMEX> conducted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a million</NUMEX> background
checks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.7 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">95 mph</NUMEX> wind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> swept through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champs-Élysées</ENAMEX>, the rest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">northern France</ENAMEX>, and parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, according to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">As many as 62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are believed dead in the rare
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">hurricane</ENAMEX>-strength storm.

            An article in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does more than lambaste <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
for using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elian Gonzalez</ENAMEX> to advance their own interests. The writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traces Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>'s behavior through a sordid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four-and-</NUMEX>a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> year
international tug-of-war for his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> left him for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, taking along their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> requested that his son visit
him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> and promised, "as a gentleman," to return him in two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelito</ENAMEX> in the charge of his inner circle. The boy
would be abducted again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks later</TIMEX> and returned to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>
rose to power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, he took back his son, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> and living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s reasons for demanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidelito</ENAMEX>'s return resemble those currently
claimed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The lesson: "The shattered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is the emblem
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>." The revolution has ripped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> apart, not the
least of which is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s own.

            By contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "Marketplace" section that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can't get enough of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Unauthorized trips have jumped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>
percent a year in recent memory. "Loopholes in the travel ban wide enough to
sail a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> through," not to mention the attraction of taboo, encourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to explore any of a catalog of ways to get to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>: enlist as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">educator</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>, sail in from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX>, or fly in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has fined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> since the
travel embargo kicked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36 years ago</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business</ENAMEX>" section piece looks at the evolution of Internet
news sites, which now "include speedy, professional crafting of original
material, multimedia options, clean packaging and lots of self-promotion." How
does the article's own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> version compare with this description? There's no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multimedia</ENAMEX> option, and the self-promotion simply falls like a brick at the end,
but best of all--no inky fingers.

         
      
   
