
   
   
      
         
            Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>,

            You're completely right about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>: Why could she possibly have to leave
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> show early? Since she was taping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and it was
pushing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>, I have to assume it was a dinner. (With whom? Where? Are you
allowed to bring your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Craig</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powders</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spago</ENAMEX>?) I was delighted that she
was replaced on camera with my favorite infomercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Robbins</ENAMEX>. As an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insomniac</ENAMEX> and a borderline depressive, I'm the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target audience</ENAMEX> for his
pitch. And by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of each half-hour</TIMEX> spiel--whether it's the one where he's
being "interviewed" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeza Gibbons</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran Tarkenton</ENAMEX>--I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> ready to call
in for the tapes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, if it worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levar Burton</ENAMEX>, I'm there dude. You know,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, it's more than just a pep talk. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s tapes are a scientific
system.

            The other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> thing that struck me is this crazy immunity agreement she
struck with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. She's basically not allowed to criticize him. Apparently,
their deal is so sweeping in what she can't say about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Independent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> that she essentially gave up her <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> rights. This leaves
her in a truly sad position (no jokes, please): She has to share her weight
with the world and go public to pay her legal bills for an insane case and yet
when she has the public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> she can't scream: Eat me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>. (Or the
other way around.)

            You see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>? This is one of those regulatory
rulings that sets liberalism back a generation. Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX> has ruled that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work at home--even if it's just for a day to take care of a sick
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kid</ENAMEX>--have to be provided with all the workplace safety stuff that they'd get on
the job--proper ventilation, ergonomically correct chairs, etc. You think I can
expense a new pair of slippers?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> threat is underrated, I agree. After "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead or Alive"</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idi Amin</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alive</ENAMEX>!), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudette Colbert</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead</ENAMEX>!)--one of my favorite parlor games is "Are
they <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>?" Some are easy--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shatner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty Hall</ENAMEX>. But there are tough
ones: I can usually win when I announce, to a stunned dinner table, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrick Utley</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>.

            I know you endured the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley-Gore</ENAMEX> speeches, but we should try to catch the
debates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. I predict that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week's end</TIMEX>, a desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, with his
awkward emphasis on the wrong syllable and haltingly condescending voice will
announce: "You know, my WI-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper</ENAMEX>, was born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-nited States</ENAMEX>. There's
NO <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> goosestepping in our family tree." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will reply with long passages
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Prather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Putnam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalil Gibran</ENAMEX>. He's sooooo
thoughtful.

            Later.
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
