
   
   
      
         
            It Ain't Broke ...
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jim</ENAMEX>,

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Journalism in Crisis</ENAMEX>." It sounds like the title to any number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pew Charitable Trust</ENAMEX> seminars, doesn't it? But I don't really buy it. To these
weary eyes, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism has never been smarter and more accurate than
it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Not perfect, mind you, or tweezer-headed nitpicking press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
like you and me would have nothing to carp about. But I'll put <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> up against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> of any era you can name.

            And never in the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism has the media been more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scrutinized</ENAMEX>. Just look at the list of media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> listed in the right gutter
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MediaGossip</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> Web site! Or at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Draconian</ENAMEX> investigations of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> conducted by Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX>. There's hardly a conflict
of interest or press indiscretion that goes unexamined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.

            While it's true that newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> are shrinking, that decline has
nothing to do with the imagined crisis that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> warns about in What Are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> For? The newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and the number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
have been steadily shrinking since the advent of radio in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, and every
time a new technology rolls into the mix--TV, cable, the VCR, satellite, video
games, the Internet--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> contracts a wee bit more. A lot of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that folded were rotten and deserved to die, a sentiment that many
left-wing press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> will endorse. And while I can cite no academic study,
I'd wager that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> who looks at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or a
newsmagazine, listens to all-news radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> during his commute, and
catches a little TV news and talk radio at home is better informed than his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> from any era of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX>'s choosing. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> isn't thriving
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, it might have to do with the fact that it isn't paying attention to
the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live.

            At the same time, I believe that the appetite for serious journalism has
grown. The best marker of this trend is the popularity of national daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and the New York
Times , and TV shows such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes and Nightline</ENAMEX> . Even
the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuharth USA Today</ENAMEX> shines brighter than most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> from
earlier eras. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's dirty little secret is that it invented Web
journalism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>: Succinct stories; dazzling graphics; nice weather map;
up-to-date ball scores; gossip; breaking news; regional info dumps; user
friendly interface--i.e., a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that is in touch with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.)

            To your point that campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> coverage is poor, focusing on trivial
matters--let's not automatically blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. Take, for example, the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, whose political differences can be measured
with a micromicrometer. How would you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> cover that contest any
differently than they are now?

            Let me toss <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more idea on the fire as I walk out the door: The notion
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have "lost touch with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>" is utter bunk. It's
been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a generation</TIMEX> since the majority of the newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> hailed
from the lunch-pail and straphanger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, are better-educated and more skeptical about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> than
were their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that
they're exceedingly skeptical about--bless their hearts--is the press. This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>'s golden age.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, seeing as we both punched our tickets at alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weeklies</ENAMEX>, you at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> and me at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington City Paper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> , maybe we should talk about what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> could learn from
the alties. Many of the public journalism innovations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> wants
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to experiment with--commitment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, initiating
"dialogues" with the citizenry, and abandoning objectivity--are practiced
routinely at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> top markets. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> can find a
list of them at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>
of Alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newsweeklies</ENAMEX> Web site.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Regards,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
