
   
   
      
         
            How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC Exacerbates Stock-Price Swings</ENAMEX>
            

            OK, so on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> stocks really do go in just one direction (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dot-Com Mania Is</ENAMEX>
More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Selective Than You Think</ENAMEX>"). In any case, even though all we're going
to get for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next 24 hours</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX>) are a parade of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> offering
up a host of explanations for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s massive sell-off in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>, the best rule to follow is just to assume that all those explanations will
be wrong, or at the very least inadequate. Sell-offs can get triggered for one
reason and continue for different reasons, they can reflect genuine changes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' ideas about the future or simply panic, and so on. Short-term market
moves are, almost by definition, impossible to parse successfully.

            Having said that--and you knew this was coming, didn't you?--there are a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of interesting things to note about what happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is
the resurgence of the idea that rising interest rates actually do matter to
stock prices. (I'll have a piece on this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is that when
something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s sell-off happens, it makes obvious the extent to which,
in the short term, you can no longer separate the event from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s
coverage of the event.

            What I mean by this is that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s sell-off does not happen in a vacuum. On
the contrary, thanks to the spread of the Internet and the rise to prominence
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> and, above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>, the sell-off occurs with real-time commentary,
real-time commentary that is already, almost before the fact, labeling what's
occurring as "a sell-off," a "prelude to a correction," or "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> prick of
the tech-stock bubble." And this is commentary that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who are
making the decisions that will either continue or end the sell-off are hearing
as they are trying to make those decisions. In other words, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is
saying becomes part of the information that is influencing how stock prices are
determined.

            This matters because the true magic of a market, as I've written
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about before</TIMEX>, is the ability of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">collective</ENAMEX>, but decentralized,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> to reach conclusions that are smarter--more accurate--than the
conclusions any single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the market could reach, which offers some
evidence for this. That's why markets are better at allocating capital and
setting prices than any planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> ever could be. The problem is that most
of the experimental evidence on collective decision-making shows that groups
make better decisions when each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> reaches his or her decision
independently of everyone else. In other words, it's not through an open debate
or an attempt to reach a consensus that the best conclusion is reached. It's
only through the aggregation of independent individual conclusions that it
is.

            But when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX> is running a show called "Special: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Sell-off," and
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> are doing real-time commentary from the market floor talking about
how "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>" are feeling, it becomes much harder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to reach an
independent decision about the only question they should actually be
considering: What are these stocks actually worth? This is, again, a
signal-to-noise problem (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going Bananas</ENAMEX>
Over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stock Splits"</ENAMEX>). The signal is material information about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>'
future earnings prospects, about interest rates, and about inflation. Noise is
just about everything else. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s media-saturated investing
environment, the short-term noise can be overpoweringly loud.

            In the long run, hard as it may be to believe, this does not matter. (Which
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why bubble talk is overblown.) But in the short run, it's a
recipe for increased volatility. So huge price swings are probably with us to
stay. Yet another good reason not to adopt a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>'s mentality.

         
      
   
