
	
		
			
				The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story Continues</ENAMEX> . . . a serial enovel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferd Eggan</ENAMEX>
			
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Welcome</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Real DesertÂ</ENAMEX> 
			But he never fell into the error of arresting his intellectual
				development by any formal acceptance of creed or system, or of
				mistaking, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in which to live, an inn that is but suitable for
				the sojourn of a night in which there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and the moon is in
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">travail</ENAMEX> . . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
			
			The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel</ENAMEX>
			Hotel is next door to a perfect metaphor for the mind, and thus for
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychoanalysis</ENAMEX>. In my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> are many mansionsâ€¦To get there you
				have to leave somewhere elseâ€¦Â 
			Outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EuroDisney</ENAMEX>, on the road the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> block to hold up the
				prices of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europroduce</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Real Desert</ENAMEX>. Once a busy place
				recommended to savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> ("I travel in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s undergarments, and
				I always feel I can let my hair down here--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Foucault</ENAMEX>.)
				offering ersatz <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> vistas of
				bacteriostatic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Desert</ENAMEX> has in
				recent times had to take on the faded but patinated glamour of a
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">residential</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, on an inconvenient exit ramp on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> from
				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.
			Signs read: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Welcome to Hotel Real Desert</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free PsychoAnalytic</ENAMEX>
				Consultations! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> Vegetarian Gourmandise! Last <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Resort</ENAMEX> Before
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disney</ENAMEX>!
			The triumphant clucking of bouffanted small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> has
				all but silenced, or more accurately, is hushed by the uncomprehending
				sullen stares of adolescent louts sweating over video game joysticks,
				deafening themselves with third-rate rap in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Marsailles French</ENAMEX>.
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Casino</ENAMEX> Atroce
			Human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> learn to perceive this inherently fluid, relative domain
				in terms of fixed, solid objects existing within fixed structures of
				space and time. (a pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newtonian</ENAMEX> view, really) whereas the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>-child's rudimentary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perceptual</ENAMEX> processes are more consistent with
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s relativistic discoveries<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX>
			
			
			You sat in the casino <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Snivilling Sibbling</ENAMEX> (sic), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
				night cooling your heels in the turbid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">oasis</ENAMEX> waters flowing under the
				barstools, as the albino bartender washed glasses and practiced flipping
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">vodka</ENAMEX> bottles. An evil young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> pacified a colicky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> with wine
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spritzers</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> bottle. Your revulsion at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s ministrations
				to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, at her "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Love Satan" t-shirt</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX>-congealed pommes frites <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Liberte</ENAMEX>--or perhaps it was
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abreaction</ENAMEX> to the bass tones of the hip hop muzak and the screams
				emanating from the serial-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> video games--overwhelmed you. You
				pulled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX> in the powder <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and urged her to hold
				back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, trying to explain that she didn't have to revenge
				herself on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.
			"What is she but a vessel to be filled, a flesh bubble around <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lack?</ENAMEX>"
				the vixen asked. "And who am I, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>?" She continued in
				that untuned a capella vibrato that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> take for soulful singing
				<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Momma</ENAMEX>, I tried,
			Momma, I couldn't stop the tide of tears, just like you I cried,
			The world had lied, had took away our pride, the slow, sad slide
			Of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that offer light girls a ride, a hookup but never a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>, Momma
			I'd of died.
			But you cared for me, shared bare necessity with me, dissed Felicity
				with me, preyed God above for me, .."
			"Stop, stop," you sobbed. "How can you say that? You're white, for
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>'s sake!"
			With a certainty that it's better never to have been born than to be as
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hapless</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, you tied her off and injected her with a killing
				dose of fentanyl. As you left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> was wobbling
				around the coffee table, the nipple of her bottle clenched in her teeth;
				almost no one turned from the video screens to see you on the way out.
			The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Thinks</ENAMEX>
			"Where'd <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana K.</ENAMEX> go?"
			"Is this another one of the learning experiences I am expected to
				undergo--to suffer? I guess the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> my age have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
				extra neurons is so we can learn. I suppose that as a neonate I had
				little choice in what happened to me and must have felt breast, warmth,
				wetness, fullness without clear ideas of internal vs. external origins.
				Do I need to repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lacan</ENAMEX> here cf. the symbolic stage w/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piaget</ENAMEX>'s
				sensorimotor stage of "functional recognition;" e.g., recognition that
				something is "for drinking or "for wetness.."
			[She waddles over to the table and pulls a disposable diaper out of a
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Minnie Mouse</ENAMEX> tote bag. Lying on her back on the floor, she pulls off her
				used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pamper</ENAMEX> and replaces it with the fresh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.]
			"Oh, the joy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc ozide</ENAMEX>,!" she burbles "Although I've never seen a
				penis, I expect it's like carrying around a faucet. I've having a time
				finding the muscles to pee as it is. I'm operating the circular reflex:
				an outgoing impulse (e.g., leading to the contraction of a muscle)
				followed not mainly by the satisfaction of
				need, but rather by some incoming sensory impulse (e.g., in the eye,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">urethra</ENAMEX>, etc.)" [Pressing down the self-adhesive flaps, she sits up,
				bottle still in her mouth, and muses.]
			"Now, however, my babyhood seems to require concentrated efforts to
				construct myself, learning to be me seeing, hearing, talking and
				walking. I begin to take pleasure in operating the circular reflex 'to
				produce interesting spectacles<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>'
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX>-sized mentations of accomplishment, frustration, satisfaction,
				deprivation attach themselves to the sensations and form the bases of my
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, anger, etc. But the way they grow has to mean that what I will
				learn to call emotions are very dense mixtures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> and
				interpretation in narrative form: I feel sad because <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> happened. X
				happened because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> did Z to me or I did Z (to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX>) Someday I will know
				that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX> says innate human grammar requires subject, verb, and
				usually object--that our human brains are wired to view and thus to talk
				about the world in this way--although not necessarily in this order.
				Here adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudians</ENAMEX> will be bound to object: 'Baby, you are conflating
				organic brain with functional mind.' I dismiss this as reifying a purely
				mental phenomenon; plus it's too confounding for my developmental stage.
			"Instead I will consider a feeling I have begun to feel now: I am sad.
				An explanation will arise very quickly. I feel sad because (I am sure by
				then I will be able to imagine some causal relationship between my body,
				my bottle, and the disappearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>). I'm reminded of previous
				times I have felt sad and I will connect them into a series by way of
				the synaptic corridors they pass through. The sad-ness itself will
				already be an explanation of a somatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> or mental phenomenon.
				Sensations are on my skin or the virtual skin, emotions are
				already-processed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sensations</ENAMEX> or mental phenomena S/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> + (pleasure,
				satisfaction, warmth, i.e. security) = feeling OK. Wet diaper +
				disappeared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insecurity</ENAMEX> = feeling bad
			[She stumbles, the bottle between her hands, held up to release the
				<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> drops.]
			"I have to say parenthetically that this new stuff in the bottle
				affects the feel of things in a big way.
			"Even now, my feeling OK is associated with events and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; gotta
				love them (or want them or hate or fear them). These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> will
				become progressively more elaborate as I accumulate more experience.
				Soon I can say 'I feel I am cold and contemptuous of others because I am
				afraid to experience their rejection of me,' or 'I love him because he
				makes me feel secure and confident and wanted.' The explanations will
				not particularly help in feeling better if one feels 'bad;' conversely,
				trying to feel 'good' will not seem to be enhanced by good explanations.
				I will live through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">therapists</ENAMEX> encouraging me to experience my
				psychic wounds, my feelings, with the idea that I can achieve a state of
				being in which pain can be experienced without debilitating
				consequences.
			"I will ask now, while I have extra synapses, isn't it the narrative
				itself that inscribes the scars on our minds, our hearts, my future
				razor-cut adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. I wonder if it just wouldn't be better to
				skip the pain altogether."
			[She slips, falls on her back, unconscious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urine</ENAMEX> spreads in a pool
				toward the frayed electrical cord of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ghost Town</ENAMEX> slot
				machine.]
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rm</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1453</TIMEX> MonaLisa of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert</ENAMEX>.
			Gazing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde de Disney</ENAMEX> parking lot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MonaLisa</ENAMEX> sits framed in her
				window, an ultralite cigarette in her hand, her arms supporting her
				gravity-afflicted breasts, once <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lunar melons</ENAMEX>, now barely able to plump
				up over the mass of her moist <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and the aluminum sill, cooling in the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moonlight</ENAMEX>. Her face, the face on which the ends of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> have come
				and gone, is not pensive, not secretly smiling, but cowed by the
				suffering she has felt and is all too sure to feel again. She has taken
				it on as weight; the excess of everything gradually pulled her pelvis
				out of tilt, her bowels out of line, her womb a little adrift. She has
				just returned, in fact, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where she lay under the knife
				for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours</TIMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> hewed away adhesions, occlusions and
				finally her ovaries and a pear-shaped mass of no longer definable
				fibrous tissue. Hers is the face of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, drugged out of pain and
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sorrow</ENAMEX>, drifting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demerol</ENAMEX>. She felt something <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours ago</TIMEX> when she
				came to her full animal consciousness, her autonomic systems in full
				alarm at this latest outrage on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> believes she has nearly
				fulfilled her aspiration to drama-less calm. "I need to keep my head
				straight," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> says to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">moonlight</ENAMEX>, "no more nut-rolling on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novy</ENAMEX> or
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>."
			
			"I shall grow another breast
			in the middle of my chest
			what shall it be
			
			not like the other ones lying there
			those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>.
			
			in the center of my flesh
			I shall grow another breast
			rounder than a ready fist,
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slippery</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>,
			sounder than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>. Call it
			She - Who - educates my chest.
			
			She Who.
			
			She is not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, not my son
			I'm going to groom her with my tongue
			needle her senses with my pain
			feed her hunches with my brain,
			
			She Who defends me<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>"
			
			"It's a good thing I already had my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>," she reassures herself.
				The first glowed with the iridescent colors of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a conch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX>, of a
				pussy, opening all shiny <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pinks</ENAMEX>, golden hair and sunlit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>,
				sick with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">junkie pneumonia</ENAMEX>, had to give her up--a junkie ho would only
				victimize her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, they told her. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s sun faded in the dark and
				clammy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s minging care. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,
				now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX>, had the better luck of being born in a prison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
				and fostered out to a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> with money and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and compassionate
				love. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> is thrilled to have her here on a visit now, just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>,
				unable to imagine inadequacies in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, pleased with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>, with
				herself and with the still-pink <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she has just learned is her older
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
			This, then, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> come at great pain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> was driven
				to sobriety by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> once handed over to her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, then
				taken back (at the teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s insistence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>'s sister was not
				a supportive--i.e. generous--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>). Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> was then abandoned again
				when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> returned temporarily to her dank previous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where
				she became a gibbering speed freak, an auto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>, a fugitive, and
				generally white trash. She and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> share one trait, an ability to
				recount the episodes when they were maimed and deprived of the halcyon
				life they believe is available to normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. "While she's here, I
				have to get her head straight, too," thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>, believing for a moment
				that she is in charge of a life, any life.
			
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rm</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1789</TIMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Tract</ENAMEX>
			
			Lemmy Caution checks in. He immediately boots up his computer and hooks
				into the net. Routing through several nodes, he finds that a message is
				waiting, has been waiting for quite a while.
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> starless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> much like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemmy</ENAMEX> stumbled out of the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burg Frieden</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PrinzLauerBurg</ENAMEX>, then still E <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drunk</ENAMEX>, unable to
				move his tongue, desperately lonely, he fell into the rainy gutter. When
				he woke, a piece of paper was twisted in his mouth. Dried out, he read
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ask, what is the nature of the revolution that we talk about.
				Who will it be made by, and for, and what are its goals and strategy?
			
			We are within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX> of a world-wide monster, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so rich
				from its world-wide plunder that even the crumbs doled out to the
				enslaved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> within its borders provide for material existence very
				much above the conditions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the world. . . All
				of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines Astrojets</ENAMEX>, all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inns</ENAMEX>, all of
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX>, your television set, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and wardrobe already
				belong, to a large degree to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the rest of the world. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
			
			
			He's been committed ever since, a clandestine freedom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">autonomous</ENAMEX>, placing his devices alone or with a few other cadres,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchanging</ENAMEX> plans and ideological instruction only through safe message
				drops. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, it was easier, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> were very astute
				in their description of their <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">People's War</ENAMEX> and the centrality of the
				anti-colonial struggle against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> imperialism. At first he exchanged
				tangible letters, paper signs of struggle. These new electronic messages
				are harder to actualize in practice, and the post-socialist world of
				global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> far harder to conceptualize in terms of improvement and
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barbarism</ENAMEX>. A while ago, this:
			The deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> ended our military conception of what we
				are doing. It took us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of careful talking to rediscover our roots,
				to remember that we had been turned on to the possibilities of
				revolution by denying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, the jobs the death relationships we
				were "educated" for. We went back to how we had begun living with groups
				of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and fount that this revolution could leave intact the
				enslavement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> did not fight to end and change it,
				together . . .And marijuana and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> and little money and awakening to
				the black revolution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the world. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
			
			
			But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in way too long, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemmy</ENAMEX> is to meet his
				closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrade</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oedipa Maas</ENAMEX> is the slinky trans <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> who first
				turned on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tania Hearst</ENAMEX>, later turning on to more productive
				anti-globalization struggles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemmy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipa</ENAMEX> have not seen each other
				since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. As he sets out the sling and the dildos, he sings, "the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories</ENAMEX> would walk right by me<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>"
				Perceiving the onset of hallucination from the soma, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemmy</ENAMEX> voices an
				instant message into his netserver, hoping this will be sufficient
				political struggle for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, as unsure as he is about
				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">inter/intra</ENAMEX>-gender sexual relations.
			Laughing.
			Laughing.
			Laugh.
			Couldn't stop laughing. . .
			at my own everyday pomposity,
			the narrow arrogance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>,
			the impudence of the rational,
			the smug naivetÃ© of words in contrast
			to the raw rich ever-changing panoramas that flooded my brain<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
			
			
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lemmy</ENAMEX> shuts down the computer; the door chimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipa</ENAMEX> makes her
				appearance.
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
			My Dreams
			"Sauvez ce qui pleure" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Eluard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Capital de Douleur</ENAMEX>
			
			A long dream of tortureâ€¦my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> wanted to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eubie</ENAMEX>, our youngest
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. My middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake</ENAMEX> and I had to protect him. After many
				suspenseful but mystifying clashes, everything was over--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was dead.
				Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> came in and stabbed me repeatedly and then I was transferred
				to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">torturersâ€¦blood</ENAMEX>, piercings, exhaustion. Terror before pain, then
				no strong painâ€¦Masturbated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>--ucs. Guilt? I can't let the
				murder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> happen--too much guilt if it does. . . Ethics from
				guilt. Conscious memories of tender care for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eubie</ENAMEX>.
			For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX>, the west has twisted in the meshes of a
				pre-lapsarian dream: if only I hadn't been psychically wounded in
				childhood I'd be all right, I'd have a healthy self.
			My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> had many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>. When he died we had to empty the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> and divide up his accumulations and all I got was this lousy
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX>.
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>, all bowing down to me . . .
			No really, I dream myself flustered by urgency and loss . . .need to
				prevent disasters. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eubie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> wanted to ride his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX>. I needed Eubie
				to drive me to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noe School</ENAMEX> to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who knew what I needed to
				know. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delay</ENAMEX>, excruciating wait while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> is put on the rack . . . I
				searched the tall <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> under the eaves, strewn with papers and junk,
				searching, searching for the paper with the phone number . . . calling
				information, getting a number, not clear whether it's the number for an
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> or a direct line. . . the phone is different. . . my mother
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">said 'nothing</ENAMEX>'s changed" . . . I get hysterically angry: 'look at the
				numbers on the phone. Are they different or not?' 'Yes, they are,' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MabelRuth</ENAMEX> admits things have changed. . . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jabbering</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> from the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roofers</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> . . . a gas-sputtering lawnmower, clattering
				against the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> . . . I'm in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. . . I know it's not my real
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> but it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> invaded by lying hoodlums . . . who will be hurt
				next? . . .
			I think our human brains are an evolutionary accident. The difference
				between chimp and human brains is very significant in terms of size
				and--over time--has led to marked differences in cognition if not
				perception. The difference does not look like the results of any
				evolutionary pressure. The random gene changes that led to a much larger
				brain do not seem to offer survival advantage commensurate with the
				energy expenditure required to supply it. I conclude that our brain
				began as a genetic mishap, for no more purpose than that apportioned to
				any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, mineral or vegetable.
			I am kissing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake</ENAMEX>. . . now I love him . . . he reluctantly
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surrenders</ENAMEX> to his love for me. . . his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is beautiful, athletic, warm
				and welcoming . . . his mouth softly moving, thrilling, familiar . . .
				his baseball hands, his football legs . . I realize now that I wasn't
				jealous of him because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> liked him best, but of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake</ENAMEX>
				liked him more than me . . . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX> sees us kissing and me lying on top,
				getting ready to fuck . . .maybe it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake</ENAMEX> on top . . . he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> .
				. . she tells him it's ok. . .
			"We shall see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> engaged in attractive occupations, giving no
				thoughts to material wants, free from all pecuniary cares and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX>.
				As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all work, there will be no idlers, all will earn
				more than they consume. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> happiness and gaiety will reign. A
				unity of interests and views will arise, crime and violence disappear.
				There will be no individual dependence---no private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>, only
				maids, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX>, and so forth all working for all (when they please).
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elegance</ENAMEX> and luxury will be had by all<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>".
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
			The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clouds Above the Real Desert</ENAMEX>
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> in contemplation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cloud of Unknowing</ENAMEX> is the cloud of
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrons</ENAMEX> around the nucleus--here/not here, energy/matter-- either,
				depending on what's happening, the universe's rules of operation. A
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Tree</ENAMEX> grows even in this unreal desert, cells grow,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photosynthesis</ENAMEX>, the works. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, as the rule of the physical
				universe would have it, reflects light. In the universe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> inhabit,
				reflecting light is a necessary result of the assemblage of matter on
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>--necessary also to the survival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and to its presence
				among other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, rocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>." Pumping his harmonium, he sings:
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Tree</ENAMEX>
			
			that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about fifteen feet</NUMEX> tall
			tree tissue organized to move <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> from root to crown
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osmotic</ENAMEX> pressure, umm ..hmm, and transpiration through the leaves
			
			we are to presume that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> knows nothing
			--it has no brain--
			it's more primitive than "real" trees
			but it can repair itself, and it can react
			--slowly, I say, umm . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hmm</ENAMEX>--
			to phenomena, emergent or adverse.
			
			its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are sensitive to the pressures (pleasures):
			quickening sap and warm breezes
			reflecting light greenly
			the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Tree</ENAMEX> fallaciously, pathetically,
			likes afternoon light,
			likes being seen
			just so, just so . .umm..hmm
			by discriminating coyotes and quails.
			
			"I wish I knew enough to assert clearly that this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spinozan10</TIMEX>, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kantian</ENAMEX>, idea of human perception as a
				necessary and proportionate interaction of human body with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>,
				obviates any quibbling about whether or not matter is just our idea of
				things."
			[The] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">discernment</ENAMEX> of relatively invariant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and processes and
				the creation of mental maps where the key coordinates map relatively
				stable things, . . may be the most practical way to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> on this
				planet--else why would we make the mistake of believing in solidity and
					<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fixity</ENAMEX>?11
			
			
			"Else why do we? I want to assert that molecules, atoms, photons,
				electrical and chemical energy, make us see
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Tree</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> gives: it 'trees' to us. We see it: we can't
				help it, the rods and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cones</ENAMEX> react to light, the reactions excite a few
				cells, then more and more. Brain studies seem to indicate that the
				excitations are not on/off--not digital, but analog--the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotransmitters</ENAMEX> and electrical flow are emergent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> of the
				eye-brain-mind process that are modulable over an infinite range, not
				merely by quantifiable increments of cell firings and cell non-firings.
				And they are not yet coded, nor are they in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>. Afterwards,
				apparently <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">500 milliseconds</TIMEX> after, we are looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and
				utilizing previous neural pathways in relation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
			"Only then are we 'affected' by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, and only then do we cogitate
				an idea, which is coded, is in symbols, of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'tree</NUMEX>.' No part of this is
				any more or less 'real' or objective. It must take active work to look
				at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>: the reception of minimal sensory input is necessary not
				sufficient by itself to arouse attention, our eye-brain-minds select
				which datum is to be enriched through concentration. From there the
				processing must actively combine memories, previous categorizations and
				new data through neural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>. A particular tree becomes a tree in
				many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contexts</ENAMEX>, as if the brain makes as many as possible available from
				which to draw.
			"And if this is true of a mere <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, a fortiori
				it is even more true of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interaction</ENAMEX>."
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">â€¦'Just</ENAMEX> as he looks now!' and I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Mellifont</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stand</ENAMEX> before us with
				his sketch-block. I took in as we met him that he appeared neither
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspicious</ENAMEX> nor blank; he simply stood there, as he stood always
				everywhere, for the principal feature of the scene. Naturally he had no
				sketch to show us, but nothjng could have better rounded off our actual
				conception of him than the way he fell into position as we approached
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">(â€¦</ENAMEX>) We stayed while the exhibition went on, and the conscious profiles
				of the peaks might to our apprehension have been interested in his
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">(â€¦</ENAMEX>[He gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche</ENAMEX> the water-colour sketch] . . )
			'He'll have to rest after this,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche</ENAMEX> said, dropping her eyes on her
				<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water-colour</ENAMEX>.
			'Indeed he will!' I raised <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> to the window: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mellifont</ENAMEX> had
				vanished. "He's already reabsorbed.'12
			
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Suite C-3.3 Dialogue</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Anthropic</ENAMEX> Principle13
			
			
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyril Burst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vyvyan Lord Throbbing</ENAMEX> are seated together on a
				reassuringly threadbare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louix XV</ENAMEX>, mauvely gazing at the vermillion
				lights over the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Aqua Swimming Pool</ENAMEX>.
			
			Cyril: I say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vyvyan</ENAMEX>, pass me a gold-tipped cigarette, there's a dear.
				You know, you butch thing, many cosmologists posit different levels of
				universes, hoping thereby to answer questions regarding the seeming
				uniqueness of our own. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Martin Rees</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astronomer</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>, says contemplating alternate universes could help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
				distinguish which features of our own universe are fundamental and
				necessary and which are accidents of cosmic history. A light, pet?
			
			Vyvyan: Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyril</ENAMEX>, when you talk like this I am aflame! Stroke my
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hyacinth</ENAMEX> hair and tell me ours is the cosmic accident. You may randomly
				kiss my slim-gilt lips.
			
			Cyril: Oh, don't! . . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Alan Guth</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> introduced idea of inflation
				in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. His--the most artistic--universe is getting larger, and going
				faster. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guth</ENAMEX> says the universe is "the ultimate free lunch."
			
			Vyvyan: I love a free lunch, if it costs someone a great deal. Let's
				feast on nightingales' tongues and sip absinthe. I'll call down for more
				music and madder <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>.
			
			Cyril: Oh, fickler than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Hughes</ENAMEX>! I long for constants like the
				speed of light. Only a narrow range of settings (for these constants) is
				suitable for the evolution of complexity <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">or Life as We Know It</ENAMEX>.
			
			Vyvyan: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> as What? Say it again about the multiverse.
			
			Cyril: I will not. I try continually to avoid repetition.
			
			Vyvyan: What?
			
			Cyril: I try continually . . . Oh! Ashbery!
			
			Vyvyan: Auden! Auden! . . So my dear, despite these deafening drapes,
				is this a lucky universe, or what?
			
			Cyril: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Brandon Carter</ENAMEX>, a theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">posited</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthropic Principle</ENAMEX>," asseverating that these coincidences
				were not just luck, but were rather necessary preconditions for us to be
				looking at the universe. After all, we are hardly likely to discover
				laws that are incompatible with our own existence.
			
			Vyvyan: Our mission, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyril</ENAMEX>: contra the laws
				promulgated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX>, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
			
			Cyril: How thrillingly political of you to say so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vyvyan</ENAMEX> my unicornus.
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman Dyson</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>, once said, "The universe in some sense
				must have known we were coming."
			
			Vyvyan: Yep!
			
			Cyril: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Steven Weinberg</ENAMEX> is positively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miltonic</ENAMEX> in his comments on the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universe</ENAMEX>, which he sees bubbling progeny like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">buds</ENAMEX>. According to
				string theory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> says, the laws of physics that we
				mortals experience are low-energy, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> dimensional shadows, of sorts, of a
				<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10- or 11-dimensional</NUMEX> universe. cosmological constant.
			Ah, here's a snack; I'm ravenously puckish.. Oh! I thought you ordered
				carpaccio, but this is turnip tartare with nasturtium!
			
			Vyvyan: My own, economise now! And you are looking a trifle
				cosmological yourself.
			
			Cyril: Well, if you say so, my precious little fatty. Now, according to
				astronomical observations, otherwise undetectable energy--"dark
				energy"-- accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two-thirds</NUMEX> of the mass-energy of the
				universe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, outweighing matter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. But according to modern
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quantum</ENAMEX> physics, empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> should be seething with energy that would
				outweigh matter in the universe by far, far more, by a factor of at
				least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1060</TIMEX>.
			
			Vyvyan: And what to wear in dark energy? So the speeding-up of
				inflation lends more energy than was thought to exist? And the
				cosmological constant,, a formula to account for this discrepancy, must
				be within ranges compatible with us!
			
			Cyril: Just, just so. And, as we know, the logical consequence of this
				is that we "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queers</ENAMEX>" in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indolence</ENAMEX> have seen through the canard of
				vulgar Marxism. We live the principle that production is not the basis
				of human life.. Instead it is enjoyment! Fourier!
			
			Vyvyan: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ergo</ENAMEX>, my dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyril</ENAMEX>, what all we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> do is enjoy the
				impingement of this probably-unique world on us and ours on it, just
				like the lilies of the field. How lovely to be wanted by the entire
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universe</ENAMEX>, just so!
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suite K-347 The Mirror of Production</ENAMEX>
					14
				
			
			Flicking her jet beads at a bat, feeling very horny, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>, Countess
				Dinesen-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youssopoff</ENAMEX> (nee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blitzen</ENAMEX>) can barely keep herself still on her
				twilit balcony. She is waiting for what this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> obligingly calls "un
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ouvrier de santÃ</ENAMEX>© sexuelle." Her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberry</ENAMEX> and a glass
				of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> long over, she smokes another opium-laced cigarette as she
				<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> her ropy throat. Through a geneology almost impossible to trace,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> is the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix Youssopoff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
				queen who killed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rasputin</ENAMEX>. He made a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Morganatic</ENAMEX> marriage, fled to
				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> intriguing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> managed to recover her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baku</ENAMEX> oil refineries
				and grew richer through the sale of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandts</ENAMEX> and a suit against
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS Television</ENAMEX> that proved her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> actually did murder the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Czarina</ENAMEX>'s starets<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX>
			
			She reads from her commonplace book, makes a notation in her crabbed
				<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-Cyrillic hand.
			"The productive-man notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> 'hallucinates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s predestination
				for the objective transformation of the world (or for the 'production'
				of oneself: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s generalized humanist theme--it is no longer a
				question of 'being' oneself but of 'producing' oneself, from conscious
				activity to the primitive 'productions' of desire16". <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> dials her message machine to leave this memorandum: "B
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quotes Marx</ENAMEX> for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> 'begin to distinguish themselves from animals
				as soon as they begin to produce their means of subsistenceâ€¦' Remember
				that."
			She asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merle</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maltese</ENAMEX>, "Why must <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s vocation always be to
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinguish</ENAMEX> himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s existence an end for which he
				must find the means?"
			Sliding back the curtain on the sidelight of the door a little, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> B
				critiques the notion of production of subsistence: "it is the
				instrumentalization of nature." She summons up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>: 'Labor is, in the
				<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, a process in which both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and nature participate, and in
				which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of his own accord starts, regulates and controls the material
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-actions between himself and nature. He opposes himself to nature as
				<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, setting in motion <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and legs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and hands,
				the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, in order to appropriate nature's
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> in a form adapted to his own wants.'17"
			"How tedious," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> sighs. "Why can't these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> see that labor is not
				the basis of human existence? Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcuse</ENAMEX>, for all his slavering after
				erotic freedom, says labor is grounded 'in an essential excess of human
				existence beyond every possible situation in which it finds itself and
				the world. . . [it] is necessary and eternally 'earlier' than play: it
				is the starting point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> and principle of play insofar as play
				is precisely a breaking off from labor and a recuperation for labor<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.18</NUMEX>' But that is so wrong!"
			Taking her own version of luxury in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri III</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1551-1589</TIMEX>)
				straight-back wooden chair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> tightens her black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toque</ENAMEX> and murmurs,
				"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> doesn't see that in his symbolic exchanges primitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (sic)
				does not gauge himself in relation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX>. He is not aware of
				Necessity, a Law that takes effect only with the objectification of
				Nature."
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primitive 'society</ENAMEX>' does not exist as an instance apart from symbolic
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchange</ENAMEX>; and this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> never results from an 'excess' of
				production. It is the opposite: to the extent that these terms apply
				here, 'subsistence' and 'economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>' are the residue of symbolic
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchange</ENAMEX>, a remainder.' "
			Impatiently re-telling her jet beads, she thinks, "survival is not a
				principle. We have made it one." She remembers <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and her other
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Baudrillard</ENAMEX>, saying "For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primitives</ENAMEX>, eating, drinking,
				and living are first of all acts that are exchanged: if they are not
				exchanged, they do not occur. It is symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, where the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relation</ENAMEX> (not the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'social'</ENAMEX>) is tied, and this exchange excludes any
				surplus: anything that cannot be exchanged or symbolically shared would
				break the reciprocity and institute power. Better yet, this exchange
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excludes all 'production</ENAMEX>.'"
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good old Jean</ENAMEX>," she sighs, "stealing from Bataille like that."
			The door chimes. A gorgeous young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> rings her bell. With highly
				stylized sincerity, long eyelashes down, he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> he is at her
				service. "My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahmed Oedipus Ben Maas</ENAMEX>," he says, "and for me,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'work'</ENAMEX> is something other than laborâ€¦The artisan lives his work as a
				relation of symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, abolishing the definition of himself as
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'laborer</ENAMEX>' and the object as 'product of his labor.' "
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Above all</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> adds, lighting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of her cigarettes in the red gash
				of her mouth, "artisanal work is, according to etymology, 'demiurge.'"
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9 Rm</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1876</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ferd</ENAMEX> on the Brain
			
			I'm on assignment, re-building the organ at the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Petit Monde</ENAMEX>"
				experience at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro Disney</ENAMEX>. Oddly, though the singing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are
				totally animatronic, dancing and piping their tunes by virtue of
				computer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1s and 0s</TIMEX>, the organ is manual (and pedal). I spend my days
				scrambling through forests of big and little pipes, for it is a very big
				organ.
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> I'm relaxing around this musty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX>,
				reminiscing about a day in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> when some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich queen</ENAMEX> threw a pool
				party for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> With <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> up in the hills, within spitting distance of
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hollywood Sign</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> with purple blotches all over their backs and
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chests</ENAMEX> played in the sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, while a few long-timers sat in
				wheelchairs, wrapped in bright blankets, wheeled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushrooms</ENAMEX> in big straw
				hats. It was in that pool that I met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferd</ENAMEX>.
			Ferd was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>--he had no more money than it takes to buy a used
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX>--but he was the big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> because he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PWA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> bubbling on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn</ENAMEX> with precious-- tentative--joy in the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sunshine</ENAMEX>. We all loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferd</ENAMEX> then. He was healthy enough to work for our
				benefit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours a day</TIMEX>, he was edgy enough to get our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> funded at
				the vanguard of sexual healing as both treatment and prevention
				strategy. Ferd was a little like our figurehead as we breasted the
				waves, our sun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> as he ordered the world with and for us, and a
				little like a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> who, under his bonhomie, was transparently
				terrified of friendship.
			He slid into the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> next to me and we bobbed up and down smiling and
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cruising</ENAMEX>, I trying to assure myself I was still cute and attractive,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferd</ENAMEX> called upon to concentrate so long on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that sexual desire
				snuck up on him unbidden--in fact, he would later say, unpermitted in
				his job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and animator of our clump of radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, since a sexual liaison would reduce his availability to
				"listen, handhold, inspire, cajole, hug, solace" the others he thought
				in his care. That <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> he pulled himself out of the pool with a
				slight turgidity visible in the folds of his floppy yellow trunks and
				smiled as if he expected to be back to bob some more with me.
			He didn't come back soon, not until after I fended off a handsome guy
				with really bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AZT</ENAMEX> breath, who I knew wasn't likely to take up with me
				anyway. He was already twice a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of wealthier, lonelier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who left
				him <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and money for cosmetic surgery. I had nothing to offer but
				sweaty organs.
			"We're walking next door to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferd</ENAMEX> said
				when he came back, smelling of sunblock, lime and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX>. "Want to come
				along?" I did. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huxley</ENAMEX> property, explained our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, was really just
				a crater as a fire had destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldous</ENAMEX> wrote and
				took his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX> struggled on alone until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
				Sign was so close that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OOD</ENAMEX> took up most of the view on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side.
			Ferd started in about his acid trips. He had met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leary</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millbrook</ENAMEX>
				once in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>, he had done light shows at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fillmore</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janis</ENAMEX>, Country
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Incredible String Band</ENAMEX> (one of his fey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sly</ENAMEX> and the
				Family <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Circus</ENAMEX>. "I wish there was still acid to be
				taken," he said, "now that I'm not scared about blurting out 'I'm gay'
				to some straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie companion</ENAMEX>."
			"That must have happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>," I replied. "Surely you've
				come to terms with all of that by now. After all, here we are all
				together, having fun, living proof that God doesn't punish the wicked
				with anything more than painful, ugly death and stigmatized suffering."
			"Yes, surely I should feel cheered by your reminder of how good we have
				it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferd</ENAMEX> said. "But let's don't call each other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX>. Actually I
				take <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-depressants</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, so I don't bother with scared or unhappy any
				more.
			"I think our consciousness should be altered, early and often." he told
				me, his good eye engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>. "We need to experience being without
				relation to time--escape from a conception of a forward moving series of
				events the most sense-rich of which felt as the present and less rich
				assigned to a recallable but fading past. Further, the brain's capacity
				to take in and re-view sensory input led to the development of neural
				pathways that could access and perceive or experience the occurrence of
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and cogitate on the process itself. Sensory input is reviewed
				through the same neural pathways (or analogous or related or proximate
				ones) that process raw sensory input. It is unclear whether the brain
				always knows the difference between processing the sensory input we
				usually think of as perception of reality and processing the processing
				which, as mirrors can reflect each other, can approach infinity as sense
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> become perceptions, become organized ideas, become abstract
				categories and then categories of categories. Given what little is
				understood about the brain, it is not possible to say whether these
				processes are or are not organized in hierarchies. The brain may assign
				more or less attention energy, ranking by importance or immediacy or
				proximity or some other order--or not.
			"The result of all this, I think, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> have a brain that
				processes sensory and internal mental phenomena at too many levels, too
				often, too much, with inadequate mechanism to turn the processing off.
				We have brains too good for our own good; we think and abstract feelings
				and memories too much. This ceaseless idling is what we have learned to
				call our feelings, however remote the neural processing may be from
				somatic reactions to events perceived as happening now. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HAL2000</ENAMEX>,
				our brain (and by brain I keep trying to mean all the data processing
				mechanisms from senses to memory to thinking) thinks what it does is
				real. What psychological literature and philosophy have always
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confounded</ENAMEX>--the subject and object and later the divided subject--become
				less compelling as explanation and certainly as a concept to provide a
				comfortable relation to 'external reality.' But the brain is best seen
				as actively seeking, processing and thinking at all levels
				simultaneously: consciousness is a trick of our brains describing us to
				ourselves, stringing processes and events into a self, asserting to us
				that the self of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any other day</TIMEX>, selecting data
				and memories to substantiate itself."
			"Yeah, you're right," I said. I never thought he was sexy after that.
			<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Reception Desk</ENAMEX>
			
			While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MonaLisa</ENAMEX> recuperates, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novy</ENAMEX> might fill in at the
				front desk. Usually dressed for her main job as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conductor on Wild Ride</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de M. Toad</ENAMEX>, she would be irritable in a pantsuit that barely stretches
				across her chest and chafes her crotch. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novy</ENAMEX> might be musing about her
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> or daydreaming about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>. She'd not be impressed by the
				small bald <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> across the counter, signing in as Mobe 68.
			"Will you be needing any special attentions, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobe</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>?"
			"No, just be sure my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is plugged in to the charger and send up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
				bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vichy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. And put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferd</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> next to mine."
			"Very good, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobe</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>. And here are the keys for you and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferd</ENAMEX>."
				She might think to herself that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were pop music has-beens from
				<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; she'd put them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">smelly suite</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>.
				"Overlooking the pool, nice views."
			As they walk toward the elevator, the organ grinder might come up to
				them and ask, "Aren't you . . .?"
			"Yes, I'm. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX> .
			"Ferd? Remember me from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Being Alive PWA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>?"
			"Oh yes, I remember . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>. . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, . Aldous Huxley! And of course you
				recognize my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo .</ENAMEX> . ."
			"Never mind, just meet me upstairs. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nice, .</ENAMEX> . .<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>?"
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> would look at their shoes (one pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pradas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pairs of
				canvas sneakers) as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobe</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> walks away.
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, that wasn't a bit awkward. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, how funny to see you here.
				What are you doing?"
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> might be feeling a little nonplussed himself, and may already be
				regretting this encounter. In an attempt to make things easier he might
				answer, "I'm rebuilding an organ at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EuroDisney</ENAMEX>, and I'm running pretty
				<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX>. Can we have a drink later and catch up?"
			"Of course, let's call each other. I'm up in what they call the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidential Suite</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo</ENAMEX>' is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and more a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> than a
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX>, really."
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool</ENAMEX>. Call you tonight." He'd kiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferd</ENAMEX> and walk quickly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
				shuttle outside.
			Mobe 68 meanwhile would have gone up, sharing the elevator with an
				middle-aged Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who looks very familiar.
			"Are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>?"
			"I was, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Art Ensemble</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> is my name."
			"Wow! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Jamaal</ENAMEX>, I saw you play in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, Your
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chanting</ENAMEX> and clarinet were awesome! With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leroy Jenkins</ENAMEX> doing incredible
				things on the violin. I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobe</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>."
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanks</ENAMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. I've heard your music too. Here to do a recording
				<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gig?</ENAMEX>"
			"No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, I have no plans at all. I just travel now."
			At the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, an emaciated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> could get on carrying a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maltese</ENAMEX>
				with rheumy eyes and a bad underbite, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> walks off, saying.
				"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, here's my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. Nice to meet you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobe</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>, but be cool--the past
				is emptiness; 'here and now.'19"
			The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Countess Yousopoff-Blitzen</ENAMEX>, might not be concerned that the
				elevator is going up. She would know that her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> wait for
				her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Snivilling Lounge</ENAMEX>. She'd look up, expecting a mirrored
				ceiling, smoothing her throat and lighting a cigarette.
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Excuse me</ENAMEX>, I don't think you can smoke in here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobe</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>.
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> would croak and jab the down button. "This must be
				your floor. Please get out."
			As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobe</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> turns his key, he could be trying to concentrate on
				<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> compassion and the tasks ahead of him.
			
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foucault's Nephew</ENAMEX>
			Come rain or shine, my custom is to go for a stroll in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idiocy</ENAMEX>
				of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Life</ENAMEX> environment every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX>. I hold discussions
				with myself on politics, love, taste or philosophy, and let my thoughts
				wander in complete abandon, leaving them free to follow the first wise
				or foolish idea that comes along, like those young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rakes</ENAMEX> we see in the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repressed Sexuality Land</ENAMEX> who run after a giddy-looking little piece with
				a laughing face, sparkling eye and tip-tilted nose, only to leave him
				for another, accosting them all, but sticking to none.
			If it is too cold or wet I take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> TacoBilious
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CafÃ©</ENAMEX> and amuse myself watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hustlers</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> Hold-'em. One day
				after dinner there I was, watching a great deal but saying little and
				listening to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as little as</NUMEX> I could, when I was accosted by one of the
				weirdest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in this Land of ours that has not been sparing of
				them. The notions of good and evil must be strangely muddled in his
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, for the good qualities nature has given him he displays without
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ostentation</ENAMEX>, and the bad ones without shame. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX> is devilishly good
				looking, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">queer bird</ENAMEX>, and has made himself the boon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> of every
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EuroDisney</ENAMEX>. He comes by it honestly, as he is
				the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Foucault</ENAMEX>.
			He accosts me: "Hello, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philosopher</ENAMEX>. Are your thoughts consoling you
				in these troubling times?"
			I: Not much, but when I have nothing better to do I enjoy watching the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>.
			HE: Oh, they're not here to be watched. Not at these prices!
				<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Thirty-five</NUMEX> euros <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter</TIMEX>, whew!
			I: And how have you been keeping yourself? I heard you were hooked up
				with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dread</ENAMEX> who runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Hanky Pavilion</ENAMEX>. No new vice squad
				complications there?
			HE: No, he's turned it into an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>+ dance floor, and it's writhing with
				e-trash heteroid clothes hangers. Now it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Idyll</ENAMEX>.
			I: Don't you welcome the acceptance of our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kind</ENAMEX>? Imitation is sincere
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flattery</ENAMEX>?
			HE: If that's acceptance, fuck it. "If we are all part of God," as the
				saintly Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cresswell</ENAMEX> said, "then God must indeed be horrible<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.20</NUMEX>" I can't see anything
				special in being queer anymore. "We're all over!" they keep screaming..
				Yes, yes. We're over. We're passÃ© and boring. Though some clueless
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> continue to sing. "queer planet."
			I: You however, continue pursuing "practices and pleasures<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" You must
				have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> up the . . .
			HE: Up! Just to play for a brief <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Ugh, the prep. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX>
				suddenly began to act out his words with the most extraordinary
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postures</ENAMEX>. )
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimming</ENAMEX>, then shaving your balls. I fell in the bathtub <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>.
				I was standing on the edge, trying to see my ass to shave it, when I
				slipped and cracked a disc. Now my hands tingle all the time. Then
				there's the cleaning out. the showershot or worse, the bag. and the
				<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-day</TIMEX> runs. slammers the worst. I finally said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dread</ENAMEX>
				that he was a sleazy old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> buying muscles instead of love. He sent
				me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EuroComfort Inn</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> and now I'm on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> again.
				They only let me stay at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Desert Hotel</ENAMEX>, and in a mildewed room
				they can't rent, cause my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> once endorsed the place.
			I: It's no wonder you are so abandoned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX> For that matter, doesn't
				crystal just exaggerate our fundamental alone-ness in the world?
			HE: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philosopher</ENAMEX>, I may be tweaking, but I know my ontology. "It's
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">understandable</ENAMEX>, but wrong, the notion that each of us is alone,
				imprisoned within the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cranium</ENAMEX>, when in fact even the physical
				universe of matter depends on us to exist, and even more desperately the
				sperm and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> that make us and the genes and social conditions that
				shape each of us. The other is always before us, demanding that we be
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selves</ENAMEX> in response. It's fatuous (no, self-centered and delusional) to
				think we think alone. Our mythologies of lost or fractured selves
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gluttonize</ENAMEX>--slobber--over the illusions of sameness and difference, self
				and other."21
			
			I: You know all of this is artifact of language, no? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Althusser</ENAMEX>?
			HE: I've been interpellated more times than you can count. When I am
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interpellated</ENAMEX> then I am clocked, called out, made to answer to hey you,
				but the you I create (in response) has to answer back, has to
				interpellate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>. I is always a response, not to the mirror, but to
				an other. All the world--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> included, is hung up on the fears of
				alienation, disintegration that our dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> lived to feel.
			My own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>! All of this is the tragedy of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Century</TIMEX>. WWI
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frightened Europe</ENAMEX> out of its class complacency and squelched important
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> movements. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution of 1917</ENAMEX> created a hope, and at least a
				pole of support for liberation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>
				frightened the world into a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX> reforms, but then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX> sent
				all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to war, let them kill in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and then
				sent them home to individual suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. None of them knew how to
				be with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, so then came the baby boom. Feeding on
				schedule or feeding on demand, but overfeeding. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> and the
				Draft to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Nam</ENAMEX>. My own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> are still lost, tripping in
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> desert somewhere since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 60s</TIMEX>.
			No wonder <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 60s</TIMEX> were aflame. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> left to crusade against racism,
				war, sexual oppression. Suddenly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX> shouts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>, come over here,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>!
			I: Who is this angelic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> with white hair making toward us?
			HE: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timmy Tilden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Tilden</ENAMEX>, tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20s</TIMEX> and
				30s, who was imprisoned twice for sex with teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>.
				Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, his only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> said he "felt things so deeply. . I never
				saw him with anybody who could have been his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX>. How must it be
				like that22<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
			I: Can we change our lives?
			HE: I hope so. She said "There must have been so many things deep
				within him that he could never talk about. I suppose he died of a broken
				heart." Anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>--she was
				a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Lord</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tildens</ENAMEX> ran her out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> with a
				film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. A long story shortened: .her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tilden</ENAMEX>'s
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>, was rescued from a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and
				brought to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sithole..</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>'s exceptional looking, but stay
				away. He's seventeen, falling into bad habits already : an albino black
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marketeer</ENAMEX>--small-time <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX> smuggling--he's so innocent
				he'll hurt you.
			I: And why do you have so much to say about this dangerous young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?
			HE: Because he's my young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bud</ENAMEX>, aren't you Timmy? I take care of my
				red-eyed little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">polar bear</ENAMEX>.
			TIMMY: You know I hate that name! Can you get me a drink, please?
			HE: I'll get you all you need <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>. Come and party with a couple
				military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">studs</ENAMEX>? It's all set up, they just called on my cel. In my room
				<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>? Lots of favors!.
			On that note, I made my adieux, and strolled off to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TomorrowLand</ENAMEX>.
			12
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1954 Joseph and His Brother</ENAMEX>
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Jamaal</ENAMEX> is not completely enthused to be recognized, as he is a
				fugitive from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>, accused (falsely) of complicity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Army</ENAMEX> killings of police in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. He is waking his
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">employer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried Rheinfahrt</ENAMEX>, from his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midmorning</TIMEX> nap. Laying aside
				volumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidegger</ENAMEX>, he massages the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s knees until he
				opens his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-blue eyes.
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ja</ENAMEX> . . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aah</ENAMEX> . . . In the jugness of the jug, sky and earth dwell. .
					..23
			
			"You are awake now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herr Siegfried</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> says calmly.
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ahh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>," he croaks. "I think I understand. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kant</ENAMEX> talks about
				things in the same way as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meister Eckhart</ENAMEX> and means by this term 'thing'
				something that is. But for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kant</ENAMEX>, that which is becomes the object of a
				representing that runs its course in the self-consciousness of the human
				ego. The thing-in-itself means for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kant</ENAMEX>: the object-in-itself. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kant</ENAMEX>,
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the 'in-itself' signifies that the object is an object
				in itself without reference to the human act of representing it, that
				is, without the opposing 'ob-' by which it is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all put before
				this representing act. :'Thing -in-itself,' thought in a rigorously
				Kantian way, means an object that is no object for us, because it is
				supposed to stand, stay put, without a possible before; for the human
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">representational</ENAMEX> act that encounters it.' It is very materialist,
				despite the awful neologisms."
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph straightens Siegfried</ENAMEX>'s sparse white hair and tells him, "The
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> teaches that sense impressions can be understood as relationships
				of conscious being to being. The "categories" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kant</ENAMEX> only interfere
				with this relationship. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heidegger</ENAMEX> is closer."
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ja</ENAMEX>, yes, I think so." He reads " 'This appropriating mirror-play of
				the simple onefold of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> and sky, divinities and mortals, we call the
				world. The world presences by worlding. . . ' "
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> reads further, "'That means: the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worlding</ENAMEX> cannot be
				explained by anything else nor can it be fathomed through anything else.
				This impossibility does not lie in the inability of our human thinking
				to explain and fathom n this way. Rather, the inexplicable and
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unfathomable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">worlding</ENAMEX> lies in this, that causes
				and grounds remain unsuitable for the world's worlding. ' Herr
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heidegger</ENAMEX> is saying what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> says--'As soon as human
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cognition</ENAMEX> here calls for an explanation, it fails to transcend the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s nature, and falls short of it. The human will to explain just
				does not reach to the simpleness of the simple onefold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worlding</ENAMEX>'.
				This is pretty good dharma teaching."
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> my Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, what can an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> like me do with
				this dharma? Am I just disappointed at the end of all I believed in? Is
				there no revolution to be made, now?"
			"The wheel turns," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> says with compassion. He helps his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX> hopes to squeeze a few drops through his
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">urethra</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX> sits and reminisces about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
				replaces his books and prepares him a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fentanyl</ENAMEX> injection.
				"Would you like your yogurt enema before or after? I can read to you
				from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April Theses 24</TIMEX> if you like."
			"No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, sing for me, and play the harmonium. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sing the 'Red Thread</ENAMEX>
				Blues.'"
			
			
				The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Thread Blues</ENAMEX>
				
					25
				
			
			The vitality of living labor
			Confronts the dead power of capitalist command
			I say autonomist theory contrasts the vitality of living labor
			With the dead power of capitalist command
			The working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> historically assert their power
			to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in their hands.
			
			Intrinsic to the capital-relation
			Is the class struggle of the working class
			Prior to and more dynamic than capitalist restructuring
			Is the class struggle that constitutes the working class
			Think of the demand for an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>;
			it kicked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> in the ass.
			
			Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, productive labor
			Is now that which produces society itself
			Let's use the combination of our productive labor
			To sieze freedom however momentarily and redistribute wealth
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Autonomists</ENAMEX> say we can communicate our social inventiveness
			and make the world something else.
			Â 
			The active subject of production
			Is the increasingly undifferentiated working class
			The wellspring of change in production
			Is the self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autonomizing</ENAMEX> working class
			Beyond mere <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> are moments of freedom;
			they're real but then they pass.
			
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>'s restructurings "subsume" not only the workplace
			But society as a whole
			I tell you in its processes of globalization
			Reproduction of labor power occupies a crucial but unacknowledged role
			That's why welfare moms are threatening,
			and they had to end the dole
			
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guerillas</ENAMEX> moved like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in the water
			Threatening to cut off resources and lands
			Oh yeah, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX> and elsewhere liberation fighters
			Challenged resource allocation in the jungles and the sands
			The fall of communism, sadly,
			demobilized support for progressive guerilla bands.
			
			Global capital then broke down traditional village structures
			Marched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> to town
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tragically</ENAMEX>, capital emiseration in favela and shanty
			Is what happens when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> geography breaks down
			But international mass migrations result in newer combinations,
			where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> can abound.
			
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Husbands</ENAMEX> dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are left with "free" choices
			To choose between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child laborers</ENAMEX> or whores
			A prerequisite for capitalist modernization
			Is a landless desperate, anomic labor force
			War, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and famine,
			threaten to cut off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> production at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
			
			But struggle to create ourselves as subjects
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disrupts</ENAMEX> and tears apart systems of capitalist rule
			Despite regimes of power, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> make themselves subjects
			Sabotaging, rectifying, evading, the intentions of global rule
			Sometimes distorted and mistaken,
			self-creation is quite evident among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
			
			In the north abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and ruined communities
			Where privilege is evanescing, no longer so secure
			In the south devastation and dollar-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-month</TIMEX> factories
			But then moments of freedom where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s relationships are less
				obscure
			Creative combinations of people
			are what the global dominators most fear.
			
			The points where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> can be ruptured
			Affirm labor's fundamental otherness from capital
			Let's put our hands to the points to be ruptured
			And assert that we are sentient like any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and animal
			We'll show the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blairs</ENAMEX> and Cheneys
			that their hierarchies of power can be overturned, not
			just disrupted!
			
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried</ENAMEX>, did you know it's taken me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to be able to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">sing blues?</ENAMEX>"
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> remembers how impatient he was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, how unsophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Otis</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spann</ENAMEX> seemed, saying on the radio, "If you don't dig the blues, you've
				got a hole in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>." How <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> wanted to move ahead,
				express the complexity of new feelings, of the new situation they faced.
				You had to respect those bluesmen, but we knew they couldn't understand
				what needed to be done<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.26</NUMEX>
			
			"I didn't understand, really. I was so moved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baldwin</ENAMEX>--the sins
				of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>. We wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Ensemble</ENAMEX>'s music to go further than
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ornette or Coltrane</ENAMEX>, way beyond what we thought good ol' blues could do.
				I wish I knew then what I've had to learn so slowly."
			13 In the NightKitchen
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caprice Sithole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sets</ENAMEX> down her paring knife in the bowl of okra. She
				whistles through the gap in her front teeth as she reads from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX>:
			"This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> communiquÃ© from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELF Liberation Front Today</ENAMEX>, in a
				worldwide coordinated action, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Heraclitean Fire</ENAMEX>, we have burned
				out all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HumVee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>-- "hummers"-- in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> "parks" in
				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster guzzlers</ENAMEX> turn the
				hydrocarbon resources of the Developing --read, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-exploited</ENAMEX>-- World
				into fumes of asphyxiation that linger low to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. We struck a
				blow for little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of all ages. And don't forget, "hummer" used to
				mean something nice."
			
			<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caprice</ENAMEX> worries about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. "I'm happy they can't pin this on
				him. He's been on the job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and night since he got back." She enjoys a
				humorous, danger-filled marriage with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ndabaningi Sithole III</ENAMEX>. His
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reverend uncle</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZAPU</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>), then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZANU</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> with
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mugabe</ENAMEX>), then tried for attempted assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mugabe</ENAMEX>
				in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">199627</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caprice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neddy</ENAMEX> had to beg and borrow
				100,000 zimdollars to escape from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>, leaving their professions
				and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary opposition</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">cooking28</TIMEX>.and
				managing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Real Desert</ENAMEX>.
			<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neddy</ENAMEX> has recently returned from one of his frequent "investment
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunities</ENAMEX>," driving a fleet of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
				paying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of pre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> to take paper napkins from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> and
				other fast food venues. He ships them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> with moderate profits. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interpol</ENAMEX> is already searching for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Napkin</ENAMEX>
				Ring. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caprice</ENAMEX> believes they must change their activities.
			"The bigger profits are in sanitary napkin dispensers. Just try to get
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kotex</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tampax</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harare</ENAMEX>," she counsels her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neddy</ENAMEX> is not
				convinced; he is at work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">modifying</ENAMEX> and lowering electric dryers for
				wipe-with-your-hands <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
			Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xoliswa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah</ENAMEX>, think he is so old-fashioned. The
				only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimbabweans</ENAMEX> on their minds are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chiweshe29</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Mtukudzi</ENAMEX>--and sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methembe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ndlovu30</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highlanders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. To make
				downloading of their music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> easier, they wish their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> back in
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>.31
			
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valet Parking</ENAMEX>
			<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HumVees</ENAMEX> bearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Security Operations S.A.</ENAMEX> logo pull
				to the curb. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> jar-headed young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, right hands inside the lapels of
				their black <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Purple Label</ENAMEX> suits, each carrying a titanium computer case
				handcuffed to his wrist, step out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and survey the
				perimeter. From the back seat, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with deep-set eyes, black-browed
				under a silver military haircut, commands them to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
				themselves and secure them. "We are meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in
				<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. Check for digital positioning and, of course,
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explosives</ENAMEX>-- and shred these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>."
			He strides, as erect as always, to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, who is
				obsequiously bowing to greet the new arrival. "You are Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver South</ENAMEX>?
				Would you like to go to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, or shall I take you directly to the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bunker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>? Any papers you wish to prepare<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
			"It's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colonel South</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USMC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ret.</ENAMEX>) Please get me a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Absolut</ENAMEX> and
				some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vichy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> curtly replies. "You may take me to the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Countess</ENAMEX>."
			"I will personally bring your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Achmed</ENAMEX> will take you across.
				Achmed!"
			Inspecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-looking beauty through a flat green lens, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presently</ENAMEX> says, "OK. You're clean. Lead on." At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 51</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> retains
				the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> tension of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Marine</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> fascist
				ideology of his more physical early career has been tempered by a
				philosophical acquiescence to his and others' weaknesses. A co-founder
				of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> knows the World <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Traders</ENAMEX> are near to discharging his firm
				over the flaming stink at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>.
			"It's a very low-intensity operation," he says to himself, "and the
				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatic amateurs</ENAMEX> can hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> lining up for rides if we don't find
				them fast. More than reputations are at stake. I wish it was as
				clear-cut as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, or even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>. . .Africans all over this place
				too. Our own barbarians vs theirs now!"
			"Get the generalissimo a bottle, " the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novy</ENAMEX>.
			The jarheaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> return, both on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">cel</TIMEX> phones. One is seen nodding and
				looking in the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX>, who is also on his cel--all checking
				watches.
			15
			Party Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bounds</ENAMEX>
			As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> walks in between sheets of black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX> is yelling
				"Attention!" at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jarheaded men</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HumVees</ENAMEX>.
			"<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX> you <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">maggots</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX> barks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> is not sure whether he should
				take his own clothes off. In doubt, he sits on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the mattresses
				strewn about the slippery floor.
			"Put these on each other, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcel</ENAMEX> continues to shout, throwing
				black latex jockstraps at the naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. "Come here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>," he growls.
				"Put these blindfolds on them and this mask on your own face. And get
				into those leather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chaps</ENAMEX>."
