
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX> i was just about to get on my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tread mill</ENAMEX> and then i remembered that i didn't make a call last night and i thought i'd make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i have an exercise bicycle in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> but it usually's holding clothes
 	
 	
 		that's what i did with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> put it on the handlebars so i can hang them up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and sometimes she just flops them all over the seat
 	
 	
 		well that's not why i got it right  how do you like your tread mill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i like it
 	
 	
 		you don't get is it less boring than the bicycle or not
 	
 	
 		no it's just as boring
 	
 	
 		you watch TV or something while you do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i read a book while i'm doing it but i was doing that on the exercise bike
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i do that too
 	
 	
 		i feel like i'm getting a little better of a workout and i'm losing more weight on this  than i had on the other and my legs you know how okay i'm going to turn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> i was getting all  dimpled up
 	
 	
 		really
 		are you a
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and those are going away
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so that's real good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> aren't they kind
 	
 	
 		we got it at a little bit of an incline
 	
 	
 		are they kind of expensive
 	
 	
 		uh this one yeah this is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		i know they get cheaper but i don't know  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh do they probably the more you pay though the better the machine you have
 	
 	
 		well i hope so
 	
 	
 		well you can believe that anyway right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i didn't buy it really my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> bought it because we we'd
 		we'd never get out and go walking or anything  and we go to the lake and we ski and swim in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> yeah well in bad weather you know well you'd have to do something inside do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		besides that uh-huh
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think your voice sounds familiar
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		where do you work
 	
 	
 		i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wonder if we talked before
 	
 	
 		where do you live
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no uh well
 	
 	
 		you sound like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that i talked to about books and we got into movies <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've done it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was just running out the door he's working at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night tonight</TIMEX> so i decided to do it  i haven't talked before
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> have you talked about
 	
 	
 		let's see education  uh social changes that we've seen in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years</TIMEX> yeah that one was
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's interesting
 		it's more interesting than the treadmill and the bicycle right
 	
 	
 		the most boring one was about what meal would you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for a sit down dinner
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> didn't cook too much either right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they really have a lot of variety
 	
 	
 		yeah they do i talked to this old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that was a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> about education and she was
 	
 	
 		oh a a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> well that could that would have been interesting
 	
 	
 		uh-huh she retired but
 		yeah and then <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> i talked to these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> no one night i talked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks later</TIMEX> i talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> about different things
 	
 	
 		really well that's neat
 	
 	
 		uh-huh one was about painting
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		when was the last time you painted something did you feel like you did a good job did you feel uh
 		rewarded while you were doing it i don't know
 	
 	
 		hm
 		how long is this going to go on do you know
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i don't either it's interesting though i never heard of such a project before
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well how'd you find out about it
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		how did you find out about it
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> got a letter at the office
 		i i presume and they must have been asking does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> that worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and she saw it on the computer screen and they made copies of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are you a
 		oh so they wanted any anybody don't have to work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting i had no idea that was just for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and i couldn't understand i kept getting these calls i thought it was an advertisement and they just were also called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you know there is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Industries</ENAMEX> and different things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i kept hanging up on them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> until my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> told me what it was
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i didn't know
 	
 	
 		well if you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you're supposed to get a prize is what i heard and if you don't work for them you're supposed to get cash but then on the letter it says cash or prize
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 		really
 		oh
 		oh well the prizes are pretty nice he brought a booklet home and depending on how many calls i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> was the minimum but it went up to i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> how many calls have you made had
 	
 	
 		i don't know gobs
 	
 	
 		well it sounds like a lot
 	
 	
 		this is going on my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth week</TIMEX> to do it
 	
 	
 		oh my and some of the prizes were you know pretty nice but i didn't
 	
 	
 		well like what tell me
 	
 	
 		oh i wish i had that booklet here oh i think i do it's right here uh
 		i'll look at the end because those would be the best ones okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		um well they have some watches that look really nice there's one that's got some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		for how many calls
 	
 	
 		well
 		it says F i haven't quite figured that out i thought it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine</TIMEX> but seems like too nice a prize for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> calls doesn't it
 	
 	
 		does it say
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it says
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when we have enough calls from you you will receive in the mail a numbered certificate for your calls and and explanation how to redeem
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you need to start the grill
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for gifts are you li stening to him
 	
 	
 		no i'm trying not to he's telling me to start the grill
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh  it says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for a B gift <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX> gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 		and this only goes up to F
 		so i thought that was somewhere around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
 		but anyway it's got these beautiful watches on it let me see what else it has a uh
 		uh clock radio that also plays uh
 		uh you know uh
 		tapes then it's got oh some binoculars and some pretty brass lamps
 		it's got some
 		oh a food processor
 	
 	
 		so it's not all stuff that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> makes
 	
 	
 		oh no i don't i haven't seen anything in here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Coffee</ENAMEX> the double <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Coffee</ENAMEX> you know the two oh and there's a phone in here that's hilarious it has a button you can push if you get a call you don't like then it makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine gun</ENAMEX> noise i've never seen that before
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		then there's an attache case and cordless telephone and then there's a card table doesn't have any chairs just a card table oh some more jewelry
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suitcases</ENAMEX> and have you seen those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> anniversary lamps where the little balls go around
 	
 	
 		you mean the clocks
 	
 	
 		yeah clocks is what i meant i can i'm going crazy my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s playing the piano and i can't think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		it's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those and
 		well it's got a lot stuff i mean pages and pages it's got wheelbarrows  i'm trying to look for something a lot of kitchen stuff lots of kitchen stuff the mixer a toaster a waffle maker
 		popcorn popper
 		all kinds of stuff like that and
 		here's where here's a calculator but it's not even made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> isn't that funny
 	
 	
 		did they mail that to you or he brought it to you
 	
 	
 		he brought it home i believe it came in his uh his mail here's a camera and a dustbuster and some tools someone a lot of tools a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> might like you know
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah so you're bound to find something you want
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you're bound to all kinds of phones and clocks and
 		and uh here's more jewelry and oh there's even pictures and little porcelain things to put on a coffee table oh here's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass animals brass candlesticks</ENAMEX> they're pretty
 		so i'm sure you'd find something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well you know uh
 	
 	
 		and there's even some silver plated bowls and stuff there's a lot of stuff it's a big booklet
 	
 	
 		well do you know you have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> limit a
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minute</TIMEX> time limit well that's okay and then they come on and tell you and they tell you got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five seconds</TIMEX> to say good-bye
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		you've talked enough
 		oh  oh well it's been fun this is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time to do it
 	
 	
 		we'll keep talking if we want to come up with something else let's see
 	
 	
 		right do you
 	
 	
 		let's see oh i tried exercise classes and i never would go we find we joined exercising
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> keeps telling me to i went i went back to college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> so i sit and study i sit in class and i have really ballooned up since then and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so he's says i ought to join <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those that makes you go but they're and you're saying it doesn't then you pay all that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> stuff you know
 	
 	
 		they don't either well
 		well the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one i joined they went out of business and they transferred it to another one that was really far away
 	
 	
 		that's a very common experience you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and we were going to do it there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us together well then forget that it wasn't near me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		and then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time i was going to do it at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland College</ENAMEX> and we i just get with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and we'd end up just smoking cigarettes and riding around like we couldn't find the place
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		that's funny
 	
 	
 		so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s just discouraged me on those things
 	
 	
 		right well if you if you can make yourself do the tread mill i mean gosh that's a good workout
 	
 	
 		oh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said he's never joined a course right and i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fonda</ENAMEX> workout tapes that i dubbed from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that didn't last long i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those after i had a baby i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those puts on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few pounds</NUMEX> doesn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		definitely two
 	
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 		yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> one's in college so i don't have a have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		oh Lord you're lucky well i've got a stepdaughter she's in college
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well
 	
 	
 		so there's where the money goes
 	
 	
 		yeah  tell me about it tell me  my lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us through isn't he lucky
 	
 	
 		where's you kids
 		two
 	
 	
 		well me i'm going and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah right so i'll probably have to sell the prize i get
 	
 	
 		where you going to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UTA</ENAMEX> right here
 	
 	
 		and what are you doing
 	
 	
 		well i'm um
 		going to be certified as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second language
 	
 	
 		yes i do i just got my certification huh-uh
 	
 	
 		you're kidding oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		the test is a booger  it the test the exit test it's hard it is so hard
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 		it's hard
 		oh no
 		really
 		really how are the other ones
 		i haven't taken any of the exit tests
 	
 	
 		see i didn't have to take any other exit test because i've been teaching for quite a while
 	
 	
 		oh yeah before they started all this stuff
 	
 	
 		but i've heard they're terrible
 	
 	
 		really hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bilingual</ENAMEX> is just horrendous i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> fail that twice
 	
 	
 		really oh
 		really i didn't know any of this none of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have failed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> or the education ones
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		and i really ought to take those quickly while i still remember something
 	
 	
 		yeah right after you get out
 	
 	
 		i know i know i know how are those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX> courses i'm just starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		boring and they really don't help you a whole lot now see i went to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> and i took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> through TWU
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		most of the good training i've got has been through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> just teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX> see i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX> One <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teacher</ENAMEX> and some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they give you
 		yeah
 		oh oh
 		
 		
 	