
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		was i supposed to do something
 	
 	
 		no i had to press one
 	
 	
 		good uh let's see
 		so
 		uh
 		were we right in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		should we have been there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did we do what was correct there
 	
 	
 		i think we should have stayed longer
 	
 	
 		should we have fought them harder
 		used more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> equal to their chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that weren't used
 	
 	
 		uh i think what we did was good but i think we just should have stayed there longer and continued doing what we did do
 	
 	
 		oh you agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> who says uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drive</ENAMEX> on into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we should have stayed and kind of helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> out now because it's kind of like a civil war going on now And it's almost like they're killing each other off
 		and there is not going to be anything left of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		would that be so bad
 		was there anything there
 		to begin with
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i think i don't think it would be good if we were to completely lose it um
 	
 	
 		it wasn't ours
 	
 	
 		well no i just mean that that the world in general
 	
 	
 		well we've got to talk so it's just just as well we argue
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		Um
 		i don't know i think we should have helped the the innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> out a little bit more than rather than just quitting where we did
 	
 	
 		i agree
 		wouldn't it have been wonderful
 		if we could have freed the country
 	
 	
 		yes  But i think that's almost impossible next to impossible
 	
 	
 		yeah so other political things that's going on i heard mister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> say uh excuse me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> say that he uh
 		wanted to improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh see i haven't really been keeping up with them so i really don't know what he said what did he say about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh he wanted to take the current secondary highway system and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		turn it into
 		interstates like
 		the rest of the country
 	
 	
 		we don't have the money for that
 	
 	
 		but wouldn't it be wonderful
 	
 	
 		It would be really nice because i'm kind of tired of driving in pot holes
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and back east you all drive at fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> don't you
 		what's that oh okay um i say back east you all drive at fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> don't you see out here in the west
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry i dropped the phone
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot of our secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we drive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> oh yes well
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> went home to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		between
 		here and west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there was probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty five miles an hour</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		nonstop have you have you ever been out here
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		how far west have you been
 	
 	
 		only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you've never
 	
 	
 		i've never been past <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you've never seen the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> desert
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh i've never seen anything out i never seen the great i've seen
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountains</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've never seen i've seen pictures of it but
 	
 	
 		Mountains
 		Yellowstone
 	
 	
 		i've never been there i've seen pictures i just i'm a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm paying for my own education and i'm i come from a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and we we we're never able to take vacations because there's there's twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the family
 		so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 		well my college education uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty six</TIMEX> worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> for seventeen or eighteen now
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		uh know virtually nothing else uh yeah i got my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> got my BS in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Science</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i know it's a funny degree uh anyway uh i know nothing other than the west in fact uh
 	
 	
 		really
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		down in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s located there's streams and water and things i don't understand <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the gulf and
 		it's really interesting so tell me about where you live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well um i'm i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler</ENAMEX> and that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> away from where i am now i'm at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clairon</ENAMEX> And um it's it's pretty like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">windy</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hilly</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh how high is the highest elevation
 	
 	
 		oh i couldn't even tell you
 	
 	
 		like uh probably
 	
 	
 		it's not like a mountain it wouldn't be like a mountain it's uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> foot
 	
 	
 		oh i don't even know
 		i have no clue
 	
 	
 		close to sea level
 	
 	
 		i would say it's closer to sea level
 	
 	
 		okay uh right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> where i live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over six thousand foot</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well see um
 	
 	
 		um
 		yes when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> i had to drive you know i drove <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> to the gulf and you know so i could have a feast of fresh seafood
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six eight</NUMEX> twelve <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> away
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know just just for fresh i
 		i'm really interested in the basic concept differences between west and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> coast and the central parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> have you been from home
 	
 	
 		uh the farthest away from home
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		probably i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when i was growing up
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panhandle of Texas l</ENAMEX> ook at your map later and see the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fifty miles</NUMEX> north of that up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panhandle</ENAMEX> to just go buy a pair of jeans we'd drive an hour
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		when i was growing up now things are different and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buy jeans in town but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we thought nothing at all of wake up waking up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> hopping into your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> grabbing fishing poles and driving <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes Now see for me that's a long ways
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it is i imagine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		even well like i i'm in like a little town right now it's smaller than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler</ENAMEX> and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler Butler</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about an hour</NUMEX> north east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> So that will give you some idea of where i'm at and i'm about
 	
 	
 		okay okay i'll look at my map later
 	
 	
 		i'm about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> north east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow how neat
 	
 	
 		and uh i mean just this this little town here is basically a college town
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> here this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> would be nothing It would be absolutely dead because it's completely made up of fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 		and and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> when we come uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX>'s family lives up there we come up here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and it's i mean there's just no one around
 	
 	
 		so are you working your way through college
 	
 	
 		um well i go home in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and i work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and between what i make in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and student loans that's how i go to college
 	
 	
 		well how neat what's your major
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh what do you plan to do with it
 	
 	
 		um well like i said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> and loans uh
 	
 	
 		no  No no no um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> works down in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> C and i'd actually like to work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> rather than a bank or a something i'd rather work for a company
 		and um like be their financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		oh that would be great that would be neat
 		let's see uh so we're all excited in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX> is coming to town
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yes the uh new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in in the city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're expecting our local economy to
 		
 
 	
 	
 		take a boom a little bit
 	
 	
 		uh maybe not a boom but uh at least recover to where we can all hold <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular forty hour</TIMEX> jobs still
 	
 	
 		well well what would be the unemployment rate out there
 	
 	
 		uh
 		unemployment runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately six</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		see that's what it is here too
 	
 	
 		but now under employment
 		i would suspect to run closer to eighteen or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the problem is that
 		there are no good permanent full time jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without
 		a technical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> degree
 	
 	
 		yeah It's even getting hard for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> people to find jobs
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they are out of school for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> and they have a job that has nothing to do
 		
 		
 	