
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well who's the team
 	
 	
 		well i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> is going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really well i i'm picking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> because uh they just won it
 	
 	
 		they just won it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		holy cow i just walked in i i didn't even i guess it's i can't believe it's over already
 	
 	
 		it's just yeah it's just over just uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five ten minutes</TIMEX> ago i guess it was a good game uh they won by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		what was the score
 	
 	
 		either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or eight</TIMEX> it was a good game
 		but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> was just too much for them <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> just couldn't couldn't hang with them
 	
 	
 		well i suppose they must be still must be pretty good if they took on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and see i was i was really thinking that they might have a let down because i i i was in a basketball pot and i picked uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> for i guess more or less an upset but i i was thinking that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> might have a let down after playing such a tough game with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX> but uh i tell you what they uh they came back and put it to them
 		it was a good game
 		but i i i had thought all the way through that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX> was going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that would just walk away with it
 	
 	
 		well you and everybody else
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right i tell you what they uh they they looked like they were just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> among boys
 		but they they they fell i tell you
 	
 	
 		well a lot of pressure on them though i think uh
 		i don't think they had the same type of enthusiasm enthusiasm or attitude
 		probably too conservative or too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they they just need to go for it instead of uh worrying about the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> because i think if they would play their game i don't know if there's anybody that could that could keep up with them
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well what about professionally
 	
 	
 		but
 		uh i i was since the
 	
 	
 		i'm out in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> there so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suns</ENAMEX> are starting to look pretty descent but there  i think yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 		yeah here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i'll tell you what the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Mavericks</ENAMEX> are having just all kinds of problems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i tell you
 	
 	
 		well i used to live out there and uh seems like they've well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarpley</ENAMEX> just got pulled over again
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah so he he's uh he's probably going to be going to jail and and the problem with him is he's on a guaranteed salary like for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> so whether he plays or not they've got to pay him <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten million</NUMEX> dollars so if they
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh they can't hardly trade him because nobody wants to pay that much for him and if they just keep him that hurts their salary cap so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s got <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> in a big old bind
 		but uh they they i think they've just got to forget about him and uh try to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> without him
 		maybe go for some good they ought to get some good draft picks this year
 	
 	
 		who who else do they got on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> now i
 	
 	
 		they've uh they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Harper</ENAMEX> that's a real good point guard him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolando Blackman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh really they're about it they've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Williams</ENAMEX> that that i guess sort of was supposed to take the place of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarpley</ENAMEX> but he uh he just doesn't have the offensive skills
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Donaldson</ENAMEX> who's been there forever playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah how's he doing this year
 	
 	
 		just all right but he's getting to where uh i don't know if it's his age or what but he just can't play the whole game they've got to get somebody young that can uh run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that's still big
 	
 	
 		how about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh
 		not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCrae</ENAMEX> but uh
 		let's see are you uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins Perkins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they traded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins Sam Perkins</ENAMEX> they traded him he was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and uh they traded him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and that he was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and then they they've got a
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right okay
 		yeah he was a finesse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> he was good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and then they they uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> went out and got oh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fat Leever</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex English</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney McCrae</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dantely</ENAMEX> didn't they get Dantely
 	
 	
 		yeah they didn't and i'm not for sure what the deal is on him i think he's been hurt but he hadn't played
 		he hadn't played in probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>
 		and i've i've gone to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three or four</NUMEX> of their games and i don't even think he was on the sidelines so i i think he hurt his knee or something but he he definitely didn't turn out to be anything like he was supposed to
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		i think that was involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins Perkins</ENAMEX> trade to tell you the truth
 	
 	
 		it uh you know i i bet it was
 	
 	
 		oh oh no no no no no no it was what is his name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGuire</ENAMEX> that was
 		McGuire  yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right from uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> that's right that's who that was yeah because i don't think they got anything from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX> i think he was a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> or uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> his contract ended and they didn't sign him
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		i don't understand that i thought that he was always a good player
 	
 	
 		you know he was but he just went for the the big bucks i think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> was going to pay him like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen million over five years</TIMEX> and he got something like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eighteen</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nineteen million</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Angeles</ENAMEX> so he just went where the bucks were
 		and shoot you can't blame him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's that's a phenomenal amount of money
 		but uh yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> are sucking it up i tell you
 	
 	
 		are they over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i don't think so they they were right before the uh uh
 		oh what do you call it all-star break but ever since the all-star break uh
 		shoot they've they've played terrible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so now it'd be really to their benefit to to really play uh some bad ball and and hopefully get a lucky uh lottery pick
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because uh
 		there's no way they can even i think mathematically they're out of the play-off scene now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know they they need to just play for a play-off pick
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suns</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		or a
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suns</ENAMEX> are are pretty good
 	
 	
 		well they had i don't think it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year the year</TIMEX> before they were doing really good and i think they had an off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're uh
 		yeah and they did they made some trades uh
 		oh they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i can't think of his name that was real good
 	
 	
 		did you say white or black
 	
 	
 		white uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> yeah and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		he's the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if if they could get somebody to help compliment him you know i think they'd be uh awesome because that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can play
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> is is something else
 		but uh
 		i don't know it'll it'll be interesting
 	
 	
 		i haven't been i don't follow basketball real close but
 	
 	
 		i i really don't follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> that close either they they just play so many games that uh you know it's just hard t o keep up with them
 		but college i really enjoy college basketball
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> didn't fair too well in the tournament
 	
 	
 		the most
 		no they sure didn't sure didn't
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm from the  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">midwest</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you keep up with the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i kind of watch you know see what's happening
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		more of a football powerhouse i guess
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		more of a football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouse</ENAMEX> up there i guess
 	
 	
 		well no <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> is you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> won it last year
 	
 	
 		is basketball pretty big
 		do what
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> uh
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State Ohio State</ENAMEX> was ranked like number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most of the year
 	
 	
 		that's that's true that is right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and and you know there's always
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that go to the tournament
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from the big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> it's it's
 	
 	
 		yeah so that's a tough conference
 	
 	
 		they are they're really good in all the sports they
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		actually in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> you know looks like has gone down a little bit so
 	
 	
 		yeah because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX> used to be just a perennial powerhouse
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan</ENAMEX> too but uh well i tell you what i appreciate uh the conversation
 		and uh we'll have to we'll have to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> ends up
 	
 	
 		yeah we'll see
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		alrighty well uh have a good one
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	