
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how did you first get involved in camping
 	
 	
 		oh i guess uh it's hard tell i guess probably i didn't do much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> because we grew up on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and my whole life was camping uh but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		later on uh later on i think when my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> got involved she and i got involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Princesses</ENAMEX> we used to go up at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Possum Kingdom</ENAMEX> and do a lot of camping at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Possum Kingdom</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are you a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i'm i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		i guess i grew up uh camping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> were big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day one</TIMEX> as far as i can remember we grew up in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and they were uh we were always hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Texoma</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		some camping area all of either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and we were camping uh seem like every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> we would go somewhere
 		i when they talk about the definitions of camping it kind of struck me as funny my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX>
 		who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> and go camping uh a lot during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and fall but their idea of camping is a little bit different than mine they have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> wheel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> that they pull
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that has you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> a TV and microwave and stove and all that kind of stuff and he pulls it with a big pickup
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 	
 	
 		when i when i when i go camping i usually take a sleeping bag and some cooking stuff and that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's they yeah kind of cheating isn't it
 	
 	
 		well it's not like leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> when you take it with you the whole idea is to get away from it
 	
 	
 		no hum
 		yeah
 		oh sure speaking of uh southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> uh you go up into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arbuckle Mountains</ENAMEX> at all camping up in there
 	
 	
 		i have been and uh some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scouts</ENAMEX> have been up in there they have got some great hiking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> and camping areas up in there
 	
 	
 		yeah we went up to uh i talking about being an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princesses i</ENAMEX> was actually in it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> four with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one three</NUMEX> with the other and with my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> we camped up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp Classen</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'm not familiar with that one
 	
 	
 		and uh well it's right uh
 		you know i'm trying to think where it is it's not too far over the border and it's up in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arbuckles</ENAMEX> and it's near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner Falls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh uh that is just absolutely when you consider how flat everything is here that absolutely beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's a fact
 		yeah well a lot of my camping was up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arbuckles</ENAMEX> as i was growing up there's a place that used to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Platte National Park</ENAMEX> up around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sulphur</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> and and not too far from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner Falls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they have i have heard they since changed name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> to something else but it was one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> with uh a natural
 		uh spring fed river that flows through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp sites</ENAMEX> you know all along the river the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was real cold because it was spring fed but just like i say it's a beautiful area lots of hills to go camping in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> never believed in tent camping uh we had some old army cots that we would sleep on uh come
 		good weather or not a many of times we were sleeping out under the stars and it would start raining and we would all wind up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and that got pretty cramped sometimes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a lot of good memories in in in camping you know it helps you unwind and get away and forget about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and everything else back home i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah uh another thing how about uh have you been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans Texoma</ENAMEX> side
 	
 	
 		no i haven't i've never been up there
 	
 	
 		oh for goodness sakes that is that is just really nice we kind of
 		you know i've been at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> and in my young single days i used to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> there a lot then i sort of forgot about it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> started asking they say picture of it over at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> and we started going there again we sort of rediscovered it
 	
 	
 		well that that's true i've never thought i've heard about it countless times but never thought about going up there
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh it got a lot a lot of campsites you know there's uh
 		uh concrete pads that you can put <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> on there's places to pull in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">RVs</ENAMEX> and plug them in up uh there's even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and what we we used
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they have got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> log <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin shelters</ENAMEX> that are basically uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> walls and a roof log cabins with a concrete floor and a picnic table in them and a ceiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and screened uh windows
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		so you can kind of go in there and just bring your sleeping bag
 	
 	
 		well that would be great there pretty cold
 	
 	
 		and sleeping bags and air mattresses you can camp on the floor you got a roof over your head
 	
 	
 		shoot let come what may
 	
 	
 		yeah let come what may
 	
 	
 		and they're fairly close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> aren't they i mean they're right on the late
 	
 	
 		yeah they're very close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> within like uh a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred yards</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they got a place where you uh can keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> while you're there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they've got a place where you can keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> you can they've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> that you can tie up tie up and it it's uh it's in a protected area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so and i i've got a son
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		really started going about seventeen he's seventeen now he was he was fifteen then but uh i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son son</ENAMEX> and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> like to go and uh they have got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> down in the protected area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where the fishing pretty good and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know we'll we'll leave him down there at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> with his fishing pole and sometimes go after him if a big storm comes up
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's time to quit
 	
 	
 		but you know he can walk back to the little cabin in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five minutes</TIMEX> from there but it's it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety nine</NUMEX> acre i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a ninety nine acre</NUMEX> in fact they have acquired some more now that they are going they're going to clear but it's a long term lease from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's great i'd forgotten all about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> side and that's but you got to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> to use it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you you've got to be a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> but if you are a master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> the membership to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texoma</ENAMEX> is free
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's outstanding
 	
 	
 		uh you can you can get a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> do you your family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> at all you you camp with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> how how what
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that is uh thirteen and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> had learned to
 		uh ski oh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> he's a slalom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skier</ENAMEX> now and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and she just now started to learn to ski
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		yeah
 		what kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> foot Bayliner it's inboard outboard just a ski <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> it's about the right size for us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah when i was yeah in my young in my young single days i had a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turbocraft</ENAMEX> are you familiar with that
 	
 	
 		yeah i know them
 	
 	
 		yeah i had a uh a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">uh sixteen foot hundred and nine</NUMEX> horse power cylinder <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i i had that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> and then i traded it for a eighteen foot uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> horsepower V <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		goodness
 	
 	
 		and uh oh that thing eat gasoline  uh we could suck <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up thirty gallons</NUMEX> in an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> of skiing
 	
 	
 		yeah i expect it would
 		yeah but boy it would move you across the water though
 	
 	
 		yeah it will move you across the water and it would pull <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> slalom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skiers</ENAMEX> without batting an eyelash
 	
 	
 		that's what you want plus out on Texoma you have got all that you know mass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to get across
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah p lus it it planed in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> so you never dragged on anything because there was was nothing under it but unfortunately what i did was and i i guess what what happened when i was single i had it
 	
 	
 		outstanding
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i skied a lot when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> came along when they're real little they can't really participate and i guess i was paying more on insurance and maintenance than i was getting out of it and i sold it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		you're right
 	
 	
 		and never had a chance really to get back to boating again
 	
 	
 		absolutely that's what happened to us we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> in early marriage and along came the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and it kind of sat there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we wound up selling it and it's been about uh i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> uh since we got back into boating now they are big enough to
 	
 	
 		yeah you rediscover rediscover you rediscover it when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get old enough to do it yeah
 	
 	
 		you bet plus they can help now too they don't  go along for the ride
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right where do you
 	
 	
 		well i guess that's our uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> uh so we'll yeah call this thing to a halt i appreciate talking to you Bill
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay i just i can i just let me ask you one more question where do you ski
 	
 	
 		sure
 		uh
 		well i had only had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> now uh most of the time we either go out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lavon</ENAMEX> or uh we have been going up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> uh she her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live up on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beaver Lake</ENAMEX> in northwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> real good it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		dammed up the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">White River</ENAMEX> real pretty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> lake but we are hoping to explore a lot of the lakes around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and just stay close to home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i'll tell you i i would recommend too Texoma is nice because there is no many places you can ski there
 	
 	
 		oh right yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> area has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nice launching ramps
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them is in a protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cove</ENAMEX> and the other one is okay if the lake is calm it's out more in the open uh the other place that i would really strongly recommend is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Possum Kingdom</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i have heard a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Possum Kingdom</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that is absolutely the prettiest that
 		when i learned to slalom ski it was the only place i didn't mind swallowing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i swallowed a lot a lot of water learning and the only place i didn't mind swallowing half the lake and i didn't feel grungy about it like i did at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lavon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		it's not over crowded
 	
 	
 		ah no it's not over crowded it's uh it it far enough away so it's not over crowded and it's surrounded by cliffs so no matter how much wind it is there is always a big portion of the lake that's calm
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		see that's one of my biggest gripes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Texoma</ENAMEX> as many times as we would go up there it's it's so rough
 	
 	
 		yeah its too open
 		yeah and there's uh they have got some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> to fifty foot high cliffs around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Possum Kingdom</ENAMEX> and you just get up and ski uh adjacent to those and uh and it doesn't make any difference how windy it is you don't notice it
 	
 	
 		that sounds
 		oh no
 		well that sounds like a good place to start out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> i am looking forward to it
 	
 	
 		yeah oh okay well you ready to wind up hey nice talking to you my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> yeah good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right thanks a lot Bill nice talking to you good bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	