
 
     		
 	
 		yeah so it's got to be the most controversial thing if you could pick on the list
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		oh we don't have capital punishment i believe you do
 	
 	
 		yes we do
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we we have uh the death by lethal uh by injection
 	
 	
 		yeah the the only thing about capital punishment is the i i remember someone saying i think it was a chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> in this state
 		he goes if you make a mistake how do you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> back that's the whole his whole basis was if you do have that error
 		you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been in jail for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and they're finally exonerated and then you know if if there if you killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and it's like oops too bad
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean i think i've heard of cases where someone did they uh the they were uh it was capital punishment they were killed
 		and they found out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> that the he really didn't kill the person
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		i believe there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case i don't i don't know where i read it or anything but i think there there has to they have to have put innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to death before i mean
 	
 	
 		i'm sure that
 		that that have to has happened but  then there's also the um number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have
 		created or committed murders etcetera that have not been put to death even though they were sentenced to death row like like look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> i mean he just happened to have the right timing
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and yet he although he may never be free to kill again there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like him that are free to kill again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who sits you know it's the same thing about the war i'm this type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you you know you need it
 		but you're the one who you can't you can't make the decision and go yes or no i'd be a terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> because
 		i would you know i knew we had to go to war and i knew you know it was the best thing but i didn't i would not want to be responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting hurt if you know if i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i didn't want to do it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		i don't think that i could sit on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and be part of sentencing someone to death
 	
 	
 		well uh like
 	
 	
 		i i i would find that too difficult
 	
 	
 		yes but like you say there there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that do such terrible things well i had one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> was uh crime
 		and it was talked about the the way society has worked out there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that economically trapped
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they really their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't bring them up properly they have absolutely no morals because no one taught them
 	
 	
 		correct
 	
 	
 		i mean morals isn't something that's just in your heart and
 		you're born with it you're
 	
 	
 		something that's taught
 	
 	
 		it's something that's taught it's something on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> that you see so if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> eat dog world
 		it it's just really too bad that we have to have something like capital punishment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		i i don't know how much of a deterrent it really is
 	
 	
 		i don't think it's a deterrent at all i don't think that anyone that uh commits a murder actually thinks that they will ever
 	
 	
 		you don't think it's a deterrent
 	
 	
 		even uh be punished let alone put to death for it
 		i mean look at the mentality  of your average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who smokes cigarettes they don't think they're ever going to get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and yet it's written on every single package
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who murder someone don't even get caught let alone prosecuted to the to the extent of the law
 	
 	
 		so even though even though you don't think it's a deterrent which i have a tendency to agree agree i mean it's a deterrent it's it's the ones like carefully thinking it out and stuff
 		they think about it but a lot of the street crime that goes on and stuff they don't really care and they don't really care what happens to them i can see where it's not a deterrent
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i think for probably possibly the premeditated murders i think it's possibly a deterrent but
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> violence the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> murders so to speak i don't think it is
 	
 	
 		does it matter to you do you have a lot of violence where you live
 	
 	
 		not where i live uh but i live outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where where you work
 		so is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> a bad city i talked to someone from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barrio</ENAMEX> she said it was very bad
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> has much more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> violence than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Dallas</ENAMEX> does have um an area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> however the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen to nineteen year</TIMEX> old boys  are shot and killed or shot at least shot
 		frequently the uh the county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> that handles all the gunshot wounds here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		handles fifteen gunshot wounds a day
 	
 	
 		oh jeez
 	
 	
 		i mean a day
 	
 	
 		and that's relatively calm city
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it it obviously is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it it i understand that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>'s relatively calm
 	
 	
 		oh it's very calm i mean you can  our uh bad district i wouldn't advise going walking in there alone at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> but you could
 		and if anyone was bothering you you could make such a fuss where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would come to your aid even though you're in the worst part of the city
 		um the only difference is that every street light is lit instead of every other street light so we're we're a really we're uh pampered up here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and when they do have a crime a murder let's we had quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> a young <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years old</TIMEX> um
 		raped and beat and beat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these two twelve year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> really bad it just shocked the whole state
 	
 	
 		goodness
 	
 	
 		just how can anything happen like this and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that did it were so ignorant
 		they didn't even remorse they didn't they didn't have any remorse for what they were doing but they were just so ignorant
 		that one of them says well i didn't realize that was because i was beating her in the head that she was really going to die on me you know it's like
 		although why did you do it she was screaming all i wanted to do was shut her up he he acted like he didn't even think that this was going to kill her i the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were really quite ignorant about it and it
 		it was a tragedy on both sides but it just shocked the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that something like this could happen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean usually if something if someone robs in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> or something
 		and uh a home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> confronts him i mean it's not a blaze of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and stuff you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> might hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start running
 		i mean if this happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> the i'm sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> would be armed and just take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean we're really fortunate to live here but
 		doing these conversations it makes me feel really bad that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that
 		can't can't get out of the situation they're in and they're they'll eventually end up even if they want to be good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they'll eventually end up uh more or less <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of crimes even though they're doing the crimes they're more or less a victim
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yes they're the they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of neglect and
 		and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> of
 		of perpetuated
 		nonconcern for human life
 	
 	
 		yes it's it's really sad
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just it's it's just a lack of concern they don't have you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		the ones that are involved in you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> i think are searching for self-esteem and they find som ething like that in uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> activities
 		and they never had this at home and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't have it if they happen to know their parents
 	
 	
 		yes it's it's it's bad sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have no choice because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are are worse
 		i mean it they'll do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in front of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they bring this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX> and girlfriends <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they they treat them like little slaves they holler at they hit them
 	
 	
 		the other
 	
 	
 		and they go they go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> more or l ess for uh family oh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> nice to me he doesn't hit me
 	
 	
 		yeah the uh the we were shocked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two mornings ago</TIMEX> with uh the news that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forty year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had sold his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> son
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> worth of crack
 	
 	
 		oh jeez
 	
 	
 		and they found the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> had been unharmed but they were trying to sell him you know they were trying to sell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX> they were trying to sell him on the black market
 	
 	
 		that's stupid
 	
 	
 		i mean it can you that that just repulsed me and it repulsed everybody that i work with i mean it you know we
 	
 	
 		we sit up here on our pedestals judging but we're not there but it's just it is totally unheard of that you you you even think it would happen
 	
 	
 		and it was just you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty</TIMEX> miles from me
 	
 	
 		oh jeez
 		yeah i know
 	
 	
 		but it's it's it's it's real strange uh it's it's a world that um
 		is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are going to get us all i mean drugs
 		actually i think we're doing capital punishment to the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think we ought to have capital punishment for the true <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 		not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are selling it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that don't know any better i'm talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know who are bringing it to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i think they deserve capital punishment because they kill
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		they kill a lot
 	
 	
 		well then they wouldn't do this for the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingpin</ENAMEX> that they were going to um institute the death penalty other or was it life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> or whatever for the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kingpins</ENAMEX> i don't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's so full of bullshit
 		the the drug war is just terrible you can't trace it because a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are probably tied up into it i mean you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> it was the the military
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		
 		
 	