
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		all right well what kind of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> what type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> you like to go to
 	
 	
 		um casual ones but with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> you know not too fancy but uh i i won't go to a fast food place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really can't stand those uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um do you like i mean what is it about uh the the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> you go to that you like i mean what makes you like i said what makes you want come back
 	
 	
 		um
 		quality of the food
 	
 	
 		is it well see uh qualities one thing but to me
 		the uh not necessarily just the friendliness of the service but the service is real important
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to me uh i will go back to a place where uh i smile during the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> you know and just not just because of the food but i mean because either the waiter or the waitresses
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you had a good time there
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly uh that's real important to me i i can't stand going to a stuffy place i mean it's just that's not me um in your you know like you said fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> aren't any good either
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i don't necessarily uh you know there's a place here uh it's um it's good it's a barbecue place and it's uh you know you go through a line and and get your stuff
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but they make it fun you know they they they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> behind the counter are are laughing and joking with you all the time and i you know that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why i like to go back
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is excellent obviously that that is like i said that is important
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um you know if i don't know that i would go back as often if it wasn't for the idea that i have fun there
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		there's some places though that i go to they don't have the best service or they're not the friendliest but i'll i'll tolerate it just because i know that's the kind of food i want to eat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's other places but like you said the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> doesn't matter it's you have such a good time there
 	
 	
 		have you ever gone to like dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> or or uh things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i have not in not in a good while but
 	
 	
 		well see i'm uh i've been to dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> but the every time i go it's you know on the nonmeal show type you know type thing so i've it's been a while since i've been to one uh
 	
 	
 		just to see the show just to see the show right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um normally its comedy i i enjoy comedy although there's one that i'm i'm really looking forward to going to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of weeks</TIMEX> it's a i just found out that well i'm sure they've they've had them for a along time but it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's like a mystery uh theater uh that you you know you eat dinner and all through dinner they're they're doing this act and they they get supposedly get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> involved in it and everything and that that sounds like that would be hilarious you know
 	
 	
 		um
 		um
 		yeah that sounds pretty wild
 	
 	
 		cause because i love watching mysteries on on TV anyway and i love figuring them out before they do you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course that's probably a lot easier on TV to figure it out than it is in other things because TV they have a tendency to do a lot of things uh
 		that aren't you know what i mean um predictable exactly but i mean you know the the dinner a dinner theater like this ought to be just wild i don't know
 	
 	
 		predictable yeah
 		yeah that does sound like a pretty neat idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so um i mean is there anything else about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that would make you go back though
 	
 	
 		well there's this uh there's this type kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> called a brew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX> are you familiar with those
 	
 	
 		no hadn't heard of them
 	
 	
 		where they they brew their own beer there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and there's i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and there was a lot of them there and there's actually there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm a i'm a home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brewer</ENAMEX> myself so i just am envious of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you go there  and a couple you have gone to you can order like a sampler
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and while you're eating your meal and usually their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is good too they they bring out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> that they brewed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> and you just test it's like uh beer tasting thing while you're eating your meal and it's really neat
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah that sounds kind of neat
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is location at all important to you
 		like you know how far it is from your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah i usually don't  go somewhere that's too far away
 	
 	
 		well yeah i i guess
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> is always been the one closest  you know the closest as long as it's it meets the minimum criteria you know of good food
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i guess for like lunch places that's really important because you usually that much time or or whatever
 	
 	
 		um no kidding
 		
 
 		working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> that's pretty important
 	
 	
 		oh so that's why we're getting all these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's what i figured but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i didn't i don't want to assume that that's what i figured no i'm a college i'm a university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so uh
 	
 	
 		so yeah that
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		that also has a has a little bit of bearing on what restaurant choices you have when you're flat broke all the time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah money does
 		yeah i can see that
 		so
 	
 	
 		but uh i'm going to be starting working full time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> so maybe maybe my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> will change
 	
 	
 		so you graduating are graduating or
 		yeah well maybe i don't know i'd uh i really haven't changed that much since i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in school um of course you know i'm not sure you ever get out of school to tell you the truth and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		depending on what industry you get into or whatever like uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> being electronics uh you never get out of school so you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually i graduated
 		with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS</ENAMEX> in double E in in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX>  and i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> ever since then
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one semester</TIMEX> off and and i've been taking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at least one class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every semester</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well like i said though my my change my taste in in food really hadn't changed all that much in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i mean a little bit yeah uh especially in you know i didn't have the money to go to these dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and stuff before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		whereas i you know i have gone to a couple of these things before you know lately and you know it's like i said i missed the dinner dinner part of it but i've gone to the theater
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but i you know like i said that's that's probably so price really i guess does have a lot to do with it i hadn't even really considered that before
 	
 	
 		um
 		i've become a lot more health conscious and that's why i stopped eating fast food and places like that
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		yeah well that's probably true to so
 	
 	
 		i used to love hamburger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> and i don't go to them i don't eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> anymore but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		well unfortunately i'm not as good about that as you are i still go every once one in awhile
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i used to just i i used be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX> of hamburger places
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grill</ENAMEX> that's the place to go for the best burger
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well it's like i said you know the different there are different reasons for different things like that and you know hey you're right health is one thing that just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		now i go for the best place to get uh tofu or whatever
 		not quite that bad but uh
 	
 	
 		i was wondering yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well all right well i think that should just about do it
 	
 	
 		yeah good talking to you we'll see you later bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah take care uh-huh bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	