
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> are you thinking about getting
 	
 	
 		well none at the moment  No no no
 	
 	
 		well when you decide to
 	
 	
 		i currently drive a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i would imagine i would imagine that if i change or if i get another car a new car i will go with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> or something similar uh in that regard
 	
 	
 		so you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		absolutely i have had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> now and it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's everything it's supposed to be uh i haven't had
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minutes</TIMEX> trouble with it and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the only thing i have
 		against it in that's it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> but is it i still feel a little even after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> i still feel uncomfortable driving it because i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> before that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it's a little bit larger but that's the only the only difference that i see really
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i would my my criteria would be at the moment it would be uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> uh personally
 	
 	
 		uh-huh Yeah it's the this the car i had before this one was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thunderbird</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact and uh i loved it i really did
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		But uh um i finally decided to go check out what the uh what the uh foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were So i bought myself a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S X</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		But even though i love the car i've got now i think my next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> will probably be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> again because if i can at all do it i'd like to stay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> i always have up until now i just for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time decided to go outside So
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> drives a
 		still has a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> and it's a very it's an excellent automobile
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but you know price and so forth i'm not a real car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so i i
 		i do not uh
 		opt for uh something that would be
 		you know
 		expensive you know i want i want something that's serviceable serviceable something that i can use and uh and i and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LX</ENAMEX> and it's you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're talking when you think about price it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several thousand dollars</NUMEX> lower than the comparable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> or something along those lines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and as i said as far i'm concerned it it has been extremely uh uh serviceable and everything i wanted
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s done a real good job in the last uh say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years or at least the last five to ten six years</TIMEX> so of really turning around their um quality i think um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i think so too now i
 		you know in travel and renting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> uh in i've driven you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and so forth and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> i just will not touch it uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> before i bought my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> i purchased a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">um Citation</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah those were not good cars
 	
 	
 		and uh i was ready to get rid of it  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> after i bought it and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i shopped around and i would i probably if i had thought i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> wanted to pay the amount of money i probably would have gone with uh uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> or even a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> or something comparable from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh but it was just i had i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who uh has a uh an auto shop
 		and he purchased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sables</ENAMEX> that was uh manufactured for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> and he just absolutely swore by it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was upon his recommendation and so forth for you know comparable
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">comparably</ENAMEX> equipped you know with cruise control and air conditioning and AM FM radio and all these other things uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was just there was no there was no comparison uh the only thing that i find you know if i would have anything against it is that it still has that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soft American</ENAMEX> ride uh uh not well that about the only thing i find you know disadvantageous to it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but my criteria is simply something that looks good something that's serviceable
 		and i you know i drive around a lot but uh and it's you know it's very comfortable on the highway i can drive for you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten hours</TIMEX> or so and
 		not really be tired in any way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but those are my criteria and i i probably in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another six months to a year</TIMEX> or something will probably start looking around again and if there's something out there that uh
 		is comparable to what i have now
 		so i'll go ahead and get it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh You know the only thing i'm looking at right now um i just i just bought you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> that i've got about uh say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months ago</TIMEX> i guess it was
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		So the only thing that that would um get me to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> right now would be if see at the moment i'm single
 		and if i were to get married and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that would have to have something to do with it But uh i don't have any plans for probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another two three years</TIMEX> of even looking you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are too expensive right now to uh
 	
 	
 		i see yeah
 	
 	
 		to even think about buying new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple of years</TIMEX> you know it's
 	
 	
 		in our parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots uh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three days ago</TIMEX> i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i i can't remember what the name is it's the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand</NUMEX> dollar one whatever it is
 		and it looked it resembled a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mazaratti</ENAMEX> very very closely
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and
 		it's an absolutely beautiful automobile and well appointed and so forth but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to pay that much money for an automobile uh is just
 		i can't i can't conceive of doing that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh i went to a a car show down here about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks ago</TIMEX>
 		and um you know of course they had the normal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> that stuff But
 		then you started looking at the uh uh they had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrari</ENAMEX> there they had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> and and all these other kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferrari</ENAMEX> didn't even let you near the car i mean they were that's how expensive they were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then you saw uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred thousand</NUMEX> dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty thousand</NUMEX> dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and
 		you know even even though i i i do enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i enjoy um driving them i enjoy uh riding in them and everything but uh i can't see buying or paying more for a car than i would for a house you know i
 	
 	
 		that's true well
 	
 	
 		that doesn't seem likely
 	
 	
 		uh the difference there is too is uh is between us is that
 		i am not really crazy about driving i never have been since you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had to force me to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license when i was young when i was sixteen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i've never really cared now what i was you know before i was married and before i went to graduate school i used to do little
 		you know sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> racing i never
 		it was never my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it was always someone else's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that sort of thing i enjoy but to go out and drive
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> never has really been had any appeal to me in that regard so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i guess we've discussed that enough don't you think  we won't we don't we won't get the recorder or the uh system to shut us off uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> that's happened to me almost every time i've
 	
 	
 		i think so
 		that's happened to me once so uh
 	
 	
 		well when it's it's very easy when you get a topic you get on a topic that you know you enjoy and
 	
 	
 		yeah like uh you know i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i did it was on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid the Mid East</ENAMEX> the crisis out there and everything that was had a great conversation but uh then they came off and told us we couldn't do it any more so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		
 
 		well i was talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last evening</TIMEX> and we were talking about fishing and uh we were cut off uh-huh well we were told to quit okay well you have a pleasant evening
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		you too uh-huh bye-bye
 	
 	
 		take care good-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	