
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh what do you think about our involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well actually i think it's good i i i hope that we uh uh get a chance to uh promote peace out there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because i think without peace we're not going to get uh stable oil prices and
 		and uh i'd i'd really like to see stability in in that area because i'm always afraid that's where uh another big war is going to start
 		not that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> was a small one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah that's probably true i i suspect that if any world war is come at this point in time they're going to come from there
 		uh i would think anyway i mean it just seems to me that that's that's the most unstable part of the world as far as i can tell
 	
 	
 		i saw um just recently where uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is supposedly going to be uh putting pressure on all the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> supposedly to to come to a bargaining table to uh
 		actually i heard that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> were even talking at least mentioned about giving up some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golan Heights</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that'd be interesting because i um i actually um um i'm i'm i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and i'm actually sort of not not not not not really a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX> per se you know i'm not
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but i have a um
 		i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> you know who are sort of adamant you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> should it's his right and they do whatever they want and i think they've been sort of hard nosed about the entire thing
 		and uh you know in some sense may the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> may be right they may you know may be it is better if they give up just a little bit just to sort of settle things down
 	
 	
 		well uh i guess it's one of those things that uh if it's going to really promote a lasting peace if there is not going to be a peace
 	
 	
 		right then then then it then is it worth it at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i i because the way i mean sort of the way to think about it is well
 		they won you know they sort of took over the um
 		they're one of the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in in in history that has been told that they have to give back what they took in a war which they didn't start
 		basically so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't i don't know how to i don't i don't know what to do about it but um  but i think that that you know in general the region is really in bad shape
 	
 	
 		do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> is going to wind up keeping uh military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> over there
 	
 	
 		um probably oh isn't isn't there a plan now to make a command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> there or something
 	
 	
 		i i haven't heard that i i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> every once in a while but i i haven't specifically heard anything about that
 	
 	
 		i just heard something about moving recently about moving um
 		there there there's some central command post in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX> i think they now want to move to somewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 		actually there was um a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i think well you know not actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> or or anything but a little bit off to the um east of it i think
 		and i they want to keep something over there so that they don't have to um
 		i guess it's i guess it's so that so they don't have to move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> out so quickly or something i'm not quite sure exactly why they want to do it
 		but they want to keep some sort of central command post there
 	
 	
 		what i thought was interesting is that uh apparently the formal cease fire has not actually been signed yet
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh  well i guess there's still the possibility that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could still break out
 	
 	
 		yeah that they they they claim that's why we're still there i mean you know why only you note it's only only a small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have actually come back yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think that's actually the scariest part because when in the way what what's happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> right now
 		you know just in itself it it it being so crazy there
 		i have no idea what i mean what do you know just to imagine that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> they're going to turn around and someone's going to say we don't like you and just start attacking again and
 		it's going to be worse
 		i don't know um
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't i have i i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and and coincidently actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah so i am we are sort of we are the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks at home um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh pardon me i'm just sort of putting away some things from dinner now  in the background but we um we
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she has sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> actually well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and um i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and we we talk a bit about it but we try and keep it out of out of the home life
 	
 	
 		do you uh does does she ever want to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no she was she's actually um
 		i think it's um for her not not really relevant because she was she's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> generation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who were born here would like to go see it though i think they would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> but but they recognize that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>'s not the place that one wants to visit
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right about now</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		you know just something about the place makes it not not quite enjoyable
 	
 	
 		do you ever want to go over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i'd actually been there um i was there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> when it wasn't as you know sort of dangerous to be out there i guess
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i do i do i do like it actually um i would never live there i think i'm too Americanized and um sort of have too much you know too much invested in sort of
 		the the easy life but i do like the food
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if that if so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if that if if that amounts for anything
 	
 	
 		okay well who you know do you have uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosher</ENAMEX> foods there at your house
 	
 	
 		yeah actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is Kosher but um it turns out that one one of the strangest things about about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is that
 		no um most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> don't realize that but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of as sort of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> food and so forth um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know um in general really isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that is eaten in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> so you you i'm sure you probably typically think of it like bagels right you know bagels and lox
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		turns out you don't you don't you don't really find bagels in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> what you find is sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> foods the same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> that you find in um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and everything else you find things called  have you ever had those
 	
 	
 		yeah no no no uh kishkes or knishes or
 	
 	
 		which is
 		oh oh knishes no you don't you you you don't see a lot of that that's basically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's it's very different i'm i i was actually very amazed when i sort of figured this out for myself that everything i grew up with really wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> it was more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		i got you
 	
 	
 		it it it it is very strange um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		still get your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matzi</ENAMEX> and all that right
 	
 	
 		that that starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's what i'm making that's what i'm d oing now i'm making dinner
 	
 	
 		oh really i dated uh i dated a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
 		and i was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goyim</ENAMEX> at at all the you know Seder dinners and everything and i used to have to go with rolls of not pocketful of change to buy all this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would sell me
 	
 	
 		ought to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> from
 		that's great well you've you've you've really got a handle on this stuff i've noticed you
 	
 	
 		not not
 	
 	
 		got got the vocabulary down and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah not uh just just enough to get by
 	
 	
 		that that that's actually real good yeah we um we actually we have the reverse situation turns out that um um most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s not but i
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but i um i sort of you know do a lot of these things so so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Seder</ENAMEX>'s you know our our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Seder</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and this is a rare exception there are going to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> which and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of them will be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two two years ago</TIMEX> we had a Seder we had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> each night
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sixteen</ENAMEX> seems the magic number for us
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and i was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> both <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so
 		so which to me is wonderful because it means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who never would get these to see this um
 		so get to see it and my view is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passover</ENAMEX> is should sort of be in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in in in in</ENAMEX> in my mind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX> is sort of a generic holiday anyway because it it sort of predates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well they had the matter of fact i just watched uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Heston</ENAMEX> this uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten</ENAMEX> Commandments
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i caught the end of that
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> i try and catch that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but yeah that's what always amazes me actually is that um
 		is that you know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i always sort of bring this up about she her her being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> you know and my being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and all we look alike we act alike we sound alike well not totally alike but you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um um it's amazing to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> sort of all hate each other
 	
 	
 		well that's uh to me it's it's really um
 		i i i guess i guess i can intellectually uh kind of come to grips with all of that but you know emotionally i have a real difficult time believing that uh
 		that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that believe in God and and love not war and to forgive can't get together
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i mean i i know that the problems are so deep but i mean even even within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> uh religions different sects they can't get together
 	
 	
 		right that that's actually the part that that that i find really strange i mean i i i sort of understand somewhat i mean i i knowing the history i understand that the hatred of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> for you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> or whatever and i can sort of handle i can sort of handle that and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
 		but i sort of think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> sort of running around having jihads against themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i mean and and that seems really weird
 	
 	
 		or the uh the the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		you know i mean i i
 	
 	
 		same same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't i'll i'll i'll never understand it uh my view is look what'd you ever do to me
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		didn't hurt me you know at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at the moment so um and and i i don't know there's a there's something about there's a poem somewhere i don't know if you've ever seen it or not um <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Everything I Ever Wanted to Know I Learned in Kindergarten</ENAMEX>
 		have you ever seen this and it talks about how you know if we could just all get together you know when we were young everything was great because we you know just sort of all went to class together and in the middle you know we all had snack time together and then we all took naps and we all held hands and hugged
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and that's and that's and that's what that's what kindergarten was like and wouldn't it be nice if if we could solve all our problems by just sort of getting together and everyone in the world sat down and and took a nap together
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		woke up and had snack time you know and then hugged each other as as we left
 	
 	
 		it sounds like a it sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> uh type
 	
 	
 		yeah  i wonder if he secretly did that
 	
 	
 		gosh
 		
 		
 	