
 
     		
 	
 		yeah i just bought one so
 	
 	
 		well that should be interesting
 		okay you ready
 	
 	
 		yeah guess so
 	
 	
 		here we go
 		
 
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> did you buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Mazda</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> how come you got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh price basically
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		price and uh what it
 		all the things it came with for the price i couldn't beat it
 	
 	
 		you couldn't couldn't find an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> built car
 	
 	
 		uh i didn't really look at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> uh had a couple bad experiences with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		just not holding up so
 		uh my last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was a foreign foreign made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and it held up real well and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> before that was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and it fell apart so
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		i just  decided to go foreign
 	
 	
 		i've had pretty much the i've had pretty much the opposite experience
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah i generally drive a a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> super <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> you know like one fifty or something and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i traded and got something different i got a little Datsun uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> cab
 		it didn't last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> i had had more trouble with that
 	
 	
 		really
 		hell it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> though i would probably think to go <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> because everybody know has got a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made truck
 		they just seemed to be more rugged but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> just seem to fall apart
 	
 	
 		yeah i that's that's probably true i'm getting ready to i think i'm going to trade off the super <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> and i'm considering going with either one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door S10 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blazers</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX>
 		but i can't decide which one
 	
 	
 		get out there and test drive
 	
 	
 		yeah that's about the only thing to do i'm just i i'm looking for uh fuel economy and and durability and i've got to have some high road clearance we got some property and i need to get out in the pasture a lot
 		but i don't need to haul a pickup as much haul around stuff in the pickup as much as i used to we got an old one there at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> we use now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i just got to have something i can get out in the field and of course that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> is only getting like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles a gallon maybe twelve on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> and that just kills me
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		especially a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> a gallon or more for gas
 	
 	
 		i don't know how much going to
 		how much better you're going to get with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Blazer</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		well those small ones uh those little bitty ones i'm going to go with the small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wheel drive i don't really i i haven't had a use for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive tell you the truth
 		they say they're getting eighteen to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> in them yeah i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's got a uh he bought a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> with the positrack rear end instead of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		he's getting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen to eighteen</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty to twenty two</TIMEX> on the road
 	
 	
 		oh that's not so bad then
 	
 	
 		no he's not really and he's not he said he's pretty heavy footed he's clipping along at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five or so</TIMEX> around there when he can get away with it
 		so i think i could probably stand you know twice the gas mileage
 		it wouldn't hurt my feelings a bit i just don't know if i could stand one that small because i'm fairly large and i've always driven a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know i haven't been in the now ones that you know they look big on the road some of these uh
 	
 	
 		they don't look too bad i just you know i i have have to get in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to find out i just don't know if i could stand you know being cooped up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> of hers she's never sold a car she's bought
 		she has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty nine</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> a fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a sixty seven</NUMEX>
 		and anytime i drive any of those i just you know it's like being in a coffin i just feel hemmed in i've got to have something fairly large
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think probably probably my whole problem is going to be trying to find something that will that will blend you know uh fuel economy and and price and uh durability
 	
 	
 		durability yeah if you got to take it out in the field
 	
 	
 		you know the little those smaller trucks
 	
 	
 		yeah they show them jumping over those ramps but hey
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that's
 		i think it would be fun if you didn't have to pay for the repairs to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that's what they don't show you when they get you know when they get them off they show them jumping up and down hills and like that but they don't show you the repairs
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know the front ends impossible to line up on mine
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last time</TIMEX> i lined my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> front end up it cost me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten</NUMEX> dollars
 		so i don't know
 		how you getting gas mileage in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> have you had it long enough to know
 	
 	
 		oh about uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty six twenty seven</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> it's a it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinder
 		and it's kind of a
 		sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">coupe</ENAMEX> guess a little sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		you do most of your driving you do most of your driving in the city you do most of your driving in the city
 	
 	
 		it it does pretty good
 		huh
 		yeah i haven't even had a chance i've only had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three months</TIMEX> i haven't had a chance to take it out on the road
 		i'll probably be heading down your way in uh oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of May end of April</TIMEX> i guess when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s out
 	
 	
 		um well watch it coming down south down when you get through uh round round <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundrock</ENAMEX> they got a highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrol</ENAMEX> that just patrols up and down that thing in those little fast Mustangs
 	
 	
 		i'll have to keep that in mind because uh
 	
 	
 		he just he just lives out there he makes his living on the road out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundrock</ENAMEX> and where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown Georgetown</ENAMEX> or  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Georgetown</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on down through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundrock</ENAMEX> he just he just patrols up and down through that area now that's a neat little car
 		those little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five little five</NUMEX> point oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mustangs</ENAMEX> the fast ones
 	
 	
 		oh uh
 		yeah i i wanted to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mustang i</ENAMEX> wanted to get a convertible but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">convertibles</ENAMEX> you know they tack on an extra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five six</NUMEX> grand
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's like i can't see paying that for a
 		for just
 		being able to take the roof down
 	
 	
 		you can get a sunroof a lot cheaper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's probably more functional
 		i don't think i had a convertible once in college and it was fun when you know during the warm months
 		but God it was miserable during the winter i don't care what they say
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like i got and plus the way crime is going around here in the city you know take a knife to it break in
 	
 	
 		yeah and those convertible tops used to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> i don't know what they are now probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> by now
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure they're
 		yeah and you tack on the insurance they can add to it because
 	
 	
 		if you ever roll one that's pretty much it
 	
 	
 		insurance
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that
 		that that that and the windshield post doesn't stop much
 	
 	
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that rolled a convertible not too long ago it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> totaled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> he walked out of it though
 	
 	
 		um
 		you don't give those they don't give those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMWs</ENAMEX> away
 		those are expensive machines
 		um
 		well think we about done our <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right i got a meeting to get to so
 	
 	
 		okay
 		good talking to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see you later bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	