
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well i'm uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> so i'm heartedly in favor of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> converting to metric
 	
 	
 		i bet you are i bet you are i don't know you know when i was in uh when i was in high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> you know we did probably
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or two or three weeks</TIMEX> on the subject you know and tried to teach you the whole thing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> and of course when you're that age you really don't care anyway and i didn't get into it very much but then i took a a list of a basic math class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of semesters</TIMEX> ago
 		and we uh we were pretty heavily into the metric system and and before we started i just thought oh no i don't want to do this you know this is just going to be so hard and once i really realized how easy it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it was wonderful i mean it was just incredible how much simpler it is than what you know i guess we just all have this mind set that oh this is so hard and we can't do this
 		and it's really not hard i was surprised at how very easy it was i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just uh
 		you know automatically have their minds set against it and don't give it a chance you know so
 	
 	
 		Yeah well i think uh you know from an elementary standpoint it would help to get rid of some of the the oddball conversion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> like
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve inches</NUMEX> to the foot and
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six inches</NUMEX>  to the yard and things like that but uh i think uh from my work experience i found
 		well when in college
 		i learned uh to use a rationalized system of measure which turned out to be the metric system
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and an awful lot of the problems that we did on exams and our homework assignments and everything else involved converting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> or nonstandard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> into this uh rationalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M K F</ENAMEX> system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so i became quite accustomed to uh to a rationalized system and and used to making all the necessary conversions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and since then i have discovered uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> are very prone to make mistakes
 		because they will pick up a textbook and uh and find some formula for solving a problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they fail to realize that the formula is expressed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rationalized</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M K F</ENAMEX> system and they'll proceed to plug in inches and feet and pounds and uh  things like that and they come up with a funniest answers you ever you can imagine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it just don't work
 		i bet i bet
 	
 	
 		and some of them don't realize that they've made a mistake and so uh you know a lot of energy and uh a lot of work and so forth uh goes into building something only to discover it doesn't work
 	
 	
 		right right well you know i think that the that the only way that we are ever going to get this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> switched over to metrics is just to start other with with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		Yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you you you're going to have to start with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that are in when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and you're going to have to teach it well not like i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> on it in a math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and that's all you ever hear about it you know they're going to have to start
 		with the little ones and teach it right now and then when you know those little ones are our age you know that's what they're going to know and that's what they're going to use there's no way you're going to get you know most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult population</ENAMEX> to automatically relearn and switch
 	
 	
 		Yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's just not going to happen that way but i do think if they would start with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now at you know in you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years from now</TIMEX> we could be switched over
 	
 	
 		yeah i kind of agree that uh maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> on or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> we should have gone into a uh sort of a dual display arrangement where you know our our speed limit signs were
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		were sort of a double sign with a a big <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles per hour</NUMEX> and a little <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers per hour</NUMEX> type uh marking on the side
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		and then over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the kilometers per hour</NUMEX> gets bigger than the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles per hour</NUMEX>  and eventually disappears
 	
 	
 		they'll
 		very good idea yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and little things like that i i notice in a lot of uh
 		uh technical literature that you pick up and catalogs and so forth that you will find the metric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> expressed in parenthesis or sometimes the other way around the metric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> are expressed first
 		and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> equivalent that's uh is put into parenthesis for reference
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think i think it's going to take that but i you know i  i think it's going to take a lot more than that too you know it's going to take it's going to take this education with our with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i really believe that but you know you it
 		we we knew that we weren't going to have to ever use it again we knew we were going to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> of it in math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> so why take the time to really learn it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i mean you would you know learn enough to get by on the test and then you forgot about it because you knew you were never going to see it again in the rest of your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of school
 		you know and and that that's not the way to convert over you're going to have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know teaching it dually even you know teaching both systems which is a lot i know a lot more for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to have to teach but that's the only way they're going to get switched over you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think also equally important is that uh it needs to be put into practice in in everyday life we're seeing a little bit of it now that you go out to work on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and you discover your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrenches</ENAMEX> don't fit
 	
 	
 		oh yes yeah
 		yeah yeah that's true too that's true
 	
 	
 		you've got to go out and buy a metric set
 	
 	
 		buy a whole knew metric set yeah
 		well i think you know it's something that's going to take quite some time to happen
 		but i i still don't think that they're doing all that it's going to take to make it happen you know it's going to happen slowly no matter what but there's going to have to be a lot more education involved than there is right now to get it to to get it to switch over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i was a little disappointed that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is lagging the rest of the world but all of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world have made the change and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> which are probably the most stodgy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">originator</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system of measure uh they have gone metric
 	
 	
 		even they have switched yeah so yeah we're not uh we're not necessarily on the cutting edge in everything are we  just like we think we are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		so well i think eventually it will happen you know it's just going to take it's just going to take a lot of education and a lot of time and like i said i was just totally amazed at how at how very easy it was you know i i just couldn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i just when i going into it i just had this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> and i went there's just no way i'm going to be able to learn this and when i sat down and really said okay just you know forget your old prejudices and really look at it you know and once you look at it's so really simple you know you
 		there's really nothing to memorize there's nothing to learn it just all works the same you know you just you know transform that little you know dot from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place one way to the other you know and that's about all you have to do so anyway i think it will happen eventually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		I
 		i think one of the other concepts that uh comes along with using a rationalized system of measure is uh a technique of keeping track of units
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when you're solving a problem that if you're sitting there trying to uh establish a relationship with some physical system uh when you come up with your final formula if you analyze the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> of measure they should come out right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the the basic units of measure are are distance and time and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass</ENAMEX> and electric charge
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so if you convert all your measure into those uh fundamental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and analyze them you can uh get a pretty good sense as to whether your formula is correct
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe you left out a factor of pi or something like that but
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well you know i think uh i think it's going to happen i don't know i don't know what else i could suggest to them you know if they ask me what should we do
 		i don't know i wouldn't know what else to suggest to them just education start with these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know and like you said you know start making it practice you know start showing all the street signs and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> of course i think all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are manufactured that way they aren't aren't all of them
 		most o f the new ones i'm seeing are are made with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles per hour and kilometers</NUMEX> on them
 	
 	
 		Well i
 		most of them have uh the option the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American American</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have uh the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the miles per hour</NUMEX> as the big scale and they're little tick marks uh sort of hidden on the scale which shows <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers per hour</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		But those that are manufactured for sale in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and so forth are quite the other way around
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and in a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that come to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> particularly those that have the uh electronic panels there's a little push button some place on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> that you can switch <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">between uh kilometers per hour and miles per hour</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		is there really huh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> convertible has little buttons that you can choose what display you want to see
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting yeah well
 	
 	
 		Yeah i noticed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> has a uh a button on the temperature gauge that you can switch between centigrade and fahrenheit
 	
 	
 		oh well that's interesting too i had never seen that yeah you know you look at most of the you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> clocks and stuff like that it tells you you know fahrenheit and centigrade and it's going take those kinds of things you know switching you know
 		getting us all accustomed to seeing both you know but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't pay any attention you know it's going to take some education right along with it most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't know what that means you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well we also need to be a little bit careful and maybe we start
 		to not use the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> measure anymore like when you listen to the weather forecast the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather man</ENAMEX> may give the temperature in centigrade and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fahrenheit</NUMEX> and everybody ignores the centigrade and listens to the fahrenheit to the fahrenheit
 	
 	
 		that's right because that's what they're familiar with
 	
 	
 		and we we sort of have to get accustomed to the fact that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> temperature is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty seven degrees</NUMEX> centigrade  yes
 	
 	
 		right that's going to be hard to do it's going to be very hard to do you know you
 	
 	
 		and that it's a nice day when it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five degrees</TIMEX> outside
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know i'm so used to saying oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and three</NUMEX> degree fever and you know just say it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty nine</TIMEX> is not just going to sound very bad  you know
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> think that you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> is boiling over
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right that's right your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s still alive with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and three</NUMEX>  so yeah it's going to take a changing lot of our old prejudices and you know just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		making up our minds that yes we are going to do this and we're just going to forgot this old way and we're just going to do it you know and i don't think the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is probably ready to do that you know
 	
 	
 		Yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no i hope we get to the point where maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of generations from now</TIMEX> when somebody reads the old adage
 		
 		
 	