
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well how many credit cards do you have
 	
 	
 		um
 		i've only i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> maybe
 		i try to limit them because i well one i don't use them
 		uh too much and i use my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> just for about for about everything and i pay it all off
 		so i try not to i just use it for free money for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> basically
 	
 	
 		sounds like we have no conflict we had for a while i was carrying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was carrying a different one
 		and since the slips all look alike uh you commingle them and then you get the statement and you try to sort them out and it and it uh
 		it it causes more confusion about it i finally said gee this is kind of a waste of time and then when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> came along and offered a free one uh i accepted that and we've been using that one
 		uh the interesting thing is is that uh the amount of money you can can run up on them i don't know do you know any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that run up big big bills
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm you know i'm in the age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> you get out of college and i think a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have them maxed out
 	
 	
 		well did um were you able to get one while you're in college
 	
 	
 		um i don't think i ever tried
 	
 	
 		just curious because i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a senior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and he's heading off with any kind of luck but there has been i've had a couple of ads for a for for to provide a card for a college student
 		uh what do you think about the idea of providing one for somebody like that
 	
 	
 		um
 		well
 		
 
 		yeah i i you know it's
 		you know feasible i mean i know a lot of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who have them you know who had them but
 		just depends
 	
 	
 		well that that that i guess from the from the card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuer</ENAMEX> uh that since since it's it's in monitor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> gets it for them that really the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> becomes the one that's responsible but it's
 	
 	
 		yeah so basically if you want to take the risk
 	
 	
 		yes it's whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> wants to take the risk
 	
 	
 		it's your risk
 		do you trust your your son
 	
 	
 		yeah to to go run up a big bill and the thing is there some  there some advantages if he got off some place and stranded i i'm i'm leaning towards doing it for for convenience
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i'd say do you know
 		have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a thousand</NUMEX> dollar credit limit or something
 	
 	
 		a convenience
 		yeah and the idea that you know if he got in trouble there's some some ways of getting out and that he doesn't have to carry cash
 		the uh i i like the idea of credit cards that uh i don't i don't i don't carry cash around and and uh i don't even carry checks around i let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> take the checkbook and
 		she writes the checks and i record them so it's uh
 		it's uh it's but it's interesting that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can that can uh the amounts of money you can run up with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on on credit cards and uh i i had recently had some dealings with a fellow that they had run up he was making oh considered a modest salary for an engineer
 		and he had run up uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a years</TIMEX> salary in in various debts to
 		and he wound up declaring bankruptcy but there it it's hard to believe that you'd run up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> of
 		uh well it was a combination of things he had uh there were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there were several credit cards and then there were several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> but uh i i guess what's interesting have you seen the uh the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> the ads where they're offering to extend payments on
 		uh things like uh like the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s offering
 	
 	
 		the the extended loan payment for your car
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw that
 	
 	
 		the interesting thing about that is is that uh that that they're encouraging you to incur more incur more debt and
 	
 	
 		well it's it's it's business and they're making money off that
 	
 	
 		and they make more money if you extend your loan
 	
 	
 		yeah and and it's so it's business so and you notice that they're they're only going to do it to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so they've already shifted the risk if they assume that car then they just have to sell it themselves and they'll recover the loan
 	
 	
 		and they know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> own a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that new unless absolutely dire circumstances or anything they're not going to keep on if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> were older
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the interesting thing about it is is that from a uh uh an economy standpoint or in economics i i thinks it's i think it's poor poor uh economics to to carry all that consumer debt
 		at least from a tax standpoint so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's interesting that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is encouraged to incur all that debt and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> none of it will be deductible and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent or so
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's interesting that that uh they encourage us to do things
 	
 	
 		what now what's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent we can deduct
 	
 	
 		i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent yes of your of your consumer credit
 	
 	
 		i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		oh if you had a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> that means there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another hundred</NUMEX> dollar deduction i've given you
 	
 	
 		i didn't think you could anything on a loan or
 	
 	
 		yeah it's on uh yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean a mortgage i know you can
 	
 	
 		yeah on the uh there's there's there's a place for consumer debt and then you take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent of it on the
 	
 	
 		oh i've never itemized yet
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so maybe that's
 	
 	
 		it's on it's on schedule um
 	
 	
 		schedule a or
 	
 	
 		schedule a under uh
 		well it's the same place it's the same place you put uh interest but but see that's what that's what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> squirrelly laws that uh you can't you can't take out a a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mortgage
 		uh like some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where you can take out the mortgage and declare that and so uh it's fully deductible the laws are a little squirrelly but it basically comes down to it's not in your best interest to borrow money from a tax standpoint
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i try i i really do i just try to stay out of debt and i and i use my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> for for as much as i can and i pay it all off and
 	
 	
 		sounds like you're you're very responsible very financially responsible it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's uh there're a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really run my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> drives quite a ways to work and he's got just enormous debts and he's
 		uh but i mean what do you say it's like shucks  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> i'm sure sorry you've got all that debt well he's had had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in college and and this kind of thing and that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that the whole credit card issue i think they certainly encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to run up the debts and but i agree with you i don't i try to limit my debts well i did buy a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		and i took a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> note out on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when i right when i got out of college and uh
 		i'll never do that again i still got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> on it to go and i'm
 	
 	
 		it's it's remarkable how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as soon as they get out of college buy a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and that uh apparently that's been going on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> long time i didn't do it i i bought a second hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when i was the middle of my senior year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you you think you're starting out well until you start paying all those bills uh apartment rent and
 	
 	
 		yep
 		miscellaneous things like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and and other things these habits you get into eating and and uh it's it's it's amazing how it what you learn
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		yeah and and
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		well anything else good to say about credit cards
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah they're they're convenient you know that's that's a
 	
 	
 		i might just
 	
 	
 		probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big thing about them and
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you don't have to carry the cash and and uh and it's it's it's certainly accepted more places than the places you know it's hard to cash a check if you're out of state and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i was used to using my credit card like at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Skaggs Alpha Beta</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and stuff and now i'm out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		they don't allow they don't do that
 	
 	
 		they they none of these grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> take any credit cards so now i have to carry cash when i go to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> which is new to me you know i got to have sixty bucks on me or something
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		carry all that cash with you
 	
 	
 		that was interesting cause i always you know you didn't have to worry about carrying that much unless i knew i
 	
 	
 		well you know they they
 		they've started towards a little bit of the debit card have you seen the debit cards where they actually debit your account when you
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard about them
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think that's where
 	
 	
 		that's mostly locally the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> will line up with uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen a couple although the so many of the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> don't do that because of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the time</TIMEX> frame which they get paid
 		in general that uh they i've seen checks deposited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very next day</TIMEX> i mean cleared my account <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will write a check for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and
 		you know almost well i guess it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after uh technically it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> but they they they took that check and scurried it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and the bank scurried it back to my account and you thought there'd be just a little bit of float but apparently that's why the uh
 		the uh the uh grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are reluctant to do that because their volume that is quite high and they have uh
 		the profitability of the cash flow is a big issue for them so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		anyway well it's good talking to you
 	
 	
 		all righty
 	
 	
 		maybe we'll get across we'll cross paths again good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		all righty
 		take it easy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	