
 
     		
 	
 		okay what types of music do you like to listen to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i primarily listen to classical music when i have my druthers partly because i find it more soothing i don't know a lot about classical music so far as uh any background in music but it's the  the music i enjoy the most how about you
 	
 	
 		i like classical music also i uh like you i don't know a whole lot about it and i i would like to buy more classical tapes and stuff but i'm not sure
 		which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> or which i really like so i kind of hesitate to buy something There are certain kinds i like and certain kinds i don't
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i tend to listen to the classical music uh on the radio a lot there's uh one particular well there several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in this area that play uh classical music all the time but there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in particular that
 		is on both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX> and FM so i can listen to it without uh worrying it's cute though because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when they get in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i have uh the button pushed for that they always switch it to something else
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because naturally that isn't their taste
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at this point in time anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand that
 	
 	
 		are are you involved in music
 	
 	
 		uh no not really My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is but not i do uh the world a favor and i don't sing aloud to anybody but myself
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well my whole family uh is somewhat musical um and not from training but just because we sing in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> and
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s quite involved and all that sort of thing so um i think that one of these days maybe she'll get involved in classical music too because that's usually what happens if you unless you get into rock which isn't her voice style so
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		yeah i i don't care for rock at all i guess i'm real old fashioned
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in my musical tastes
 	
 	
 		no i well most of it is not all that exciting in that it is terribly repetitious
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it's loud and repetitious without having a great deal of meaning now i do like folk song um and there have been some nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> songs over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that you know kind of still hang around
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um but the more popular music i don't care for usually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um even when i was a teenager i didn't really like the music of that period so much because i found i liked um a little bit more melodious music than what was often the popular
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> and roll kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with that too
 	
 	
 		although now i kind of enjoy hearing the rock and roll i guess it makes me think i'm young again
 	
 	
 		yeah now rock and roll seems tame compared to like the New Age and all that stuff
 	
 	
 		isn't that the truth it's funny in fact it's interesting to me that so many of the songs now i grew up
 		in the late fifties and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early sixties</TIMEX> and so much of the music that was popular at that time has come back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you you don't hear everything all the time but you hear much of the same music perhaps a new version of it but it's the same stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um which is always kind of funny um and i remember my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years older</TIMEX> and at the time that i was
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a teenager late teenager i guess i can't remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">year Smoke Gets In Your Eyes</ENAMEX> became popular i think it was done by maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Platters</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then and she laughed and she said well you know when i was a teenager that had been you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> before she said that was a version of you know a song then and she said it's very similar but they've changed a little bit she said i like the original version better
 		well they did it again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about  two or three years ago</TIMEX> and i laughed again i said oh no here we are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		crops up every so often i listen to um the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> radio station when i'm in the car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K L T Y</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right it does indeed
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like to listen to some of that music
 	
 	
 		yes now that there there's some wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music when you can find good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> uh the problem problem that i found um in this area is that the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there there is inconsistency in the quality
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here if you get someone who's very good at selecting it's okay but sometimes they kind of get on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a binge and they play the same sort of thing over and over again without really necessarily quality
 	
 	
 		yeah where do you live
 	
 	
 		uh i live in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i thought maybe you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> because that's the complaint i make to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> about the radio station too i said oh they're playing one of their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> songs it seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> they pick <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and they just play them over and over
 	
 	
 		yeah  and it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and i i you know there's so much available that i don't understand why they do that but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have have sometimes um well they've gone to a few of the concerts and so on of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> that come for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth group</ENAMEX> at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and um and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they when they buy a tape or something sometimes that's fun because it's different and something i've not always heard and you know i enjoy that
 	
 	
 		right
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Patty</ENAMEX> songs he likes to sing those in church he'd buy all the sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> he could get his hands on if he had the money to
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		yeah that's nice so is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well just an amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> sings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> and he likes to do special music and stuff at church
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		well that's a good thing to do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like to hear him sing he does a good job
 	
 	
 		that's nice uh well do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no not yet we're expecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well wonderful that'll be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess we'll start listening
 		yeah maybe so we'll start listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s music
 	
 	
 		oh there's some wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uh children</ENAMEX>'s tapes
 	
 	
 		yeah there are
 	
 	
 		you can uh you can get and i know when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were younger um we found a lot of really nice tapes that they that they liked um there was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Agape</ENAMEX> music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and um
 		i some of the songs i still find going over in my head over and over again because they were really um
 		very memorable even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are now my youngest is almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> but i still find some of the same tapes i uh some of the same songs from those tapes i enjoy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um there's one that's um a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> singing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Practice Makes Perfect</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she's playing the piano and so she she gets the wrong note every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> but then she keeps repeating it practice makes perfect and then you know talking about that so far as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> life too and it's really cute
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		yeah that sounds really cute
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to sing to my stomach because they say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> can hear quite a lot while they're still in the womb and i said then when when it's born you can hold it and sing that again and maybe it'll comfort her you know when she's fussy and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yeah well do you know something because i have always played classical music
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or classical style it's not always classical as you know the official uh word might go but um
 		even when i was pregnant of course i listened to that and when our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was you know an infant um of course i when i was around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i played that music too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when he first made sounds that you could detect they were in the scale the music scale
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		someone else noticed it and i said well i guess that's true and it was somewhat melodio us in other words it wasn't just you know it was really funny
 	
 	
 		how strange
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> babbly i'll say that is  well we'll have to keep up with that then
 	
 	
 		right right i do think there is probably an influence there because i noticed that even though popular music
 		the the wilder stuff was around when my uh older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were were you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> when they first start listening to music on their own they first get ask for a radio of their own and so on um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> um really listened to to more um ballady or um
 		pleasant sort of songs rather than and even classical rather than the real hard rock stuff that so many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> listen to
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i i never i didn't want to say too much for fear he would think it was wrong and wouldn't do it anymore
 	
 	
 		right yeah have something to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> against
 	
 	
 		right  but uh but i must say they all kind of like a variety of music which is nice i like that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good yeah variety is good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i guess that covers it It was real good talking to you
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking to you and good luck with the baby
 	
 	
 		um well thanks bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	