
 
     		
 	
 		um what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> do you live in
 	
 	
 		uh we live in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story just like a ranch style home you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the standard</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		with with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> and fence
 	
 	
 		how about you guys
 		are you in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house apartment</ENAMEX> or a house
 	
 	
 		i'm in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in uh Plano
 	
 	
 		well they say that those are easy to find or difficult to find
 	
 	
 		yeah they are if uh kind of depends on what you're looking for mine's just a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom place</ENAMEX> that's uh
 	
 	
 		how are rents doing i haven't looked at rents in a long time
 	
 	
 		uh it's hard for me to tell because i haven't rented in uh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh just i'm getting back into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> life
 		and it's
 	
 	
 		what's a what's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> are you in a um well Plano most most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> are pretty nice so you're probably in a you know
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		well they vary from from place to place it's hard to tell you know how well they've been kept up how old they are and these are probably oh one of the nicest that i found and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hundred a month</TIMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> place
 	
 	
 		ooh that does get high yeah i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah it does considering that you know you uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> payments are not a whole lot more than that
 	
 	
 		yeah i was going to say our mortgage is is between depending on you know it it drops um seems like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six months</TIMEX> we um got lucky and we refinanced and it but it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> and something but it went down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like seven hundred and</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's really not i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about nine hundred dollars</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouse</ENAMEX> in yeah in actually they're near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plano</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> too but i couldn't believe it but you know
 	
 	
 		wow that's a lot for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouse</ENAMEX>
 		but that's what happens when you get up in this area you know you got all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are up here and these they i guess they know they're going to get it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and then i think that um nobody was really buying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> there because of just i mean we've been in ours for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years</TIMEX> but uh there's no investment in it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		all it allows you to do is itemize
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true you just take off your mortgage interest and that's about it
 	
 	
 		on your
 		on your taxes yeah that's really about it it's uh have you ever owned your own home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah i've owned uh several and built several uh
 	
 	
 		so you know what it's like yeah it's like when you first this is our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one it's not um and it's not that exciting after a while
 	
 	
 		well well and especially around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> or at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> area they basically all look alike because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah suburban track yeah
 		we uh we lived out of state for a while and came back and uh we lived in a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and now we say gee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> really is big and polluted
 	
 	
 		isn't it i can remember i've only been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> but i can remember coming to work from i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wylie</ENAMEX> and i could see downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now there's this brown haze over it and it's moving north
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really it's really sad because they're they're not doing anything well we're getting off the subject i guess but just like with housing i mean they're not doing anything about pollution they're not doing anything about it's going to look like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know um i used to think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> was better than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> because their zoning for where you can put a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> next to a now it looks just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> to me you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it does how how long have you been in this house
 	
 	
 		we've been in here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so we've got you know we've got some investment in it but you really don't get anything out of it
 	
 	
 		no you really don't were you said you were out of state for a while was that a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> than than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah smaller we were up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how were the how were the house prices up there
 	
 	
 		my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> um the prices
 		actually a lot better because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> is about the size i'm trying to think like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> that type of size
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the prices what you get here for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred thousand</NUMEX> you could get there for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about seventy five eighty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really and we didn't think it was that clean but then after you're gone for a while it looks cleaner you know
 	
 	
 		hum
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well you know a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i've talked to that are coming down from uh like what i call the back East especially from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are selling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred thousand dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> up there and buying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and fifty hundred</NUMEX> and seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> down here
 		and they've wind up getting better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> here than they had there
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so in a way i guess it works both ways you know
 	
 	
 		i guess it's yeah but and here i guess it depends on what you want you know here once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX> in marketing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that came from that area probably like what you're talking about they had no um they had a lot of property but not a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and now they have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and hardly any yardage around it
 	
 	
 		that's a fact
 	
 	
 		but but they love it i mean they they they think that they're getting you know you say um sun room to them and you enclose and you can sell
 	
 	
 		i guess that's true and they don't have to worry about yard upkeep because they don't hardly have any
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and a lot of them i know a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that work there and they don't miss in public relations and they don't miss having a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> to run up and down to you know
 	
 	
 		that's true there's not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i said you haven't heard about tornados  how about bugs you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah gosh i remember when i was little uh we didn't have a i lived grew up in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> and we we never did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area it was tornado <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> up there and every spring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would drag me up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three o'clock four o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and pajamas and teddy bear across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and we'd go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		to this day i don't care if i go or not you know if it's going to get me it's get me
 	
 	
 		that's exactly uh growing i grew up in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and uh we used to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX> actual cellars so it's funny to hear that word because i never hear it you know it's like the back porch used to be a stoop you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh um the housing is just we like the older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and i don't know if we're going to stay here or not depends you know i mean
 	
 	
 		you ever thought about building a house
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		you ever thought about building a house
 	
 	
 		yeah actually when we were up north um but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> things changed so we ended up coming back down here and all that because it helped my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s work but um
 		we really would like to but we don't know if we're going to do it unless we stay here you know it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true especially well well <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is like anybody else you never know how long you're going to be here or be in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it it's real tough i mean the economy any more i mean i think everybody just lives under an umbrella the uncertainty with housing and everything you know it's um pardon me
 	
 	
 		yeah do you work
 		do you work
 	
 	
 		yes i do
 	
 	
 		so how do you handle do you got any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no we don't
 	
 	
 		so you got he's working and you're working and you got this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">big house</ENAMEX> to take care of how do you manage both of those
 	
 	
 		uh how do i take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house well</ENAMEX> i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> i don't i shouldn't say that i don't have an ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>  i don't have we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that live near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell Road</ENAMEX> and they have like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four thousand square foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and she's got a uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a live out nanny um but any rate i don't have any of that um i don't know it's really not too difficult with no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		you basically can take care of everything yourself
 	
 	
 		we have a
 		yeah we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and we're pretty i mean we're not fanatically neat but um we keep things up you know it's not like where there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> or anything in the yard by the time you need to um get around to fertilizing and cutting in the spring
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		what about home repairs and stuff do you have to do all that yourself or
 	
 	
 		um no we're pretty much um we we've been around long enough as a couple that we learned a long time ago not to wallpaper together
 	
 	
 		wow you too
 	
 	
 		and things like that um we pretty much hire we subcontract mostly everything i mean other than anything that's not a um i mean i know how to fix a running toilet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		he does what he needs to but mostly if it's something major um you know cleaning out the air conditioning ducts or something like that we just hire out to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah sounds like you you've already got the makings for being a general contractor
 	
 	
 		yeah no thanks i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		if you don't wall paper it well together you should probably not build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		have you ever done that i mean you sound like you may have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah i built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in my life and
 	
 	
 		and how'd that go
 	
 	
 		oh they the the building process was a lot of fun but puts a lot of strain on things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		getting to agree to things that i'm sure and i also think that once you get to be um you know certain when you get to be thirty something and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> something gets to be a little bit older
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you start um the dollar value on things
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		i you know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> are very materialistic
 	
 	
 		oh you bet
 	
 	
 		i know i'm supposed to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that own the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that own them are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home homes</ENAMEX> themselves and you know um spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> dollars a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> for custom draperies for custom drapes just doesn't
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well to some of them i guess it doesn't matter you know that maybe they've got enough coming in to to take care of it but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		i mean and and you know you see a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that came east from uh west from uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX> and it's just a hoot to watch them
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah they as far as they're concerned they've come to the promised land you know they've got it made already
 	
 	
 		right right exactly so well was it hard to adjust living in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> after being in a house
 	
 	
 		oh yeah because you're combine uh confined by space you know i had a i came out of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty one hundred</TIMEX> square foot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house house</ENAMEX> and i had room for everything
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness yeah
 	
 	
 		in fact i had more room than i knew what to do with i don't know it's it's seems like room uh stuff always expands to fill available available space but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well in a way you can travel light
 	
 	
 		yeah you can yeah you know you learn you adjust you figure out
 	
 	
 		how is how is apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling</ENAMEX> living in terms of general privacy and noise and things like that
 	
 	
 		it's not as bad as i thought it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's not as bad as i remembered especially going to college and living in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> there you know how noisy that can be
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i do
 	
 	
 		uh there seems to be a a more a mature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> at least where i am uh even though you know there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all around and there's there's traffic and there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX> and stuff like that but still uh
 	
 	
 		everybody pretty much keep keeps keeps to their own turf so to speak
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty much and uh there's never really any any oh i remember in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> there's just seem like there was a fight or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or something going on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> you don't run into that up here i think i think because there's so many uh professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if you want to call them that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that go spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> at work and they want to come home and they want some quiet
 	
 	
 		yeah relax and try to go to sleep really yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah  you see a lot of activity outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> riding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> or playing ball or jogging or doing this and that
 		and uh they're trying to to unwind
 	
 	
 		and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> in general is getting a little more well it's gotten so big it's almost a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in it's own right
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty thousand</NUMEX> something like that
 	
 	
 		isn't that something yeah the price of home now we paid
 		oh we paid um <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventy eight nine</NUMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> like i said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a decade ago</TIMEX> not even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine years ago</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'd say they appraised it it's gone up you now maybe like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's an investment but it's something that you know when you're first married or starting out you think if you really have something but you really it's just real nowadays with the way income tax i think housing is strictly to itemize
 	
 	
 		oh you bet and the thing that that gets me is uh you never really catch up you never really finish doing things and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly we
 	
 	
 		you're always paying for something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and even you know i mean like we had i called them prefabs just a track home you know i mean we we had one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that was nicer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> but um it was an older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but then you buy an older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and you're always fixing things up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh you are constantly there's always something going wrong
 	
 	
 		so you know
 		
 		
 	