
 
     		
 	
 		well in the norman in in the normal route of way we do things how about the ladies go first
 	
 	
 		alrighty  um
 		well i uh have have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> who will just be entering public school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> so i'm really just starting to get involved in uh in what's out there and how they do things um
 		as as far as the system as a whole i really don't see a a problem with it i do see a problem with graduating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that can't read and are not
 		you know productive in society or productive to themselves and uh i think that's the main problem at this point
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		all right i'm uh live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> and uh um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we're not even suppose to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because the uh the way the taxation and all that crap is there really legally isn't any funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so uh i mean when you when you take uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and put them in situations they have to make decisions based on money to fund public education and they can't get their finger out of their ear long enough to
 		to get that major subject in line something's wrong so i think here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> mainly that the the
 		they're not serious they're more serious about what the salary should be for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> than they are for what how the level of education should be for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> so i'm not i'm more opinionated about the observations than than the than the true facts but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's just a shame to me that that that the our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> and school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three least</NUMEX> paid utilities um that have the biggest impact to our well-being
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		i have a i have a real issue with that um i think that if from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> when they when they pull in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> the uh test
 		that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten eleven</NUMEX> twelve year uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> take and and and you see that their their education is below the norm throughout of all fifty states then that's saying that something's wrong with the educational system here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i have a real concern with about that
 		um um matter of fact i'm very content to send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> out out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to college in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> uh verses having her go down here and not learn anything and then uh so i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my my opinion i think i think there's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> uh hopefully hopefully the new uh education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of education will do something to fix the problem but uh
 		i don't know they got to quit worrying about uh the uh religious uh overtones in our textbooks and get on with teaching the product
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they get bogged down in a lot of small issues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> can blow up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and not really get down to teaching what's important
 		teaching these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know how  really the basics is what it comes down to
 	
 	
 		exactly i i was astonished to find out that that across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in all public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> it is not mandatory for them to take phys ed
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		half they don't even a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> don't even uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> nowadays don't even know what what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitness Education Program</ENAMEX>'s all about they don't have to do sit-ups and push-ups and all that crap we had to do when we were going to school
 	
 	
 		huh
 		i remember
 	
 	
 		and yeah and uh i'll i talked to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen year old</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> who's uh goes to uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> schools high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or or junior highs i guess and she said that that she had a a choice she could either have taken tennis or weight lifting so she chose to take weight lifting
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		over the regular gym i mean give me a break i mean the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> sit there and they drink and they drink <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cokes</ENAMEX> and eat popcorn for for for lunch for lunch and then go out there and lift weights
 	
 	
 		and talk yeah
 	
 	
 		and don't learn anything it's just a real i have a real problem with the whole system they need to put some sternness back into the into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and let them be able to uh get the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> out and get some discipline
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah then it comes down to what you said before though about them being uh some of the lowest paid public you know public service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that there are and yet they're so important
 	
 	
 		i used to
 		i used to date a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who taught English at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade level
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i was absolutely flabbergasted at what she they would that she was paid true she was young you know but still it's the principle of course if she got her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree it'd all be different but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		well you know it's hard though because then you start talking taxes and uh  that's bad word
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh taxes lord forbid forbid lord forbid taxes goodness gracious if we would uh plan our expressways a little better that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> we'd cut that in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and give to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> we might have such a problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 		there's an idea
 	
 	
 		maybe i should run for office huh
 	
 	
 		run on that then no income taxes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> huh i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too so
 	
 	
 		this is true
 		that's funny that's funny
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well gee
 	
 	
 		well that's about all i have here
 	
 	
 		well me too i uh i think we both agree there's some problems there but
 	
 	
 		yes ma'am
 	
 	
 		we'll small maybe do our small part to fix them up
 	
 	
 		surely i've enjoyed it bye bye
 	
 	
 		all right you too bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	