
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Brian</ENAMEX> i going to press number one and we'll go
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hey um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie</ENAMEX> i think my first introduction to the metric system was in physics in college and i think prior to that i didn't even realize that another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> existed
 		uh but it makes so darn much sense to me
 		over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system i i i have a hard time understanding why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't take to it
 	
 	
 		is it
 		well um
 		yeah i'd
 		i agree with the the ease in the use of it
 		and uh
 		the it certainly it's so much easier to do your do computations calculations to measure things with it to in every every aspect of it is simpler except there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big stumbling block in it
 		and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and that is all of the tool and die equipment in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that has been here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last hundred years</TIMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand
 	
 	
 		and tool and die equipment doesn't wear out too often
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		so i think that's the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place where
 		uh they will have a hard time uh getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to change
 	
 	
 		yeah and i noticed that too in uh in uh uh metal stamp metal parts that we buy
 		we at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time went back through and dual dual dimensioned them all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it's uh it's easy to put down point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one inches</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mil
 		uh it's kind of difficult to have its metric equivalent
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh in in terms of the numbers that you've got to carry around i guess one of the things i i think metrically
 		i've got a uh a and it drives my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> crazy you know she'll say how far is it from here to somewhere she wants to go and i'll say oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eight kilometers</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she'll look at me and give me this crazy look but my uh my my uh hobby is distance running
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and basically all of the races are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K fifteen K</ENAMEX> nobody runs in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i guess that's got me thinking metrically
 		also uh uh we have lived overseas From nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> we lived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quadalampor Malaysia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and for in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six and seven</TIMEX> we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baggio City</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i guess you just get used to seeing distances beside the road marked metrically
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and ultimately at some point you know it doesn't happen overnight but at some point your frame of reference is metric at least in terms of distances
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i uh lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> from when i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and
 		so by the time i got into high school and took some physics there and then into college um where i was a physics major in college so i'm more than
 		uh familiar with the metric system
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		but
 		i think that initial period you know from way made it familiar for me so i wasn't afraid of the metric system and and and i knew how much it made sense and how much easier it was to do things that way
 		so i i it's too bad that more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can't don't have the opportunity to to really use it
 		to to get to a point where it it's something other than something that causes them fear and confusion
 		because if you just
 		the initial in the initial stages of anything no matter even if it is something that ultimately will be simpler are going to be confusing
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 	
 	
 		and it's getting over that hurdle that will
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		finally get us into it if we ever get into it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i don't think it's going to happen in in in our lifetime at least not in mine
 		uh i think uh there's a gigantic psychological barrier which may be a worse barrier than the old tool and die uh dimension in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i think that the uh the ultimate solution will be to start introducing it uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at</TIMEX> at the introduction to school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh hang on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sec Brian i</ENAMEX> got to get rid of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you there
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		okay i think the uh uh the solution is to start it at the earliest uh stages of schooling
 		and uh uh make that the system to which kindergartners and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> are introduced
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the drawback to that is i don't think we have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in our other than physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in our school system that are comfortable with it
 	
 	
 		right  right that may be true also i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemists</ENAMEX> seem to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemists</ENAMEX> that's what i got my first degree in chemistry too and i and you know we don't talk in quarts and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">pints</NUMEX> we talk in liters and milliliters
 	
 	
 		it
 		okay
 		no
 		i mean can you imagine how ridiculous it would be to try to do calculations i mean it boggles the mind to try to think to do all the chemistry or physics in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system at this point although gosh all those
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i i don't think we could even think <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and i'm just thinking now in our business you know we make we make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chips</ENAMEX> and uh we assemble them though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's interesting we are uh uh basically talking well we talk about a package size yeah we talk about it in terms of uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hundred mils or six tenths of an inch</NUMEX> i guess we do that
 		but on the other hand we talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that it takes uh to move a die out of a package in other words how much uh uh how how well do we have the die uh inhering to the to the base
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we talk about that in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilograms</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so we use it a lot we talk about uh gold ball bonds bond strength we talk about that in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">grams</NUMEX> or in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilograms</NUMEX> to push the uh push the ball off its substrate
 		so we we tend to have a mixed bag in new concepts uh that have come along with the electronic age i think just sort of get introduced metrically so that's the way we do it
 	
 	
 		right it's interesting in the in though the work i'm doing i'm uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh the kind of things i do is manage uh research and development contracts and we do everything from
 		basic research all the way through uh we have a couple of systems that are actually um places where they're producing a product
 		and what i've noticed is that the places where they're kind of doing fuzzy thinking and uh
 		doing the initial uh
 		development of an idea use the metric system
 		and they talk in terms of metric uh uh units
 		in turn around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> however that have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> that are actually producing a product
 		do most of their carry conduct most of their discussion in terms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> units
 		which i i find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's interesting that it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are still doing the work that are actually making the stuff are using the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system
 		but the ones that come up with the they're doing these theoretical analysis and the number crunching um
 		are doing it in terms of the metric system i i
 		it kind of seems strange
 		but
 	
 	
 		right you you mentioned just a side light here you mentioned you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> whereabouts
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo</ENAMEX> our our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> there is in Cantinas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm there several times a year
 	
 	
 		no kidding uh
 	
 	
 		and uh of course we fly into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sao Paulo</ENAMEX> and and drive on to uh uh Cantinas
 	
 	
 		and do you fly into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camgonias</ENAMEX> or the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> down there down so uth
 	
 	
 		uh i use the other one
 	
 	
 		yeah okay the international airport
 	
 	
 		i can't think the name of it
 		yeah the international <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> because i i generally fly in from uh well the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times i've come in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menaus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh before that though it's uh it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio De Janeiro Sao Paulo</ENAMEX> uh type flight
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		and uh i just love it there i i absolutely uh uh uh love the i look forward to the times i go down there where did you get your from where did you get your physics degree
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Academy</ENAMEX>
 		uh i'm one of those
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 		yeah you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> are are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian employee</ENAMEX> about now or or military
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no no i'm i'm still in the i'm still a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lieutenant
 		i just graduated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh okay okay you're you're you you're a bit younger than i thought uh back to the the metric system
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've got a uh an automobile an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Skylark</ENAMEX> that's got an odometer that's a digital odometer in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in other words i can push a button and it's in metric and i can push a button and it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i keep it in the metric uh all the all the time and we were taking another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> to a ball game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was uh floating up there around a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a a hundred a hundred</NUMEX> which is about is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about sixty two miles an hour</NUMEX> and it was floating up there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a hundred</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> looked at me she said my God slow down i didn't realize you were going this fast
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so we we you know we have a hard time getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting uh uh getting them to think metrically but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's going to be a big psychological barrier and i don't think that we can educate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all the way to their adulthood and then introduce it to them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because if we if we keep doing that it's it's not going to work
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		but but interestingly enough we think it makes sense to to think metrically with our money
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know ten cents makes a dime <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dimes makes a dollar uh which is basically thinking metrically
 	
 	
 		right
 		well the whole
 	
 	
 		but why twelve inches make <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a feet</NUMEX> a foot and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> feet make a yard  i  you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't
 		or the whole number system is digital so how can you have uh or it's it's base <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> rather and so how can you have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how can you have these uh strange i i
 		
 		
 	