
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jay um</ENAMEX>
 		could you tell me uh what your thoughts are about crime
 	
 	
 		i tell you what here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's uh it's awful bad because that they're i i believe there's starting to be a lot more violent type crimes
 		uh where you see armed robbery and and uh rape and murder you know are starting to be a lot more prevalent in this area
 		and uh that's that's getting that's getting scary because i grew up in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i moved here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and uh it's been a rude awakening i tell you
 	
 	
 		oh so that's
 		what do you do work in Plano
 	
 	
 		uh right right
 	
 	
 		how how far away is that from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		well see it's it it's really just a suburb uh i really can't even tell where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> starts and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Dallas</ENAMEX> ends
 	
 	
 		oh so it
 	
 	
 		but uh i grew up in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh moved down here to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano an</ENAMEX> and uh
 		it's uh it's definitely a big change
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh that's the same with me well um
 		i grew up in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> there's nothing but farms
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i still live in the same area it's it's built up somewhat and crime
 		really hasn't been a problem it's been uh
 		uh mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> coming in and you know robbing or breaking into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and stealing uh
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		radios and cassettes and things like that
 	
 	
 		not really the violent crimes then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		not so much in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> i live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but but the closest large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> and then it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> which is about uh
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		oh forty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five fifty miles</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		which is really not that far
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> is only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> miles from from where i am
 	
 	
 		okay so that's real close
 	
 	
 		but the cities down there yeah and and
 		and the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up is uh is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> between me and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that they're stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">handbags</ENAMEX> now in broad daylight they're taking the the crime now the latest thing up here is
 		uh they'll somebody be driving along whether they're they're in their early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>'s or or teens
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they'll steal jackets they'll holdup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they'll take their jackets and chains you know just get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh Lord
 	
 	
 		because they have got some of these like the leather jackets are are quite expensive
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know i've heard about that uh also for tennis shoes
 		there was uh uh  a big surge going on oh just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i think where uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> uh were uh knocking off other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to get their tennis shoes
 	
 	
 		they just  that's that's incredible
 	
 	
 		yeah i tell you what though if you go price some of those tennis shoes i can see why now you know they're getting up in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollar</NUMEX> range
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		and that just seems ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah for a pair of tennis shoes
 	
 	
 		for a pair of tennis shoes yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah no shoe is worth that that price uh
 	
 	
 		so
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know not to not to go out and scuff up and
 		but
 		i don't know what the it's
 	
 	
 		i don't know what the answer is though to to try to fix that problem
 	
 	
 		it's probably the uh the times now um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i know you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> down there have had have had a problem for a while which we're experiencing now with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah just economic overall economic uh times around here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> have been tough
 	
 	
 		yeah and rents are are extremely high i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they just don't care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it's either it's either you go out and you and you steal something or you you bash somebody over the head
 	
 	
 		to get it yeah
 	
 	
 		or you starve
 	
 	
 		well another another problem i think is the the drugs
 		you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to get money for the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they'll just go out and do anything they can to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we had we had uh an incident in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> not too far from where i live where uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> made a raid on and and most of them were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> or or
 		or in their early twenties
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		which is unheard of in a small town
 		you know you don't usually associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but they did they made the raid you know and the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was upset
 		but i'm not so sure now if if uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are really prevalent they're saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> now is is uh one of the major contributors
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		like all of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> now on campus uh i guess most of them drink or have binges on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and going to school
 		is also always very prohibitive now unless your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are wealthy
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know you either have to take a loan or most of them don't work or if they work they work part-time for
 	
 	
 		yeah it's hard to get a job you know
 	
 	
 		minimum wage yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not sure down there if you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are all picking up but up here it's it's terrible
 	
 	
 		you know we really haven't uh because the oil industry just hasn't come back like it was
 		and so much of our economy was based on that
 	
 	
 		so you're still suffering then
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		as far as that goes
 	
 	
 		right that that and real estate you know just have not come back uh even close to what they were
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is you know you can see some economic turnarounds but uh and i don't think it will ever be back to what it was because it was you know it was really blowing and going there for a while
 	
 	
 		yeah i was down
 		i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> about uh twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years ago</TIMEX> and then i just went down again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> for a week
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and it was it's like one huge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> when i was flying in
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it was just all lights
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but you couldn't tell there was a problem
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know because it's so huge
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		part part of the problem too i think up here is i mean um
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		all the banking crisis all the white collar crimes uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stock brokers</ENAMEX> have been getting away with bloody murder the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> have been getting away with bloody murder
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		nobody's being prosecuted
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		what's going to stop them from you know other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		right what's
 		yeah what's what's the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> going to do that's that's you know being threatened or thrown out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and he's got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to support and he's got no job
 		um
 		i'm not sure how much of that is is crime rather than just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out there for a good time yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's true too yeah yeah
 		but you know the violent crime is is uh definitely something's got to be done on that
 		because
 	
 	
 		yeah because there's more and more there's more murders we had uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		just in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> murders
 	
 	
 		golly that's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Rhode Island</ENAMEX>'s just like a neighborhood compared to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> down there it's just so so so small
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and nobody even cares or nobody seems to care
 	
 	
 		they just overlook that as uh common occurrence
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah and if it's if it's drug related they turn the other way because that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less problem that they have to put up with the law enforcement
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh that's
 	
 	
 		and uh if they do come in i've got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and they say that you know they apprehend somebody and they bring them in and uh they let them out they're out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> before they get their reports done
 	
 	
 		golly that's terrible isn't it
 	
 	
 		so there's no checks and balances
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure what what to do about that or which way it's going to go
 	
 	
 		well see i'm not either because i'm i'm really not for higher taxes you know to go out and pay for uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be out on the street
 		as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and things like that but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they're being overwhelmed i think anyhow i mean
 	
 	
 		i think yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		the fire power against them now is is atrocious
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		you know they've got
 		all kinds of automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and these poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> out there uh trying to uphold the law
 		um
 		i don't know i kind of think they should bring back capital punishment
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 		well i do too and you know i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> argue that that's really not a deterrent and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't think about that but i've i've got to believe that
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		in the back of their mind if they know they're going to go out and kill somebody and that you know they're going to get the death penalty then and that it will actually happen
 	
 	
 		it's yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so many so many of these jokers get the death penalty and then you know just end up in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty years</TIMEX> or forever there's no
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know with the chance of even getting paroled and uh you know that's just
 		i just don't understand that
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		and when i say there's no deterrent you know of the death penalty
 		um that's like saying that
 		you don't put up any stoplights anymore because it's not a deterrent for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to stop at crossroads
 	
 	
 		right that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		so it it just doesn't hold water and you look at some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that that have the death penalty
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they don't have anywhere near the crime rate that we do of the violent crime rates that we do
 	
 	
 		right right because you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> just shoot you on the spot you know forget that trial and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and all that you know they just
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah i yeah i wouldn't want to see it go that far
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know give them due process and then and then let them
 	
 	
 		and then do it huh
 	
 	
 		and then let them appeal yeah then you'd get yeah because some of it some of it's it's it's just down right
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh mean i mean they go out there just just for the sake of of harming somebody
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and those are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know can you rehabilitate them the some of the ones that are you know perpetual
 	
 	
 		exactly and and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know i don't even know if they are worth rehabilitating if if uh they go out and commit some of these violent crimes
 		so but i don't know what the answer is we'll just have to i guess each each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will just have to try to do their part and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah he can
 		
 
 		because it's eventually it's going to it's going to swing back
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it was
 		they had the death penalty way back and then it swung the other way and everybody's swore you know we're no better than they are if we if we put the death penalty in and
 		
 		
 	