
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i think the crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is horrendous
 	
 	
 		compared compared to what
 	
 	
 		compared now to when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> came here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> when i came here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> it was not near as bad as it is now it's terrible now my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has already been broken into once and there was an attempt
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> another time i mean i can't it's horrible i'm afraid
 	
 	
 		do you live in do you live near downtown
 	
 	
 		no i live well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Cliff</ENAMEX> but uh
 		uh we never had any problem here before we we really did not in my neighborhood we're not wealthy at all know you know we don't have a rich neighborhood and when they break into our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> they don't get anything
 		much they get a little jewelry and maybe you know a VCR's and it just irritates me to no end that somebody has broken into my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and stolen my things you know just
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 		hum well i live i i live in in north
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">west Garland</ENAMEX> actually west <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a mile</NUMEX> south of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one ninety</NUMEX> so we're really quite far north and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we just moved into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that has lots of windows and i course i have a friend <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> that lives right behind me so i don't know if that'll do any good but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh it it's interesting though that you've been broken into uh you must you must look at this whole mess a lot different did you see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that they the the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> got a pay raise and the the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> didn't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i hadn't i hadn't heard that
 	
 	
 		it just on the news i was just watching a little of it just
 		before you called it uh and they cutback and they cutback on overtime and they have to take electric clocks home and you wonder what that does to the fighting crime if if they had an electric clock on their desk they were supposed to take it home to save energy
 	
 	
 		are you serious  that is the city
 	
 	
 		i'm serious  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Clark</ENAMEX>'s on channel eight
 	
 	
 		that sounds like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for a while and i do know that they're they can be really strange
 	
 	
 		what what what do you think why why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> breaking into your house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they want to see they take what they do they break in and they take your jewelry and they take it and they sell it they hock it and then they buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i really think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they want the money for the drugs
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so i think <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is the root of it
 	
 	
 		what time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> are they breaking in
 	
 	
 		well okay i used to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">second</TIMEX> shift and when they broke in i was working at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i i work in payroll now and i <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work days</TIMEX> but uh they broke in
 		they knew my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> told me evidently they were watching me and they know your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hours</TIMEX> see that's what so spooky about it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and they broke in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX> and uh since then i've put in a security light and i've marked everything i you know that i have i
 		put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license number on it ugly too i mean where it could be seen because i don't care don't i just don't want them to get it and hock it again
 	
 	
 		well are you uh you said you're not in a in a rich neighborhood but are there are there obviously um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the area
 	
 	
 		no not right here i i have never even seen like uh what they call a crack <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or anything i wouldn't
 		no there's nothing like that here that i know of now i'm sure there are somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Cliff</ENAMEX> but i've never seen it we're not in a bad area you know i
 	
 	
 		do you think they just kind of hit your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at random or but they were going down the street
 	
 	
 		they've hit they've hit my next door neighbor they hit uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> down so they've hit several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood one of them twice
 	
 	
 		so they
 		okay so they're really just looking for
 	
 	
 		they're just looking
 	
 	
 		a nice enough house to find something to steal
 	
 	
 		just something they kicked my door in they literally i had a solid wooden door with a dead bolt on it and they backed up and put their foot to it and kicked it in molding and all
 	
 	
 		oh that's scary because everybody feels you're supposed to have dead bolts
 	
 	
 		that's real scary
 		i have a and i my insurance  paid to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> come out and i we put in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another solid</TIMEX> door and another dead bolt but it doesn't hold it
 	
 	
 		well my the front door on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i have has uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		so does mine now this one does have glass in it
 	
 	
 		well i i wonder you know you know it i don't know this is tough but i guess the issue is is if it's drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what's the solution
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i don't think there is a solution i i really
 		i really don't know i really don't and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> told me to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and if they if you're here and they try breaking in shoot them now i have never heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		well that
 	
 	
 		but that tells you how bad the situation is that tells you how bad it is and there aren't enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and they they didn't get here till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six the next morning</TIMEX> i got home at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> immediately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		several times my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> came over immediately we didn't even know if they were still in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> went through looking
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they advised on the phone that we'll have somebody go through and look now that's terrible and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> did not get here until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven hours later</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that that's real scary
 	
 	
 		that's darn scary
 	
 	
 		but is the is the solution uh cutting off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> supply
 	
 	
 		if it's possible i guess i well or is it is it or is the solution legalizing
 	
 	
 		or
 		or is it
 		yeah or yeah uh do you see that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know are they going to if if you cut supply it's going to raise the price
 	
 	
 		somethings
 	
 	
 		or if you uh
 	
 	
 		if you legalize it it uh well you couldn't legalize everything okay i just don't see that you could but if you legalized marijuana
 		and then uh taxed it and everything then everybody'd come out okay i think on that deal
 	
 	
 		well how how expensive is um how expensive is marijuana it's not very expensive is it
 	
 	
 		i don't even know i really don't know
 	
 	
 		but i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are i'd be curious to if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are wouldn't you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are breaking in are probably
 	
 	
 		hard drug users
 	
 	
 		are probably crack that have got a pretty high because i would think a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> worth of marijuana i don't know what it costs but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i should think that'd be more than  a lot more than just ordinary recreation it would be interesting to see if to the problem is is is what do you lock them up for you know
 	
 	
 		and then the thing is keeping them locked up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they pick them up they lock them up and then they they let them go
 	
 	
 		but they don't have enough proof  them
 	
 	
 		they don't have anything to keep and you never get your stuff back you never get your stuff back
 	
 	
 		and then we got to raise
 		well we had interesting enough we had a in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> before we moved we had some neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> came by and stole uh uh drill and our saw and and i had them marked and uh
 		we called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> about a week la ter the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> caught these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> riding a motor um
 		a motor scooter or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a go it was a go-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cart</ENAMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>
 		and he got to talking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and we recovered the drill and the saw it was but uh it it's one of those you know it was uh not a not a real expensive neighborhood
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh but it's it's interesting that the the motivation and the question is what's the motivation not to steal and i i guess that's what bothers it's like the criminal you know if somebody says well let's lock him up for life well
 		how should he you know what bothers me is the incentive that he's if you if you know you're going to be in there for life why should you just be good
 		but if you if you say i'm not going to let you out till you have a skill and we think you're reformed well that's not how they do it they let them out when they time is served i
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i i guess the problem is is is what it would take to do that would be more money than we it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> issue and which i guess we're not supposed to talk to but anyway the idea of how much money would it take to reform these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and lock them all up
 	
 	
 		and they think these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kids</ENAMEX> are probably teenagers older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> that have been doing this around here
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		they uh they weren't real professional well we don't know for sure but they hit they took they knew right where to go that's what scares me
 	
 	
 		in your
 	
 	
 		they went they went right to my jewelry they did not ransack my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they went right to my jewelry box and i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> that had my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX> in it and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamonds</ENAMEX> in it that i had made and it was worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to two thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		they got and they i mean they had pay dirt when they saw that i mean and i couldn't i worked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> then at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you you know with machinery and i couldn't wear my jewelry i can wear it now i wear everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't leave anything home i wear everything  you bet  but uh
 	
 	
 		everything of value
 	
 	
 		they got that and the diamond necklace and stuff so they really hit pay <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> and then they grabbed my VCR also but they didn't just tear it out they very carefully unhooked everything laid everything out you know i mean it was just unbelievable
 	
 	
 		well did they did you take your TV
 	
 	
 		no they left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> TV's and one was small they could have easily carried it but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> said they must have been on foot it looked like they were on foot they left my silver my silver was sitting here in a chest
 	
 	
 		yeah but who buys <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		well i did
 	
 	
 		well yeah but have you bought a place setting lately i have a niece that's getting married
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh she's not even um selecting a silver pattern because it's i've forgotten my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was telling me what the cost is just incredible to you know a place setting is is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> or something i mean your silver probably is worth a lot but uh what are they going to do walk down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and tell everybody what would you like to buy uh a
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they could they could
 		no well they can hock it see they take everything to the pawn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and just hock everything but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know they just hit the jewelry well i guess if they knew their jewelry they knew their but they did take some cubic zirconiums too i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> that they looked awfully real
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i did have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> that that wasn't real and they took that you know and i said
 	
 	
 		well how would they know i mean they they'd have to be pretty sophisticated
 	
 	
 		they just grabbed
 		they just grabbed but boy they sure hit pay dirt with that one ring luckily my insurance you know reimbursed me but i can't replace those diamonds
 	
 	
 		no and and and yeah how to put a value on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> that you'd made
 	
 	
 		you know
 		to have and that had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> in it you know so oh i was sick
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that is scary
 	
 	
 		but i still haven't bought a gun
 	
 	
 		well see that's the thing scares me about it is um who gets shot with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> they say that a large number of the homicides are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that know each other
 		that uh i've forgot what the percentage forty or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> it's surprisingly high that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that shoot each other know them i mean it's not like you know a
 		
 		
 	