
 
     		
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		well like i told you before
 		
 
 		and you're talking about  credit cards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we put ours up
 		i mean i had a delightful <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening one  night</TIMEX> cutting a bunch of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> up
 	
 	
 		um i wish i had
 	
 	
 		well you should try it
 	
 	
 		well i it was done for me after a while i had a uh i had a business going
 		and this was back in the eighties i don't know if you remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and silver prices and all that
 		but uh i had a coin shop
 		and everything was going great while gold and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> was up and it started falling
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i started paying expenses and stuff on my credit cards and things got worse and worse and finally boom
 	
 	
 		you lost your business oh God what a nightmare
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah yeah it was i ended up going into bankruptcy you know it was one of those things  uh oh it'll get better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> you know  things will pick up
 		and so there i was in old bankruptcy court
 	
 	
 		well you weren't charging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> were you you can't do that can you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh you can
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i was buying from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and uh
 		you know they take payment any way they can get it
 	
 	
 		oh that's a nightmare
 	
 	
 		yeah course on on stuff that i was on merchandise that i was buying on cards it was i was getting the money back because i was selling it i wasn't buying you know just to hold onto it
 		um
 		but it was things like you know rent and phone bills and advertising and
 		all that other good stuff that ate them all up
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well  i remember before i got married you know when you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> from college they'll send you all those credit card applications you know of course you fill them all out because you're honored right and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i had stuff for like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanger Harris</ENAMEX> and you know it got up like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> and i thought well that's okay cause all they wanted was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars a month right  i wasn't thinking a thing about it
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes
 		that's the way they suck you in
 	
 	
 		yeah i was just stupid and every time they had a sale there i was because you know got get such good bargains
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know
 	
 	
 		well just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the mail i got uh
 		i got got my
 		guaranteed acceptance by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we've been getting those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i went back to school and got my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> and they started sending those things to me again
 	
 	
 		yeah as soon as your a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> they get your name
 	
 	
 		yeah they did
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		course i guess i guess i've been purged from their records i used to have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX>
 		uh back when i had my business i got one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		they they goofed up bad on my first on my very first bill because i was using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> strictly for the travel expenses
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the bill would come in and i'd pay it and the very first bill i paid it and then i got this nasty letter from them saying you're overdue pay
 		so i i said well it just crossed in the mail so i didn't do anything about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks later</TIMEX> i get another letter even nastier
 		and said we're going to turn this over to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> if you don't pay
 		and i looked at that and i said uh-huh
 		so by this time my checks had come back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> so i made a copy of the check that they had cashed
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		attached it to their letter and sent them a nasty letter with the card cut in little bitty pieces saying thanks but no thanks
 	
 	
 		and now they weren't check in
 	
 	
 		yeah they were i tell you they don't talk about they're charging that enormous fee every year
 	
 	
 		now what is it now
 	
 	
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to fifty five</NUMEX> on the gold card it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> for the Optima
 		oh i'm sorry fifty fifty
 	
 	
 		what do you mean fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> you mean fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah for the green card
 		and it
 	
 	
 		but then what's the interest
 	
 	
 		well now that's the card see
 	
 	
 		and interest is like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eighteen</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah it's um
 		well of course on the green card you have to pay it when the bill comes in so there isn't any but on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Optima</ENAMEX> card it's um
 		let's see right now it's running at about it's not too bad it's actually it's about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen and a half</TIMEX> percent which is pretty good
 		as far as credit cards go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		credit cards
 	
 	
 		well they're dangerous
 	
 	
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't hardly use them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">hum-um</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> don't either
 		mine don't either they have um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> has a uh has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card and that's it
 	
 	
 		i've got all my gas cards because i don't want to carry money around i'll do that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah now i i do use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> cards
 	
 	
 		now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impact</ENAMEX> is kind of bad too though
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know especially if you get forget to record those little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> is just too easy i mean that's the that's the whole problem with it um have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well and you're tempted if you've got cash a little bit of cash and you don't have enough for the purchase right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course you got to charge it and keep your cash
 	
 	
 		sure
 		naturally that's i got in all kinds of trouble doing that
 	
 	
 		what what are you saying
 		oh uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says i might buy it but i i don't really usually consider that an option
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		maybe that's how we got in trouble
 	
 	
 		having having having been out of the credit game for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> now i've i've gotten used to either paying in cash or not getting it
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's hard isn't it
 	
 	
 		well it is but i i i'm kind of uh grateful for the experience because it's taught me a lot of restraint
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well it makes you feel good when you whip out the cash instead of your plastic
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly i i um i just went out and got a new VCR yesterday
 	
 	
 		with cash
 	
 	
 		with cash
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it it's
 	
 	
 		do you work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i wish i did
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah you could have got a discount couldn't you
 	
 	
 		yeah i could use a discount  i have to wait for the things to go on sale
 	
 	
 		but there's always a sell
 	
 	
 		yeah especially on electronic goods
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		especially now
 	
 	
 		what is that thing i saw Circuit
 		Circuit world or something
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> have you been in that
 	
 	
 		yeah they they're not their prices aren't that terrific
 		they they used to be but they've gotten they've got to pay for all that national advertising now
 	
 	
 		oh it's national
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i've seen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they're they're all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> now
 		they uh they they used to be good i remember when they first opened up they did have good bargains
 	
 	
 		well what else
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you have a place there called uh or you probably have something similar we call it Service Merchandise
 	
 	
 		yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you got Service Merchandise yeah it used to be Service Merchandise was the place to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX> came along and that was the place to go to get your TVs and washer and dryers and refrigerators and all that
 		and then after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> went by they just sort of kept creeping up on price and actually Service Merchandise is cheaper than them now so
 		so so much for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 		okay what else can we talk about who do you work for
 	
 	
 		i don't i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> i'm a professional student
 	
 	
 		we were talking about that just today
 	
 	
 		it is
 		it's it's great
 	
 	
 		we could be just lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it is great i love it
 	
 	
 		where are you going to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh North Carolina State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you're on Spring Break
 	
 	
 		not yet
 		ours don't ours doesn't start until uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so where are you
 	
 	
 		where am i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you mean where oh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah good ole
 		the burgeoning metropolis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what what a dead place yeah
 	
 	
 		is it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've got a nice little business at home and i sit around and tinker with that most of the time
 	
 	
 		so what are you getting your degree in
 	
 	
 		um uh human factors
 	
 	
 		and what do you do with it
 	
 	
 		not a thing
 	
 	
 		well what is it
 	
 	
 		uh its
 		it's it's really looking at systems and design systems and seeing how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interact with them
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so it's sociology
 	
 	
 		it's well it's more psychology and engineering uh my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s is in industrial engineering
 	
 	
 		so you're working on your doctorate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh lord
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> in human factors
 	
 	
 		oh that'll that'll sound wonderful won't it
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		get you a little name plaque
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> uh
 		i mean uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use human factors <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> is what i'm looking at right now
 	
 	
 		aren't aren't they laying off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		they might be but not at not at the human factors level
 	
 	
 		well i heard it on the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i could swear it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there there
 		um no as a matter of fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> right here or in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> which is a little suburb of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> just just hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more human factors person
 		doggone it if they'd just waited a little bit longer it could have been me
 	
 	
 		hum
 		how much longer do you have
 	
 	
 		um i'm i'm i'm going into thesis or going into the uh dissertation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and get that done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm going to start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> i probably won't finish it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX>
 		but uh i'm i'm trying to get a uh
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		a uh intern position with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> right now so that i can find an area to do my dissertation in
 		it's hard finding an area to do a dissertation in this field
 	
 	
 		because you
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		why there been so much work done already
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that and and it's it's limited application in some respects um consider in the area that we're in here there's a lot of places that use human factors <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most
 		
 		
 	