
 
     		
 	
 		it's it's hard topic topic because is it is it is it doing a good job or a bad job and you got to divide it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different categories whether you live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or whether you live in a more rural place like i do
 	
 	
 		yeah and are you talking about public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> being lower level high school level or
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well public school all the way up kindergarten all the way up to uh uh high school
 	
 	
 		state school
 		okay but you're excluding high-level education
 	
 	
 		yes well yeah i am
 		um actually actually i think that i at the higher level education i don't think there's so much of a problem there it's pretty much funded well there are small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> that i'm sure are struggling
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but uh it's the job that the the high school and the grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are doing that i see in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> like ours <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> even a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> up here where if i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 		uh i would seriously consider moving if i had a child i wouldn't let them go to a public school system there but of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trapped economically and they can't do that
 	
 	
 		yeah i know down here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s are you know i don't know they rate i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> after living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> down here rate you know bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and
 		having been through grade school up there and coming down here to high school i can understand why because they're so far behind and so poorly staffed half the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> don't know what's going on
 	
 	
 		well that's really too bad because it it it's giving some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> unfair advantage i mean we our high school up here is like a junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> what we learned
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that was my experience going through junior high up there when i came down south for high school i was just repeating what i'd already done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because we were so far advanced and uh the you know i'd been in a parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> before junior high and you know even the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are behind the parochial schools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know i i like the concept they've got now where they have more directed education you know you you pick a career path or you get counseling earlier
 		and then you you learn the things that help you rather than spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> learning the same things over and over
 	
 	
 		oh they they have that down there that
 	
 	
 		well they talk about it and there are a few in some of the more like in i live in a big metroplex and some of the the better parts of the metroplex the the suburbs that are richer have those kind of target schools
 		but uh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like if if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> owns a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and you're really interested in that there's no reason that you should take college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prep courses</ENAMEX> when you can get some general business courses in high school
 	
 	
 		right
 		or if you're going to go the science route you can go to a target <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that specializes in science or art you know there's no point in you know i'm an engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and if i have to go take art classes you know i'm not going to use them
 		and through high school i could have gone so much further if i'd gone to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that was directed
 	
 	
 		yeah that's where i was fortunate i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> and we had a vocational um electronics in our high school
 	
 	
 		right in high school
 	
 	
 		so when i went to my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX> of tech school uh i had a very easy time because our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> had a a good program
 	
 	
 		right
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are just they're just overrun you know they don't know what to do there's too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't care
 	
 	
 		yeah i find that that the that in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> it's more less the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go there
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		to socialize not really to learn and the parents send them there because they're supposed to and plus it gets them out of their hair and i also find that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that you can send a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to school but if don't work with them as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> i think you're putting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> at a big disadvantage
 	
 	
 		yeah and you know there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that you know want to go learn but most of them just want to go play
 	
 	
 		yeah well i could i could see if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> doesn't have any encouragement if  they're you know come from a broken home and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are more concerned about
 		trying to work and or maybe they're unemployed and they're mad at the world i can see where that wouldn't be very good for a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you know he's coming up will you help me with my homework and they're no get away from me i've had a terrible day
 		so it's got a lot to do with economics in the area that you come from
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i'm wondering with the boom down here it's well not at the moment but a lot of the industry's moving southward
 	
 	
 		yes are they going to move to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so oh i don't know
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that but a lot of the industry up in uh you know the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> is moving south  and i'm wondering if that's going to have any effect you know on what you see now we're we're we're behind down here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i say we because i live here if that might not turn around in the next you know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe the maybe they'll bring their good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with them  you know if the industry comes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hopefully they'll promote good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that i come from the the uh the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> has something to do with the top rated high school
 		because of their tax base for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and plus for for the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> that's going to that school it's going to raise the level of the school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemists</ENAMEX> they're they're you're most likely to do better in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they're going to help you
 	
 	
 		you hope
 	
 	
 		yeah you hope  well i think i i don't know i just think it it's it's a duty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to do that
 		i mean jeez my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> always helped me and i don't know it's just like you say it's the way you're raised and the economic situation you're in
 		i can see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one years old</TIMEX> and she's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in her first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> i don't see where she's going to have much time for him  so i don't know it's just like
 	
 	
 		i guess you just have to wonder is it up to the is it you know who whose supposed to make the change the the state the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the federal government you know where's the money supposed to come from is it
 	
 	
 		i don't know actually i think it i think it should be a civic level the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> level and a a system level really to find out and to to see what they need and not overinflate it
 	
 	
 		you know what what do you advocate more taxes or better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of what they got
 	
 	
 		like if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are getting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> raises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in industry have been getting cut back and you're getting raises <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every eighteen months</TIMEX> you got to go hey now wait a minute we're in a recession here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> didn't pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX> just because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are in the recession and they're even though
 		we've uh enjoyed very good employment here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past ten years</TIMEX> now we got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> uh unemployment when it used to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going whoa
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		starts hitting closer to home
 	
 	
 		yeah but i always  see it's all it's all money this like a couple other topics we had talked about was crime It it's it's all money based
 		and what you can do unless you just get down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> level and and then if you're in a bad situation where you have to send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to a bad school
 		who knows but maybe we do we need some more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> instead  they seem to have done a the good job in the past
 		in uh some places uh you couldn't go to a public school it was miles down the road and the only school you could go to was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah they're a lot more strict
 	
 	
 		yeah the i don't
 	
 	
 		you uh have to learn you aren't given the chance to you know screw off all the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i don't know if i would do that to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> though  but so hum pretty much though see i don't have any good ideas or
 		or anything that would contribute see this isn't a subject that i think a lot about because i'm never faced with it because our school system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> it seems to do a really good job
 	
 	
 		well i know i'm in the you know the only reason i asked about secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or you know advanced education is because down here you know going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> the education i'm getting i think is kind of shoddy for a public school
 	
 	
 		is it
 	
 	
 		i i don't think i'm getting what i should but you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's next to free because they they pay so much of it it's state supported
 		but at the same time it's really not it's not like going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> my engineering degree will be nothing like somebody coming out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> and that's it's really too bad
 	
 	
 		well that
 	
 	
 		but that's i don't know i think it just builds on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> that they've already built you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and college junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> that don't have the background for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> kind of curriculum so
 	
 	
 		well
 		so you have to go to a lesser engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> we have a very good public school up here and a degree out there means a lot it's a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Vermont</ENAMEX> um
 		we also have some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> college well there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a four year</TIMEX> colleges they all have a pretty good reputation but like you say you
 		
 		
 	