
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have a favorite type of music you listen to
 	
 	
 		um most frequently i listen to contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music but i like all forms
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i uh we i listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and rock and classical
 		jazz is probably my least favorite although i enjoy it too
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i tend to favor uh rock and roll mostly from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and seventies
 	
 	
 		oh yeah some great sixties tunes
 	
 	
 		yeah i listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGPS</ENAMEX> classic rock
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGPS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i'm in Plano
 	
 	
 		uh  well probably around the corner  um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> i listen to it every once in a while too
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you play any instruments
 	
 	
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		never have
 	
 	
 		i'm not musically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		well i took piano lessons in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade once for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one semester</TIMEX> i'll never forget Mrs Burkhalter
 	
 	
 		
 
 		Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burkhalter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she had that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> mentality
 	
 	
 		
 
 		where uh uh where'd you grow up
 	
 	
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		yeah the only thing how to play on the piano is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> handed thing or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		chopsticks
 	
 	
 		no it's not chopsticks it's the other one that has the um
 		oh i don't even i don't i don't know enough about music to do it but you the bottom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> uses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> and the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> just uses one hand
 		and it's this little melody i it may have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well i have no idea what that is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i just know i hated it
 		but i took up trumpet after that and ended up playing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX> marching band
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		which was fun
 	
 	
 		yeah i went to i went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> and we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">marching owl</ENAMEX> band which is quite a it's not known for its musical abilities more so its um comedy abilities
 	
 	
 		it uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh we had a great time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> was heavy into the big bands so we played a lot of tunes by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny Goodman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Dorsey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well that that was fun
 	
 	
 		so it was a lot of fun plus i got to get to go to all the athletic events free
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that has its plusses for sure
 	
 	
 		well which uh sixties uh rock bands do you like the best
 	
 	
 		oh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creedance Clearwater Revival uh Crosby Stills Nash</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX> when it was still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		there uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Sabbath</ENAMEX> did a few albums that i really like
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah they i know it's kind of strange um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX> is more seventies
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah certainly but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Brick Road</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i love that album
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i've got all those
 	
 	
 		yeah i had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Brick Road</ENAMEX> and something happened to it it escaped me and it was sometime in college and never have seen it again
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh i started my uh music collection in college when i started winning radio contests
 	
 	
 		how'd you win radio contests
 	
 	
 		well they would uh tell you to call in and be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and win
 		so i had a touch tone telephone in college and uh i just started calling in and winning all kinds of contests
 		i had forty record albums before i even had a stereo to play them on to play them on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		i ended up winning about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> radio contests in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> school years
 		so i accumulated my record collection mostly from that
 	
 	
 		that's incredible i've never won not one thing from a radio station i haven't tried i probably haven't tried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> times
 	
 	
 		it was
 		yeah well that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX> i i won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times a week
 		it doesn't have near the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has the contests here are a lot more competitive
 	
 	
 		yeah have you ever won in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah but not the same type of contests um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they have contests on the radio in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and i think i won one of the movie mystery contests <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they sent me a small flag in the mail that which which had postage due
 	
 	
 		you're kidding me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 		it was a
 	
 	
 		oh it's not it's probably not quite the same
 	
 	
 		it wasn't much of a victory actually i did win tickets to the to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beach Boys</ENAMEX> concert
 	
 	
 		i saw them i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beach Boys</ENAMEX> concert i like them too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i've never been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> concert bet it was great
 	
 	
 		uh yeah they were uh they were very good i was impressed
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> was great too
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then i'll go ahead and make another tape and uh record a bunch of uh old tunes like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loving Spoonful</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Dead</ENAMEX> something from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birds Rolling Stones</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i enjoy listening to those old tunes they don't play a lot of that stuff on the radio any more you have to pick the right station
 	
 	
 		yeah i use my scan button a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whole lot
 		
 
 		i enjoy mainly the old the older rock and roll tunes rather than
 		a lot of the new stuff the lyrics are so repetitive
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		that i just kind of get lost in it
 	
 	
 		i uh yeah i haven't made any kind of effort to keep up on recent music especially in rock and roll
 		there's not just too much uh new stuff that's well
 		it's not as creative
 	
 	
 		it doesn't seem to be
 	
 	
 		and the lyrics aren't as uh
 		inspiring  if you want to call it that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah some of the tunes used to you know you felt like you needed to go out and do something about it
 	
 	
 		yeah lot of pop music out that just isn't very thrilling
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		course the head bangers i stay away from those entirely
 	
 	
 		is there still that type of music available
 	
 	
 		certainly is just turn on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> any night
 	
 	
 		oh
 		no i've got small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  i don't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they'll be playing the latest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bon Jovi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Snake</ENAMEX> or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah i uh
 		i tried when um i guess i was in junior high high school
 		when uh
 		Led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeppelin</ENAMEX> was real big and everybody i tried to you know really go the whole way and i couldn't go with even
 		with most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Led Zeppelin</ENAMEX>'s music i didn't enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and some of the stuff you know the classics they were fine but
 		some of it was just too heavy even then
 	
 	
 		i always like the easier listening rock the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby Stills Nash</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Eagles</ENAMEX> uh in more recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> very talented
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		Z <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z Top</ENAMEX> is different very creative they they really uh made uh quite a transition
 		they used to be almost a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> band
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh playing such
 	
 	
 		yeah they play they play some they get some play time on the country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> even
 	
 	
 		yeah such classics as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Grange</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touche</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i've still got my Fandango album that one didn't get lost in college
 	
 	
 		right
 		but uh they they really did change
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		all of a sudden they became a top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> appealing to the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they've got they've now they've got some good videos
 	
 	
 		uh very good videos yeah i'm kind of impressed
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		quite creative and appealing to the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to the pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> i guess you'd call it that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Palmer</ENAMEX>'s got some creative pretty creative videos videos out too
 	
 	
 		i i was thinking that yeah he's his his videos are pretty wild i like his music too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and there are some that are that get artsy to a point like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Winwood</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		now see i know a little bit
 		i know a little bit about other groups
 		i uh
 		like i said i listen to primarily contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		but i spend enough time on scan that i hear what it what is still on the radio well i don't know
 	
 	
 		well who's uh who's who's popular now with the uh contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music
 	
 	
 		oh probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Grant</ENAMEX> is the biggest one yeah she's even she's got a song right now that playing on a few of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby Baby</ENAMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		i don't listen too much
 		right yeah i've heard of her uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's neat when you think about how she wrote it and stuff otherwise the lyrics are kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's just like oh i love you and i you know this that and the other  but she write she wrote when she was talking to her baby
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and if you've got a baby i mean it's kind of neat thinking about it talking up to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and to to an infant
 	
 	
 		right that's interesting
 	
 	
 		so it it makes it neater but
 	
 	
 		well i don't think i'd ever make a song writer
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> has tried to be a song writer
 		she's waiting for her big time
 	
 	
 		yeah well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get lucky and i guess if you're persistent enough sometimes it works out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well
 		yeah i hope that it does for her she deserves it she's a nice person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 		i uh
 	
 	
 		well what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> plays uh that type of music
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety four</NUMEX> point one is KLTY
 	
 	
 		okay
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and uh then there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> point one is KCBI they do more uh
 		they spend a lot of time with uh
 		oh this
 		preaching kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so i like music i like listening to music so i don't usually listen to KCBI
 		and then there's another one called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journey</ENAMEX> that's somewhere in between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of those it's in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between ninety and ninety four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe i'll tune in to one of those some time
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety four</NUMEX> point one is fun
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		i mean it's it's
 		it's mainly
 		um just family oriented stuff i mean yeah it's very its definitely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> but it's not it's not hymns
 		
 
 	
 	
 		right okay
 	
 	
 		you know it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amazing Grace</ENAMEX> every other time
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i still feel like every time if i ever feel like reminiscing over the old stuff i'll go ahead and throw on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> tape
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		get something from from the Guess Who or
 		
 		
 	