
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay what is your uh general opinion then of of taxes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't think that i'm paying too many tax you know too much tax myself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i uh as far as uh you know federal and state uh the uh the state i live in has a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> sales tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's quite a bit different than uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've ever been outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but uh
 		when i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i was told oh well there's no personal income tax well they nail you on property taxes in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and then that's how they get their money to take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		right yeah uh
 		as a matter of fact they're talking about changing the the tax situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> because the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are not
 		they're not equitable within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> so they're changing that they're talking about changing the uh the tax base and how the taxes are distributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> which will probably mean uh another increase in property taxes
 		either that or uh starting a state income tax
 	
 	
 		yeah i i found it interesting uh when i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> the fact that uh the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanted to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> was to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school district because it was the best because it had more money than you know other places
 		and uh i just um
 		in the uh like here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> uh i just bought a uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and forty one thousand</NUMEX> it'd be about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty thousand</TIMEX> down there  and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the tax basis is actually uh less than the full price of the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you end up paying property taxes on what they value the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at i think they only have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> valued at probably about
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ninety</ENAMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whereas when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i notice that they put the tax basis at at almost the uh full price
 	
 	
 		almost full value right yeah
 	
 	
 		and so there was quite a difference there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i think that the way they they levy taxes is a little bit uh
 		crazy i think if if they uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and i'll use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> as an example uh house prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> were falling
 		and so they decided well in order to get more tax revenue we're going to have to raise the price uh you know we're going to have to raise the uh the the uh tax per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> of value on the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and same time they were approving new starts in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> hand over fist well when you start having a large supply of homes
 		then of course the price goes you know the value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is going to fall and the existing family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> were the ones that were falling the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> they were building cheaper and and able to sell cheaper and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> weren't buying the existing family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		they were shooting themselves in the foot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know if they just would have thought well gee if we don't you know if we put a freeze on new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> starts
 		that will bring the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> back up our tax base revenue will go up and we won't have to increase taxes and make it more of a burden on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are living here
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess that's a possibility
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as i understand it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> does not have any uh state income tax is that right
 	
 	
 		no no they do have state income tax
 	
 	
 		oh okay so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's and they uh they divide it up by um you know you pay a state income tax and then fifty percent of your state income tax is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> tax which is collected by the state and redistributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay then uh all of your state income tax is deductible for federal income tax purposes
 	
 	
 		that is correct
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> did you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> after the uh after they stopped letting you deduct uh sales tax on your tax return
 	
 	
 		um yes i did i only lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> and um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> and uh part of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay so so you couldn't deduct state income uh state sales tax when you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		so what do you think about the difference between those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> situations
 	
 	
 		um
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i was oh i believe the uh tax sales tax was somewhere around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven eight eight</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> it's only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> um it was nice to have that uh you know deduction when it was available
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but when they revamped the you know supposedly making things more fair um
 		i've heard a lot of different arguments uh pro and con about whether we should allow deductions for sales tax or even uh
 		maybe we should put more emphasis on sales tax because when you think about it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that purchase more items are the ones that are better able to pay the taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are out there barely struggling to pay their uh house payment and buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> aren't going to be out buying you know anything else
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know have the uh disposable income that are probably more able to pay the income tax
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or pay the sales tax are the ones that are really you know have the money and they're out there buying the items maybe they should be you know paying more of the burden um
 		there was there's another crazy thing that gets me it's like the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you have the less tax you pay
 		and to me that is completely crazy and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so i mean you know i uh i you know it it's kind of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">odd</TIMEX> when i talk about this with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because it it just doesn't make sense to me you're getting more services
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are going you know you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> instead of somebody that only has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or none and so you they're paying more income tax to pay for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to go to school it just you know doesn't make sense
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's an interesting uh interesting concept i hadn't thought about that how you you you know that that's right i guess  in a sense
 		i guess the you know the idea is that uh the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you have in the family the more allowances you need you know the more uh capability you need to uh to
 		pay for food and clothing and stuff for them so the they give you more allowances more dependent allowances for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i understand what you're where you're coming from with the
 	
 	
 		yeah now the other side of the question is about are we getting what we're paying for um
 		for the most part i think we are but there is a lot of inefficiency uh both on the federal level and on the state level
 		and uh hopefully we'll
 		you know as we start to go into computerization and all the processes maybe we'll be able to streamline it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i haven't kept up with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> politics other than that dirty little uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> fight
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i mean uh we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> who's uh pretty hard nosed and uh he's you know we're <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred fifty million dollars</NUMEX> short
 		and every time he comes up with a plan to cut the money everybody starts screaming and yelling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh every time he wants to cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> budget or do something else or try to do something you know they start screaming yelling they won't let him raise the taxes and and they they won't let him cut any programs and he's like what do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> want me to do
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that's i guess uh one thought that occurred to me uh is we're we're talking about having uh national uh military or or public service deal for young people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe a program like that could replace some of the uh welfare programs
 		if uh you know if we're going to do that then we ought to really get some benefit dollar benefits out of it that uh to reduce spending in some other areas uh
 		you know to do something to eliminate what uh what they refer to as transfer payments
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		because uh that's i think that's where our real you know the real problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is not is not what the not what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s doing but where it's spending its money it's it's encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
 		to uh
 		not do as well as they can you know uh not have as much output and
 		all that you're paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not to work and you're paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know like you said you know more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you have the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> you have you know the allowances you get
 		and uh
 		the more you have the more uh aid for dependent childre n you can get and all of these things go into it so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh some kind of a national service uh concept that might be geared around reducing that would be a i think would be a big step so
 	
 	
 		yeah that and i think uh putting more emphasis on local handling of the problem i think this is something that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> came out and said in his uh in his address uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um you know it used to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> would take care of their own
 		and that you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and then all of a sudden everybody starting looking to the federal government
 	
 	
 		right it uh
 	
 	
 		and uh you know once you start up at the top and try to get those dollars on down to the hands that need them you know there's a lot of places the money stops and disappears along the way
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh maintenance and overhead and you know and and those kind of costs
 	
 	
 		yeah right i i think that a a big part of the uh you know the government concept over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX> has been uh redistribution of uh of wealth in in effect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know you you tax the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have the most and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't have anything get it for nothing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and i don't think that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way myself it uh
 		it kind of rings of you know socialism and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just i don't understand why
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> uh seem to think that that's the way to go you know that
 		uh there are not i don't think that there are that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that feel that way that with what they could get support for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or making the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system work in the way it's originally designed to
 	
 	
 		yeah there there's uh you know once you reach a certain plateau in in finances um
 		
 		
 	