
 
     		
 	
 		so what do you think about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of public service
 	
 	
 		well i know it's hard for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to think about giving up their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you know free their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">carefree years</TIMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i have known that have done that i like from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		they are just they have such a better more mature outlook on life and i think they're better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because of it they're much more responsible i know um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that i go to um the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of their life when they turn nineteen you know they're encouraged to do that missionary work and i believe i really believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh make our society better
 	
 	
 		you know i i really agree with you um i uh though i've never done that myself i i'm was a basically an education major when i graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and i accepted a job that at the time was just slightly above the poverty level to teach
 		to um very rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in a very low income district and i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> teaching there and i think it was probably one of my largest eye-opening experiences because i come from nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		middle class white suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and i did it um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason i wanted i was working on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degree so i wanted to stay close to where i was working on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degree but also because i just thought that it would be interesting to live someplace else so totally different than my own upbringing and i it changed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it probably changed my political views it changed my understanding of the world around me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think um in fact if if i had to do it all again i you know i i after that you know you never think of it because i guess because i paid for all of my college education myself i never thought about
 		doing that because i had all these college loans i'd started paying back
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um because so that was that was one reason why i never considered it but now that i'm further along and i'm still paying these college loans
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i think realistically you know you can have your college loans delayed now because i had them delayed because i'm back in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i've had them delayed because i'm back in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and on that form it says if your joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> you can have them delayed
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i thought that was you know very interesting and i i would have thought of that earlier i probably would have done you know just like is that is this is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormon</ENAMEX> church
 	
 	
 		yes yes but if
 	
 	
 		that does that um-hum because one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> uh did that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and i thought you know that really now that i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years old</TIMEX> i think that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two years</TIMEX> out of my life would've probably like you said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to be able to travel someplace else whether it be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i think would've been a very good um experience for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i think so it puts you out on your own and and in a time after high school um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's kind of a selfishness i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are kind of
 		kind of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't look forward to and and things like that and i think that it would help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to become less self-centered and to be more responsible when you're out on your own trying to um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		thinking less of your own needs but of other people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i think you know we have such a need now you know i taught you know i i think i was paid
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about nine thousand dollars</NUMEX> to teach for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and i worked in a very rural school district and i i one of the things i taught was a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i taught except for one was pregnant many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they were they were high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juniors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i and i just there you know they came from poverty they were going to continue in poverty
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and it was it was the school district couldn't hire many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it was very difficult for them to hire and i think you know in the sense that aspect of public service for education in some of the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for um just social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in some of the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and some of the rural areas where they just need advice on medical um
 		things i think it's a really good idea and even if it is overseas see i never i i tell you sometimes i worry about things overseas because we have such problems right here in our own country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it would really um and i don't  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i've known like from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> that have done that are they do military service which you know i don't exactly recommend but still
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they have benefited from it and um you know although i wouldn't want
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> voluntarily but it's it has helped them and they are just a lot more mature than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think it would also help them if they then went on to college i know that my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first couple of years</TIMEX> of college were um
 		uh probably too carefree at the beginning and then at the end i had to be too serious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's right a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they flunk out or they get they just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are so excited to be away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> they just spend all there time partying and they do a lot of things to themselves and that we don't really want our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be doing and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 		um-hum that's right
 		i yeah i think i think this was this was a very interesting topic
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because it's something that you know we don't talk about in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> probably enough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know
 	
 	
 		because because we're so
 		we love our freedom and our freedom of choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep that's true
 	
 	
 		and um having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but you know our like in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> it it is you're free to do that or not you're encouraged to do it because um you know it it helps you and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course we think it's helping other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		oh i think it is
 		i really think i think um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you should i you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today i teach i spend a lot of my time teaching college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i find great disgust in them in their in their um  their self-centeredness
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and their inability to understand um multicultural or multiracial situations and i really you know they don't understand uh how other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live um they don't understand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and they're preoccupied with drinking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep i think that's uh just just having a good time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> and he always refers to it as uh short-term pleasure oriented i guess he's a technical aspect he likes to apply to it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are short-term pleasure oriented and everything has to be an immediate reward and it has to be fun
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's really true
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		yes well i i don't know how that would ever happen here but at least um
 	
 	
 		well they say i think i um have read recently that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has increased the uh funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> because i guess because of the changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>
 		uh they've increased funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> some of the i guess it's some of the peace dividend in the sense you known when they're decreasing some of the military spending some of that money has gone into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> and some of the other overseas programs uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		well i have seen a big change i think in high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that um i know when i was in high school i had an idea of what i really wanted to do with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what my what i was going to study and at least i had some interest in a lot of the youth that i come in contact with are they say oh i want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> i want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> why because they make a lot of money
 	
 	
 		yes yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and they don't have a goal they don't have a goal they don't have an interest in their own field of study they're just looking what's going to pay the biggest cash
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's very true you know how many is it they say we have so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and i guess i i live near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> being in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> it's something like one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		area yes
 	
 	
 		area are lawyers
 		and and i i just sort of think that's ridiculous yeah with
 	
 	
 		yes there's too many people
 	
 	
 		you know with the great needs that we need <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in science and biology and uh you know the the problems we have with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and and that how come everybody is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> you know you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right and not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to do that to for
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because of a service that they could provide you know if you want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> because you know that you can provide a service that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need because you have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> um but if you're just doing it because you think that's the best way to be rich
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you saw statistics that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> make the most money in the long run yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's kind of sad well anyway well i guess i better go
 	
 	
 		that's interesting um-hum
 		okay hey thanks so much for the conversation
 	
 	
 		well good luck to you i enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		well thank you very much bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thanks bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	