
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all righty so uh do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s still a threat
 	
 	
 		well i guess i'm maybe naive but i never did feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was a big threat to us i mean obviously there's the the the possibility of or was the possibility of war
 	
 	
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		uh but i somehow think that war is one of those things that that maybe is inevitable but uh
 		i don't look at it as a threat in the same sense that that i think this question was meant what about you
 	
 	
 		well i think have have you ever read the book nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay you know like how uh these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> there was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> continents that were always fighting with each other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and you could picture it as being <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> versus the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> during during the whole time and what they would do is they would get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and kill them as soon as they got them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there could realize that they were the same as as themselves you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> of wars were were the same as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in that country
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you didn't want that to happen and to me it had always been that way i mean what happens is you have a government right and this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> controls everything right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> inhabiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are the same as you are
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and what goes on is that every time somebody attacks a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> supposedly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> attacks a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it's not going to be within the borders of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> itself
 		like i was telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm really mad because the whole thing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> this was going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lithuania</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lithuania</ENAMEX>
 		they they were announced to be a separate country
 		but yet the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> told its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> to go in there and get those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> didn't go in there and try to save those people
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it's like you're not going to go in there and say no listen there's a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> why because you're going into the border
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right once you get into the border then there's a threat but what happens is you don't mess with us we won't mess with you but let's mess with the neutral countries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and now it's like you know they're saying other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were were i guess other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were still crazier about it you know like other people
 		you could think that they might use a bomb here and a bomb there
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has never been known for throwing an atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> anywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> has
 		you know it's like they it seems like they can their their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> or whatever can can go in there quicker than an atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> can and do do the job with uh you know less suffering
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know but i think i think the thing is is that
 		there the thing like they were saying they go you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> could start a nuclear war because of whoever is behind the button
 		but not the USSR the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> wouldn't do it
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they got too much at stake
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but i guess there was concern uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq Iraq</ENAMEX> would use
 		you know nonconventional warheads with with the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and things but yet it didn't happen i mean why not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		my my point of view to that is is that it would have had so much i mean the attack would have been so complete on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> if they had i mean the first you can imagine the first uh chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> used
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that would have meant a total attack of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> country within you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> of when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> was shot
 	
 	
 		oh so you think it was fear that kept <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> from using it but yet the
 	
 	
 		right and what happens is what happens is suppose they get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> which they eventually will he's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less thing to go against him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean if he were to use that he might as well commit suicide because he's going to be captured and you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> also makes a lot of uh you know treaties with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like saying okay if you give up then you can come live in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and we'll take care of you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		we'll overthrow you but yet you can still come live here you know
 	
 	
 		right i don't think we've done that to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		uh  no
 	
 	
 		i think that's that's that's not very likely
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but yet you know as as the parallel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is using the chemical warfare on his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i guess that makes sense what you said that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh within their own borders they feel freer to do what what they feel necessary
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know there's there's just
 		you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will go like they like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> goes and goes into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> and what see i don't believe in war that's my thing i don't believe that anybody should die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and so then you know you have because what happens is suppose i'm i go to war and i'm holding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and i'm just looking at myself holding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and whoever shoots <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> survives you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but that same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and you know his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are going to cry and you know life ends there and to me that's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i mean i just don't believe it i think there are other ways to fix it even though sometimes there aren't but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's pretty hard to think that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just going to shoot each other down and it's legal in a situation like that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well or that at that it resolves anything in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> that that negotiations couldn't resolve
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> lost so much money during the war that it was ridiculous and he all he was trying to do was make money at the beginning so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and keep his power but well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it sounds like neither one of us thinks that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> is a real threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i i don't think so i think uh they're getting they're especially getting their life back together now because a lot of things that you saw on TV a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
 		would love to stay in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> just as long as they were able to express what they wanted to a lot of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they said that they wouldn't leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> unless <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> told them that they couldn't travel anymore and compete
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it must be a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it's just that you know
 		they won't let you get out and when you want to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that's what you want to do
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so oh well i got to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		okay well thanks bye-bye
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	