
 
     		
 	
 		want me to press the one button
 	
 	
 		i'm ready whenever you are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">okay sir</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> i'm sorry about that do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no no i do not i uh i live in an apartment
 	
 	
 		okay well that would kind of preclude having a pet
 	
 	
 		well
 		well not really most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets dogs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course
 	
 	
 		well we've got we've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and this is a very very special <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> because uh we lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty months</TIMEX> we worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biejo City</ENAMEX>
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> and uh as you know uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Filipinos</ENAMEX> are quite poor
 		and and uh they don't uh generally they eat their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh well not generally but dogs they do uh so having a pet uh is is a luxury most of them don't have and we uh were able to find one that was born in a store
 		and the uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Filipino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that ran the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> was giving them away and we took him home with us when he was uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks</TIMEX> old
 		and uh ultimately my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and i had to stay on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months</TIMEX> after they went back
 		and uh eventually i shipped him home by air and you know you have to really love a pet to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred and forty dollars</NUMEX> to ship him across the ocean
 	
 	
 		i agree and how they you know the uh
 		the uh health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> let him in the country
 	
 	
 		yeah there was no problem because there was a veterinarian in our neighborhood and we had all the proper paperwork and and i shipped him uh uh by air
 		and uh let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> know when he was going to be in and they went out to the freight claiming area out at uh DFW <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> and claimed him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it was it was it was it was pretty interesting uh did you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> when you were growing up
 	
 	
 		i always had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> when i grew up
 	
 	
 		oh okay what did you have
 	
 	
 		oh i had uh i started with a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh an old you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alley cat</ENAMEX> an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> but i had dogs primarily and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		mostly purebreds
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		we had a large yard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we did not have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> in the house
 		uh they all they were always outdoors
 	
 	
 		yeah they they they lived outdoors and you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> i have a i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> uh
 		uh when i was living in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola Florida</ENAMEX> uh we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh cat</ENAMEX> that
 		i got from again from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> it was born in a barn
 		uh it was they had a a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> so there were lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i picked out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and got it for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and uh had it uh spayed and
 		declawed
 		and we did keep it in the house
 		restricted to the uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and it was uh not a bad experience but for the most part i'm i'm reluctant to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i just i just don't do not feel that
 		particularly dogs uh i do not feel that they
 		fare well
 	
 	

 		yeah they're they're
 	
 	
 		uh in the in the house
 	
 	
 		and it's amazing how they how they adapt to the outside i was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> and we had an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eskimo</ENAMEX> Spitz
 		and he was never in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> in his life and i can you know i remember like this sounds like old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> stories but i can remember thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five below zero</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> on the ground
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um-hum well i yeah i had a malamute at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		and
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh stayed outside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was raised in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> would get fairly cold the only problem with it is that the bloody thing would
 		sit outside my window and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bay</ENAMEX> at the moon at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>  and uh you know it's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf</ENAMEX> origins uh came to the fore particularly during the full moon and but i always had uh dogs i had a terrier
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then i had a uh
 		let's see i had a terrier then i had a cocker spaniel
 		then a
 		then the uh malamute
 		and then the last dog i had was a uh basset hound
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they all stayed outside
 	
 	
 		oh for goodness sakes yeah uh the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> we ever had uh we lived prior to living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>
 		and we were told when we got there that it'd be good to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> because uh there were a lot of uh breaking and entering and robberies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the uh native <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> by religion are scared of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> in fact the lick of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> is supposed to be something very very bad something very evil
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what happened uh was anybody that had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> at least the native <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malays</ENAMEX> made up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> if you had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> uh you wouldn't get ripped off by a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Malay</ENAMEX>
 		now the other fifty percent was part some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> and they might then they didn't have any qualms any qualms about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> so we went down to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPCA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gautolompora</ENAMEX> uh actually had uh uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">SPCA</ENAMEX> there and we went down and picked us up a little old female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mongrel</ENAMEX> and uh and brought her home and she made an excellent pet
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh except the only problem is we played badminton in the yard a lot and we used to have to get the little shovel and scoop and go clean the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before we went and play badminton
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i'm i'm a runner by by hobby and she used to love to get outside the gate and i'd put her leash on and take her running with me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> i read that you shouldn't do it particularly in the tropical climates where we were and when she came back she'd drink <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> panfuls of water
 	
 	
 		yeah i bet
 	
 	
 		but anyway it wasn't it wasn't in the heat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> i'd always go running about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock in the evening</TIMEX> or something like that but boy she was ready i'd get that leash and she'd come over and start jumping all over me to get ready to go
 		and and
 	
 	
 		well the you know the last one we had the the uh my uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> owned a plumbing and heating business and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i
 		frequently worked for him during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was in college and i was in high school
 		and so uh this was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that we trained to ride in the automobile
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so we used to take it to work with us when we would go on a job
 		pack it a lunch
 		and it would you know get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and find a nice cool spot to rest and
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i would go work and we'd come uh
 		break for lunch and and the uh
 		unpack the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s lunch and so forth and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpenters</ENAMEX> and so forth used to get just a hell of a charge out of it
 		because you know here are these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know walked in with clean clothes you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> my my of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wouldn't let us leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> without the clean clothes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and bringing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> on the job an d they didn't realize we were working for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> so  that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh for goodness sake
 	
 	
 		it was uh but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here they're you know as i mention them the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> have uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course they you see them out walking every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> but they range you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> upstairs that uh above me uh has a long hair dachshund
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> is German
 		but uh there are some huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> around here it's really phenomenal i cannot see i mean i've seen everything from
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Danes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shepherds</ENAMEX> and just really huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and how they keep them confined
 		uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> are are fine they're relatively large but
 	
 	
 		i'm sure
 	
 	
 		to stay there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> is fantastic you know fantastic
 	
 	
 		well we we we live in a in a in a residential neighborhood and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> pretty well run a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have fences in their backyards and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are kept inside fences uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat cats</ENAMEX> are pretty well on the run
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are responsible and they've all been spayed or neutered so we don't have gigantic litters of kittens running around here but they uh it's interesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> across from us has always taken in strays and she's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> somehow or other must have get into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> accidentally
 		uh when the door was open and found where our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> is and he likes our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> a lot better than he likes hers and when i pull my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> i can hear him she leaves her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> door open most of them sleep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and no matter what time of night it is he hears my car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> and he's over here and he's forcing his head in the door when i open the door and i go in he goes in he gets a great big mouthful of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> because he knows i'm going to pick him up right off and put him back out again and some days
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he'll follow me up the front walk so i'll run around the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and try to go in the back door and he'll he'll go around and beat me there so i've got so that now i fake him i make a move toward the back so he runs around the back then i go in the front door
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i i can i can get in without him but he's he's he's fat as a
 	
 	
 		it's amazing yeah it's amazing how they get conditioned it it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah he's he's he's
 		he's fat as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> and she took him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> said you got to stop feeding him so much or he's going to die of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> and so she said to me you've got to stop feeding and i said i don't do it intentionally i and if i'm in the house
 		already sometimes i can keep him out if i'm trying to come in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and he's trying to come in too i just kind of put my foot out uh against his neck while i'm i'm trying to uh get in the door and that works
 		but other times i'll forget that he's out there at the door and as soon as i open it to go out he's by me like a shot and by the time i can get him he's got a great big gigantic mouthful of food
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well he might be canvassing the neighborhood you just might be the last stop on his uh on his route during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i i think i i i think he he likes our food best uh somehow or another our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> has become a housecat
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he uh he sleeps with us he sleeps with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i and either he sleeps across the foot of the bed on top of either my feet or her feet or above the covers
 		and uh except when it's extremely cold and we don't get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many days</TIMEX> like that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	