
 
     		
 	
 		well a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> offers uh
 		usually a good vacation time and they offer uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> and and
 		medical and dental programs sometimes as well as just the ability to takeoff uh personal leave or whatever you need
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that i've found coming in handy lately is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> duty uh being paid for that or or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a full days</TIMEX> pay plus whatever the the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> pays you
 		it's nice to be able to do that and not have to concern yourself with your job as it were especially if you get on a case
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		and you get sequestered or something then you're there for months
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when when you get sequestered and you're there for months
 	
 	
 		right that would be uh a
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		problem of course in my job i don't know who would do it while i'm gone that long we're desperately trying to find time to uh train someone else to do it but i feel certainly it would still be there if if not burying me but uh it'll be there when i get back
 		uh flex times another benefit that i i like that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s been doing uh though officially they just started it uh
 		uh relatively recently uh we were always given the privilege with our
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> that was there we were really small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and there was only one shift so we didn't interfere with anyone and
 		he liked the idea of having someone there early enough to handle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> shift's concerns and late enough to handle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> shift and so he allowed us to come in basically as we as we wanted to and as it worked out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> of us were there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six in the morning</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and later on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well eight</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock</TIMEX> some other ones would show up and that puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the five o'clock time</TIMEX> frame and it really worked out well and then then of course they came long and sanctioned it and
 		and actually made it a little worse in that they said they didn't want any of us starting before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty</TIMEX> so
 		uh it wasn't too much of a blow but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we were interfacing with didn't like that too well
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		they have to hang around a little later to get there third shift work in but uh
 		it's it's nice to have flex time especially being able to take off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the day</TIMEX> and uh not hurt your pay if you come back and finish your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> that's that's a real benefit
 		what have you found that you like in a big organization
 	
 	
 		well as as you say the the um
 		benefits are the biggest part of it i think that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with costs uh for medical insurance and eyeglasses and dental and all that
 		it is a boom a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a plus to have that even as far as your uh salary goes you know along with it
 		because it's not out of pocket money and it they also have good insurance uh life insurance policies good retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">um jet</ENAMEX> funds all that stuff i think you know the IRA's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the profit sharing the stock options
 		there are a they offer a lot of ways for you to save money too if you have any extra you know that like the uh code over the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of thing or they match <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> i guess it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i think that uh a a lot of it's the personal recognition that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if they do a good job
 		uh the incentive you know to want to do a good job
 		and the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIR</ENAMEX> awards banquets and things i think they do a lot as far as trying to motivate people
 		and they're uh meetings
 		to keep you full informed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't find that much in small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> because you can kind of interface but when you get a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like ours i think it's great that they take the time to you know give us a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> meeting to tell us what's going on
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that type of thing um
 		uh
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		we interface kind of like uh on the tip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and things i think that's a good deal
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it gives you a chance to feel like you're a part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and that you're heard
 		and know and if you have ideas that type of thing
 	
 	
 		um-hum do you find that your vacation time do you manage to use it up or do you end up into the must use okay
 	
 	
 		oh i use it up
 	
 	
 		there's a number of us in our little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that end up having to take the must used <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> of us in fact uh just
 		tend not to get around to taking it all at once and uh by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> it kind sneaks up on us and i managed to carry forward the maximum amount there is and
 		and uh i'm still doing uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half of one day one day a week</TIMEX> so on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thursdays</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you have a mandatory
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		uh do you have a mandatory shut down
 	
 	
 		no we don't have uh we do have mass vacation but in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> it doesn't apply we're so busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's why see see you can you're able to do that but we haven't got much choice
 	
 	
 		right too
 	
 	
 		that's the if i had to say one thing negative that would be it because i feel like you know you earn your vacation time and you should be able to take it when you want to
 	
 	
 		take it when you want to yeah
 	
 	
 		but we're not allowed to we have to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> shuts down you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i can understand it from there point of view in on the one hand because they have to you know consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> that they're supplying
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it makes it very hard especially if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and one has vacation <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and one has vacation another time you know you're not in the same area
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so you have to take a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two week</TIMEX> shut down and it's not at the same time
 		so that isn't too nice
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they were going to try to do something different about that too they were going to try to schedule the whole site to go down at the same time
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		to eliminate that and that you're talking about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's quite a feat in itself
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		we've got um if i take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> off during the summertime when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are out of school i can manage to be home in time to uh take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> leaves she works
 		uh oh i starts about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> or twelve o'clock uh at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and works until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> that's just one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late night</TIMEX> to it to clean teeth as it were and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he had a hard time finding someone that was willing to work that that that seldom and in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">those hours</TIMEX> and she didn't mind keeping her hand in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were growing up as it were and
 		she worked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and then occasional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> and uh with with the vacation time even if i takeoff the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve times a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> i still don't eat up all my vacation and end up taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week</TIMEX> somewhere else and then having a day or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> left over on top of that so
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		it's it's kind of nice to be able to do both and uh i'll probably be doing that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> now until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get old enough to stay by themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah really that's excellent
 	
 	
 		so yeah it's nice to have these little little benefits that i know wouldn't uh wouldn't happen in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> several of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have left uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metroplex</ENAMEX> is just full of little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and they've left <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> to go to a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
 		and ended up you know even though they started with some vacation time uh it just did they had to schedule it around when they could get away and
 		it just wasn't as convenient as being able to say well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> i think i will you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh then they don't have quite the job security although you know now there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting cut but
 		still but by and large the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are still there in even in the defense industry uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if the job has got something you know something worth doing as far as the contract goes if there is a contract then you're probably pretty secure on that contract
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		well they're doing a lot with um automation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> also that's what i do
 		uh where you have to go to school to or run the new automated automated equipment it's all computerized and and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh there's a lot of job security in that because it takes so long to uh come up to an experience level where you're able to you know you have to be able to maintain them do the maintenance uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		diagnose what's wrong with the machine and you know do whatever it takes to get it started again and things
 		and interface with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> in the toolroom
 		so you're kind of like your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> as far as the machinery goes
 		and um it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a two year to three year</TIMEX> experience before you're able to really um i would say payback
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and and do the job well
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		and you're still learning even after all that time because they're very complex machines
 	
 	
 		yeah it's good that you can
 		pick up something that adds to both your your security and your knowledge base
 	
 	
 		exactly that's right
 	
 	
 		you're getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things at once there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well have
 	
 	
 		and they offer uh a lot of uh opportunity to go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's another good uh benefit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has and they'll pay for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of your schooling with no commitment to them
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will send you to school but you have to sign a paper that you'll work for them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 		or uh you know to that affect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you're kind of locked in so that if a career move comes up where you could take advantage of it you can't if you're you know signed in a contract
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whereas at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> they don't do that
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've looked at several uh
 		courses as it were the only problem that we have is things that are that are specifically on our job
 		uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that apply to our job other than the real basics like just the math and the physics and the like
 		uh all of them are taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> that are very remote in other words there like there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they're they're just a few in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that even have this type of training but just keeping up on the basics i guess are things that we could continue to do but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> there's no shortage shortage of uh good schools
 	
 	
 		well we have we have lots of
 	
 	
 		you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s only uh an hours drive from here
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so a lot of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can go you know to uh a good school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and right in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> there are some nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> too <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> college and
 	
 	
 		we have lots of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> they just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only only one</NUMEX> in the entire area offers a course in what's called
 		
 		
 	