
 
     		
 	
 		i i assume i assume you have kids
 	
 	
 		uh we have one she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only nine months</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		oh well she she doesn't have to worry about public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		right well my degree is in teaching so
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		so i
 	
 	
 		well we have a little bit of a basis for conversation i was a substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for about a year
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh thought i wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> so but before i went through all of that i wanted to see how i was going to like it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they uh
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> where i came from they they allow you to substitute if you got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> degree
 		so i went out and played substitute for a while and decided nope not for me
 	
 	
 		did you teach in all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> or in all grade levels or
 	
 	
 		yeah it was i just took grades <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> i thought i was going to be smart and get the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well my degree was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade but i taught junior high
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i expected it to be a lot of trouble but it wasn't that bad i taught remedial reading kids
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and well they don't call it remedial reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> they call it something else but but anyway at the time that's what i taught and um
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		you kind of group your behavioral problems together that way
 	
 	
 		hum hum
 	
 	
 		when you have your slow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> but it it wasn't too bad we we got along real well
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i sometimes wonder if i didn't mess up i maybe should have taken the higher grades because at least you can
 		if you have to you can get mean with them
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		those little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't understand it
 	
 	
 		yeah i especially with the real young ones i started out wanting to teach elementary lower like primary and then top primary and thought well no i don't like this as much and ended up moving up and
 		got up until about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade and so that's what i got my certification in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i had decided long before i was even married that i wanted to if possible teach my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at home and not put them in the public schools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and my reason for that was i don't like
 		the
 		uh what's the right word the varied
 		inappropriate influences that you find so much in the public schools
 	
 	
 		well that's a nice way of putting it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you can find a lot of good public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> if you if you look real hard
 		but i don't think they could cover everything that you could
 		teach your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on an individual basis
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have that option
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and plus it also depends on the district you're in as i mean on the i've seen some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> where all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are lousy it doesn't matter what you do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh accept for the private ones of course we're talking about public
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know back when i was going to school  uh you just didn't get away with things these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get away with now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you you pulled stunts like that and you were down at the principal<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">'s office</ENAMEX> and
 		usually bending over to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the best
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um but now nowadays they can't even they can barely scold the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for something you you know without getting sued
 	
 	
 		and the the um the crime is just escalated and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and even in the the lower the lower schools
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well the thing that really did it for me i was subbing in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> grade class
 		and uh
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> comes to school with his lunch box
 		and inside this lunch box he's got
 		easily <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one dollar</NUMEX> bills
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i asked him uh what are you doing with that
 		he says my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> gave it to me
 		and i didn't believe it for a minute
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		so uh but uh you know the not a lot i could do about it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		can't stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> from bringing money to school if he wants
 	
 	
 		crazy for him to but
 	
 	
 		well i have i i've fully i think i understood what the what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was doing
 		he was a uh
 		well let's just say he was one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX> that you wouldn't doubt that he was selling something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but not a lot i could do about it
 	
 	
 		well we had the problem when i was in with teaching um i was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ninth graders</ENAMEX> that i worked with and if we did have a a student come in and they were drunk or they were on something you had the option of calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and have them taken out of the schools
 		or trying to teach them something while they were there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you don't know if you were reaching them or not but we felt like you know maybe just going ahead and try to teaching them was better trying to teach them was better than have them taken out
 	
 	
 		yeah because uh that just that doesn't do a lot for them i mean it alleviates your problem but it doesn't do anything for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right uh most the time if they were they were some of them were even better behaved i've only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> instances where i could it was really noticeable but they were better behaved when they were
 		um i don't know if it was alcohol or something else that they were on but
 		it ended up better
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know that's something
 	
 	
 		i think there's a problem too with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> trying to um
 		to be so versatile that they do lose sight of the basics you know they've been a big drive in especially in the seventies to return back to the basics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and i'm not
 		completely just you know just teach the basics in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but i think there does does need to be a reemphasis of those because of our our lowering grades in the standardized test and such
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		oh sure i mean it's it's it's indicative across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that we we've done something wrong
 	
 	
 		but
 		right
 	
 	
 		and when you see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> who are taking all the uh science jobs all the engineering jobs all the mathematical jobs
 		and you know here we are we can't we can't balance a checkbook without a calculator
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> also and i've seen how their sc hool system works and i they go by a complete rote system you you just memorize everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the</TIMEX> of a certain time period you spitted everything back out and the better uh memorizer you are the better your grades going to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't completely agree with that either
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but there there definitely needs to be a balance somewhere
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's that's a great deal what law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s like
 	
 	
 		oh is it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is that what you ended up going into
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh i just same sort of thing they just you you sit there and read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> cases and then you get one exam for the whole semester
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's how well you can remember it all
 	
 	
 		how how much you can stuff in your brain
 	
 	
 		yeah and i found that a particularly useless way of studying
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i never did i always tried to understand things not tried to memorize
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and consequently some of the very best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were had excellent memories
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they couldn't put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> together as far as the law was concerned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh it didn't show me anything a year and a half i gave it up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wasn't really want i didn't want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> anyway  just wanted the degree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		well i don't know what can we do about it
 	
 	
 		good good question
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		probably taking
 	
 	
 		money money is not the answer
 	
 	
 		no there's plenty of money in the system it's just
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean they're they're throwing more money at it now than ever before and things are getting worse
 	
 	
 		i think it's uh like a lot of things in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the United States</ENAMEX> we've got so much built up in um
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> and in the politics of it and in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX> plays that it needs to be pulled down and started over again and there's no way that that can be done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not without  wiping out a whole generation of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the school system and so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		maybe on smaller smaller scales
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i uh as much as i didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> when i was going through it
 		from my perspective now i can see that it's a lot better
 		than what we have now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think part of it is that they've got to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> back to the local school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i mean it's it's silly that these that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are handcuffed when it comes to discipline
 	
 	
 		um-hum right into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> it needs to be
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly i mean i
 	
 	
 		be able to be enforced
 	
 	
 		i i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are so afraid now of even saying something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> because they're going get they're going to get complaints or they're going to get sued or something
 	
 	
 		it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in lawsuits you know they're kind of fearful of everything
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> help create that
 	
 	
 		that's that's true i've well at least i've heard that i i i haven't fortunately been in a situation where it's been applicable to me but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		well i think i think i i mean what we've turned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> into now are just day care centers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know somebody okay we're going to send our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> here for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours a day</TIMEX> and he's out of our hair
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the other part of it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have quit becoming parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they just
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it has to be reinforced in the home
 	
 	
 		oh sure i mean mean you you can you can have the best school system in the world if you don't get anything anything at home then it's it's not going to help either
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i i don't know i don't know what the i don't know what the answer is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's an interesting interesting thing you want to do i how is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> about keeping your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> out of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do they allow it
 	
 	
 		yeah they allow it under certain circumstances you have to to prove that you're teaching them something you have to follow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a preferred curriculum um well they try to encourage you to to follow a specific curriculum although you don't have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then if you have particular religious beliefs they have to be
 		they're kind of monitored
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know they they will allow you to i can't think of any examples  but certain religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> don't want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because the influence and maybe if they was a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mennonites</ENAMEX> or something like that i don't think they're is in in this area but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they they are monitored by the uh
 		by the
 		state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> board
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's interesting i remembering reading a few cases about that when it when  some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> first tried that and they got sued
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got taken to court by the school system
 		i'm glad the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> won i mean that's
 		seems silly that uh i mean we started that's the that's the way you got your education in this country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh
 		
 		
 	