
 
     		
 	
 		okay it says what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> would you buy next what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> would you buy next
 	
 	
 		well we've been thinking about buying a van
 		because it'd be nice to uh pack the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in
 		and
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are you going to buy one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX> or you going to buy a full size
 	
 	
 		well i don't know uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of ours let us borrow their full size van <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we took a trip across cross country and it was really nice uh but they are harder to drive because they're so much bigger
 	
 	
 		was the gas mileage decent or
 	
 	
 		we got <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eighteen miles</NUMEX> a gallon
 	
 	
 		oh that's not bad
 	
 	
 		yeah it wasn't that bad and uh but they are big and they're kind of hard to drive
 		uh definitely next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> we'll get will be a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because we can't afford a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they're so expensive
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh i've never i've really never had a new car i mean i'm pretty young so but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they go out and buy new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i've i've been employed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> so i i have enough money to go out and buy a new one
 		but instead i go out and buy toys and things  oh um but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		see my situation's really different because i always had an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that always worked on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and he got into business and he only worked on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind of car
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah and what happened is he his he had a business and they and they bought a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> a lot of the same kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> what ended up he eventually had his own private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">junkyard</ENAMEX> which is
 		terrible to look at very illegal but it was very cheap for us to run our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> because pretty much everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of us kids
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		would have one i mean me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> have the same kind of car my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> drive the same kind of car my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has the same kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has the same kind so it's you know when we get together and go places
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and we meet places it's like gee you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> don't like one kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's a very strange car i don't know you if you have them down there but it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes i've seen them
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not that popular down south i don't
 		i maybe it's something to do with the front wheel drive and they're supposed to be good in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> but they're very popular up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> used to bring his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that might be i don't know
 		yep
 	
 	
 		to him to get them fixed because he was he was really good at it and uh he didn't charge as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> so and he also was really nice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's the way to go
 	
 	
 		he'd help them out a lot if they were broke down he'd try to go fix their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> on the road instead of calling the tow <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> so that saved them a lot of money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah one thing i like to do is is go to a police auction and get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because i've heard you can get pretty good deals but you have to be kind of patient because you can't always just go in and get something right away like like like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX> has a car auction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> from like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> till twelve
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard that that's a really good way to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> up here they they only come around like once a year in the summertime they have a state auction but but they don't um
 		they don't repossess that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> up here figure in a big metropolitan area there would be a lot of uh where they repossess they uh take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for illegal activities you know it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is a pretty big area we got i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million and a half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		can imagine you have a good you have you could have a good uh choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but then of course there's more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested in them too
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		huh i don't know but i know someone who goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and buys <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that have been wrecked or uh salvaged they probably they might have been stolen and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> buys them and they sell them and i've known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have got really nice late <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model cars</ENAMEX> very cheap but but they have a dubious background they have salvage stamped on their title there's
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that the the whole underneath the car the frame was twisted
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and they didn't really know it it was a real nice late <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model car</ENAMEX> real pretty on the outside but they couldn't keep tires on it it kept eating the tires
 	
 	
 		yeah but if you can get a good deal you know if you can save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars five thousand dollars</NUMEX> buys a lot of tires
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've boughten other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> the same way and and have done very well
 	
 	
 		yeah one thing about
 	
 	
 		i mean i the my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that i drive came out of um a salvage yard but i see see it wasn't um
 		wasn't in an accident it had burned the whole inside of it burned the wire and cable burned and of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> being the clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> he was had an identical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but it had been in an accident
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		huh
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so we took the wiring harness out and the engine and the transmission and everything else and we put it into the the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX> that was burned we had the shell all sandblasted and painted and he he pretty much built me a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		that's a pretty good deal
 	
 	
 		yeah i was i was pretty happy i got what i pretty much wanted i could have had it any color i wanted
 	
 	
 		i think the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> we get too might also be one of those uh import <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinds</ENAMEX> because i don't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> now i don't think they have the quality and that's that's too bad because i mean i have to keep the money in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but on the other hand with my money i'm spending i want to get something that's worth my money
 	
 	
 		that's true but you know i always thought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> weren't any good but i uh rented a car i rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> and i was impressed i really liked it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh i was talking to my older sister <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and uh she said she had to get a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and they were thinking of getting something big enough she's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they go camping a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and she was thinking of getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> she says they're not very pretty but like she was really impressed but i liked them a lot because
 		they resembled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> when i got inside the door was big you know it wasn't it wasn't like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Rabbit</ENAMEX> you know i i mean it had a full size door handle on it and it was the interior
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		was very plush and padded it it was just i liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> a lot and when you shut the door it made a real solid  sound
 	
 	
 		yeah that's nice
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the performance it you know it it you could make it do anything on the interstate you wanted
 	
 	
 		that's nice
 	
 	
 		so i was really impressed if i if i didn't have have if i didn't buy uh used Saabs
 		you know if i didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that help me out i would even think about buying something like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> as opposed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Rabbit</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that's one thing about
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wants a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> and i can't talk him into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX> he wants a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> and they are they're very popular and i guess they run
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they you they just keep running and running and running they have a really good track record
 	
 	
 		yeah i knew a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> here had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> and he had like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred and twenty thousand miles</NUMEX> on it and only had to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> never had a problem with it
 	
 	
 		yeah i know this this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they go they have this old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> truck and he goes yep i say you know this thing's been running for me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> he goes boy i wish i had the money to treat it right i'm like what do you mean
 		he says i haven't tuned it up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and i change the oil about every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> because he can't afford to um change the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> as often as as he would like and he can't afford to tune it up
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so it it's amazing even when you abuse them
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had a he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> i think and he had like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred fifty thousa nd miles</NUMEX> on it and he sold it and uh never had a problem with it whereas i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevette</ENAMEX> and
 		it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s almost almost twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and i got seventy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one thousand miles</NUMEX> on it is all and i've had problems with it just all the time
 	
 	
 		all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i i have problems with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i'm not saying it's not perfect or anything but i wouldn't trade my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> for anything i
 	
 	
 		i bet now isn't that isn't that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> car
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		it it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> car i'm just being stupid and sentimental it's just because it's about the only kind of car i've ever had i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> once
 		you know it's like if i had to go out if i
 		to buy a truck i could i could go out and easily buy a truck but i'd have a hard time going out and buying another car if it wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well how did you like your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it was it was fine but it was an old one and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was pretty much it uh uh was something that i bought to resell because it was really uh it was a nice old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>
 		and at that time i was going to college and i liked to go camping and bajaing and going up dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and i was ruining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so i sold it
 		and i saved some money by buying a junkier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> that i could beat around
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so it it worked out pretty well
 		i've never had problems really getting getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it's it's refusing them
 		because uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always come to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and try to sell their old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to them because they know that they deal and sell them  yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s very shrewd with them
 	
 	
 		that's that's a pretty good deal
 		i always told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that if i had to do it over again i would uh have my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> and used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> and uh she'd be be a travel agent
 		that way if i needed another car i just go get it and whenever we wanted to go someplace we just get tickets for a real good discount and take off
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's a good way to do it um the thing about it is you got to you got to like to work on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> to be a mechanic if you want to be involved and that's a hard job
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		well i you know i always
 		dream of buying a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but
 		yeah i don't it just the money just isn't worth that that shininess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		who can afford <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thousand</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes they're very expensive i mean even
 		
 		
 	