
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh let's see i i believe in the trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i think if it was up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> alone that
 		there would be real possible for uh payoffs you know briberies uh unfairness <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-sidedness you know all those kinds of things
 		and i i also like the unanimous decision because you have to persuade everybody to be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent absolutely sure before you convict somebody
 		i really i really agree with the uh innocent until proven guilty
 		theory i think that's
 		that's a good way to do it
 		you know that's about all
 	
 	
 		well i think i think basically we're in a lot of agreement uh in that i certainly agree that
 		for any case involving serious injury to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> then maybe that needs uh some kind of legal definition
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but for anything involving that a trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> certainly should be mandatory
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there should be uh with our
 		overworked
 		uh judicial system it seems to me like there ought to be a means of
 		of um
 		not having to take everything
 		before a
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> court you know maybe there ought to be some kind of of uh as as as an example where called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty now
 	
 	
 		um-hum really
 	
 	
 		and and maybe instead of of uh
 		just kind of blowing it off and just spend a day or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day and a half</TIMEX> like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe we should commit to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that week</TIMEX> you're kind of an ad hoc let's hear about it group of i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> instead of twelve
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and each each case is presented to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">of twenty five</TIMEX> and those cases are of lesser degrees of magnitude
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was caught burgling uh and he had his pockets full of stuff you know when he was caught uh you know that kind of stuff you can just turn to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and say you know your pleasure your honor
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there's not a lot of discussion about that kind of thing but the way our system our court system works that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s going to have to hang around in jail or out on bail or something like that for an extreme period of time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i just think our system is overworked and we're starting to stress the true meaning of of right to a speedy trial
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's a good idea maybe this pre <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could decide you know which kind of uh
 		you know where they could go from there do they need a big lengthy uh twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> jury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> or do they need a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> jury or you know those kinds of things and
 		the degree of the of the you know the seriousness of it you know how
 		is this open and shut you know like you were saying or do you need somebody to go off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and try to figure out what really happened you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		you know we
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh that could be a good idea to uh that could work
 	
 	
 		you know kind of deltaing off what what we've been talking about here uh i believe that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our we've we've become almost litigious uh society where we're everyone everyone is very quick to sue or to threaten to sue and that kind of stuff
 		and although we're supporting a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of society called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> maybe we don't need to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know maybe instead of of being so quick to sue you uh if you have a disagreement with someone
 		instead of tying up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and time and that kind of stuff maybe you need you and if you want to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or your your opponent
 		need to go face this group of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wapner</ENAMEX> like you know that they have on TV and let
 	
 	
 		huh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		either he or that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> decide whether or not you have a real case and let's you know let's get rid of some of this harassment suing
 	
 	
 		yeah right that
 		right that's that's a good idea i in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> it says uh if you have something against somebody to go to them first
 		and if that doesn't work then to go get somebody you know a little bit more wiser and older and take them with you and go to them and if that doesn't work to take it to the whole church
 		so that's right off that same kind of principle
 	
 	
 		you bet and if
 	
 	
 		that's a that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		if we could all deal with those kinds of beliefs we wouldn't have half the
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's true too
 		but uh you know that whole Biblical concept like that that's true in a lot of our um
 		you know the the way the whole judicial system and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is based on that it doesn't work on that but it's based out of that
 		and uh so that you know that could work there
 	
 	
 		yes i'd forgotten what that's called there's a a real name for that like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Judean</ENAMEX> law or something like that
 	
 	
 		um
 		what is that called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Judo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian ethic Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX> ethic
 	
 	
 		well that may be right it's in there some place i think we both know what that we're talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of our legal society
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh to
 		and too the that was sort of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of ye</TIMEX> shall be treated fairly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i guess the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> started out with we'll treat you fairly i'll treat you fairly there as long as you do what i say
 		uh that's sort of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX> version
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		i know i did a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> school lesson <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time on the difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Testament</ENAMEX> where where there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vengeful</ENAMEX> Lord in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX> and there's a loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Testament</ENAMEX> but that's a whole different subject
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 		really
 		really yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well i i think we have exhausted my pitifully small knowledge on on the legal system
 	
 	
 		mine too
 		yeah mine too
 	
 	
 		but it's been a pleasure talking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah same here what what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		i'm living here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> okay i was just being curious
 	
 	
 		well that's quite all right
 	
 	
 		okay yeah well i'm i'm from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area oh okay well that's that's neat
 	
 	
 		well so am i  in fact i'm at work out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewisville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh are you really wow okay well i'll let you go and it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		my pleasure have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		oh you too bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	