
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i i don't think that it's it's wrong for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to require <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing for certain types of positions for instance
 		jobs that require use of heavy machinery and things like that where there's where there's uh endangerment to their own life and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives
 	
 	
 		all right i agree with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are uh driving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and things like that i definitely think they should be tested and and i'm not i'm not opposed to any testing i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i know i certainly wouldn't want to uh
 		you know be endangered by somebody in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that accidentally dropped something on me or you know because he was on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> while he was there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well how do you feel how do you feel about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> drug testing prior to hiring
 	
 	
 		oh um
 		i was tested uh
 		within my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i think it's it's it's kind of a push to uh weed out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and because i don't know of any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that are doing this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i feel i feel like it's really just within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> it's um
 		it's okay i think your record should stand for itself that
 		you know if you've been tested at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and you've always come up negative or whatever then i don't see what the big deal is that they have to go to all the expense of testing you over and over and over and once you've established the fact that you're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> proves that you're not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they could uh save money by not doing that
 		you know every time say if you change jobs that you you wouldn't have to do it if you'd just been tested at your other work place
 	
 	
 		well what about random testing though
 	
 	
 		oh right
 	
 	
 		do do you feel like that's an invasion invasion of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s rights if not everyone is tested
 	
 	
 		uh not if it's done fairly and that's probably my question is how how do you know it's done fairly
 	
 	
 		i don't know that you do if it's random then it's random and that's not necessarily fair
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they might tell you it's random
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then you know it's kind of like a a lottery somebody in their lifetime may win <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> where another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doesn't win anything and tries and tries and tries
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well i happen i know that for instance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> double A they drug test and it's not random
 	
 	
 		oh i see how'd how did they how do they pick their people
 	
 	
 		um well i think all college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> have to do an initial drug test at a certain point prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> and from that point on uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> double A does have something to do with it but it's almost
 		discretionary on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>'s part of each individual individually individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> to identify the ones that have the problem
 	
 	
 		oh i see so do you
 	
 	
 		and and the ones that test positive have to retest after a certain period of time
 	
 	
 		right
 		well do you think that should be implemented in the work place you know as like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> thinks or has suspicion that someone is using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> do you think they should have the right to send them
 	
 	
 		well not being a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> i don't have a problem with that personally but i think that might be a violation of someone's rights if someone's
 	
 	
 		to be tested
 		right
 	
 	
 		having personal problems for some reason that's causing them to have behave differently and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> assumes they have a drug problem i mean if someone assumed that of me i would be upset
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		right right
 		yeah it it would almost be like a
 		a uh
 	
 	
 		it's an accusation and and it's and it's based based on on uh perception that someone has of how a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> would behave when some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> behave
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh normal uh you know
 	
 	
 		right and then how would you feel afterwards when you came up negative
 		and you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> has accused you of using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right exactly it it i don't
 		the i think almost the only way that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing can be done fairly is if it's across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> from from the janitors to the executive management
 	
 	
 		right
 		i agree with that
 		because i know personally myself i've been in the same job for
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> it'll be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and i've already been drug tested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what type of job do you have
 	
 	
 		well i'm an environmental engineer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've been drug tested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and i know many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have never been tested in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i work for is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> plus
 		so see i i for some reason i've come up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times that's pretty high statistics
 	
 	
 		well does your job require does your job require you to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> equipment or to  operate any type of machinery that might endanger endanger someone
 	
 	
 		no no not at all it
 	
 	
 		well it that doesn't i i mean i i
 	
 	
 		it's a legal job you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so see it's really strange
 	
 	
 		hum that is odd i was drug tested uh not for the job i have now but for the prior job
 		uh but i know that they sent that the job i had before that well the job i have have now requested my uh uh
 		my uh medical record from my old company
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so i don't know if i wasn't drug tested based on that or because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who hired me didn't request the drug test because i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does drug testing on occasion
 	
 	
 		right
 		well does your the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> say for instance does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">before</TIMEX> before have the right or do they have the ability to say hey we've already drug tested her and and she came up negative
 	
 	
 		well no i don't think they can they can force another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to not drug test me just by saying that i i didn't i mean they they don't know that i don't use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they just tested me once
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i used to work for a power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so it was very important that they make sure their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> especially linemen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh were clean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and since i was just you know one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> folk i guess it wasn't as important to them that they test me regularly but i know they test most of the service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fairly regularly regularly uh just across the board
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		and are they tested random
 	
 	
 		no they're all of them are tested once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> it's a rotation
 	
 	
 		they're
 		oh okay
 		i see
 	
 	
 		but it but again it depends on what job you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that are out there fixing power lines are tested a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> with with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that fix the power lines aren't tested as much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but but see they make that clear to them as they hire those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> what the what the drug testing schedule is they say we we're testing you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> and we'll test you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three months</TIMEX> thereafter while you work here
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay so they know that and they
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's made very c lear upon hiring
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh okay</ENAMEX>
 		well
 	
 	
 		well have we spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our at least five minutes</TIMEX>  okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think so yeah <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay nice speaking to you
 	
 	
 		nice to talk to you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	