
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		all right we need to discuss the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		on a national and a local level why do you think the apathy exists i blame it to apathy
 	
 	
 		i i
 		yeah um i i suspect the apathy is is due to something like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just feeling that that their vote doesn't count anyway i mean why why bother voting if
 		um if your vote won't make a difference so for instance in um the last presidential election i'm sure a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is going to win either way why bother voting
 	
 	
 		why should i go out of my way when it doesn't matter
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right i think that's and and the other side of the coin is um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying well if i really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog candidate</ENAMEX> i still think they're not going to win so some are saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> is certainly not going to win why bother voting for him so
 		i think i i think that's a big uh a big a big reason for it how about
 	
 	
 		oh i think so too and i think the other thing is the news media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> puts such a blitz on it that they've uh had it predetermined with a half of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percent voting you know
 	
 	
 		um that's true actually i never thought about that that that's a good reason
 	
 	
 		and i i think the you hear the news you know you start out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> you hear the news and by time say you get off work and go to vote you feel like it doesn't make any difference
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		due to the overabundance of news we have available to us
 	
 	
 		um-hum that
 	
 	
 		what do you think on the local elections though
 	
 	
 		i think on the local elections it's actually um i think um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote in the larger elections because
 		they feel like well you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s real important and you know if i elect if we help elect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who's going to save us then the then the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will be saved but they figure local elections don't mean that much i suspect so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't really worry about their local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> or something figuring that you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i think wrongly figuring that that well what good is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> going to do anyway because our federal taxes are more important right now and you know and stuff like that so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that that that they don't have
 		um that that it doesn't doesn't matter as much whereas i think it's probably just the opposite is true
 		i think it's probably the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could have more effect on a local level
 	
 	
 		oh i think so too absolutely uh i think another thing
 		and uh i'm making a judgment here that may or may i think it is totally wrong well
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are um have um a lower income which you automatically equate with lower education
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		tend not to be registered
 		and they don't register and they don't understand that you can't go and vote and register all at the same time or when it gets down to the point of someone saying are you going to vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> they say well i would
 	
 	
 		um
 		right but
 	
 	
 		and i believe in this but
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's possible i still think that that a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are the ones who really think that their votes don't make a difference though as well
 		i think it's those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know any better about how we vote are are are a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think that well look at me i'm just a little nobody my vote's not going to count anyway
 		you know and i think that's probably a portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that's massively under represented i i i would guess
 		that that that portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is massively under represented and
 	
 	
 		i had an interesting comment one time a thought that would never have crossed my mind i had someone tell me that
 		i will never register to vote because i don't serve on a jury
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hum what do they have to do with one another
 	
 	
 		that's i i i just i that i just wandered off from that one i was just so surprised and amazed with the statement that they say only registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> can be picked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection
 	
 	
 		oh so they didn't want to wind up being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> ever
 	
 	
 		so they were if they don't vote they don't have to be on a jury
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize that actually that
 	
 	
 		there is convoluted logic for you
 	
 	
 		yeah there is there there there are much easier ways to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		just go in and say oh i want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> i can spot a guilty person <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		oh i just right right there are so many other ways but that one just it defeated me i didn't have any answer for that one that one was just beyond my imagination
 	
 	
 		well that that just seems to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who just doesn't care about much of anything around sort of you know doesn't doesn't sort of likes rights probably but doesn't like responsibilities responsibilities
 		no i think
 	
 	
 		that's a good point you're probably right
 	
 	
 		i mean that's that's what it what it boils down to is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to say you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well i don't want to be on jury you know i don't want to serve on jury duty i don't want to vote i don't want to do this and that well then they could you know i
 		put them in the reverse situation in the place where they don't have the right to be on jury duty and and they don't have the right to vote i suspect their opinions would change very quickly
 	
 	
 		which
 		and that was what i was thinking exactly about because in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> they had an election and they had what like a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety eight percent</NUMEX> turnout
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		a massive turnout at last someone wants us to vote they were standing in lines to vote
 	
 	
 		yes they were they were doing that unfortunately what what they were they had they had no idea what they were voting on
 		it turns out
 	
 	
 		and their vote didn't count
 	
 	
 		that's right but but it's the thought they all got out but you wonder if you know if if now the next election they have if only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of them are actually going to show up or how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> it will take until <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> show up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shows up
 	
 	
 		right that that's true
 	
 	
 		total indifference you know what difference does it make back gone the full circle
 	
 	
 		right
 		now if things go the way that that that they are there i think that they'll keep voting but i think they'll wind up like us at some point where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sort of
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> of them will end up voting and sort of caring enough to really make a statement so
 		you know i think i think that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who most need to vote sometimes are the are the ones who who are really out to make a statement because you know when when
 		when you've got an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog candidate</ENAMEX> who represents something and even if he doesn't win a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> voting for that particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> does i think make a statement to everyone else
 	
 	
 		oh certainly there's a message there even if they lose
 	
 	
 		i think that
 		yeah i think and i i think that's real important
 	
 	
 		oh and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> turn out to vote for women too
 	
 	
 		that's probably true
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think well i know it's true you see a lot of that you know rally behind the female she may lose but by golly we're going to make a statement here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hum that's good that's that's that's that's actually real good
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i said well well actually actually the the female who i would most rally behind right now right i don't know much about her politics that's about a way the way she makes speeches is a is a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for you is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i don't know her politics i just know that uh i saw her speak in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> uh convention and right then and there if they said to me vote for someone for president i would have slapped down my vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was was that the time no that was later eighty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> that's too soon she said something about uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginger Rogers</ENAMEX> did did everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astaire</ENAMEX> did and she did it backwards in high heels
 	
 	
 		that's very good
 	
 	
 		she said that i didn't said you know don't tell me what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can do
 	
 	
 		that that's that's that's very good that's i i like that so i would uh i would i would vote for her without and i i suspect she could get a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> turnout
 	
 	
 		i think i did vote for her as a matter of fact i'm pretty sure i did
 	
 	
 		say i i i would think that um that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that i think inflammatory inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are um or or emotional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> you know certain very vibrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> tend to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> out i think
 		i would hope
 	
 	
 		well and some of the issues are so emotional
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know some of the really the really emotional ones have you followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> elections on zoning
 	
 	
 		no oh i've heard of it but not necessarily i've heard it's very controversial though
 	
 	
 		i
 		everyone has made so many statements i don't live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> county
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		i've heard so many statements that i've lost track
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i honestly at this point
 		it's it's just too blown out of proportion for everyone you really even the news you cannot follow
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		what the story the actual facts are at this point i don't i don't really know if some of the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> that are just trying to decide how it should be divided
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wonder about them at some point
 	
 	
 		hum hum hum well they're elected as well so
 	
 	
 		that's correct
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		and that's another and that's another interesting question should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> be elected or appointed
 	
 	
 		so they're going to be
 		but
 		that's that's true that's true well
 	
 	
 		are they politicians
 	
 	
 		well in some sense they they should be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> in that you know you want them to respect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you don't want them to have you don't want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to be appointed because you don't want someone's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to be a judge
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand
 	
 	
 		or you want to take the other side of it you can argue that's one of those you can pick either side and we could spend a lot of time on it because
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's it's difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's situational really
 	
 	
 		so how do you think we can get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i've had one idea that i think is is is completely undoable but it but i think it but but i suspect it would work and the way to do it is to get an absolutely atrocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who you never expect to win
 		to go out and make inflammatory and ridiculous and stupid statements so that a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will go out and vote against that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for someone else
 		so given a choice between you know so so if you have so if if imagine a world where you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiot</ENAMEX> who goes out and makes you know anti you know sort of um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		anti <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> statements anti Semitic statements anti black statements <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et cetera et</ENAMEX> cetera well then i suspect a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would go out and choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to vote for just just to spite that person
 		but i suspect that that that would actually never work
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well this is true this is true i was worrying uh along the lines of you get everytime someone puts in a ballot in a ballot box
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a dollar bill comes out the bottom
 	
 	
 		that's an interesting notion
 	
 	
 		that might work in some places
 	
 	
 		that that that that that would be interesting yes i think that would work in some places yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	