
 
     		
 	
 		well we don't do much eating out
 	
 	
 		oh well we wonder how these topics get chosen where was the last place you went out to eat
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		well last place we went was uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh oh we went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popeye's</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fried Chicken</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually it was a drive through
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh ours usually consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDonald</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		well our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are a little older actually we got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a seventeen year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">and a</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen year old</TIMEX> but but we still wind up i still i like fast food reasonably well
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh i know
 		it put on some weight for us so we stayed away them or tried to but i love to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they say uh what do you look for to bring them uh to look at to uh come back to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was talking to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> while i was listening to they was trying to find a call and uh
 		i said it's the toy uh uh the play yard out in the front yard you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> has
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so they really like that sort of stuff then
 	
 	
 		yeah they they'd rather go out there and play in the yard than eat
 	
 	
 		i can remember many times that when when it's interesting though that that you know particularly when you're traveling and you go some place you can stop at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> that's that's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>
 		uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> really need to get out and run around after been driving a while
 	
 	
 		yeah well we've took a we was living out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and we used to drive back and forth to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> that's where we usually from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville Kentucky</ENAMEX> and uh you know we'd stop at the fast foods there uh
 		usually i like to go just to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out have them in a confined space where i can uh sit down and relax and be able to watch them too
 	
 	
 		yeah that that that's really nice that they started doing that because it's the problem is you take them to some place nice and
 		and you know the um even a place where they have to to sit down even if they really get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they get they get bored in a hurry
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah you know we now that we're a little older we can go to i i still like um i like buffets
 	
 	
 		yeah they got a couple all you can eat down here and uh we haven't went to them yet but i've been threatening my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that we'll go
 	
 	
 		yeah well have you been in the area very long
 	
 	
 		no we've only well we've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> little <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a little under</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		not really i don't know it too well
 	
 	
 		you say you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denison</ENAMEX> oh okay so we were i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> of the i took a i sponsored a youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> up there and uh it was funny we went to a uh oh we must have had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> of us and we went into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX>
 		and you wander into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX> with that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> and they sort of hate to see you coming so they're they get the business but
 		with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of people it's uh it it it was kind of funny and we went in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then it was so crowded and we went and i'm trying to think it's right off anyway i don't know if it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Inn</ENAMEX> anyway we went to another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and and uh
 		they the rates there are fairly reasonable but uh you know even those places are starting to have you know video games and things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play video games
 	
 	
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> does he he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the four year old</TIMEX> i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> that he plays with
 	
 	
 		oh well that gives him something to amuse him while there uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well he likes those crane games you know where you try to win a toy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he likes every time we pass one he wants me to win him a toy
 	
 	
 		well do you have do you have any like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chucky Cheese</ENAMEX> or trying to
 	
 	
 		well i remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chucky Cheeses</ENAMEX> was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> uh i haven't seen one here
 	
 	
 		well they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> um in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> probably me i try and think there there there's a couple of those that they combined and it's a combination pizza parlor and all kinds of
 	
 	
 		in a game <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		and yeah and and they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> full of balls and
 	
 	
 		yeah Show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biz Pizza</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Show Biz</ENAMEX> that's the name of it
 	
 	
 		that's what it is Show Biz yeah uh
 	
 	
 		well do you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Show</ENAMEX> Biz
 	
 	
 		yeah it's alright uh i haven't seen one down here i think where there was one in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> when we was there
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it was great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> the only thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> didn't like that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was uh you know they had those dancing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> and stuff it scared him to death
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well you know they're so large they animated it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's what it was but uh he he'd rather go and ride on the rides you know they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> that go up and down and stuff and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's really uh
 		yeah we were until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got older we'd go there and you know it was um
 		that right i'll date myself a little bit but it's remarkable the number of those things they need
 		merged or something but it still it's still quite popular i have to i'm not sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> was okay i mean
 	
 	
 		well we went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time uh one of my ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX> had taken me this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and uh i'd taken my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> he's about twelve years younger than i am and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i remember eating their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> and they had put anchovies and all this on it i mean they piled it up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was the nastiest  tasting pizza i've ever tasted
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		me i rather go <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master Mister Gatti's</ENAMEX> or there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX>'s down in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and that was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> i've never tasted a better pizza
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 		well
 		well do you ever go out to any of the higher higher end type more expensive places
 	
 	
 		uh no the last expensive place i went to it was a it was a  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney's</ENAMEX> huh and we went there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when we was playing uh when i was playing softball with uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		a softball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> we went and uh that's the most expensive place we went to
 	
 	
 		um
 		
  
 		well we got a lot of barbecue places around around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek Barbecue</ENAMEX> that's right in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and it uh i i like the barbecue there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it it's fairly reasonable you can get um it i mean if if you know you go through the line and and pick up your food
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's kind of hard to take two <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh to a nice place  number one they bug all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh or so we think they do and
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		they're probably just being normal though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but uh i don't know i every time i set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> to uh go out and do something my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh nixes it and says we'll stay home this day
 		and
 	
 	
 		well when the  you know it's funny when the  when the when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get a lot older though you can you can you can do as you please our son
 		graduates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and we're kind of looking forward to
 	
 	
 		yeah well i can't i'll you know i say i can't wait for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to grow up but i believe i'm going to miss this age when they're gone
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they're
 	
 	
 		uh but i i do want my freedom back i'm sure my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does too
 	
 	
 		well the you know it's it's kind of like wanting to talk you know and um but and then they learned to say no and
 		it's kind of funny but they
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the</ENAMEX> and now they get older our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s a senior in high school will talk to us but he you know you know it's mostly
 		um no it
 	
 	
 		not really anything really important in his life
 	
 	
 		no no no and it's sort of i guess it's a little disappointing but but i suppose it's it's just the way life is but
 	
 	
 		yeah i i can't you know i can't relate to that just yet
 		uh you know i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> she doesn't know the word yes it's no every time you turn around you know and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> i i can't de scribe him it's i don't know why or you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh can't relate to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen year old</TIMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		well it it you know everybody all says you'd be surprised how quickly it comes but it it uh we moved here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy six</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks old</TIMEX> and
 		and hard to believe in nearly fifteen years
 	
 	
 		uh you sound like you got a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> accent
 	
 	
 		no i i i grew up in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> okay alright alright i guess
 		close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> border
 	
 	
 		well no actually and i was until i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> i lived in in in south uh western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and then we moved over into central part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but i've been away from there for
 		goodness i haven't lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>
 		since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen sixty five</TIMEX> that's been a
 		long time ago i lived several places <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> yeah i spent
 	
 	
 		military
 		yeah my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but so i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what were you in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> uh i he tried to get in there
 		they wouldn't take him
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i was i went in in nineteen and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> when they were drafting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was on the draft <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh i i was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> so i can't say that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> then too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well it things are different when uh everybody in in fact that it that was <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> era i was in fact i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh
 	
 	
 		it was it's it's a different world
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know uh i don't just just out of curiosity how do you feel about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> getting a welcome home that you all didn't get
 	
 	
 		well see i never had a hard time coming home it didn't uh you know there all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who spit on them and all these kinds of things i i came home and got married and i i never uh
 		i and could now but i didn't and i mentioned that to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and she said well you never wore your uniform when you were off duty but i didn't uh i flew into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 		um but i had um when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 		but i by then when we landed actually went into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle Tacoma</ENAMEX> and i changed out of my uniform  civilian clothes and
 		and i never  course i stayed in i stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> a number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but i never had any problems
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and all this the all the of course i wasn't in combat either um i was a staff weenie
 		
 		
 	