
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> do you have a computer a personal computer
 	
 	
 		yes i do i have um uh fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">megabyte</NUMEX> hard disk on a so i got a i little you know lot of room for information i'm a  i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> at work
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so uh but i i do all of my programming on the mainframe and i uh don't have a lot of opportunity to work on the PC except at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i find it very interesting how about you
 	
 	
 		um i have one uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> or um sorry a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compaq</ENAMEX> portable that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> picked up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh without documentation so it was very cheap it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it has no hard drive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so that's limiting i tend to use it to log into the the mainframe at work
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and then i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">a Mac</ENAMEX> that i use for graphics and
 	
 	
 		do you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> real well
 	
 	
 		um i don't there's something about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> a lot of things about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> i don't like i don't like the size of the screen i have an old uh Plus i don't like the keyboard but i it's extremely easy to use
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's very good for for graphics and actually i i mean it's to the point where programs are easily readily available and inexpensive so i did my income tax on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have um uh it's not really a budget package but a a financial tracking package you know for my checkbook and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		um-hum  i've i've heard a lot of wonderful things about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> except it does have a limitation as far as the screen goes
 	
 	
 		right and i mean you can you can buy an extra screen  but but it's somehow because the screen comes with it it it always looks awkward to have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> screens
 	
 	
 		that's true that's very true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i found uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is um uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> year college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and he in high school had no interest in the computer at all
 		and so he when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> said you know you have to type your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> at least with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> he was willing to sit down and type his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>  and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now he does play with with the the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> clone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um  and has learned quite a bit about it and tends to use it instead of instead of instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> so even without any propaganda and stuff he he seems to have switched
 	
 	
 		is he interested in computers then did this give him an interest in it other than you know using it more as or less like a word a word processing machine he
 	
 	
 		uh no i mean he sees it as a tool much as i do
 	
 	
 		as a tool um-hum okay
 	
 	
 		and um he no he's in international studies
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds interesting too
 	
 	
 		so he's basically you know whatever whatever the computer can do for you fine i'll learn enough to to make it work well for me but i'm not gonna be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh i understand that you have to have a certain i mean either you like them or you don't i think a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are afraid of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are intimidated by them i guess more than anything until they get get to uh learn what they can do and and how it can work
 	
 	
 		right
 		but i think that is it is very frustrating because you know you're sure you did X
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it just doesn't work and and so you tell somebody who knows about computers and they say no you obviously didn't do that because the computer doesn't  doesn't balk
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right and even even using it as much as i do you know and you'd you'd oh well i did that i know i did that you know and then the results come back and no you didn't  they catch you every time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so anyway i guess you have to have a sense a humor too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when you're working with them
 	
 	
 		right and talk to them  and yell at them
 	
 	
 		so um-hum yell at them and like to choke them so many times i wanna choke <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> say you're not doing what i want you to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i i have one mainly i bought it because i'm in uh taking a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> along with work and  it's very useful in that respect but i hope to do something more with it
 	
 	
 		basically you're using it as a word processor you mean
 	
 	
 		right exactly and it seems a shame to have all that equipment but uh not do anything with it but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> i hope to do more
 	
 	
 		and what would you do
 	
 	
 		i don't know  i know there must be something more i can do with it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh in my spare time someday i i hope to do something more with it i have a lot a  ideas but putting them into work is another story
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		well it's been very interesting
 	
 	
 		well thank you very much for calling okay have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	