
 
     		
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> hi
 	
 	
 		my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Ken</ENAMEX> my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yes i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everybody's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> God okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester New York</ENAMEX> everybody else but one has been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		okay well i guess we should get on with this um did you get the message about what it was right yeah okay go great let me just hit the button
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yes
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay um do you think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> represents a threat to us
 	
 	
 		i think they'll always represent a threat whether
 		whether or not there's an active cold war or not
 		uh it's it's a a totally different economy based on different beliefs and and uh different priorities
 		and
 		uh given the the uh military powers on both sides i think it's always a threat
 	
 	
 		yeah that's interesting i don't i i suspect they're not our biggest threat anymore
 	
 	
 		probably not no
 	
 	
 		i suspect it's probably some crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		who's our biggest threat but um i wonder if they're i wonder how much of a threat they are i agree with you that that they'll always be somewhat of a threat given that they have that there's just
 		it's just so big and there's just so much military machine there
 	
 	
 		um-hum and it's and it's recognized that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> are us and them and and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> are always pitted against each other
 	
 	
 		right
 		but i wonder how much longer they're going to be a them
 	
 	
 		i don't know  they they're going downhill pretty steady
 	
 	
 		huh
 		that's
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		but i i agree right now they're not i don't believe they're a large threat right now i think there's always some threat
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i agree i mean if we were to if if something were to happen i'm sure they would all of a sudden band together just for the sake of
 		for the sake of uh of of unity against us or something if if if need be but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		actually i feel kind of sorry for them right now because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are are uh wanting
 		things that we have that they're not allowed i mean just some basic freedoms and and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is not allowing it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> seems to be going back on some of the things that he's been trying to push
 	
 	
 		yeah actually i noticed that i mean this this this most recent scam of his where he said
 		where he just decided that instead of having uh
 		instead of having
 		i can't i can't think of the word now um
 		if they're having demonstrations for in in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> he decided well i'll just cancel all demonstrations altogether
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i i think that he he he's actually he i think is becoming very dangerous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because he's making those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> angry at him and he's also i think he's also making
 		um the military angry at him i mean i've heard stories now where the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where the um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is running around and they're sort of getting restless
 		and a restless military is the kind of thing that happens you know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baltic States</ENAMEX> when they just go in there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up
 	
 	
 		see i'm concerned that that since he's banned demonstrations altogether that he's going to do the type of thing that happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> and he's going to wipe out no telling how many of his
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> uh right in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Square</ENAMEX> and uh it's going to cause a more civil war than is already occurring
 	
 	
 		that's interesting
 		i i wonder i don't know if he's he he seems
 		the thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> strikes me that he wouldn't be that dumb  i don't know though
 	
 	
 		i don't know i mean and it it might be something that he wouldn't be able to control
 	
 	
 		that's that that's that's something that really true that may sort of that military thing i was speaking of before i think that's that's certainly true i mean his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> may just go out and say well we just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> said you can't do it and we're just not going to let you do it you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's real scary actually i mean i i would suspect their own problems would keep them away from us for awhile but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it could be real dangerous
 	
 	
 		yeah we've got our own worries at the moment so
 	
 	
 		yeah right we don't need to worry about them
 	
 	
 		i guess as long as as uh they're fighting each other we don't have to worry about them wasting their time with us
 	
 	
 		yes but wouldn't it be nice if no one had to fight anybody else
 	
 	
 		well sure that but that's a that's an impossibility i think
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		given the the uh differences in the world and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just too different
 	
 	
 		well i don't i don't know i think that underlying underlying underlying we're all pretty
 		probably not as as different as everybody thinks
 	
 	
 		but unfortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> aren't that insightful
 	
 	
 		right well that's that's certainly true i just
 	
 	
 		they just see that
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> prays differently and to someone else than i do so therefore he's wrong and he's bad and we have to wipe wipe him out
 	
 	
 		that's true i was i was discussing with someone before um this uh someone before actually one of these calls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact about um
 		another topic but it came up under these um
 		this this this poem <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everything I Wanted to Know I Learned in Kindergarten</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you've read that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before
 	
 	
 		no i haven't read it i've heard all about it though
 	
 	
 		that this this is the idea that i think is actually very is is what i think we should all revert to
 		the idea that um basically they said you know everything happened in kindergarten and and in kindergarten we learned to share
 		and we learned to um play with each other we learned to take nap you know and to take naps and and whenever we'd start a fight we'd all apologize and hug each other
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and that would be all if we could just do the same thing
 		sort of with with with everybody else i suspect we'd we'd be fine
 	
 	
 		yes but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> grow up and they forget
 	
 	
 		yeah unfortunately
 		because because i often i often sort of wonder how
 		having never been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> um how different the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there really are you know how how much everyone always thought of them as you know sort of the
 	
 	
 		that's one of the places i would most like to go not right now of course but at at some point i would like to to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to just to see all these things that you can can see on television now and can read about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> we didn't have this kind of information i mean we didn't know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what things were like
 		so
 	
 	
 		i would i would love to go there i mean like again again not now but at some point to go see what what this is like i mean this this is am azing because this is
 		this is an this is an example of an entirely different culture that wants to be like us like you said before as well so it'd be interesting to watch
 	
 	
 		yeah i and i the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i just feel so sorry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that they can't
 		they they i mean they they can't do any they can't change it they try and they
 		there's nothing that they can do
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's and and the ones they even feel
 		somewhat worse for even um the ones in like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baltic States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where they don't have a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> that you know at least at least <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has some sort of strong leader i mean they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> who may who may yet sort of help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baltic States</ENAMEX> i think are just sort of trapped i mean they were taken over couple of you know not too long ago
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then just sort of told well you're here now you're part of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and
 		you be this way
 		uh i i think it's a sad state of affairs but
 	
 	
 		it's it's probably not dissimilar from the uh what are they the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX>
 		i'm trying to think of the name of the the  something like that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah the yeah
 	
 	
 		who are actually who are actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> of of i mean some of them were split off into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> i believe and some of them are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> when actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they don't they're their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their own beliefs and their own culture system and they were split up into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different countries
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and they're very dissatisfied and they're they're causing wars right now and
 	
 	
 		yeah that yeah and that
 	
 	
 		and i don't think it's that different from what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baltic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> are are going through
 	
 	
 		um um um uh actually it sounds very i mean very similar they're sort of being they were sort of forced and now they just want to sort of speak up and say hey we want our piece
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they have other problems they have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> to deal with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> i i mean i think their big problem up there is you know unfortunately not only are they
 		there there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> fighting for the same place where they all want you know whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltics</ENAMEX> are saying well we want our own we just want this little tiny piece of land
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		the the one that i think
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that i work for is married to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> and so she has a lot of insight because she knows a lot of the history of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> over there and within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> there are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and that's they don't all have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and and some of them are mad about it
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		um-hum um actually uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX>
 		um so i i also i know some of the history and so forth
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and actually the real funny thing is that i'm i'm i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> we're sort of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks ourselves
 	
 	
 		oh huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so we i i know that and i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and i know and i sort of toured the area and i know that it really is very
 		lots of different cultures in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place i mean and and it's the same thing i it's it's almost the same thing out out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> right now there you know there are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can't take a whole bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just aren't the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and don't want to be together and put them together forcibly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean we did it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of hundred years ago</TIMEX> here but they wanted to do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i could put the
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred years ago</TIMEX> were that different i really don't
 	
 	
 		that's that's certainly true
 	
 	
 		i mean they had the same ideals and the same basic beliefs
 	
 	
 		right um
 		i wonder i wonder if now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> don't have ideas very different from that so at least
 	
 	
 		they they they might the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baltic States</ENAMEX> might be feeling the same way that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX> felt when they were leaving to come here
 	
 	
 		that's possible
 	
 	
 		to to escape
 		
 		
 	