
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh how you doing
 	
 	
 		fine i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you're right here okay yeah i'm i'm actually working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> i just uh called and came in
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh are you
 	
 	
 		so do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah you
 	
 	
 		yeah i just got a little booklet uh this not what we're supposed to talk about just got a little booklet in the mail with the gifts and i thought oh i better make some calls
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know i know aren't they
 	
 	
 		yeah well i haven't get a chance i haven't got a chance to look at them yet
 	
 	
 		i love it in the
 		it was a lot nicer than i expected
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh got a few calls at home she talked to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in i guess they give them to computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> too
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> or something like that she's talked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've talked to i don't think they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> one i think worked at a university <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> um and the furthest away i've talked to someone has been New York
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah great uh we're supposed to talk about the elderly now i guess uh
 	
 	
 		so
 		yes we are
 	
 	
 		do you have anybody that you uh have are close to that decision on or anything or i've thought about it for myself and all and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is uh
 		in a retirement home she's not in a nursing home uh
 	
 	
 		oh well that's not did you push the button
 	
 	
 		yeah did i did we push
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		let me  i'll hit it again just in case
 	
 	
 		okay just in case
 	
 	
 		i did it right as she said yeah
 		but uh she's she's down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> it's it's a uh
 	
 	
 		now what's
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's a brand new one it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> uh
 		retirement home for nuns it's at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity</ENAMEX> no let me see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity</ENAMEX> i keep calling it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity</ENAMEX> it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity</ENAMEX> i'll think of
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incarnate Word</ENAMEX> and they have a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for the nuns and they take some lay people
 	
 	
 		well isn't that neat
 		isn't that neat
 	
 	
 		yeah and that one's really super now i i know what they're talking about on regular retirement yeah there's not too many they do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are really sick you know have nurses
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh that's good
 	
 	
 		and then they have other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> that we visited uh that are very nice i mean it's just super
 	
 	
 		that's neat just supervised more or less than anything and security i guess for them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they they they have uh like uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> with locks we've been there once at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> she just went in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		she drives and everything she she's perfectly healthy uh
 	
 	
 		right what made you all decide to put her or had what made her decide to go
 	
 	
 		well her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> died they were in the military together and she just did not want to take care of the house
 	
 	
 		right by herself
 	
 	
 		and she visited the place and then fell in love with it and decided to just shun all responsibilities of any kind so to speak and so
 	
 	
 		ah
 		
 
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		she's happy as as heck uh and they serve meals of course
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and they have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and a swimming pool so that's nice now i
 		i know the ones where you're really ill we visited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> when she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that was in one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were all more or less hospitalized type you know really really sick it's a tough question
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right shut-ins and
 		yeah it really is i worked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> as a teenager i volunteered at at
 	
 	
 		oh you got experience more experience than i do then on it
 	
 	
 		well  it was really it was really sad heartbreaking i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i just oh i just felt for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that especially the ones that never got visited
 	
 	
 		oh that would be awful i never thought about that you know
 	
 	
 		that just bothered me
 		that just bothered me so much especially you know at my age i was probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fourteen</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that really made a bad impression on me so i've always thought
 		not not really bad of them i mean because they are most of them i i believe are probably pretty good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but
 		i don't know it's just a
 		that would be a tough tough decision
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that uh hopefully we as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are learning a little more about it and they're getting nicer
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i've seen on TV where they take <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is one my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> when they were getting some points for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> took them to an elderly home and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that really pumps them up that uh
 	
 	
 		helps yeah
 	
 	
 		is very nice to see young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think that's one of the sad things is when you're in an older home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you just have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> your own age you never get a chance to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or anything or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> or anything you know you can't take care of them
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		obvious obvious you can't take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in a nursing home but it's nice to have them visit and everything
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah and get that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know sometimes that even helps them you know just being around young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the because some of them are so
 		um you know just stationary i mean they'll get in a wheelchair or they'll just sit in a chair and and till you come along and really try and pump them up they're just
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stationary</ENAMEX> and i feel like gosh that's all they do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long
 		so
 		um so i do love to see young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> and everything i think that's a real real neat idea
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you do get more by stimulation stimulation my in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> just visited she's just about seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> again perfectly fine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and and she visit us here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		when she went back every time she goes back to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> there too she said she's much better she's much more alive and and uh active when she's been on a visit with somebody else you know and
 	
 	
 		that's
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and our routine has come obviously hectic with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and everything and she's much and so the stimulation part is really important i think like any animal anything you just lay around uh that's the fastest way to die i think you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		stagnant  yeah that's exactly right i think they're really neat um of course i've seen those reports on TV the horrible ones and that scares me
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'm afraid i'm a TV flipper anything bad i like i like to flip  i flip it off but it is sad it's sad yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it really is it it's sad to think that we would do that to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you know i've seen them on TV with uh bed sores and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh they just stay in the same clothes or the same sheets and not do laundry and i just think how can you do that these these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have given so much of their lives you know to
 		to America you know or whatever and here is here is how we treat them we just put them in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and leave them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right when i was uh younger we i lived in the east i'm from the east really
 		and it seemed like there several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i knew that had their uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i guess they would be but well in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">seventy</ENAMEX> living with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them was even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was fairly old and i guess she she had her own separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and i think whether it's more a custom up there or maybe because i was younger and it's just not a custom anymore
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to have uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> live with you anymore i guess that uh well we are getting away from that which is not right
 	
 	
 		i think it's
 		right i think it's neat i think uh you learn a lot from them you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		from all their experiences and and that's one of my favorite things to do sit around and listen to their stories
 	
 	
 		oh right right
 	
 	
 		i think that's neat because they really have a lot of good ideas insights
 		that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is really old he he had him late in life and he's he'll be eighty this year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i just uh he lives with different
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the family he'll switch from time to time i just
 	
 	
 		well that's nice in a lot of ways
 	
 	
 		yeah i just couldn't imagine locking not locking him up but putting him in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and just
 	
 	
 		but that you were implying you said that by mistake yeah right
 	
 	
 		lock him up
 	
 	
 		that's what i think about it for me i think well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> better not do that to me i don't want that you know so i i think of it well how would i want to be treated rather than
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know
 		right right right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know it's easy to say well yeah let's let's put these old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but when i think i don't want to do that you know i don't want to be have my little home i always threaten my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> i say well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i'm going to build a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> behind yours and then and i'll take care of your lawn he says but i'm not going to one of those places right yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you're not going to put me away  that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she always you're going to lock me up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> aren't you i can tell i can tell you're going to lock me up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's what we that's the way we call it which is really wrong but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and the one she's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> it's you know it's everything but the opposite of what you've seen i mean it's it's a little hotel hotel you might say
 	
 	
 		i know it
 		right
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		again a swimming pool and grounds
 		and she has enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and a and a separate living area
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		they don't have kitchens or anything but they have little it's like uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		on each floor they have a little kitchen area where you can go down and have a make a meal you know
 	
 	
 		yes
 		prepare your
 		well that's great can now can she leave um on a day by herself
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's it's it's nothing like that it's like living in the hotel i mean she's totally on her own
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's neat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and she still drives which we do does scare us some because she has dented a few things you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we keep thinking about that you know because she they get less alert and they don't care and i've seen some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> on TV you know the ones from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> that just run into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they don't even understand what happened you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		i know bless their hearts you hate to hurt them by doing that that's like their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last thing that they can still do and you take away that driving ability and that would really be hard we've
 	
 	
 		i know
 		i i know go ahead i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		uh well we've thought about doing that for for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> because he's
 	
 	
 		oh he still drives
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's great well it's wonderful in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> respect but i don't know if you can afford the insurance yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well luckily he drives a big old tank
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so he i mean i don't think he he could get hurt i just hope to God he doesn't ever hurt anyone but he he hasn't had any accidents luckily
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's good i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are all different
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i i wonder if they should give them a test or at least maybe uh not take their license maybe give them a refresher driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> and just to just to see how well they are every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		i saw that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> that
 	
 	
 		are they doing it
 	
 	
 		they um you know they're testing that they're you know thinking of doing that and i think that'd be a great idea because
 		you i think they do come become less aware and
 		they just
 		i don't know they and they don't hear as well for one thing and that doesn't help
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well everybody needs retraining it doesn't hurt uh
 	
 	
 		no that's
 	
 	
 		you know the best <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and all the opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> still have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> and i don't know why you couldn't
 		after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five every five years</TIMEX> have a refresher course and then take another driving it would it would sure the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would would probably help pay for some of that you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		right at least that way the burden's not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of taking their license or their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> away
 	
 	
 		right there you go there's a good point very good point
 	
 	
 		it's on the state
 		
 
 	
 	
 		very good point but i think they need should do that and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> will have said
 		
 		
 	