
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		if you want to go first go ahead
 	
 	
 		oh i think i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um woman</ENAMEX>'s role has come a long way we've gone more into the business aspect of uh
 		like i say of i don't know working more and then and we i think we've even gone into more of the labor aspect of it also
 	
 	
 		yes definitely
 	
 	
 		uh with the pay and everything you know
 	
 	
 		well i feel that uh i we've missed as far as the top jobs go you know the the higher echelon
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because if you look at most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> there isn't a woman
 		you know that's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> or that type of thing they're mostly all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> there there may be a few but very incidental  and uh i i really think that it'll be a long time probably before we see that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense um i'm i'm an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in my fifties so i feel that we've lost some things in the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have to work today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that that they're not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> by choice anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's most of the time you know even even if you want to say home you can't you really can't
 	
 	
 		oh and a lot of times you can't yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's
 		you you know it's it's gotten to be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to just survive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> between taxes and the cost of living and i don't think raises have kept up with you know a lot of the stuff
 		uh you know as far as your medical insurance and uh just groceries and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> and all this you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think that we we did come a long way in the sense that we have we're allowed to vote in you know like you say we're out in the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> but i think we've lost something too
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> um she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> and well there's twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> never could really work you know because she was kind of pregnant from day one she never really had a chance to work
 	
 	
 		oh God love her
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh she worked before she got married but um she um she doesn't believe in she's very old fashioned she doesn't believe in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> working unless she has to
 	
 	
 		that's what i mean and and you know there's a lot of truth to that if you're not going to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> then that's fine then you you know a career is is a smart choice and i think it's great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if you you have a family i think you owe the family a responsibility
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and just get a day care or someone to take care of it and not really have the bonding process that takes place with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and stuff you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> lose and i think that's why there's so many problems you know with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today because they don't have the family roots anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i'm not saying that that it's totally gone but it's nothing like what it used to be
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know in that sense
 	
 	
 		yeah um and also like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> thinks and i mean she she's kind of right with it when both
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um partners</ENAMEX> of of the marriage work she feels that that's taking more away from that's that's increasing more unemployment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that need to work
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		you know like for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that don't have jobs if you know she feels that if those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> weren't out there just because they want to do it she said that you know they could stay at home and with yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		they don't want to take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing that's very true but then they shouldn't have a family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's what i'm saying you know i i think it's great that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have a choice today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that there are ways to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> you know like those basically there's contraceptives and all kinds of ways to prevent pregnancies there's no need to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> if you don't want them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well what what do you think about that do you think that um
 		what do what do you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are not having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> because they want to continue their business
 	
 	
 		that's fine that that's the freedom of choice and i i agree with that because anyone who has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that doesn't really want them isn't going to be a good parent
 	
 	
 		i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well i shouldn't say they're not going to be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> they won't be a caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> like they won't have that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		or they won't be as good as they could be
 	
 	
 		right that's that's what i mean it they'll feel like it's uh a job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's not like something that they really wanted
 		like i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i mean i i i wanted every one of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sorry i had any of them and i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">third</TIMEX> shift for a good part of my life just so i would be home with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i had to work but i tried to make it as painless as possible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in fact at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i worked as a second shift and uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> we were all sitting at the breakfast table and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were talking daddy this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> that and i was sitting there it was like i didn't belong anymore
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it was because i had worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine months</TIMEX>
 		and when they were coming home i was going to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i wasn't there at supper time or bed time or they couldn't tell me what went on at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because they'd be coming in the door i'd be going out
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		so we were i i felt i was losing my family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's why i said that's it i either have to quit or you know try something else so i went on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> shift
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i worked that shift for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> years
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		Bless you
 	
 	
 		yeah just so that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would would have me at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i feel that's very important it really is and it's too bad because because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> miss out on so much too so i mean in the sense that we've come a long way yes but we've sacrificed a lot to get there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i agree
 	
 	
 		and uh i really think that if uh like after <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> went to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and all that that was like out of necessity because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> weren't here anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then it got to be a point where they got some independence
 	
 	
 		and they just enjoyed the income the extra
 	
 	
 		exactly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can afford the necessities a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> affords the luxuries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i notice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know like we had <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> before we had homes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had to walk before we had a car
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years old</TIMEX> they have their birthday what what do they get they get a car
 	
 	

 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		and uh it to me it's like we've lost our values in this country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we really have and i i'm not trying to be uh you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prude</ENAMEX> or old fashioned or anything but
 		i i don't think if you unless you earn something and you've worked for it and you have a sense of pride about it because while i did this in uh you know no one gave it to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you'll take better care of that and you'll prize that possession more than someone handing something to you
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just like college too i think that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> goes to college and you can help them fine but i don't think you should pay the whole way
 	
 	
 		see yeah see now um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> there's no way they could afford to send twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to college and um
 	
 	
 		of course
 	
 	
 		so far there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> of us that have gone and my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has paid his entire way and i'm on my i have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> left for and i'll you know i'll graduate and i paid my entire way and that's the way it'll go down the line and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like we i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because i'm paying for college and if i want a car my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> always said if we wanted a car we paid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and we paid for our own insurance and and i think that's right because
 	
 	
 		sure
 		but i'll bet your values are a lot higher
 		you know your your and your self esteem and the way the way you uh you know think about things is probably a lot more common sense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		than these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that don't have that responsibility
 	
 	
 		um-hum like i've had my you know like um like i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> up here that have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> their money's just given to them like they still get their allowance they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years old</TIMEX> and they still get an allowance
 	
 	
 		you that that
 	
 	
 		well i've held a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> job since i you know i was in the eleventh grade
 	
 	
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		and i have had to take care of my own money i have my own checking account i pay for my own life insurance and i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that don't even know what i mean i tell them i pay for my own life insurance and their mouths just drop to the floor
 		you know
 	
 	
 		sure they probably don't even have any
 	
 	
 		well if they do they don't know of it you know
 	
 	
 		or yeah exactly
 		and that's what i say you'll you'll be you'll be so much better off for it as you get older because you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> resent things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> tell them and and stuff but it's because you've been there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and no one can tell anyone anything anything you know you're going to find out for yourself but i mean i don't think you should just not listen to advice even if you don't take it just listen
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know there's there's no harm in that whereas sometimes you can't even get that from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		just attention you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but really uh what what do you feel the changes in the future like with the abortions and that type of thing
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in politics and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> someday maybe
 	
 	
 		actually i think abortion's going to take a turn where there's not going to be as many
 		because i think contraceptives are going to be more popular i mean i realize that they are popular now but i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i really i really think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to start using more contraceptives and with the abortion it
 		i i don't think there's going to be many abortions but i don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will do when they get into politics you know about abortion
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it'll be freedom of choice
 	
 	
 		well i i still think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a choice i you know if you can live with it and it's not you know your conscience is clear
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then i mean all all of us are going to answer to it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> maybe or maybe not i don't know i mean no one's said for sure you know
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i think if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> would get into politics or enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> get into politics i definitely i think it'll definitely be freedom of choice
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i mean i think it should be anyway
 	
 	
 		i i do i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> and i we we're not supposed to you know say that that's okay but i really feel that it's freedom of choice
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah because i mean you as an individual what you would do that that to me is your business
 	
 	
 		i do
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		and and different circumstances call for different things
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly that's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	