
 
     		
 	
 		okay do you want to go first
 	
 	
 		well i could barely hear what the switchboard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> was saying as what was the topic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fitness</ENAMEX> and exercise
 	
 	
 		oh God  No why don't you go first
 	
 	
 		okay um i like to do uh weight training and and cycling
 		and just walking uh and swimming i i used to do a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and running and volleyball until i had some knee surgery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> said that running and jumping isn't real good for my knee anymore so i had to kind of change my lifestyle a little bit
 	
 	
 		well let me ask a personal question how old are you
 	
 	
 		thirty eight
 	
 	
 		oh well then you you get the over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> everything goes downhill flop
 	
 	
 		uh well the the rest of me is in pretty good shape it's just that left knee that just doesn't want to do everything it used to
 	
 	
 		oh well you're lucky then because i've battled <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> all my life i mean even since i was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two or three</TIMEX> that's when they diagnosed it and usually most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just absolutely crippled and uh i do water aerobics
 	
 	
 		really
 		ooh
 		oh i bet that helps
 	
 	
 		religiously do water aerobics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i used to do it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and now i'm down to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four</NUMEX>
 		but it's about the only thing that keeps my mobility in shape in in there uh  i tried weight training  and i'm telling you you just i just can't lift the things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the shock on the system is is just too much so i have stuck to water aerobics basically you know the weightless thing and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		trying to keep in shape that way but you know it's hard to find i mean it's really hard to find a place that's going to offer water aerobics because what i'm finding is that if they do offer it you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are
 		i think they feel this is going to be an effortless sweatless way
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		to get in shape without having to spend anything or it's the geriatric crowd
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so i've considered even becoming licensed to teach it
 	
 	
 		well i mean if if you know what your routine is you can do that by yourself and you probably do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah but you have to have an indoor pool
 	
 	
 		this is true
 	
 	
 		so to find an indoor pool where either you can do this by yourself without you know drawing a lot of looks means you're really going to do a strenuous workout activity you look very odd in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place where i was also able to do weight training
 	
 	
 		well now at
 	
 	
 		and that does look very odd in the water
 	
 	
 		i can believe that have you tried the uh the pool at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Spring Creek Fitness Center</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no and you know that's the only place i haven't tried and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have told me now that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> facility
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i have been told that thing is just lovely
 	
 	
 		it is they keep it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one</NUMEX> degrees year-round
 	
 	
 		huh have do you use that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		um a fair a fairly a fairly good amount uh more on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> uh i try to beat the traffic in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> when i workout in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> i try to come down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Fitness Center</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum do you know if they have child care there
 	
 	
 		um have you done your attitude survey for this year yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you need to put that on there seriously
 	
 	
 		they don't i don't i don't work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you don't
 	
 	
 		no i used to work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> as matter of fact i was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that they had in the field in a management position actually when i was working there i was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that was pretty much in the industry and i used to fill out those attitude surveys and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh  me and the uh insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adjusters adjusters</ENAMEX> are are very familiar with each other and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> still works there and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i get my attitude expressed through them but i find it to be very sometimes it's kind of shoot yourself in the foot short sided mentality to save a few bucks uh and
 	
 	
 		this is true
 	
 	
 		never having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> before i started to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i came down here and you know they did an attitude survey like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> after i had been working here and i asked about you know day care for the shift <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		boy i was pulled in by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and told that you just don't say that you know and it's not applicable to me and i was kind of horrified
 	
 	
 		well it's not
 		now what year are we talking about
 	
 	
 		we're talking nineteen seventy eight
 	
 	
 		okay uh things have become much more enlightened since then
 	
 	
 		they couldn't have gotten anymore in the dark ages
 	
 	
 		yeah you know we still don't have a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more sympathetic to it
 	
 	
 		i understand i understand that they're now covering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s preventative health care and uh the reason i'm at home is when i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i was scheduled to go back and i tell you how much in the dark ages it was um
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		i had been rated number one in the field and then i took uh when i became pregnant i also got meningitis and then delivered the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> early
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		my gosh
 	
 	
 		and they put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> on a heart lung monitor when i took her home and the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> was not going to cover this because it was considered preventative treatment sure
 	
 	
 		could you hold the phone for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX> thanks
 		
 
 		okay i'm back
 	
 	
 		and then they used to uh and then i had a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one eighteen months later</TIMEX> they told me to put them back to back and of course to maintain
 		and i was flat on my back for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five months</TIMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one because that's when i go into labor that's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half months</TIMEX> and i don't even know it
 	
 	
 		wow
 		of course it's real easy to take care of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when you're on your back
 	
 	
 		oh yeah very easy very easy and they they put me on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> fetal monitoring then to to you know to
 		to try to control the labor and see how far it was going and after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was born since it wasn't premature then they said they wouldn't cover the cost of the monitor i think that's kind of when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> hit the roof because it was a uh thirteen thousand dollar
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> but after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was born i was going to go back to work and that was when they had God it would have been the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> layoff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i'll tell you how they handled this and i was just outraged i did not know that since i was on personal leave of absence that i had been uh terminated
 		until i filed my insurance claims <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four months later</TIMEX> and they didn't have any coverage under my name and i went back and i said what
 		the hell is going on here you know and they told me that uh oh well you know you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works here and he's got a good salary we didn't think that you'd be coming back anyway and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		you know we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here that really you know need to be working and so that we had just you know it was this way we didn't have to layoff an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and we'd just let you go
 		and it took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> of arguing i said you know you've got to put this in writing to me and because until they put it in writing i couldn't get my insurance benefits and i couldn't get my uh termination benefits either
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		i was just pissed as hell that they could do that
 	
 	
 		i i can believe that
 	
 	
 		but i i guess things have gotten better i've been told that there's flex hour and those kind of things
 	
 	
 		oh yeah flex time is great
 	
 	
 		i still don't think that they after my experiences that they could you know get me to go back ever again
 	
 	
 		i i can understand i can understand well it's been good talking with you
 	
 	
 		but let me ask you this since you use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> exans how much is it a month
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh shoot it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about ten</NUMEX> bucks a month
 	
 	
 		now is that for an individual
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean uh to add <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> is is you know maybe another dollar or something it's no big deal
 	
 	
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now are if you if you if you pay your your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> charge do you then pay separately for classes you're taking
 	
 	
 		uh you do for classes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> but to i mean to use any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> is is no extra charge
 	
 	
 		God that's cheap
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		that's really cheap
 		do you have to be an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> to join <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		or or a dependent or a dependent of one
 	
 	
 		or the dependent on God i am so dependent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> it's offensive to me  alrighty well i i'm seeing that my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">codependents</ENAMEX> have turned on the hose and are getting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> fence
 	
 	
 		really
 		
 
 		wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah  so my uh position from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> has been an adjustment but boy i think i'm going to go contact <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>
 		i really think i am i mean that beats any offer i've heard in a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah it's great
 	
 	
 		huh alrighty when you're there on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> is it crowded as hell
 	
 	
 		uh well it would depend on when you go it's not it's not excessively crowded on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		see i'd want to be there in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> like from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine thirty to ten thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think that would be bad at all if you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> you'd probably wanted to come to the to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> site
 	
 	
 		oh i i'm actually right on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plano</ENAMEX> line
 	
 	
 		oh well then you could go either one the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> one is a lot more modern has a lot more
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		niceties amenities and you'd probably like the pool there
 	
 	
 		oh God it sounds like i would i might do that then okay i learned something here
 	
 	
 		well i'm good i'm glad well thank you you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you can go back to work now
 		thank you
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	