
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Debbie</ENAMEX> how are you
 	
 	
 		oh just fine
 	
 	
 		what do you think of this weather
 	
 	
 		oh it's been beautiful here lately
 	
 	
 		oh i love it
 	
 	
 		yeah i was i was glad that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> was nice because sounds like you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes you can hear her huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> and we hunted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and the weather was really nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah i'm glad it was nice too i
 	
 	
 		we had a
 	
 	
 		got a chance to to go outside and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just have a nice day
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the um i remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> wasn't it raining a lot this yeah all that flooding and everything
 	
 	
 		it was raining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we had
 		uh-huh we
 	
 	
 		i'm glad we don't have that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> so far
 	
 	
 		oh oh it was awfully rainy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it was a it was a very very wet spring remember how they had all that flooding down uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">south</ENAMEX> of downtown all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got flooded out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we live just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity Mills</ENAMEX> and it floods there you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 		did it
 	
 	
 		quite a lot um it's not it doesn't usually damage any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> or anything but you can't get off of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> to um
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		i did
 	
 	
 		to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX> and that's a problem
 	
 	
 		yeah oh gosh yes uh the  a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> for that matter now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm i'm we're not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we're from further we're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> so it's it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the weather down here is a lot different than than it is uh uh at home  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah we're not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> either um
 		we're i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh so you're really
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's not like this in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> but i don't like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> down here it
 	
 	
 		it's awfully hot
 	
 	
 		it's terribly hot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> here i just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when we moved down here our we had a our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> didn't have an air conditioner
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding
 	
 	
 		i'm not well we didn't well i we really really don't need it very much in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> where we're from
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but um oh we suffered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that first summer</TIMEX> we traded that thing in  as as soon as we could because it just it's indispensable down here to have air conditioning
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure
 		i i think you would probably
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it would be terrible
 	
 	
 		
 
 		down here yeah i'd just i think it's a necessity
 		we um
 		we have
 		i guess we bought that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> that's where we we moved from and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we we had a feeling we'd be coming back this way and again there they don't sell all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> with air conditioning it's you know it's really a not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's
 	
 	
 		it's almost a luxury
 	
 	
 		oh it is you know uh
 	
 	
 		we didn't have air conditioning in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that would be nice oh i i get the the our electric bill in here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> is just about kills me it's because it's so hot
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yes it does
 	
 	
 		because i don't think they build them as energy efficient down here as they do up in the north i just really don't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i don't think so either no
 	
 	
 		because of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters winters</TIMEX>  i kind of miss winter
 		since it it didn't do anything down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no we didn't even have any of the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> ice storms
 	
 	
 		no we didn't no we didn't did we
 	
 	
 		no isn't that surprising
 	
 	
 		that was that is surprising
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i i it was uh really odd
 		but we went home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and i we had well we ran into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and in the ice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		as we were coming into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and then it snowed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> a foot
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		so we got our fill we went home at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> for
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so and we you know we had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> and i i really don't miss that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says he certainly doesn't mind
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shoveling</ENAMEX> missing the shoveling i mean we had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> and  he didn't like that at all but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i'd rather have the snow than the ice
 	
 	
 		yeah oh definitely
 	
 	
 		because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> we have a we have a lot of ice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> but uh but the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> is really bad
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because it knocks out power lines and and you just you just absolutely at least when you've got snow just about everybody has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive vehicles
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> you know that's that's a whole
 		you don't you don't need a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive vehicle you sit and spin  uh
 	
 	
 		it doesn't matter right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> wasn't bad for that because um it so at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> where we lived it was so sunny most of the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that at right after it snowed it would almost always be a bright sunny day
 	
 	
 		that's a
 	
 	
 		and all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> would be clear you'd still have the snow on the yard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could play in it but it'd be a bright sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and you know it would it would melt and you could drive around and it was really no big deal
 	
 	
 		that'd be nice
 		did you all work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay we got we had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that moved out there
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and they're still they're still out there though uh
 	
 	
 		that's
 		good  they scaled down quite a bit they have a lot of changes out there lately
 	
 	
 		
 
 		did oh they're they are everywhere they
 	
 	
 		that's true  certainly not localized there
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but we i don't know i i don't really miss the snow i miss the change of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		the fall is what i really miss from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just everything just kind of gives up and dies here
 	
 	
 		yeah it just turns brown and makes a mess
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		nothing pretty about it
 	
 	
 		no it just the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> just go to about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> and then just oh well it's time to die  so it just it's just an ugly mess
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> don't live in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> anymore but for a long time i would purposely go back and visit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just so i could see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and the fall and such a pretty time
 	
 	
 		yeah my grand
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> took a tour of the oh of the northeast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past Fall</TIMEX> and they really enjoyed it they said that the color was just fantastic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it really is and i think you don't
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i growing up there i just assumed that's how it was all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i never really realized it was such a local
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		thing i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">maple tree</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">maple maple trees</ENAMEX> have a lot to do with it maples make a lot of nice color
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which there are none down here
 	
 	
 		nope
 	
 	
 		it's too hot for them
 		we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Maple trees</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> so we have a lot of nice color too but uh the northeast really has the
 		corner on that
 	
 	
 		yeah they they do
 	
 	
 		on the on the real nice color
 		but uh i i like spring i like i like the reason it's i like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> comes
 		quickly here
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too i'm ready to
 		get outside and get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> outside and
 	
 	
 		yes uh yes
 	
 	
 		and seems to just even my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> it really changes her temperament she can be in here all grouchy and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		put her outside and hey she's fine
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 		oh my my my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> she hates to be put in indoors anyway and just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think long <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> would really mess up mess her up  uh
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> born he was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and when we first moved here um
 		he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> i guess just turned three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> we were here it was over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred every single day</TIMEX> it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh whew
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he was lethargic he really he wasn't used to the heat at all he

 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would go outside and he'd turn into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zombie</ENAMEX>  and walk around like he didn't know what was going on but he's used to it now i think he's i mean
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		he certainly doesn't like the heat but he doesn't become lethargic anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah well when we moved down here it was it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and and it was just like a shock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how oh being it's just so much different
 		i mean the heat when it gets hot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> it it it'll get hot for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX>
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the in the in the mid</TIMEX> to upper nineties and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's terrible and then it  and it always just goes away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just i just couldn't it was just oppressive the heat down here
 	
 	
 		that's a good word for it
 	
 	
 		and i just couldn't
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um  make my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> understand this is hot
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really hot
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well it's been good talking to you
 	
 	
 		well nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		hopefully we'll have some more good weather but
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we'll see
 	
 	
 		okay take it easy bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all righty bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	