
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where do you get most of your news
 	
 	
 		i watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> news hour and i subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		where where are you oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really okay
 	
 	
 		um-hum i get my news from a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> i take the the paper everyday and i read it on the way in to work on the in a carpool uh-huh and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and i watch the uh actually i watch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> news before i leave for work and then you know usually over lunch there'll be a big topic of conversation on something from the news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i normally find that uh i i'm probably the most um news hungry of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> so i don't we don't normally talk about the news at lunch
 		i i find that i have to only subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> simply because i used to get it during the week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um i would always end up arriving at work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late</TIMEX> because i would always end up skimming the headlines spending too much time reading it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh  yeah
 	
 	
 		so i have to cut myself down to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> plus after work um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> news hour is on public television and i enjoy that quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that i work with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so here lately with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> news we've had some very interesting conversations over lunch
 	
 	
 		i will admit i work with uh someone who's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
 		and he definitely has a very different slant on the news he's very very skeptical of the news media and i will admit i'm reasonably skeptical also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he's i don't know uh he's
 		much much much more so It's sort of interesting though because he does bring a a much um different perspective with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> goings on um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he was always speaking in terms of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> imperialism reasserting itself and i suppose it's a different attitude that we normally don't hear in the country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i i uh i like the print news much better than the television news because television news tends to sensationalize
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		true um the
 	
 	
 		i understand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> probably doesn't
 	
 	
 		they um tend to spend
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		quite a bit of time on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story they will have maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> main stories and just spend a very large amount of time sort of like the uh what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i guess they only normally stick with just the one um story but they they can do a much better job since they don't have to chop it into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">little two minute</TIMEX> stories
 	
 	
 		they don't report on every murder and shooting that happened in in every little town
 	
 	
 		no no it's very much national interest news a lot of times they end up um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		with these panels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and they go back and forth where everyone's giving some opinions and sometimes that i i don't know the value of that because i saw plenty of jokes and and um
 		oh editorial cartoons about all the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> making their living during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Gulf War</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've been getting a kick out of those lately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although um
 		i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only twenty five</TIMEX> so i've never actually been through a period of war and i don't know anyone in the military and i don't have a lot of background knowledge in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		military strategy and and weaponry and and all that kind of stuff and i thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> were very interesting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when they started to speculate i
 		i saw that for what it was and thought all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> don't know what's going on but i thought they were they they were interesting and and they shed some light on what was going on for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i will admit it's interesting i i i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six</TIMEX> so i don't have any more experience in that than you um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it it was very interesting that it seemed like some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> had their axe to grind you know there were some that were screaming for air power there were some that were saying the air power wasn't going to do it and they seemed to mold the events
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to their view of the world which i suppose just about everyone does but these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> had a a uh national soap <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> to stand on and and express this view
 	
 	
 		you know one of the the best television news shows that i saw during the war was a show on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> and it was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and it was hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was so interesting because they were relating the war to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> and they also had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> calling in live from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and asking questions
 		and they they had all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> in the different areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and and all they had them all uh
 		on i don't know what you'd call it other than on line they had them all on hold and if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> asked a question that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> could best answer they would cut to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would answer the question it was just very
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">informative</ENAMEX> and interesting and uh i was real impressed at how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> handled uh
 		translating the war for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i didn't see anything like that although i did uh i guess one thing that i found sort of interesting this is getting a little off the topic but
 		there was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a big push you know with the local T V <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> to have little hot lines with counselors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh learn how to talk about their war with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i thought that was a really unusual thing
 	
 	
 		and our local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> here i don't know if it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEB</ENAMEX> statewide or whatever but they have videos
 		that uh i don't know if they still have them but they were free rental videos that had something to do with the war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it it with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s aspect um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh it was it was
 		right it was something for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		that that they they had several advertisements on television pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> going and and uh getting the video and watching it with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and discussing it and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i suppose that is a valuable service that again not having uh lived through another war i don't know if that's a common thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought of or if that was
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		a a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with people
 	
 	
 		back during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> conflict that no one will will have the guts enough to call a real war uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the that type of technology just wasn't at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s disposal
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		so i don't think there's ever been a war that's been so thoroughly
 		covered by the news
 	
 	
 		and probably more importantly one that lasted short enough that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s interest didn't flauge too badly
 	
 	
 		yeah i tell you what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three days</TIMEX> i was glued to the television
 	
 	
 		i will admit the same thing i would come home and flip on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> and they would run these extended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two three hour</TIMEX> versions of the program and i i was just i was
 	
 	
 		and i had
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horrified</ENAMEX> and fascinated  by what i was seeing
 	
 	
 		i tell you what the uh the war started let's see was it a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> must have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i was i stayed up until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> sitting right dead <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in front of my television just watching practically with my mouth hanging open
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i was watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and they would they would switch back to one of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaus</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be standing there in gas masks and you'd be hearing the sirens and it was just i was amazed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i didn't have that exper ience i i don't have cable so i i'm pretty much limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> which i thought i thought they did a very good job
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question for you i
 		you say you take the newspaper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i i found the newspaper situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> very interesting we've got
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fairly well relatively weaker paper the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> which has a very strong subscription
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> have you said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you have just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> paper or do you have several
 	
 	
 		no there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and they're pretty close
 		uh the one that i picked is more similar in format to the newspaper i grew up near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> there that run pretty much neck and neck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the one i picked here had the same format as the one that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> took as i was growing up i mean the same type of typeface on the headline and that kind of stuff i mean it's it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		piddley stuff to pick a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> over and i enjoy the comics are better in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> like this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> has The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far Side</ENAMEX> and the comics that i enjoy and the other one has some weird ones that i've never heard of so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i actually take both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> i figure i'm only taking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and i can afford that i i find the news reporting in the the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		Mourning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> to be better but i sort of have a liberal political slant and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mourning News</ENAMEX> just has an incredibly conservative editorial um outlook
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> just to balance that out a little bit
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> takes probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six Sunday</TIMEX> papers He takes both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> papers an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> paper both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> papers i guess he takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX> paper and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Braunsfel</ENAMEX> paper
 		but he's a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Texas State University</ENAMEX> so he's getting all the sports sections
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so you know he has these stacks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that go unread unless
 		
 		
 	