
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 		what kind of hobbies do you have
 	
 	
 		well if uh i like to do i like to make stuffed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> i i sort of have not been doing as much as i did you know before i had to work for real  but i like to do things like that and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know bottle covers and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that sort of stuff and dancing
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the dancing i've i've kept up with because you know you don't have to
 		well you don't have to get a lot of stuff out you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you do
 	
 	
 		well i sew
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		clothes you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's like a hobby because i don't ever make anybody nothing but me
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or maybe little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i've i've done weddings but not not not big weddings like you know
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		big big weddings just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>'s dresses and stuff like that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so
 		i don't want to be paid to do it because then it becomes a job and then it's not a hobby you know
 	
 	
 		wow
 		yeah and then it then it puts a lot of responsibility on you
 	
 	
 		and a lot of stress too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know especially i don't want to do this and i don't want to do that so it's then it's not a hobby it's more of a job but i like to sew you know it calms me down
 	
 	
 		oh well that yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i like to sew too but you know if i'm not in the mood to sew i can screw things up like you wouldn't believe
 	
 	
 		oh yes and then i go ballooning
 	
 	
 		yeah  and then it lies in a drawer for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five or six years</TIMEX> at least
 	
 	
 		hot air
 		no hot i go hot air ballooning
 	
 	
 		oh do you really
 	
 	
 		yeah in a hot a hot air balloon
 	
 	
 		oh wow how exciting
 	
 	
 		in a hot air balloon
 		yes now that's fun
 	
 	
 		oh i'll bet
 	
 	
 		and uh well i don't i don't own a balloon but i <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> he owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> balloons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he'll call us up and say let's go and so we'll meet you know real <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think we're crazy because we get up so <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> but i love it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		and i always tell people if you ever go up in one you just that's it you be hooked
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they're so pretty and you know
 	
 	
 		is it is it hard to make it come down where you want to
 	
 	
 		well you don't have a choice
 	
 	
 		oh it just comes down when it wants to
 	
 	
 		well you don't have a choice of where you're going
 		so when you get ready to come down you have to you know you it's more or less like letting the air out he can land more or less where he wants to it's just that there's no like if he wanted to go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place he would have to know which way the wind is blowing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		but other than that that's the only fall back you know because the winds change he goes the other direction and and we we have to follow him around you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well have you flown in one of those where they have a whole bunch that go you know like up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah that's just Plano they have Plano festival
 	
 	
 		yeah how long have they been doing that
 	
 	
 		uh
 		let's see now i think we're on number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> we're almost to number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i think because i've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well that's neat
 	
 	
 		so yeah and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesquite</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> they do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in Mesquite
 	
 	
 		what about that one they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now that's old that is that is the largest
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the oldest one isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the largest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the world they they have over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six hundred</TIMEX> balloons
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how many do they have like at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> one usually
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about sixty</TIMEX> it's it's getting larger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i think we had eighty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> it'll
 	
 	
 		um-hum more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get involved and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you have sponsored balloons you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah because those things are pretty expensive aren't they
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> they all have balloons you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> don't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX> i mean yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX> they don't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX> whatever it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		none of the major electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have them but uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern Bell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-Up</ENAMEX> they have balloons
 	
 	
 		yeah i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI Detroit</ENAMEX> a long time ago that had one that a bank
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know had sponsored
 	
 	
 		yeah now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> they sponsor different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> out here like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank One</ENAMEX> sponsored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one one year</TIMEX>
 		and i can't think of the rest of them but they they you know they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> for certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloons</ENAMEX> and all they do is just put the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> or whoever's sponsoring that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> that balloon yeah it's pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it looks so pretty when they're all you know when there's a bunch of them that way
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh yeah and it's so peaceful we went out to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Texas Stadium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one time</TIMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> jamboree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we we was inside of the stadium like like i was thinking it the Astrodome
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they filled it up the football field
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and inflated all the balloons
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's it was so pretty that if you got way up at the top it looked like you could just dive off and and and bounce on a bunch of pillows you know  it was good it was fun i had fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		wow
 		sounds fun
 	
 	
 		but that that's my that's probably my main hobby that sewing and reading books that's about it
 	
 	
 		oh i like to read too what kind of books do you like
 	
 	
 		do you really
 		romance
 	
 	
 		yeah i like those i like mysteries i like murder mysteries too
 	
 	
 		uh um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever read any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Koontz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's he's sort of it's he he's writes real good but usually it's the kind though that you don't want to start if you have to put it down very soon
 	
 	
 		go anywhere yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah the he does well they're sort of scary
 		you know but they're they're just really really good
 	
 	
 		uh uh
 	
 	
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watchers</ENAMEX> you know they made a movie of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Watchers</ENAMEX> here not too long ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was a book that he wrote that that was my favorite one it's about this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>
 		and this it was he was an experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> thing you know
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were trying to do like like robotic stuff and everything
 	
 	
 		oh i seen that movie
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well the the book was just ever so much better
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah it was great
 	
 	
 		i don't like i don't like scary books i can't  i can't read those i get paranoid
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you like uh uh who is it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Holt</ENAMEX> is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah she's one
 	
 	
 		yeah those are good i like those
 	
 	
 		but i like i i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Steele</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well that's i
 	
 	
 		i have every book the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s ever wrote
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of her books have been on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them's been on TV
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of them on tape and i'm fixing to tape this other one that's coming on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
 		Changes yeah
 	
 	
 		oh what what what one is that
 	
 	
 		Changes
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and i had the book and i hadn't read it in so long so i read it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> to see if i could so i can watch the movie
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah usually the the movies are not as good
 	
 	
 		the book is always the book is always better
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but you know but because i know some of the stuff like that one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Krantz</ENAMEX> made that one they did that one really they did okay but i liked the book better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was good
 	
 	
 		yeah that's usually the way it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes they just change them completely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you think it's the same but it's really not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaws</ENAMEX> do you remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaws</ENAMEX> did you
 	
 	
 		yeah the book was different from the
 	
 	
 		yeah the book was a lot better i thought
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but they just they just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so what else do you like to do besides reading
 	
 	
 		well my dancing is i i like to belly dance
 	
 	
 		oh belly dance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you mean like those little thin in the little roll the bellies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can't do that i've always tried to do that i've always wanted to though i didn't how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can get they stomach
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well you know it's it's real funny because when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started it was like i saw someone at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> party this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and she'd been belly dancing since she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> you know so i thought well jeez you know that looks like fun i'll learn that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> ha
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i mean you could just you could just take lessons forever forever i think
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		um
 	
 	
 		course i'm tend to be a slow learner i guess anyway but it's a lot of fun and it's it's a good way to get exercise you know fooling yourself because you don't realize you're getting exercise
 		you know it's so much fun you don't really think about it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and exercising i mean let's face it exercising stinks
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh i go to aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> and stuff but
 	
 	
 		i like that
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		aerobics yeah i like aerobics
 	
 	
 		are you do do you are you at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so so you go to the fitness center
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		no i go to jazzercise
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh yeah yeah i well the only time i can go in too and all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that are available are like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> which is you know i i go to those when i can
 	
 	
 		oh they have them at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> over here
 	
 	
 		yeah well they have uh the they have them like at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know here but i
 	
 	
 		no we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six and seven no six</TIMEX> and then one is at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven ten</NUMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i like jazzercise  i like it better than aerobics
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a lot of fun
 		well yeah that's the same kind of thing like belly dancing you know you don't really realize that you're working as hard as you are
 	
 	
 		because you're having fun
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's sort of cute too
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah i like jazzercise  i'll tell anybody i'd go to jazzercise before i'd go to aerobics
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well see i belong to the fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> so i feel like i have to go to the aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to get my money's worth you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to belong i i but i stopped that because i never used it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the the fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> so  oh well that's a waste of money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well it's so neat because it's right there and i can go just right after work and you know before i get home because once i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that that tends to be it so
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm thinking about it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wants he wants to go to and sign up for the weights
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah and yeah that's handy and they're just there you know when you want to use them
 	
 	
 		so but
 		um-hum and they're open till i think ten
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i i did the family thing so my sweetie could go too
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do the weights
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		he'll he'll he would never do an aerobics he'd die before he in aerobics class
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but  he likes the weights and the you know stationary bicycle and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes the weights period that's it he wants to be up like he wants to he says i'm going to pump up i said uh-huh
 	
 	
 		body build huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah because i'm always looking at those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i love them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i always ask him how come they don't ever have no hair because  i've never
 	
 	
 		i think they shave it
 	
 	
 		yeah they do and i told him i said well if you do it you can't shave your hair
 	
 	
 		yeah and put
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry i can't handle it
 	
 	
 		and then then oil up i think
 	
 	
 		um-hum they do and then i don't know how they get because normally they're not that pumped up and i
 		
 		
 	