
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		all right
 	
 	
 		i've uh as far as i'm concerned i find that the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have lost so much
 		because they have become more aggressive and more dominating and i think that comes about from their being a definite factor in the job market now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well i tend i tend to agree uh in some ways i think it's uh i think if anything a lot of um
 		the changes that have occurred um in some ways they're for the better because i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should have a choice and i do believe in the being able to have a choice as to as far as what you would like to do with your life but by the same token
 		and i know this for myself because i've worked and i've not  worked
 		um that it makes it uh sometimes it makes life more difficult i think when the roles now are less defined as far as you know what uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should or should not be doing that
 		it it makes it can make life more difficult there are more things to work out i know when i was working you know you have all these problems with
 		with the child care and and with uh pleasing you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> on the job so you have added stresses from there and then you still have all the things that um
 		that you need to do at home and and that doesn't change you know just because your your going out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for so many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours a day</TIMEX> doesn't uh make those other things go away and the other responsibilities are still important um
 		so um have you have you worked outside also and um feel that it that well how do you feel as far as uh what would be a happy medium or or what would you like to see
 	
 	
 		i would like uh yes i have worked outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and i was in one of those safe occupations i was a school teacher
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when i taught for my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> career
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we uh then i stopped teaching after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s business business was established and we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i stayed home with those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		raised those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and now that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has retired i am back substitute teaching which
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		if anyone has ever been involved in that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> it's fun and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> you wonder why you're even bothering because your fighting for your life but i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> and i've always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciplinarian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		but yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i'm i'm not real sure that the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are being forced into the job market as many of them imply i think they're going in by choice
 	
 	
 		oh i believe i think so yes
 	
 	
 		yes and and i have no problem with that but i think the male needs to be the dominant person
 		and i think too many of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professional wives</ENAMEX> in our small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> uh are not letting that happen they are very aggressive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're uh they almost have what i would call a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">killer bee killer bee</ENAMEX> instinct
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they have to be in charge and and i think i think they lose a lot by what i call neutering their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well what do you think though um um i don't know i the the
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> problem i guess i have and maybe why so many women younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now are choosing to go outside is i feel that in general in this society
 		that being at home is not looked upon as um a job in itself whereas you know you hear a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are home saying that it is a job in itself but i know when i was working
 		and i was a an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> so i was always with men
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they were single many of them and i tried to explain to them well my day doesn't end when i leave at i used to leave at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> i keep going to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and they had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they used to look down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that were home they'd say oh i bet you go home and you know at least you get out of here at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and you can go home and put your feet up and watch soap operas and i used to be infuriated because they really had no idea
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what was involved once i got home now taking care of them running them everywhere helping with homework the bath the whole you know everything
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i think that one reason that so many younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> feel in uh compelled to go into a profession is that they feel that if they stay home they are not respected
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and that being home is not a respectable uh position in society and there's a lot of truth to that and i don't know how you feel i don't know how you felt when you were home and what kind of feedback you got but i can see with the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
 		that they definitely are looking down upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are home and yet by the same token i think some of it is jealousy you you once in a while you hear them say things like
 		i wish i had the choice you know i wish i was the one i would stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would go out and support us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> had an education and could support us and the only value i see coming out of this is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now in in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> home they now actually have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i see my sons-in-law i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's a beautician and i see my sons-in-law cooking
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and dropping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> off at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitter</ENAMEX> and picking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and having a much better relationship with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> ever did because he left home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five thirty in the morning</TIMEX> and he got home at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> fifteen
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh he ate his dinner and he was asleep in his chair because he was exhausted
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		so now the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> are having a chance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and i think that's an advantage
 	
 	
 		and they enjoy it
 		yeah and they do enjoy it i i see you're right i see many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i think that is healthy because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and i think it's a a wonderful advantage for the young for the for the particularly for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> for the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> to have a relationship with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and and i don't think you
 	
 	
 		right oh yeah
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we get into so much of the mother dominating figure if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has more input there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't understand why the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> feel like they have to build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and they have to that kind of job uh to go out there and shovel that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tar</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		and drive those big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and we just recently finished a long drive through the west a little <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over five thousand miles</NUMEX> and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point we sat down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i didn't realize it but i sat at a counter to have a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> that happened to be for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> only and here's this young girl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with the tattoos and she was has just had just driven a load of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> to some place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and she'd been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i ask her how old she was and she was the age between the age of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
 		and she had been driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and i thought gosh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean why would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> choose that rough and tumble life style when
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess i'm still i'm a maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a little bit of a male chauvinist in that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's a very considerate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but he also thinks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> should be taken care of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">and</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and she should vote but after she talks to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> about how she ought to vote
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		now it probably doesn't work that way in our household because i have strong opinions about things too but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">yea h</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i like being taken care of i like my luggage carried and my door opened and i think the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are losing that and i think that's sad
 	
 	
 		well it
 		well that that's true there is that part too and i guess we also have to examine though and although your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s probably been as much conditioned as you know  anybody else um i guess having
 	
 	
 		he was raised in the south i think that's a little war condition  both
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah and and you have to i guess you have to question too why a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> especially i think middle age and older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> why they feel that way and
 		and i think it gets scary for them to see change also they've been used to being really to be honest in in society and in a way number one and they come home and everything's done for them and their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> is served
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think it's frightening to them to see the roles switching and i think i think this reaction comes more out of fear now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		um he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> older than me and but he has his attitudes are
 		very much pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> pro-career which is kind of interesting he comes from a culture where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are stay at home and do everything um and yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um he's the type that he is willing to have to take on more responsibility
 		um if that meant you know for me to be able to uh uh advance or go back to work or whatever i'm kind of more  thank you  i'm kind of more middle
 		of the road i think that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are small i think it's okay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to work especially there should be some a lot more part time
 		but i think it's um
 		i don't believe in this career you know this career drive when when they're small because i think  they're downstairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>  i think that's very um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unfair to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> usually work fifty or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty hours a week</TIMEX> i refused to work more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> i was part-time and even that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> race but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think you have to put in perspective that you know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> came home from school i wanted to be here i didn't want i don't want a job where i'm traveling around and and i'm away and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think you can have both it's more hectic but i think you have to put into perspective what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need first then
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of my problem with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> is
 		
 		
 	