
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay have you ever served as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		never i've never been served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> never been called up in a jury although some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have been jurors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i never have either
 	
 	
 		you haven't huh if you were uh what do you think about the whole concept of a trial by your peers
 	
 	
 		well i think it's a good idea i think our justice system needs a major overhaul and i'm not sure what needs to be done to fix it but i think they've got a lot of problems
 	
 	
 		i think the major thing they need to  correct is how long it takes something to get to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and to get to trial
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		and i don't know if that's just a pure volumes number or or what but uh
 		sometimes i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is ignorant in the facts of law and how things should be determined and they're too easily swayed by their emotion
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's true
 	
 	
 		hence is possible error as you can see in all the ironsides
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		TV shows
 	
 	
 		yeah do you would you prefer all trials by a judge
 	
 	
 		no i think there are certain things that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> can determine as far as uh guilty or not guilty but as far as the affixing affixing affixing of punishment and fines and things of that nature
 		i don't know if that is best left up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to decide to award you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> dollar kind of settlement versus a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> knowing you know it's true that you know this may be sad and all that thing but uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i think is best in most cases suited for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of guilt and innocence but not the award of of penalties and fines and punishment
 	
 	
 		yeah i would agree with that i think you're right i think they sometimes get carried away by the circumstances and make huge settlements thinking well it's only going to cost the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true but uh i do like the idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> being the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who decide in the matter of uh if it's a jail term versus life and death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the death penalty and such
 	
 	
 		if they give them all the information i don't know when it comes to sentencing phase i guess they tell them if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has a previous record and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes it seems like during the trial part the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s not you know misses some of the best evidence because they make them leave and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> decides whether or not they should hear it
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it it it's kind of difficult and i guess the whole system is set up to rather let uh some guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go free than to put an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in in jail
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		although you still hear about those occasionally
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do you think the verdict should be completely unanimous by the jury
 	
 	
 		um i don't know i you know i heard a very interesting and maybe it's just the TV show or movie i was watching they were going through a trial
 		and i think it was like on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the the documentary TV shows where they ask for the the verdict by the jury
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they went by each one saying guilty or innocent guilty or innocent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they took it more as just like a majority
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i i
 	
 	
 		some of them disagree i mean some of them said one way and some the other
 	
 	
 		exactly but they took you know whatever the majority was so i didn't know if that was just something for drama or that's truly the way it is i always thought it had to be unanimous
 	
 	
 		i think it does have to be unanimous
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		rather interesting
 	
 	
 		i know they can poll a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> make sure everybody agrees with what they said the verdict was but
 		i thought that they all had to agree or else they it was a hung jury
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i did i did also
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah i think i don't know how i feel about that i think maybe uh
 		majority might be sufficient
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's hard to say though i
 	
 	
 		what about in international
 		trials do you think they should have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> there i think that would be kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i hadn't thought about international trials at all
 	
 	
 		i guess the the problem with that is there's no true authority in any kind of international verdicts
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		like you know the old day with the rack we they're going to say okay you're guilty and you have to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> four million dollars well whose going to really make them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		nobody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		but i think it would be kind of interesting to incorporate that concept of you know  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from different countries
 		uh in as international law also
 	
 	
 		yeah i think maybe they'd need to be more knowledgeable though than just your average <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> off the street
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for something like that because of the cultural differences
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		things like that
 	
 	
 		i don't know how what it would take to be come up with a true perfect
 		system or if one exists but
 	
 	
 		yeah what about uniform sentencing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is that the crime and it's already  false due to some chart and determine the punishment or
 	
 	
 		right yeah like if you're convicted of a certain crime you automatically get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> it's not a discretionary thing
 	
 	
 		um-hum  i think there should be a core minimum that they get but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess there should be some flexibility because every situation may be unique that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can either increase that or keep it just at its minimum things of that nature
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		i wish that when they sentence someone if they're going to sentence him to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> then make him serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that serves a kind of if they're i guess uh if you sentence someone to life life is only forty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> something like that
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		and i guess you're eligible after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seven</TIMEX> for parole even though you're in for life
 	
 	
 		yeah and sometimes those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are young enough they can still get out and cause a lot of trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah although i guess it's your you want them to rehabilitate and become better rather than sitting in there and being a drain all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't believe that very often happens
 	
 	
 		no because uh inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> there i don't think there's no real rehabilitation it just
 	
 	
 		i don't think so either In fact i think they end up worse because the conditions are so bad
 	
 	
 		yes it's another war zone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		who knows
 	
 	
 		i think i think maybe they ought to just be punished with some some kind of real punishment like hard labor for a shorter length of time you know actually make them do something that's not pleasant
 	
 	
 		i agree get them out there
 	
 	
 		and do it and get it over with and get back in the you know world and not spend so much time sitting around letting the bad influences of the other ones rub off on them and
 	
 	
 		sure they should have them go out and doing stuff cleaning up or picking up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> or who knows what something for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is paying for them they should get some kind of kind of work out of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah something besides license <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plates</ENAMEX> and tiddlywinks
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		trading their lives for cigarettes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		those kinds of things
 		well good
 	
 	
 		well i think that covers it
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you also
 	
 	
 		um bye
 	
 	
 		have a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you too  bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	