
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay um why do you think it um failed do you think we should adopt it
 	
 	
 		no i don't like the metric system
 	
 	
 		you don't
 	
 	
 		i i i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is is um too ingrained in the inches and and just the general um background the history of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has been inches and i don't think there's a big advantage in going to the metric system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it's gonna disorient it and confuse a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and there are going to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who die because of it because they don't understand
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um you know simple things from the amount of medicine they should take to how fast they can drive and you know how far away something is and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's not in our national consciousness to do it we've always measured things in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> system
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and you know everything you know our land is in acres our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't going to understand what an amount of something is
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i agree i agree with you i don't think we should either even though i know there are benefits to the metric system i don't think the benefits of the metric system outweigh the the disadvantages that would happen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and also the um  i don't know it seems almost like there's this it's a peer pressure thing is why we keep wanting to do it is so we'll look good to the other nations
 		because i think they that's an area that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> especially <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> look down on us like oh we're just backward wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who still use this backward system who haven't really attained it yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i feel it's just pride of why they keep trying to push it on us and it's like hey we're content with this no it's probably not as accurate probably
 		you know intellectually doesn't it's not as sound intellectually but like you said i mean come on  i had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of college and i don't know the metric system and i don't care to learn it and i'm not some kind of an idiot i just
 	
 	
 		i mean it's
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 		and it's easy to translate we have a computer for just about everything now and if it's necessary to translate back and forth between them it can be done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i'm a mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and i've had to work when i was designing packages for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean i had to to work both systems back and forth and it was not hard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you get you can get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAD CAM</ENAMEX> system that can take any design you want and you can push a button and it'll convert every
 		
 
 		measurement on there you know from one system to the other in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you're educated i'm educated my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is
 		but i mean a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are flat not educated
 		and if i have a hard time you know putting that into my life can we put that off on the other eighty percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that doesn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or i don't know how much of the you know but a large percentage probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of the rest of the population
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		they don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> probably much at all and if we can't take it and use it easily well we how can you put that on like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's just
 	
 	
 		you know just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that maybe just aren't blessed with as as much sharpness and mental mental acuity
 	
 	
 		or or even have had the ability you know the chance to to go to college or to to to learn about it i think it's still good they do cover the system and i think it should still be taught in schools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they do i know now because i even when i was in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> they were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we learned what a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">centimeter</NUMEX> was and a decimeter and the various you know basically the other alternate forms of measurements and things like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and that's acceptable
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it failed too because like what you said of just you know hey this is ridiculous i think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have so much stress on them right now
 	
 	
 		because
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean if you look at the average family it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they barely have time to stop and get gas much less to try and figure out how much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> they're really getting and do all this and it's like  i mean come on let's take the pressure off
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah
 		you know you need <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty gallons</NUMEX> but do you need how many liters
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's just like another thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> doesn't need any more pressure just leave them alone let them measure their green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bean water</ENAMEX> in cups and leave them alone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 		and it it just doesn't yeah it doesn't make that much difference in the average life in the scientific community and places where it's needed
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		you know that's fine and the rest of the world i mean we are uh we if not we may not be the top i don't know if we're the top we're one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpowers</ENAMEX> of the world
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's
 	
 	
 		it may be arrogant but i mean let them come to us
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's kind of the way i feel about it we can convert
 	
 	
 		and and if they don't like the way we do it just get off our don't worry about it and i think
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's kind of like expecting expecting everyone to suddenly speak German
 	
 	
 		right it is because it is another language yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah and and  instead of having the world speak <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> we found out that we can translate and that's what i think we ought to do with the metric system
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		that's funny well that's good well i think we kept it at real good
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is that all we need to say
 	
 	
 		yeah i it's been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		you too i think that was good that was the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> usually i get distracted off the topic you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we'll end up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was telling me about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lithuania</ENAMEX> and we were talking about something totally income tax or something and i just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right
 	
 	
 		anyway the i appreciate it have a good day
 	
 	
 		well good talking to you
 		bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	