
 
     		
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh me i'm in favor of it
 	
 	
 		you are
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought i think if uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the the heinous crimes uh even if it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time offense
 	
 	
 		yeah the the i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that are crazy i did a study on it though when i was in high school it was one of these things
 		we had to pick a topic to to investigate
 		and at that time i don't think it's like that any more but at that time uh it was very unfair capital punishment was a lot more  common
 		and if you tended and it tended to be that if you were ignorant or if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> or if you were black or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> for that matter
 		the chances your chances of of uh getting the death penalty were you know like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> times greater than if you could just communicate well
 		i mean you didn't have to be um you didn't even necessarily have to be white but if you could just communicate and you could come across in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">court room</ENAMEX> with some kind of um
 		
 
 		you know sense about you then even if you did the exact same crime chances are you wouldn't get you'd get life instead of the death penalty as a opposed to somebody who couldn't communicate well
 		and at that time it just seemed so fair unfair
 		that um i i felt like i couldn't uh um
 		you know i just didn't agree with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's gotten so though that there are so many
 		you know there are so many uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know what you call it uh so many different things that you have to go through before they actually give the death penalty that i'm not so sure it it seems a lot fairer than it used to be
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i know that that um
 		like they can hold it off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> by uh i'm trying to think of the word that you were um retrials and um
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm forget i cannot think of that word
 	
 	
 		right i know what you're saying um
 		but yeah they there's you know there's always uh uh you know and and in a way you know i guess that's good i mean if you're going to  if you're going to kill somebody
 	
 	
 		you have to make sure they're guilty
 	
 	
 		right yeah you know give them give them i mean you should give somebody every every chance even even if it seems obvious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i don't know what the what the law is like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i mean i certainly haven't heard anything any anything about somebody being executed or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i think it's all uh i don't think they have uh execution here
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't either
 	
 	
 		i do know though it's easy to get put in jail for life
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you know the um there was something on TV <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> about how one state what there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in no it was a TV station
 	
 	
 		TV station
 	
 	
 		you did you see that
 	
 	
 		yeah he's they're wanting to record a gas chamber
 	
 	
 		i thought that was disgusting i mean
 	
 	
 		well it might scare some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off of doing the crimes
 	
 	
 		well yeah but you know there there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just get get their jollies off of watching that
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah i yeah i agree with you there too
 	
 	
 		and that's what that's what really bothers me you know i'm all for deterrents
 		but i i think what's going to happen is it's going to turn it into a circus
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'll agree with you there i don't agree with them showing it on television hard telling who would see it
 	
 	
 		and
 		no
 	
 	
 		but i i do think that it would scare some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from doing things you know they'll think about this and say hey i don't think so
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 		well where i could see it being very useful is for you know when if there's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time offender part of his punishment is that he's got  to see what you know what he's up against
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know what what you know what might happen but the you know for TV station you know that TV station isn't going to want to restrict how they use it
 		and they're going to show it on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> probably not the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> news but they'll show it on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock eleven o'clock</TIMEX> news
 		and i don't you know i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year old</TIMEX> and
 		you know she's she could very well be up at that time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know when we're and that's just not the kind of thing for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year old</TIMEX> i'm not sure it's the kind of thing for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		i don't think it's the kind of thing for anybody i know i wouldn't be able to watch it
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i'm i'm supposed to be an adult
 	
 	
 		right and in fact i think it'd be harmful if my if you know if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> or my any of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> saw it
 		so that has to be brought into the picture too
 		you know you just can't blatantly say let's let's show it and and the the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will see it and it'll deter them from committing a crime all lot of the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to see it too and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well there's more wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that would see it than right people
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you know uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i i i don't know i think i would
 		
 
 		say that if they put it where those <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> of uh your sex crimes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> uh show them what would happen
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> had a thing when i was younger and uh you know i was working with her
 		and she would say that they should uh
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who did sex crimes they should take off a piece of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and the most important part to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inch by inch</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says that all the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah well that that would certainly do it
 	
 	
 		that would stop them from wanting to
 		no well i thought it was funny listening to her she's just a she's she's a little bit uh dingy when it comes to things but well she's vicious
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah well you know i i think that if if i felt like the the the system was was truly fair and and uh and that they would never make a mistake  then
 		you know but you hear you know you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are who are genuinely mistakenly accused of a crime and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah like that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel</ENAMEX> something or another that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> of they had a television program about him <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		can't think of his name
 	
 	
 		i can't i can't think either
 	
 	
 		but he spent quite a few few quite a while in jail
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		that's right and and it turns out he didn't do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or you know and and it's easy you know and and you know let's face it not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> are honest and
 	
 	
 		well you see that on television also
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and you know they can they'll take somebody who maybe is mentally retarded and then it's and they're under pressure to to solve a crime
 		and some and the circumstances uh may be molded to blame somebody who didn't do it and especially if it's you know somebody who's mentally retarded who can't defend themselves very well
 		and i'd hate to see them get the ultimate punishment and it turns out it wasn't them
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a problem with capital punishment though but when you got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know uh for some reason or another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> sticks in my brain
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah well he was a
 	
 	
 		i seen him on an interview talking about how if he ever got out how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he was going to kill
 	
 	
 		yeah sheesh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that should be put to death
 	
 	
 		and uh it it it just doesn't seem right that our tax money or somebody's tax money goes to keep him alive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know he gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> a day and and he probably
 	
 	
 		that's more than some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out here who are out and out honest
 	
 	
 		right right that's right and he's probably living a lot better than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who deserve a lot more
 		and uh that does you know that does sort of you know but how you know it's just so hard  it's just so hard to to be fair and uh
 		yeah i guess i wouldn't i wouldn't mind if all of a sudden he didn't exist any more uh
 	
 	
 		i uh i don't think anyone would miss him either
 	
 	
 		no no uh i you know i i think the same thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you know the jeez you know they're just they're just the scum of the earth
 		and uh i just hate the idea that my tax money might go to support somebody like that
 	
 	
 		well as you can tell my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> decided to come in here uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		now where where where area where are you from
 	
 	
 		what
 		i'm in Denison
 	
 	
 		Denison oh okay
 		every so often you get somebody who's in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> something
 	
 	
 		yeah i got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> one night
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh no you is talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it would be wrong for us to kill him for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to kill him
 	
 	
 		i think you're right i don't think we're i think we're we'd we'd overstep our bounds if we went in and did that
 	
 	
 		i think the
 	
 	
 		though it's awfully tempting
 	
 	
 		now if one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> i'm sure you know who they are
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		if they went in and got him he wouldn't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> what's the word <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr martyr martyr</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">martyr</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i could see the word in my head i just couldn't pronounce it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but if we did it oh man
 	
 	
 		oh yeah the whole
 	
 	
 		they'd have him on a pedestal
 	
 	
 		well right now we're in a delicate situation because we've got this
 		we've for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time we're sort of aligned with a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> keeps telling me see how you know um i'm just now getting into the world politics and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i guess i just too young to understand this or something
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		uh but uh
 	
 	
 		it's complicated
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's getting easier to understand though you know plus my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> so he uh when it comes to the military he kind of knows what he's talking about
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't put every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent stock into what he says but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'll listen  and agree with what i think sounds right
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah there and you know he's got that delicate balance right there and we'd just be overstepping our bounds i think if we walked in and sort of took over
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think they uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there will take care of him now
 	
 	
 		yeah i just can't imagine that they'd let him rule any longer you know if if they had you know if they could do something about it
 		i mean his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> is going to eventually turn on him because and and you see this has happened before in history you know that it just gets to a certain point where you're just not willing
 		
 		
 	