
 
     		
 	
 		well what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		at the present time we have none we intend to purchase a pup in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		are you you're married
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and newly married
 	
 	
 		no we've got uh we've been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever about eight years  eight years</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that was just
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		sounds like us
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		only we started off ours with we had we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> before we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that's why i thought when you were saying you know we're going to have one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> or something
 		perhaps that you were newly married
 	
 	
 		no we've uh
 		my we we've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year old</TIMEX> but we've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> pet since we've had her but uh he didn't quite work out
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so um
 		we are we've been now petless for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're going to get another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> we're we've a got a vacation planned and we want to wait until we get back from the vacation before we
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's easier
 	
 	
 		bring a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		are you going to get a dog
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that's what that's what we have is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what type
 	
 	
 		big dogs
 		well our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they were our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> substitutes before we had our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right after we got married we both decided we needed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> we went to the pound and we got this mutt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's been it was alright before we had our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it was he's just he's a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hyper dog</ENAMEX> he barks and and jumps a lot
 		so we had him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> decided after we had him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> that he'd wanted for his entire life to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian</ENAMEX> husky
 	
 	
 		goodness
 	
 	
 		and i think why didn't you tell me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> when we got the other dog
 		
 
 		you know this was your dream of your life to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian</ENAMEX> husky
 		so we got the other one
 		for him and to keep the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> when we were at work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so we have the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> the older <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s a male and he's
 		he weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about forty pounds</NUMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> is a year younger and she weighs
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventy pounds</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they're big dogs
 	
 	
 		so we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> massive dogs
 		go through lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		yeah Are they primarily outdoor dogs
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i never wanted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wanted indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> because he'd grown up with them but i can't stand it indoors
 		i don't they shed and you know the mud and
 	
 	
 		and the scratches and the smell and the uh wherever yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		there for me <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are meant to be outside
 	
 	
 		i firmly believe that large <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are meant to be outside we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danes</ENAMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		goodness
 	
 	
 		and we had our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danes</ENAMEX> in the house
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		but i mean it's almost dangerous  to have them in the house
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
 
 		they're going to run you down
 	
 	
 		and uh we went through a time period that we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> Danes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goodness</ENAMEX> and all of them were in the house
 	
 	
 		we had
 		yeah and we had we had had a litter
 		and she had uh had thirteen <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of which survived and uh
 		and she we ended up keeping one of those puppies
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> and it was horrendous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hm
 	
 	
 		we wound up getting uh getting rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> selling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> and just keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was the favorite one anyway
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh when i was growing up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX> terriers which are little bitty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they weigh about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> pounds
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so we had we had one for a long time
 		and then oh gosh when i was about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> would be a good way to teach reproduction so then they went out and got a female
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then we started having <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> and she had
 		she had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five litters</TIMEX> she always had to look we always kept them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when they had the when she when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> were little
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the rest of the time they were outside they had we had a big uh kind of a play <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and part of that was their dog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it was kind of cordoned off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they had a place to stay out there and then they had the yard and they had a little run that uh they kept them in when we were trying to do stuff in the back yard and didn't want them out
 		but we had the same kind of situation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in time we had the mother the one of her last
 		her next to last litter we kept we had one one we never could get rid of
 		he was a real dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>  nobody wanted him the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> was just one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> just as dumb as a stick
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we have him
 		and then our female she had another litter we didn't think she was we thought she was too old to get pregnant again
 		turned out she wasn't
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh she had her litter i guess her last litter had like
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them survived and then she didn't make it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> after the they were born she had a she died
 		she had some kind of an infection from it all she was just too old
 		we had to feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> we had to get up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and day with those just like with a baby
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and bottle feed them
 		and we just
 	
 	
 		we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> that got milk fever right after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> were born and we had to feed all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> feed all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them that survived
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		weren't they messy too well did she did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> survive
 	
 	
 		yeah she did survive
 	
 	
 		so you could still feed it but she kept them clean
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh she didn't she didn't do something
 	
 	
 		no she didn't even she did not even take the sack this is the laziest <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that ever lived
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		when she had these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> she crawled up onto my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s stomach in the middle of the bed
 		had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> and woke up my mother
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		to cut the sacks off she didn't even lick the sacks off laziest <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> on earth she never she never nursed them she never cleaned them she never did anything to them they were like she they didn't exist
 	
 	
 		yuck
 		oh goodness
 		what's a mess
 		that was like oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> they are so messy when they're little too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we were giving them a bath about every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we were giving them a bath at least once a day but they were so horrible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because they would roll and everything and oh
 	
 	
 		yeah they just poop and it's yeah they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and crawl through it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i guess i had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> for a while when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> too i had a fish tank
 		and i had a few until
 	
 	
 		like a nice aquarium
 	
 	
 		well it wasn't really an aquarium it was an old you know how you used to have these um
 		this was a box and it was originally it was made like an aquarium i guess except it was smaller but it was its original use was to put in the refrigerator on the shelf had a little spigot at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one end</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and you could get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> out of it you know keep cold water
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we outgrew the need for that
 		and so i used it for an aquarium
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		it worked except the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> could swim
 		it wasn't tall enough i kept the if i didn't keep the lid on it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> would uh swim out and flop on the floor sometimes
 		
 
 		flip out of the thing but
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> was always happy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		those have been i mean and our dogs now our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and a half
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we built the dog run down the length of our uh back yard
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were getting i mean we couldn't even let our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> until he was about two i guess he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> when we built the dog run we couldn't let him go out in the back yard
 		because it was we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deck</ENAMEX> with a rail and he could go on that but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> were so big and he was so little
 		you know they just even walking by him they'd knock him down and the whole back yard had poop in it all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was a mess for the little one so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now we have a back yard and a dog run
 	
 	
 		uh we've uh we'll probably get real small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairn</ENAMEX> terrier
 	
 	
 		oh that'll be nice
 	
 	
 		and it'll probably be an indoor outdoor dog
 	
 	
 		yeah back and forth uh
 	
 	
 		but see my my oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five and a half</NUMEX> and so she can take part in some of the uh
 		responsibilities a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and a half year old</TIMEX> really can't quite take part of many of the responsibilities maybe feeding them
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three and a half</TIMEX>
 		yeah
 		or probably he or she is old enough to where they won't tease it too you know poke on it too much
 	
 	
 		oh she's got respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> thank goodness
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		because that's hard ours our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have gotten
 		over it with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> behind it they have the run it's kind of like a wire run
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they go the first thing they do is they go out there and play with them but boy the little one still he just wants to poke
 		my older one our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s pretty good about it he'll pet the dog you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> like you're saying and he he's pretty good with them and with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> that he runs into
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> the little one still just wants to poke and
 		and see if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> will back off you know and
 	
 	
 		i think that's eighteen months
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i think that's just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> trying to figure out you know what's going to happen and it will happen again and again and again
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it is too it's gonna get better
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think if we didn't have pets if we didn't already have our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> now we wouldn't get them because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are so little
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think when they're really little like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen month old</TIMEX> it's not fair to the animal
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are so miserable to them
 		if they're out very much
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it has to be a real mellow kind of animal that can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's
 	
 	
 		uh
 		survive it and child
 	
 	
 		yeah and not get mad at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that's the other thing too that
 		i i always felt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper the Siberian</ENAMEX> husky is really sweet she can i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could walk up and
 		they could literally probably stand on her back and she wouldn't even she'd kind of look at them  like what are you doing now
 		she's real good natured about it
 	
 	
 		well that's what you i mean that's what you need in a pet if your going to have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		we uh
 	
 	
 		well i think that's about all my pet stories right now so
 	
 	
 		oh wonderful
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm just flat out of pet stories i don't even have a pet anymore
 	
 	
 		okay well it's been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		well thanks thanks for calling bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	