
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the topic is how we can how
 		how what is our
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> doing on recycling
 	
 	
 		and how and do we have any ideas to encourage more recycling
 	
 	
 		yeah  sounds like an exciting one
 	
 	
 		well it is to me uh because
 		we're our particular little household is hot and heavy we have our glass bin our tin bin and uh our uh
 		papers that we accumulate and recycle and
 	
 	
 		where where do you live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do they have the uh collection points where you can oh okay
 	
 	
 		yes they certainly do they certainly do
 	
 	
 		yes we're we're really behind the times here about all we've got is paper recycling and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> from cans uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where are you
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		um i buy i keep my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and take those down and aluminum cans i keep those if i ever get them i don't drink <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cokes</ENAMEX> or anything like that so i don't don't usually get any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans
 		but that's that's all they've got set up they've got a uh central collection point at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">JC Park</ENAMEX> and uh that's it
 	
 	
 		well our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> and then the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> have the bins in back of them and when you recycle glass
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that seems to make a lot of difference and you have the colored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and the clear glass and the paper and the tin cans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so when you get all of that going it is it it occupies a space in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> but you very quickly get use to it and we do not
 	
 	
 		yeah and you and you and you also get rid of it so
 	
 	
 		sure well you know we haul it off it once in a while and we also do not bag our clippings on our lawns we let the wind blow it off we do not fill
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah that's why i just let it sit there and let it uh let it uh rot away and it's a good fertilizer
 	
 	
 		well this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it doesn't set it blows
 	
 	
 		oh  that's right
 	
 	
 		give
 	
 	
 		surprised you even have grass there
 	
 	
 		lots of grass give it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX> and the whole things gone there's no problem someone else is worrying about
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we have somebody else's but uh the problem that bothers me more uh you know i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> will do as good as they are supported by their local government you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if there's if there's enough need and they have a responsive local city management
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it will happen
 		what upsets me uh there was an article and i'm sorry i was reading a book at the same time it was on our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> beaches
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they are saying our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> beaches are suppose to be the dirtiest beaches in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and it's not because of litter it's because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the if you could think of the basin the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas gulf coast</ENAMEX> as a large swirling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		vacuum things that are thrown from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> swirl in and swirl in to our beaches
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and it kills some of our animals
 		there's there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> down there that has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> A and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> has a nice size facility
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Aransas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's got all these collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that he's frozen that were killed you know by plastic
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		it's horrible it's a gross collection
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen i've seen pictures of uh seals that have gotten uh gotten their necks stuck in those uh plastic uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh what do you call them they hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> packs together those plastic
 	
 	
 		yes whatever those things nasty things are
 	
 	
 		yeah because they they're they're playful and they think this is fun we'll stick our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> through here and they get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> stuck in there and they can't get out and they strangle
 	
 	
 		that's right or they starve to death because they can't swallow
 	
 	
 		and i
 		or they starve because they can't eat
 	
 	
 		or drowned
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's that's yeah that's that's terrible i mean i like seals
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		terrific
 		well they showed one baby <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> that had been caught up in some uh plastic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it starved to death it couldn't it couldn't swallow it was pitiful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's what it bothers me the same thing about uh netting tuna they they get so many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>
 		and
 	
 	
 		well they're suppose to have be working towards around that
 	
 	
 		and i
 		well they keep saying that but i'll tell you i i saw a program not too many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> ago
 		i think it was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Entertainment</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Discovery</ENAMEX> one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and they're talking about all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are making uh all these boast that you know we're dolphin free and all that kind of stuff and they just they showed them to be absolute liars
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah because you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starkist</ENAMEX> they don't go out there and catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> they buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> from other people
 	
 	
 		sure so
 	
 	
 		and and and all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do is tell them oh no no no no we have we have these safety nets now
 	
 	
 		trust us it's our nets everything's great go back sleep and don't worry
 	
 	
 		sure
 		that's right trust us
 		yeah they had some they had some uh
 		uh undercover film of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they they netted oh i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they killed probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		oh that's just sickening
 	
 	
 		yeah it is i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well and the other thing uh we have an endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species turtle</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ridley</ENAMEX>'s turtle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas Gulf Coast</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's our shrimp nets are suppose to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> proof so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> can swim through
 	
 	
 		um right right
 	
 	
 		huge fight going on
 		uh the shrimpers just say great you want us to put a big hole in our nets is that what you want us to do  this makes sense to us we're starving to death anyway and you want us to put a hole in our nets i can see their point
 		i i guess if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were terribly hungry i wouldn't be as humanistic as i am because i don't have that problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's it's really a hard hard issue to say what's right and what's not
 	
 	
 		well i think what they need to do is to come up with a better way of shrimp farming
 	
 	
 		oh this is
 	
 	
 		i m ean there's there's i i don't see any reason why they can't uh i mean there's a lot of places <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for instance have shrimp <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> i mean they they they raise shrimp
 	
 	
 		like they raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		just just like they raise anything else and and you can do it and the uh the the collection is very easy
 		and you don't go around killing everything else that happens to be in the area
 	
 	
 		well part of the problem there is so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> work for so little money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fisher</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and yet they support their whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on less than than i'd had for lunch
 	
 	
 		on fishing yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course they don't have the money to make an investment like that
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's
 	
 	
 		and it it all goes back to the government spending enough money high enough priorities on things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they it would have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> owned or supported financed if not controlled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there because the financing simply isn't there
 		because it's one of those cottage industries that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		the very poor keep going but can't do anything to change
 	
 	
 		yeah is right yeah they're they're they're in it for a matter of survival not
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		not environmentalist
 	
 	
 		well and you know they could they could be terribly sorry they're killing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they they probably are i
 	
 	
 		probably are probably are
 	
 	
 		of course i don't understand why they don't if they're going to kill them they might as well eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> too and
 	
 	
 		well they may do it
 	
 	
 		they probably do i mean
 		
 
 	
 	
 		whether they like it or not they may do it you know
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> is good
 	
 	
 		yeah that's correct <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> is very good that's the other thing wrong with the poor turtles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> didn't know it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> at the time because i wouldn't have eaten it but
 	
 	
 		well in my unreformed days i have had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">turtle soup</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and i can tell you it's fabulous
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		but of course a boot would taste fabulous when they finish with it
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's true
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it's no telling what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> really taste like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well hopefully it's real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		well it maybe it wasn't you know who who knows what i had but it was fabulous
 	
 	
 		yeah you well that's that's the other thing i mean you never know what they're putting in there you know  oh this is turtle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> you know okay
 	
 	
 		great sure it is
 	
 	
 		sure right
 	
 	
 		charge fifteen keep moving
 	
 	
 		yeah why not give it a fancy name and put a high price tag on it
 	
 	
 		as long as it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's probably it's probably Campbells or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh dear well i don't have any my big solutions all go back to elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> that are more sensitive because i think we can't do it ourselves
 	
 	
 		no i i no no i don't think we will because you need you need some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for it and
 	
 	
 		you need clout
 	
 	
 		yeah and the problem the problem i mean we've got all these environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> but they're all pulling in different directions and it's the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> results is is just a nullity nobody's getting anything done
 		and and i think there needs to be a concerted effort you know say okay here's a problem we're going to do this and you put all your resources here and we're going to do this and you put your resources here something like that i mean just
 	
 	
 		it'd be great but the problem with that is you have all of these little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> off the main problem and everyone is very concerned about one thing
 		you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> down the tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that that
 		calls her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> and kisses everyone of them everyday she's terribly interested in her turtles she could care less about shrimp
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and on she goes you just kind of think everybody's got such a splintered interest
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's what that's what i mean about all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> they're so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's exactly it
 	
 	
 		yeah they're so uh
 	
 	
 		and there's no way to to to make one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> more interested or sensitive to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> but they can be but they're not sensitive on the bottom line which means money
 	
 	
 		they
 		yeah i mean would i mean you'd ideally they would all combine together and pool there resources and and
 		and then they could have their agenda for all these different problems and come up with solutions but i mean you know work at it as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> not as a little group
 		just they just don't get anywhere
 	
 	
 		that's why i keep going back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> that it has to have some focal spot
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		we we need uh we need an environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah somebody to pull the whole thing together to make it work
 	
 	
 		gee
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean we we've been at this for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> now and just and just and nothing's happening
 		
 		
 	