
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um do you have a credit card
 	
 	
 		oh  who doesn't have credit cards
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> um i i did have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and
 		the i found that um it just made me spend a little more so when i paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them off i got rid of it now i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> only have one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know i always used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that would put something on and pay the bill right out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now i've after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Christmas</TIMEX> it seems the last few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmases i</ENAMEX> used it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and i'm still paying it off
 	
 	
 		oh i know it's it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> is the worst time for i just have to leave them at home uh because the impulse buying is just terrible
 	
 	
 		i don't know i consider myself pretty good but sometimes i can go out and i can i can over overspend my budget i guess i can afford it but it is it's a pain paying it off
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i i don't i don't know um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i had uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred dollars</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and i've put saved up enough money where i'm going to bring it down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and hopefully i can keep it around there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh that's good that's really good
 	
 	
 		yeah i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have i mean fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars two thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know
 	
 	
 		but um
 		i don't know i never i never liked loans a lot so i'm not a heavy credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX> that she probably has <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> credit cards so
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh i i i know i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are just uh uh uh uh are addicted to their credit cards
 		and they've just gotten themselves so much in trouble financially with with them
 		it's it it's just unreal i guess
 		i guess
 	
 	
 		i know it's easy to do especially if you if you have a job where you have to buy nice clothes and things
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it it i think that is the biggest problem when you really not you don't
 		don't really need the stuff but the nicer looking clothes are the more expensive nicely tailored clothes
 	
 	
 		oh of course
 	
 	
 		even though you could probably get away with a cotton dress you got to go out and buy the rayon dress or something you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you got to be they say you have to dress for success
 	
 	
 		yeah plus uh uh when you get uh uh credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> send you things in the mail all the time
 		you know uh get please get get get and you're already preapproved and all this other kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they just try to uh to to get you to get uh have their credit card and um um uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six half a dozen</NUMEX> isn't enough
 	
 	
 		how many credit cards do you have
 	
 	
 		oh i have one we uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master Card</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's pretty good
 		yeah my oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> won't even put his name on it i don't believe in those
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's like but the time we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and needed to rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> you know he believed in it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you've got to have a credit card to rent a car
 	
 	
 		yes you do uh-huh yes you do yes you do and that that
 		uh down here you have to have a credit uh you just can't live without it
 		because down here they don't take a check unless you got credit card and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license identification
 	
 	
 		yep that's right up here at some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> if it's if you're not in your home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> you have to show them a credit card
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it's it's just a another form of identification you know just to
 	
 	
 		well actually if your check bounces i guess they could legally take it off your credit card if that's why they're taking it i mean i don't know how fair that is
 	
 	
 		uh oh yeah they can
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know um
 		yeah i guess that percentage rates are like eighteen percent
 	
 	
 		well uh uh ours is ours is through our our credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and it's thirteen so it's
 	
 	
 		yeah thirteen that's not bad
 	
 	
 		that's not that's really good compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen and twenty one</NUMEX> which some of them are uh uh some of them are really extreme high
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's uh
 	
 	
 		and yeah then you have to pay your fee and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> you're really it's not a credit card because you have to pay it off at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX> but the fee for that it's really expensive isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is it i i don't know we don't uh we don't
 	
 	
 		i've never had one
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has one for to for uh for business
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> card
 		but he's never had to use it so we don't get any get any get anything uh for it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		i mean we would if we used it we would get it and then uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would reimburse any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> expenses on it but so far he's never had to use it so we don't know anything about the billing
 	
 	
 		yeah if he they they they have you pay it right out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		do they uh uh ooh
 	
 	
 		yeah because it's uh
 	
 	
 		that could get you in awful lot of trouble
 	
 	
 		i know especially if your uh
 		your reimbursement didn't come through
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> because i know they i don't know why but you can use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> and they give you an itemized bill and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can use that i don't know why you can't use other credit cards for business that way
 	
 	
 		i i don't i don't know i think it's uh just a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't know if it's easy for them to get or or or what but um
 		uh but i guess it's it's run so much different from the other ones
 	
 	
 		yep this is this is it actually kind a boring subject in credit cards
 	
 	
 		hum
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you really you just know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> abuse them but not a joke about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who pays their Master Card off with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i bet you there i bet you there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do that
 	
 	
 		oh i i i'm sure there are i mean uh
 	
 	
 		you go get a cash advance on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> credit card to pay the other
 	
 	
 		you take
 		oh gee oh gee oh gee
 	
 	
 		they i think they charge more for cash advances so
 	
 	
 		do they um it's it's some cards you you can do that and some cards you can't down here
 		i think it just depends on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> will take
 		plus
 	
 	
 		well it yeah you can't get cash advances
 	
 	
 		oh so on on uh on some cards
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i saying through my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> they they since they have their own card they don't like to give advances through other for other cards
 	
 	
 		oh well no uh it  i think that's a really bad plan in your budgeting if you have to pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> card off with another oh eventually eventually
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that that doesn't solve anything
 	
 	
 		no it doesn't
 	
 	
 		that just
 	
 	
 		be solid for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> then you get both bills back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		because it's still there
 		it's just some place else  now
 	
 	
 		i know i don't
 		credit cards almost seem unfair to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's who's got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of impulse buying
 	
 	
 		oh yeah store credit cards
 	
 	
 		like unfair advertising or something
 	
 	
 		store credit cards are even higher interest rate than say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master Card</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
 		because i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neiman Marcus</ENAMEX> card for a while
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i used it once and then i cut up because the interest rate was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost twenty three</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so i i cut i cut that thing up
 	
 	
 		so also when you give give someone a credit card like a normal credit card like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that um business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> loses <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> because i used to work in a business and we always and we used to lose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> on the credit card orders
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's the thing if if a business is taking a credit card they're really they sacrificing something too it seems the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> makes money all the way around
 	
 	
 		yeah i also was going to say they get it from both ends
 	
 	
 		because it is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> that they take
 	
 	
 		uh i didn't know
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> percent
 		i don't know which put you in better rating yep because when i used to go to the bank
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i used to take it off the deposit
 	
 	
 		oh how awful
 	
 	
 		yeah you do have to take it off your deposit
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah so it is a a service that they're offering
 	
 	
 		yeah oh boy those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are making money hand over fist
 	
 	
 		i i know should own stock
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there instead of these uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> going that are folding but
 	
 	
 		but everybody's really trying to you know it's become a real national problem credit card debt
 		and and i we've really cut
 	
 	
 		i wonder how much is numbers how many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> it's got to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		it it is it is it they uh uh you hear a lot about how much uh uh shaky the economy is just because of personal debt
 		and what they're talking about is credit cards
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's uh probably true
 		i mean you have the principal debt the car loan and your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> loan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then there's all the merchandise you buy on your credit cards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they count uh
 		mortgages as personal debt
 	
 	
 		that's personal
 		maybe they don't
 	
 	
 		i don't i'm not sure that they do i think uh
 		what they're talking about like is uh credit cards and other junk and loan car loans things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because uh
 		boy i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids people</ENAMEX> right out of college the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to get you
 		because because they uh they spend they use the credit cards real easily and real freely and then they get in real  trouble
 	
 	
 		i know i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX> she just got married out of college and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had taken confiscate her credit cards
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i don't know it's probably they're always saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are doing are the spending ones
 		but i haven't heard one uh a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> taking their credit card away from the man
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i i definitely want to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> paid off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month to month</TIMEX> like i used to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and just as soon as i get it paid off i'll probably get laid off
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		terrible can't afford my credit card anymore
 	
 	
 		oh i know it you become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> to your plastic
 		
 		
 	