
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		um
 		i i understand that it's being proposed as a requirement for uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to go into public service i think
 	
 	
 		yes all all young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> they did not specify you know exactly what young means
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think that it probably would be a a good program i think probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> is too long i think maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> would be the the longest that
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah probably you're probably right yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> is might be a little too long
 	
 	
 		yeah and you there will be a lot of rebellion in that and when you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have no desire to be there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place i don't think that they're gonna be serving anybody
 	
 	
 		that's right that
 		that would be the problem
 	
 	
 		yeah so i think it would be a good thing though to encourage other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who aren't even aware that they can do such a thing
 	
 	
 		sure would
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to get out there and do so
 	
 	
 		yeah or maybe offer them you know some sort of an incentive to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you know college credit you know something you know i'm not sure what but i
 	
 	
 		right right college credit is a good idea because
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure they need to be you know paid you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super</ENAMEX> do salary of any kind that that kind of takes away from public service
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right yeah they probably couldn't do anything monetary but i think giving giving some kind of college credit
 	
 	
 		but just you know to receive a letter in the mail that says you know you need to report somewhere by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX> you know i'm not sure that would be a terrifically good idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no i don't think so either because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um  depending on how the public service programs are set up and i'm not that that familiar with them to know
 	
 	
 		i'm not either really
 	
 	
 		but you know if  a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> flat can't afford to you know that and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> have gotten themselves into um financial situations where they have to be working all the time
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right absolutely then you'll you'll
 	
 	
 		so it's it's a really tough question
 	
 	
 		young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> whatever they just they just couldn't you know take off to do that
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah and if you put them in public service right out of high school then that's that postpones their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and that would upset a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too because they just wanna get on
 	
 	
 		only
 		that's right um-hum
 		um-hum sure would there would have to be a lot of you know thought given to something like that i would think
 	
 	
 		yeah i you know i think it it would be good for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to get involved in that kind of program but i i i think it can't be something that's mandatory it has to be something that's voluntary you know which is a pretty much the way it is now they might
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 		yep
 		that's right i'm not even really sure this point in time you know what what programs are out there
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's the other thing is that  you know instead of making it mandatory they maybe maybe need to publicize it a little bit better and and uh you know go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do programs and tell them that we need your help and you know uh uh volunteer for such and such a time and you you have a choice of where you wanna go and and and that way handling it that way they could probably get some results out of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		like maybe if if there was something you know they could do in their own own you know their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or city
 	
 	
 		yeah in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah and not to have to pull up roots and you know and go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">somewhere half</NUMEX> way around the world or something
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true  most of them probably wouldn't do something like that although there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who would do it just to get away from their parents
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah that's that's true too that's true too but
 	
 	
 		but they would have to be supportive in some way and i'm not sure those those programs are available to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah me either and you you wonder you know what kind of quality job would they do you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		just sit around for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their year</TIMEX> or would they really you know make a contribution of some kind
 	
 	
 		right exactly that's
 	
 	
 		yep it's tough it's tough
 	
 	
 		yeah it is tough it's and and i don't know who's even proposing it or or how they plan on implementing it if they do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i'm i'm not sure either
 		but i think there would have to be a lot more you know information uh you know disseminated before you say let's do this you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> would be the easiest for them you know it'd be it it wouldn't take up much much it would take up more time than anything but it wouldn't take up a lot of money they wouldn't have to spend money advertising and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum yeah
 		yep that's right
 	
 	
 		you go to school and you have a kind of a captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> you get them all in the auditorium and you you know give them your speech and maybe a little slide show or something and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that they could get some results from that because there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are volunteer and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> minded but they don't know where to go to to to do anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		yeah that's a real waste too it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it really is
 	
 	
 		i don't really see the emphasis on things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> like we you know we saw back i guess in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> that was that was a big thing with him
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i guess even back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> may be the one that actually started the thing or was it you know really interested in things like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i just don't hear much about it anymore like i say i don't even know what programs are are even ongoing now you know
 	
 	
 		i don't either
 		that's what
 	
 	
 		anyway it's a tough question really is you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it is a tough question
 	
 	
 		okay well thanks for your time enjoyed talking to you okay take care bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure same here take you too bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	