
 
     		
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		hi this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Smith</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Crow</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Crow</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Jerry</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		where where you from
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blacksburg Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> golly
 	
 	
 		right down uh southwestern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the mountains
 	
 	
 		oh i had first had thought this was just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> but apparently it's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no no they've uh got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> apparently any all over the country
 	
 	
 		yeah i've talked to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from Attleboro
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh several of those people
 	
 	
 		are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> employee
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewisville</ENAMEX> which is just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well our topic is uh TV shows you ready to get started
 	
 	
 		well
 		TV shows
 	
 	
 		yeah what we like about them our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i guess i am
 	
 	
 		okay i'll go ahead and punch one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay fine
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i guess my favorites are probably the the uh news format programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Copy Sixty Minutes Twenty Twenty uh Current Affair</ENAMEX> things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we watch a lot of that also we watch uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then i think one of my favorite shows is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we don't have cable unfortunately so we just get but we've got plenty of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> to look at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		uh we have cable here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		about the only reason i would want cable probably is is for some of the uh sports programs
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		that they don't show local
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSEN ESPN</ENAMEX>
 		but the music movie show uh cables or movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> they show the same shows over and over and over
 	
 	
 		well that's right and we never have signed up for those i just haven't been interested in what they generally have on and
 	
 	
 		um
 		and they're usually
 	
 	
 		would be just as happy not to have them in the house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh do you have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no nope we uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s grown in fact we've just been retired for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> we took early retirement and
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh
 	
 	
 		just really enjoying ourselves
 	
 	
 		i wished i could do that i've been <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah but i'm only fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		so i've still got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> to go
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> he's fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> older than that time goes by
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but he was with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> fa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and decided he'd had enough of it
 	
 	
 		well i've had enough of it but unfortunately they don't pay enough
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for early retirement
 	
 	
 		do you still have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh no all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are grown married
 	
 	
 		right
 		well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI uh</ENAMEX> on a part time basis so that's how we found out about this calling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		but uh
 		every once in a while i like to watch some of the old movies i watched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> movie last night
 	
 	
 		um-hum well we watched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACC</ENAMEX> play-offs or i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah uh in in fact it's on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		rooting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX> rooting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it ought to be a good uh good game tonight
 	
 	
 		yeah that's on
 		right it's on again tonight
 	
 	
 		it it doesn't start until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock our</TIMEX> time so we still got another hour
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		are you all behind what time is it there it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> here now
 	
 	
 		it's uh
 		it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX> here right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock so</TIMEX> you all are behind us
 	
 	
 		right we've just been watching the national news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i wish our time were like yours and then we could get i like to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX> and watch the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX> news but it makes it so late
 	
 	
 		yeah makes it so late well we're fixing to go on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight saving time uh next this next</TIMEX> weekend
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think we do to
 	
 	
 		so we have to run our clocks up forward <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and i sure do hate to loose <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that hour</TIMEX> of sleep in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hate it too i just would rather stay the way it is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		but uh
 		well i guess like like like i said my favorite show what's your favorite shows or you like the news formats
 	
 	
 		i like i like the i like some of the dramas
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		shows
 		and i like mysteries
 	
 	
 		yeah i like uh the true life adventures too
 	
 	
 		but
 		uh-huh we like uh
 		we get the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial News Network</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we like to watch that check up on what's happening with all the stocks and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i don't uh watch too much of the of the uh network shows i all i like to watch uh
 		let's see some of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the uh prime time</TIMEX> shows that i like to watch like i said or other news formats but then every once in a while i'll watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Search</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but uh
 		not too many of the situatio n comedies do i care for
 	
 	
 		no i don't care for those
 	
 	
 		and i'm definitely not a soap fan
 	
 	
 		too much
 		the only crazy comedy i  really like is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah or uh i
 	
 	
 		do you ever watch that
 	
 	
 		yeah and i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Totally Hidden Video</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		uh-huh we don't watch that much
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super</ENAMEX> uh what is it uh
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloopers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Super Practical Jokes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stay at home and watch <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX> and get involved in them but
 	
 	
 		no i don't either i just don't have any interest
 	
 	
 		i guess plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		yeah they had a program on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were addicted to soap operas
 	
 	
 		yeah in fact i think you can even uh order a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that keeps you up to date <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> of what happened on every particular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> in case you miss it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		that that's not real life to me so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		no i think it'd be an awful waste of time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i enjoyed talking with you and
 	
 	
 		well enjoyed it too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		and how how's you all's weather up there you cold
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it was pretty chilly and windy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the sun was out bright but it was kind of cold
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess it was probably in the fifties but there's a strong wind
 	
 	
 		well you
 		yeah did you have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		very nice we had company  very nice
 	
 	
 		yeah we did too
 		i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> i sure do wish they'd gave us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> off rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> off
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> was really busy
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you had company
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and then we went and visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and and uh didn't get i don't guess we got to bed till <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and then having to get up and go to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah that makes it hard
 	
 	
 		well you have a good day
 	
 	
 		well you too good TV viewing
 	
 	
 		oh okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	