
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh tell me about changes from say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> since you were an adult <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well let's see well we assume i was an adult <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>  um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you're you're able to you're able to uh vote and go to war and things like that so
 	
 	
 		uh yeah definitely able to go to war <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> but not vote not vote that was one of the changes that came about in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> um yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> was nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">seventy uh nineteen seventy i</ENAMEX> had been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's right that's one of the changes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um we had all the great civil rights legislation of nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty eight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh around here on the uh east coast uh we were heavy into affirmative action
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh that was a uh a great shock for a lot of people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh a great disappointment for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i was gainfully employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway Stores Incorporated</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh trying desperately to uh get ahead with the company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the problem was that my hair was too long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that you weren't allowed to have a uh mustache or a beard and uh you know jeans just flat out weren't allowed unless you worked on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> stock and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you wanted to get ahead with the company <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> if you were a uh black female you were destined to be store <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six to nine months</TIMEX> if you were white male you're talking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and that's basically where i ended up i uh i just flat out couldn't get a hold you know get ahead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> because they were dead in affirmative action um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on other fronts um
 	
 	
 		and is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> now uh well represented uh demographically at the higher echelons did it work
 	
 	
 		um i think so i i i i stopped working for them in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uh seventy eight seventy nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh  it's i think they're they're like all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> well represented and uh you know everything seems to be fine i i've kind of lost touch with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> we had a falling out but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as far as uh as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> goes um i'm not sure they're any any better off than they were were before management wise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh other changes um
 		just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to be more
 		outspoken now individually rather than collectively um back in the seventies we had uh a lot of uh protests against the war and uh bring our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> home and things were more organized
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i've noticed that
 		now more and more individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are speaking out for their own rights rather than massing together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so there's less you think now there's less of a a social movement and more individual movements lots of individual movements in a sense
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not sure if that was because you know eighties was like the uh the me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> and uh everybody was into me and then we are getting back into us but um it it
 	
 	
 		the me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		it's i've seen uh
 		uh a great deal of change as far as um
 		corporate responsibility and things um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s response to that you know at first not trusting and now expecting more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what about what about the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> that you've been aware
 	
 	
 		well that i've been aware of i've
 		at least in my own circles i've been aware of an increasing from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> i don't know if i can quite call myself a distinct generation from you but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> generation off i guess um
 		i've noticed uh
 		a certain increase um pessimism with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> no longer being sort of on top i had the impression
 		
 
 		well i mean there was the quote unquote losing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> which was a blow and it was right around that time when i started becoming socially you know a socially conscious adult and
 		i realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of my age have no um
 		no major success in the sense that uh you saw the passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX> and um major social change in that sense and i
 		and all the changes that have happened in the last uh even during my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adulthood</ENAMEX> have been more incremental
 		they've been continual perhaps and good gains have been made but there hasn't been the same sort of fiery speeches of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> or whatever that has really uh galvanized the population
 		and there's just instead there's been sort of an increasing oh i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> bashing and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh a lot of i see
 		among some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and even more among some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are you know maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> a real sense of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s losing it
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and losing it in the competitive market and a real knowledge uh a lack of understanding how that could be
 		and in the sense that how could <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have gone from being number one to possibly being number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to you know our former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and things like that and um
 		so i see i see a lot of uh a lot of pessimism growing um
 		and at the same time i think there's there's there's a growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX> movement
 		and sense of corporate responsible increased corporate responsible towards uh you know environmental safety and things like that and that might potentially be sort of the civil right the equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX> in in the near future
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in terms of you know some real landmark bills passing and things like that such that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cause thing about civil rights is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take it for granted now i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> doesn't
 		can't rest on the the glow of having achieved civil rights because we were born into an assumption that you know yes there's still some racism but
 		you know basically things are the assumption things are basically kind of taken care of and there's a notion of fairness that um while still far from perfect is much more established i think
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but even uh i think uh along the line of the uh goals of civil rights um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there always seems to be some prejudice to someone by anyone i mean you know
 	
 	
 		oh of course  it's human nature
 	
 	
 		you know don't like the way you look don't like the way you dress don't like your hair don't like you know it's just something that always sets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off you know you either like someone or you don't like someone or you're just completely indifferent
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and the problem is that ideally you they you know the world would like you to be completely indifferent so um but i i i understand what you say about the environmental movement um
 		it's it's been a long time coming um being a uh a very old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yes
 	
 	
 		i mean you know if you had long hair in high school in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> you got labeled a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> and you keep that image your whole life  no matter what you do and i i just
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i've seen a lot of changes i mean from the original earth day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i'm heavily involved in you know my own personal recycling we recycle paper and cans here at work and you know i do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and cardboard and paper and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know all that stuff at home and i'm starting to see more and more recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> cropping up all over the place here on the east coast
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  r ight
 		and that's a real change except it sort of brings back to the nineteen forties more than anything else  i mean all this recycling used to be in tact or not all of it but much of it did i mean recycling was a was a wartime thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		like
 		yeah
 		and then they
 		turned around and called them junkyards and started making profits off them after the war
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and now we got to the point where the junkyards you've got to pay them to take something there so things have really changed a lot i think the uh the other part about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s decline i think has to do with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		a perceived decline anyway yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah the perceived decline has to do with uh um the attitudes and the educational system
 		uh i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in in school i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school right now</TIMEX> and i'm not impressed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that are teaching them uh i had when i was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> i had uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> come home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with papers that were corrected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that had words spelled correctly marked wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and words spelled wrong not marked as such
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s teaching my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i had a real problem with that
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'd i'd say actually i mean as someone who's involved in education i'd say that maybe one of the changes is that the
 		role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> has incrementally gotten lower and lower value and society i mean relative pay which is a major way we value <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> has been
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		poorer and poorer over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> uh you know that there's been cost of living increases but not quite in proportion to cost of living and you know it's just more and more uh
 		a real low income sort of job and very low prestige i mean there's that that old saying those who can do it and those who can't teach this is the way of let's make fun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> those are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't do anything and if you have that kind of social attitude it's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hard to get sufficient numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are going to overlook all of that work for lower pay work for low social prestige just because they care about good education
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you get more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would just end up there because it's uh it's the safety net of those of you know average intelligence or something they can always teach
 	
 	
 		um i'm not sure if your familiar with the movement they have here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> but they're trying to get a uh a uh
 		a merit system here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> rather than a uh tenure system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for all the you know elementary middle school and high schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that the teach
 		
 		
 	