
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Mary</ENAMEX> have you gone visiting uh any new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> lately
 	
 	
 		hi
 		well i haven't been to any new ones but i have uh several that i frequent uh mainly because of specialties in foods
 		and i have so many  so many
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foods</ENAMEX> that i prefer uh that i enjoy such as oriental foods i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> food but i like all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i i tend to get stuck in in and i find a place that i like and i stay there um i  some of the things i like are atmosphere um
 	
 	
 		ah sounds familiar
 	
 	
 		food price um but mostly i think you know service and atmosphere are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things that you know i don't minds paying little bit if if i don't have to wait too long to eat and if the service is good the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is good
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i find like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> places that i'm going to now um
 		because whenever you find a place that's good other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have already already found the same kind of a place and so sometimes i have to go to this place in uh where i know i have to wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least fifteen minutes</TIMEX> sometimes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um they have little bar there so we sit there and um sipping on some mixed drinks before we get to eat
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds uh very much like one of our very very best places to get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they open at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and if your not there at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> you'll probably have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> wait
 	
 	
 		wow okay So this
 	
 	
 		and they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> also which is always crowded as can be  but it's it's an specially fine restaurant and when you consider they take no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> or checks
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		strictly cash and they've been in business oh for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> uh that's they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh they must have some good food there
 	
 	
 		yes yes it it's their their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> are exquisite they also have uh excellent uh liver which i happen to like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um those are the two specialties which they have that and their stewed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> which are well known all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		uh i had uh an opportunity to visit visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area and uh i went to some steak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> while i was out there and there was this one place that i visited that was really unique The waitresses were dressed like little cowgirls
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and the i don't remember the name of the place but for a menu all they had was a it was like a wooden block
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and um i think for food they had steak and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>  and they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different sizes of steak The cowboy the cowgirl and the
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i forget the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other one</NUMEX> the he-man or something like this and um and i i i found it uh to be very good The atmosphere was good it was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes right well one of the nicer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> supposedly that opened up here not uh too very long ago called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harbor Lights</ENAMEX> specializes in fish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh the atmosphere is fantastic and i was there with it's a group um
 		that uh we were having a going away dinner for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and there were twelve of us and i the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that uh we ordered each of us was quite good but the service was horrendous
 	
 	
 		oh no kidding
 	
 	
 		and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> never once came behind me um um on our side of the table she reached across the table she never once asked if we wanted coffee we had to grab onto someone else they didn't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		refill our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> glasses um someone had only eaten a portion of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and wanted to take it home and asked to have it boxed and she just pitched it out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then when she finally did bring something um to replace that she practically threw it at the person
 	
 	
 		oh that's too bad see how <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> place <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can make a big difference on whether you go back to the place again
 	
 	
 		yes and
 		oh absolutely what made me angry was that when there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as ours there were twelve of us they automatically put the tip on the bill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow okay
 	
 	
 		and i'll tell you we had some very unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were so unhappy with the service and resented paying fifteen percent tip when they had such poor service
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that's really that's really too bad i had um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place that i enjoyed going to but my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> didn't like it and then i had asked her about it and she said um
 	
 	
 		but
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that the reason why she didn't like it was that she felt that the place wasn't cleaned well um they had um younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know wiping the tables down and they weren't very
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yes right right
 	
 	
 		well trained i guess and they didn't do a very neat job in cleaning the tables off and when the waitresses came they she just put all of the clean utensils and everything right on top of these dirty tables
 	
 	
 		oh  well it one thing that gets me is when you see them do putting out the um the um knives forks and what have you and when they put them down they hold them by the edge that you are going to put in your mouth
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and that really up sets me when i see that
 	
 	
 		i i can certainly understand that in fact in this same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> doesn't like to go to she um she frequently finds food
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		struck onto the utensils as where she's got to go through uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> uh different um utensils and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the the waitresses</TIMEX> are very nice they'll they'll keep exchanging it
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes but yeah
 	
 	
 		but they don't look you know like she had complained about it one time and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> said she was sorry she picked up these utensils and and when back and grabbed some new ones and then put the new ones back down and the new ones looked worse than the ones that she took away so she is not even looking you know and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		no no and actually you know those are the kind of things that should get taken back to the management
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um because the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the the waitresses</TIMEX> have no control over the the way the dishes are and cleaned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and if they're not cleaned off well when they go threw the dishwasher <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> just doesn't always get washed off and it sticks on there and then when they dry them
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um if they air dry them or heat dry them it dries it right on it and that's terrible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah i agree the management should know about it but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> should especially if you ask them to take something back to look at the ones that she's uh bringing over to you instead of just grabbing a handful and bring them over again
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i agree with that but just don't ever get a glass that has lipstick on it oh that is terrible i had that happen only once i don't remember where but it's always
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time enough for me to be aware of the situation and i look at every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> that i get
 	
 	
 		how about fast food do you enjoy um fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't mind that um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> never cared for fast food so we didn't go that often but you know i have no problem with uh going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> or uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Long</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Silver</ENAMEX>'s or any of those once in a while not often but once in a while
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah yeah i enjoy it once in a while but i enjoy relaxing while i eat you can't really do that in these fast food places
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		that's that's very true now once in a while if there's a good ballgame like there's going to be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>  with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX> and uh um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Kansas</ENAMEX> uh cause see now i would enjoy having a pizza
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just sit and watch the game and a have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> that i would enjoy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> at a
 		at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or at home
 	
 	
 		no no at ho me just have it delivered yeah we we have number of our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> places deliver and i assume that you have that there also
 	
 	
 		at home oh yeah
 		we're just beginning with that it um it took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the pizza <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and i think it was um gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domino's</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to start yes
 	
 	
 		yeah right after they started i guess the other uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> lost money and they all began doing the same thing
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		uh we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>'s we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX> and then we have a couple of other smallers
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Ceasars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX> they're all in the general <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> where i live and so i can and then yet my most favorite one doesn't deliver
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we have
 		no which one is that
 	
 	
 		uh it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX> but i think it is local
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and the
 	
 	
 		yeah we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popaginos</ENAMEX> did you ever here of Popaginos
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		okay we have a that's a fairly large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Popaginos um</ENAMEX> and they had not been delivering up until the time where uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domino's</ENAMEX> began delivering and within a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> they started up there own delivery service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah that makes a big difference well we have a lot of businesses going out of business
 		uh in this area and i don't know whether it's necessarily uh nationwide
 		but many of the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i can't compete with some of the larger ones and they are all going under
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it would seem to me that if that if i owned a business the thing that i would want to do is a is a get little survey uh like we're doing with each other and and encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to give that information back to the management
 	
 	
 		yes yes absolutely
 	
 	
 		and then maybe somehow turn what ever negatives around into a positive
 	
 	
 		well i um uh i've been retired from education for uh oh what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> and i do i have a bunch of had i should say a bunch of little jobs such as a sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate um</ENAMEX>  of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		specialty dress <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and um i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> part-time at a card and gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> as well as teaching in a modeling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and modeling so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> just went out of business we've been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year almost two years</TIMEX> but uh and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> was precious everyone liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> they liked the kinds of cards and what have you but the location was so poor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and it was in a shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> that had a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one end</TIMEX> that took them almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> to really get that going and that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> filled up
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> selected the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in the middle strip
 		and there's still no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> on either side and it's been over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a half yes and and it's sad because it was it was a nice store and she was such a lovely young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gal</ENAMEX> to work for i just feel very bad
 	
 	
 		oh that's too bad it
 		
 
 		um
 		
 		
 	