
 
     		
 	
 		so what do you think
 	
 	
 		uh the causes of crime  um  i think it was an imbalance of of power in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that's causing the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class class</ENAMEX> to rebel
 		that's why there's such such high crime in uh
 		there's crime in uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because they don't have real role models
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		see too much crime on TV and they think it's way to go
 		i don't know what do you think
 	
 	
 		what about
 		i agree with the upper and lower level you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because that's the lowest thing for themselves plus there's nobody for them to look up to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i also blame some of it on parents
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't parents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i remember even when i was growing up
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX>  i remember when i was growing up and i had friends
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that used to do stuff like you know go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and steal stuff my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> warned us it's like i don't care what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> do
 		if you do it then that was it i mean i knew that i would get mean more trouble from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> than from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		from anybody else
 	
 	
 		from anybody else and i think that's the basic is they have no morals anymore so they don't care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i can agree with that too
 	
 	
 		but now as far as what they can do about it i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you can't make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> be parents
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		you got to kind of make want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people wanna</ENAMEX> do the right thing
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i don't know how you do that
 	
 	
 		i guess if you gave the gave them jobs that that's another problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> there's no jobs anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i've heard this one theory that if you know if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> commits a crime that they've instead of the prosecuting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> they prosecute the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> or both of them
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		now put put the blame on the parent
 	
 	
 		that'll work to a point
 		well that'd work to a point because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are just bad anyway i don't care what you do to them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so i think it depends on how much trouble that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> has been in
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> can get into anything regardless i don't care who how good you they are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		eventually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> time but now if it's a repeated thing here with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in juvenile and all this to me yeah both of them because that means she's still not doing what she's supposed to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i just watched it on TV <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty Forty Eight Hours one</NUMEX> of them  shows where this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> had been stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you seen  they was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> a little it was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of them stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you know and then when they caught him you know his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> sitting there now they're gonna take me away from you that means she was warned
 	
 	
 		hm
 		no i didn't see it
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but see by that i think that sometimes it a little late
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but i'm sure there's something can be done
 	
 	
 		yeah what about with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> you think they can do anything about just adult regular adult crime
 	
 	
 		yeah start prosecuting they but really good instead of having a revolving door on the damn court system
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah huh for well the major problem with that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are overcrowded
 	
 	
 		well they should start with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> if they would get rid of seems to me i know there's a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't understand there's more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jail right now for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay  then there are for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing drugs
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		they ought to take all them little misdemeanor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> let them go let them go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know give them a fine whatever make them do civic duty whatever put them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> in there that's what they need to put i call i call them all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools idiots</ENAMEX> whatever little rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> put all them in there
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean seriously they ought to put those good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to work
 		yeah
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> put them all in jail you know and let all the normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you write a bad check you go to jail right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay let them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not let them go and get out of it let them go and pay their crime or their time doing something else
 	
 	
 		well they
 		yeah they you still have to punish
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like cleaning up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or however they do they community time you know whatever that is  but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's you know
 	
 	
 		put don't put them in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> because they're not hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and they're they're still they can
 		provide for society whereas some of them are so far gone that they can't do anything good for society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		i don't know them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people boy</ENAMEX> they got the i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has got too many problems to be worried about everybody else
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		now how they gonna fix it i don't know the i don't think there is a ready solution
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so either um
 	
 	
 		because the economy is down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know the the the low <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the pole is getting more of the i guess the bulk of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh he's gonna have to work extra hard just to make ends meet
 	
 	
 		and they keep taking more money from us yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and get and they don't have any incentive to work if we're just gonna take fifty percent of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they might as well steal it then they don't have to pay taxes on it
 	
 	
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know they i i know that's bad but you know the just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they could of had a lottery they don't want a lottery why not
 		i would rather pay for a lottery a dollar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two three</NUMEX> dollars whatever i'm paying you know a week or whatever
 	
 	
 		they'd have a
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and never see any of that money than to have them take a portion of my paycheck
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you know they take and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> takes his the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> which probably won't be here when i get that old you know
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		because we're payin g for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> they using now who's gonna pay for mine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah  but it's it's  nah you don't count on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> but it's it's that's what i'm saying they need to do something else
 	
 	
 		no i don't know  definitely
 		i'm not counting on it
 		yeah
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		crime is gonna go up as long as the economy stays down
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's gonna get worse that's just like last night they killed them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that store where you at
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh  no wonder you don't know then
 	
 	
 		why where are you from
 	
 	
 		they killed
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but last night  they killed uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a chain food
 	
 	
 		oh man
 	
 	
 		and killed them well it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> side by side
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and one was like a a fast food place i think it chicken or something i don't know  anyway they raped the women
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		beat them all up including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i mean they just beat them
 		stuffed them in the freezer and then shot them all
 	
 	
 		ow
 	
 	
 		now  why was you know  dumb
 	
 	
 		why did they do it in the freezer
 	
 	
 		you know why didn't they just if they was gonna lock just lock them in the freezer take the money you know they didn't have to kill them or rape them or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hm
 		hm
 		that's awful  yeah we still get some in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> i mean not not too often real bad ones but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's just getting really ridiculous down here i wish i could move somewhere where this you know you got to like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		i don't think there's anywhere where there isn't gonna be crime so
 	
 	
 		well i think if it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is smaller
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and everybody knows everybody it's harder to come in there and do something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		where is and and and see that's another thing neighborhoods aren't neighborhoods anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's nobody next door to you you don't know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just huh-uh  you know because i moved out some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> before because they were loaded with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and you didn't even and the what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> won't even do anything
 	
 	
 		he's probably <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> himself  never know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you don't and so i moved because i moved <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> blew up
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		you know and this is like across the street this was a nice part of town
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and then across the street one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> blew up because they were having that making that um
 		crack stuff and then the other time i saw the cops break down somebody's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> around the corner i said see this is it
 	
 	
 		hm
 		time to go
 	
 	
 		that's it and i moved and you know now i live in like a family a neighborhood in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouse</ENAMEX> but it's nice i don't you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i'm kind of in the same same kind of deal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouse</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		it's pretty nice
 	
 	
 		i don't know how they can let a neighborhood or apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> that's what happened that's what's wrong you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't think don't rent to them  or rent to them evict them because they drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> put it on the lease if you deal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you can't live here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		most of them too scared to do anything about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		all right well listen i got to go it's good talking to you
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alrighty</ENAMEX> and i thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		alrighty bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	