
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well do you have any good ideas about this problem
 	
 	
 		well i i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX> now which is of course very close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in fact my fiance works in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> uh downtown quite a bit so crime's a definite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> also before this i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> where the crime rate's also fairly high
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		so it it's definitely a concern something that needs to be worked on i know that it affects my everyday life in that uh you know my fiance is very paranoid about making sure everything's locked
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know it it also concerns me because i have a convertible and uh you know there's certain areas around here where i'd be afraid to drive with my top down
 	
 	
 		yeah well i have the same thing  and i understand because i live very close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		so we have quite a crime rate too but i'm not real sure what to do recently it's been kind of a topic at work and
 		um i just kind of feel that there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jail for crimes that are not really against a person
 		and i think maybe we need to find another way to punish those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and put the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> where they
 		really can't do any harm and not let them out on parole in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months or three years</TIMEX> or whatever and put them to work doing something useful where they don't just eat up our tax dollars
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and that's kind of what we've come up with  but i don't know what are your feelings about that
 	
 	
 		well i mean yeah except the the problem with that of course is defining what what's a real crime then you know what what's a crime that counts
 	
 	
 		right well a dangerous thing you know where you will get hurt if they're out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
 		i mean it i think this deal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leona Helmsley</ENAMEX> has just kind of brought this all home
 		and that's what kind of sparked the discussion was that this is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy seventy two year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> gonna go use up tax dollars in jail
 		and i just i just have a real problem with that i think there's another way to deal with that other than put this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in jail to set an example
 	
 	
 		but putting it that way that is kind of ironic that she'd be using up tax dollars but
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know that really is true
 	
 	
 		sure uh
 		however you know some of the crimes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to be locked up for are uh are uh you know not even things that would be major crimes but they'd still be dangerous for example uh drunken driving
 	
 	
 		well that's true well that is a potential danger though you're right about that but
 	
 	
 		you know but
 	
 	
 		um traffic tickets things like that i mean i've known of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just to be picked up because they didn't pay their traffic tickets and
 	
 	
 		you know but
 	
 	
 		i i say yeah fine them extra do whatever but to go ahead and put them in jail it costs us money when they do that
 		so i don't know i just have a problem with overcrowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> on crimes that nobody's really gonna get hurt uh financially maybe and and things like that and yes it has to be dealt with but i'm not sure that's the way
 	
 	
 		well that that that is true that the uh
 		amount of uh
 		you know it it is true that uh
 		you know jail as a concept at least is not working in some cases
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and also i think that they can get off on too many technicalities
 		i think that it turns out sometimes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are the ones that have to defend themselves rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and i think that's another thing that needs to be addressed too
 	
 	
 		i i think a
 	
 	
 		i think you have much many rights as a victim
 	
 	
 		sure
 		i i i think it's very sad however uh you know i i i can see some of that in that and i still don't necessarily agree with that but i mean that the thing is that uh you know
 		we're talking about affecting someone's you know livelihood sometimes their life even on some of the more heinous crimes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh uh
 		it's a
 		you know you according to the system we've got they're presumed innocent or get another trial
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so yeah they they do have to do some of that stuff although i do agree with you that it's
 		that's another thing that's not quite right
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so and
 		i don't know i i've been through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two year</TIMEX> divorce recently and i find that the system sucks to put it bluntly and so you know  i just i don't have a lot of respect anymore for what i thought you know would be fair you just figure oh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will be fair well
 		forget it  you know it's not it doesn't happen they're in a hurry their docket is full they want you in they want you out
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and that's the way it is and so
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> so i definitely understand that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		course in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are elected so um not only are they not fair they try to be popular at times
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know which is not necessarily right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i don't know but i don't know how you and i can solve this  that's the problem you know we all have ideas but nothing seems to change
 		and i'm not sure how it can
 	
 	
 		well uh i i think you had a part of what we need to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> is uh
 		
 		
 	