
 
     		
 	
 		so um how do you feel about the crime in your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> isn't too bad um i know that there's been some increases in crime lately in terms of murders um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's kind of gone up in scale and  and some other things um i personally had a little experience <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> uh somebody broke my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> window and stole a uniform out of my truck
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but actually you know when you look at at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> as compared to where i used to live it's really quite a bit better um because i came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> there's
 		crime is getting to be a bigger problem than ever
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> are you from
 		oh really i have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		here you know the real problems are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> related a lot of murders um just in general the whole we've only been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> uh before that we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> but in comparison to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> it's real noticeable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		i mean you can just feel i mean i can just sense i mean i won't even i won't go to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's
 	
 	
 		you know and it it's that kind of thing and uh
 	
 	
 		that's really a shame when it has to constrain your activities like
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a neighborhood watch program in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> um the development that we live in which i think is a great way to reduce um home theft burglary and things of that sort do you have that where you live or
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well um interestingly enough right before i moved up here i'm an intern and then i go back down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> before i moved up we had a real problem with it um we've been broken into in my apartment <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		in like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half weeks</TIMEX> and one of the things that i i helped organize was a neighborhood watch type situation down there um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they were just it's one of those things where the new thing is that they operate in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight</TIMEX> because everybody went to work you know and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> were left unguarded
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but yeah i think given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are pretty conscientious about it that's a good way to to work it with a neighborhood watch
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you know um also i've heard that uh the newest thing is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are  specializing in robbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> during the time they're home
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		like on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> a high percentage of uh free time i think it's like fifty percent of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s free time is uh spent doing yard work
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		outdoors so they wait while you're outsides outdoors they know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is unlocked and then they just slip in
 	
 	
 		that's amazing
 	
 	
 		slip in slip out you know they know exactly what they're going for so i've heard that's really on the rise as far as um you know a new type of crime
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 		yeah it almost seems like they're getting quite a bit smarter  really you know
 	
 	
 		yeah  unfortunately yes
 	
 	
 		yeah unfortunately it's starting to really you know look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s habits and where they are at particular points of the day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i work with really laughs when he looks at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> because he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		the the crime level there of course is quite a bit quite a bit uh more pronounced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		but uh
 		yeah i guess
 	
 	
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		i think we've got a neighborhood watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> i'm not real sure uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it helps to know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> you know they give you you're supposed to make lists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">um cars</ENAMEX> like i know a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> right around my development if i see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that's
 		unfamiliar we we have a list is that what you you did in your program where you have a list of license plates yeah
 	
 	
 		pretty much yeah i was i was basically involved in that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of it and then i left right in the middle of it i'm not sure where we went from there but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		yeah that that whole thing of being alert and kind of noticing your surroundings noticing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who look suspicious uh activities like that sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i mean you you hate to be paranoid but there are really only so many things you can do you can have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> alarm um neighborhood watch program
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know uh as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> not go out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night um</TIMEX> you can do that which is what i choose to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah one of the frustrating things about that is that you really are limited even even if you know that the threat is there it's against the law to set traps
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's against the law to do a lot of things you know they could basically um when i was getting robbed down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> i was really considering electrifying doors um things like that like they did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> that time
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's um-hum
 		but it's not um if you kill someone in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> as long as they're in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> it's considered self-defense though
 	
 	
 		that's not always true
 	
 	
 		it isn't
 	
 	
 		no there was a there was a case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> knew he was gonna get robbed
 		and essentially what he had done is set a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a electrocution</NUMEX> a electrocution trap
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the burglar in his own home the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> came in while he was home
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and sure enough he fell into the trap and was severely burned he didn't die but he was severely burned and he took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to court and won a settlement
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah so that really that makes you think you know it's like your hands are really very much tied
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i think if if you had handgun a handgun though in other words it wasn't premeditated you had a handgun it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> someone's downstairs
 		
 		
 	