
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have now
 	
 	
 		well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> well you do have a hard time finding time then don't you
 	
 	
 		right
 		well <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> are i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them are grown they're in college or just out of college so i really have just a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen year old</TIMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		um-hum you sound so young
 	
 	
 		well i work at it  i try to fool everybody  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		to have them uh
 		i think you're doing a good job i just have one child
 		and uh i don't think um well there's not much i can do about it my  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are uh in our forties you know so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's hard to raise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> without them thinking they're the they're the pivot point of the universe
 	
 	
 		i think you're right because i was an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> too and that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason i have so many  because i really i enjoyed the big family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen year old</TIMEX> is pretty separate from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and so she's sort of like an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and it's the same type of thing um
 	
 	
 		um-hum i have a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> like that i'm in my forties like i say and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his twenties</TIMEX> and i was i was the youngest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i understand how that worked and he was treated like he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		right that's exactly how it is you know she's got all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to take care of her when things don't go right she just calls one of them you know but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's a little bit difficult though i think it was easier when they all had each other and could entertain each other and i was home more and
 	
 	
 		did y'all do a lot of organized things like uh Little League <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh soccer</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		we we really did not my next oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's in college in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is a world twirling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> she twirls a baton
 		and we did a lot of things together she and i did a lot of things together and flew we've flown all over the world for her to compete and to perform
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was a lot of fun but that that i guess you could consider that organized i mean there's a competition all the time we were very heavy into that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		other than that they were pretty much and maybe dancing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for a while or mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> sports and things like that
 	
 	
 		you know i think that's probably true the  if you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or fewer you get involved in organized events or activities and if you have a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or then you don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you can't afford to
 	
 	
 		no you can't and there's not enough time um like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they practice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and they have a game and it's just uh if there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> i don't know there there would be no way to do it
 	
 	
 		right that's right
 	
 	
 		you know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> go in one direction and i'd have to go in the other and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we could only cover <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at that
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know i spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in the gym everyday with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and my little one also competed because really she had no choice she had to go with me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us just spent a lot of time traveling and and competing and of course the competing itself really didn't matter what it was it was making the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and going all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and
 		it was a really neat experience but it took our total time i did not work um when i did this now i do work full time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my thirteen year old</TIMEX> and myself and so we really have to keep it together to get just her activities in and still have time to spend with each other
 	
 	
 		i don't think although  i think a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is probably the ideal to me
 		but i'm not sure i could afford <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> i most certainly couldn't educate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>  i don't know how my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of us i don't recall you know wanting anything in particular uh but i don't know how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> did it he worked at a truck line and
 		he just didn't make that kind of money with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but we did okay we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and but now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both work and we don't i don't believe we have as much as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did
 		and we only have one child
 	
 	
 		really well things cost a lot more i don't know how it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and i don't think our part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is particularly bad compared to some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s horrible yes have we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> moving here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and and different areas and from talking to them they're shocked
 	
 	
 		is it
 		really
 	
 	
 		what and they you know the housing so cheap in comparison to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> that they jump on it they sell their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they stash away a good bit of money
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's what i've heard
 	
 	
 		and come down here and i work with a lot of them they they think they they've really done something then when they get down here they realize the cost of living is outrageous
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		compared to to where they came from the housing's cheaper but that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm surprised to hear that i've heard very positive things about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> everybody
 		
 		
 	