
 
     		
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh have you ever been tested for a new job or anything
 	
 	
 		um no i haven't but in my job i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and we are allowed to be i mean you know this is the rules that they can do this
 		anytime uh i don't know of anyone who ever has been picked out
 		and been tested
 	
 	
 		so it's just sort of um they can if they
 	
 	
 		they can if they choose to right
 	
 	
 		yeah oh okay
 	
 	
 		have you well what have you had any experience with it at all
 	
 	
 		um not really but i've always worked on a university level but a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had to be tested before they got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> jobs and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		um i don't
 		i don't think they're very accurate because i mean i know their lifestyles changed prior prior to the drug test and i know they changed afterwards
 	
 	
 		right right see i know of that too
 		and i also know that things like antihistamines Sudafed things like that can really throw it off and you cannot get a job
 		because of it and they may not tell you the reason why
 	
 	
 		yeah i i had a friend
 		it didn't cause her any problems with her job but it came back that she tested positive for using a hallucinogen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but what it was was she had been using she had been um in the jungle and it was some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Malaria medication</ENAMEX> and she tested positive for that
 	
 	
 		see and so it really is a dangerous thing that way because i know of somebody that tested for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> and didn't get the job and
 		they weren't told why
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say the reason why after you take a physical will be because of the drug testing
 		or they would tell you or this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> never use any drugs
 	
 	
 		see i always i thought they got you got called back if you tested positive for more test
 	
 	
 		but
 		um you should because you should be given another chance or at least
 		able to justify it or something i have real mixed feelings about it i don't know
 	
 	
 		how uh do you know how wrong they are are they i mean is there a margin of error
 	
 	
 		the accuracy i don't know i don't know but i know there are a lot of things that can influence them and i think that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> deserves
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chance with it or something because most things will stay in your system for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if you could show that i i interviewed for a job recently and i was taking Entex
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> gave me a prescription for it and he said this way if it were to make the drug test positive you have
 		proof that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> ordered this for you you know and it didn't come up that i needed to do it but
 		if this could happen to anybody and if they would just say oh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s drug test is positive we won't hire them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know then you could lose out on a job when really you didn't do anything
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i'm not so sure they're that needed i mean
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 		yeah i'm not sure either the only way i can see it is that if they really suspect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of using it
 		then they have the right to go ahead and prove it because they say they can spot check
 	
 	
 		yeah if you're using it
 		while at a job i can see a problem but the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> then it's almost like it's almost an infringement of your privacy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it sort of is and this is it this i'm not real sure how i feel about it because i can see it
 		from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways you know as a health professional i wouldn't want somebody take care of me that was using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> i feel well yeah we probably should be protected but on the other hand

 		there's a lot of things
 		i should be protected from it they don't test my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for too so you know i guess you sort of you have to have trust some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> along the way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can't go around testing everybody for everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know and i i think it could be used to hassle somebody if someone was out to get you
 		i think that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> could use this you know they could keep on doing this to you or something i guess i can see where it could become a problem
 	
 	
 		and it it's like it seems like now they have trests i guess they can test your hair and they can find out if you use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to several years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh wow
 		but maybe you shouldn't be held responsible for something you did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		i know
 	
 	
 		that's the other thing i mean a lot of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or you know young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get into some things that
 		they get out of later on and i don't think they should really have to pay for that forever
 	
 	
 		yeah there's a lot of things you do as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that you wouldn't do as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can't say it was wrong at the time
 	
 	
 		i think that's true yeah
 		yeah so that probably wouldn't be too good either
 		
 		
 	