
 
     		
 	
 		what do you think uh are we spending the right amount of money on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh
 		actually i'm i kind of uh well that's like between saying yes and no it uh
 		i think that we're uh spending about what we should but i'm not exactly sure if we're spending it in the right right uh
 		uh location
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		i do believe that there  i i'm like you i'm a little mixed up on the subject i think there are more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who die of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> than there are of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is that true
 		have you heard that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and and i suppose really <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is you die from any number of things isn't that true true
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so so i would suspect that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> i think is one of them and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> and whatnot so i think indirectly there there is extra <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research being done
 	
 	
 		right um
 		but i think that
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the attitude that the more money you throw at something
 		the uh better chance you have at at curing it and that's just not true
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so i  i i totally agree it's just like education throwing more money into a grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> isn't necessarily going to make things better
 	
 	
 		right i think uh
 		you know that that money needs to be spent on on research
 		
 
 		but i i think uh
 		you know it should be a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 		wide spectrum research of research and not just uh you know research on a cure and not not on a research on how to
 		uh prolong life or or uh make the disease any any less traumatic
 		know i think money i think one once somebody has contracted the disease that's that's uh
 		you know that's unfortunate
 		but let's try to concentrate on on you know let's put resources on making sure nobody else gets it
 	
 	
 		yeah so i you're thinking in terms of of an education on how to prevent it or you're thinking of maybe uh i don't know a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh
 		right
 		right well i think uh
 		you know there's there's my opinion is there's there's a there is a limited number of resources medical resources available
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		and i think it is foolish to
 		to uh spend most of those uh a a large majority of those resources on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 		uh simply because they they uh they need attention right away or or need more attention than somebody who has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> or or slow <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> or something i think i don't know i think uh
 		too much money is being spent on on uh
 		on sophisticated medical treatment for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need to be in a hospice program
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well do you think that one reason maybe that the the funding level is as high as it is is because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> perhaps strikes uh a vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of people
 	
 	
 		yes well that i mean that fits the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we live in the people
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		that's right tell me about it i was in i was on a down in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were demonstrating
 	
 	
 		it
 		oh okay yeah the i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with the loudest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> voice get the money it's not necessarily the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who uh who deserve it the most
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i
 		i agree that there's a limited it it's almost like we have fixed number of dollars that you can spend on medical research and you have to kind of allocate it in certain directions
 	
 	
 		right although that sounds heartless that's
 		that's
 	
 	
 		but good things have come of that i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> is just about a thing of the past
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		well i know just something local to you i remember i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and so i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> there
 		and i know for example uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkland Hospital</ENAMEX> is spending or at least was when i was there spending a large portion of their budget their budget on on on basically warehousing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i suspect that's true
 	
 	
 		and yeah that's
 		you know i i you know my heart goes out to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who have the disease but i don't think that we should be
 		spending uh
 		
 
 		you know that the that a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> resources should not go for for uh indigent  <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right well certainly if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> unless you're incredibly wealthy you're going to end up indigent
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think that i mean that goes along with it too you get to the point where you can't work and
 		
 		
 	