
 
     		
 	
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um i can't be terribly authoritative on what life was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> um
 		because i'm not that old yet
 	
 	
 		uh oh i can be but go ahead
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		um i know that uh
 		i mean obviously you look at at technological the technological aspect of of social change i mean you didn't have uh you didn't have video games you didn't have home computers you didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> machines
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean uh
 		you you try to you go into a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a business today</TIMEX> and you you try to imagine the whole thing except running off of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX> paper
 		and it's almost inconceivable now because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> machines and and everything have become such you know such such a a part of the way we live and the  yeah
 	
 	
 		right we fax everything we don't even wait for the mail anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah uh a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> of mine was was talking about how it used to be where you would send things through the mail and you had to do something this was concerning the S E C
 		and so if they had business to do they had to finish it you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> in advance so they could get it through the mail
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and now it's the kind of thing where you can work up until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you can get it there you know in in a matter of minutes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know through a fax machine and because of that these quote unquote convenience type items have actually made work that much more intense and that much harder
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because you're expected to work on stuff up until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're expected to exactly and i recently read an article on just this that said <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> today is so much worse it should be less because we have a microwave and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s had to bake brownies and
 		we can throw them in a microwave for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> but the more conveniences we have the more that's expected of us and we have no downtime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like we don't stop and wait for things to happen because we don't have to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we keep moving we don't stop and wait for the things to bake and this to happen and that to happen we just hit buttons and keep going to the next thing so we have no relaxation time in between
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they say that's really a bad thing that you need to learn a lot of ways to to deal with that and get your your time in between things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's good that's an interesting point
 		but i just think our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives have changed drastically
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i think that's just of course a part of it is technology i mean our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> where would they be without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> and you know their TV shows and that and some of that is really bad i think
 		but we have all single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> so many single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> now um
 		a lot of working both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are working so there's a whole big effect on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and not very many of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> really are on their original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and father
 		you know i'm wondering what this is going to do in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten and twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there's that and there's the fact that you know nowadays fewer and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> are deciding to have kids
 		what generally tends to happen i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX> would be actually declining in population slightly if it weren't for the fact that we have continuation large scale immigration into the country
 	
 	
 		you're probably right and i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">O B</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and that's never really occurred to me but that's that's interesting i never really thought about it that way
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i saw that the numbers on that awhile back and i was like uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's true when is this good or not good
 	
 	
 		well um
 	
 	
 		we don't know that yet
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in terms of the long term effect effect on on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in terms of the culture and everything i don't know um
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know either
 	
 	
 		most of the of the next generation is going to be in or or an extremely extremely extremely large part part of the next generation is going to be you know <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> generation from uh from immigrant parents
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and they're going to be really struggling and i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is currently the type of environment where struggling up from the bottom
 		is necessarily considered to be good
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		i mean it's no longer the the uh the accomplishment that it that it once was and not that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really trying i don't think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's kind of scary
 		hum
 		well that's true but i it's just very very different and i guess every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> it's just been very different
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so and i don't know what's gonna happen um
 		i know what i'm seeing here at my well my job is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are having their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> much later in life
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 	
 	
 		so that they're establishing careers and they've got their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and they've got a lot
 		
 		
 	