
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay let's see do you live uh do you live in a neighborhood that uh
 		has been affected recently by any uh crimes
 	
 	
 		uh let me see not recently i we're <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX> is uh midway between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Worcester</ENAMEX> and it's mostly mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> that we're finding a lot of problems
 		um basically it's lined up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and there've been a lot of murders and mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend girlfriend</ENAMEX> type of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah we uh in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> is is
 		pretty uh how shall i say it
 		they have a lot of problems but the problems are confined confined to low income neighborhoods well i shouldn't say low income neighborhoods uh
 		neighborhoods where a lot of low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> live and and uh where there's lot a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and uh broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh that doesn't
 		i i
 		try to uh in my thinking
 		to keep from blaming it on the on the nationality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and more blame it on the culture of the uh you know broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		right i think <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> plays a really big part a lot of times it doesn't come out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or on the news
 		um you know they're more into as far as the news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> into oh you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> killed each other or they knifed each other other to death and we have a lot with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> problems
 	
 	
 		yes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> problems
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 	
 	
 		the the problem
 	
 	
 		that seems to be the major thing and we just recently with all the problems that there are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> we did have i was thinking we did have one crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX> where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> picked up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at a bar
 		and uh her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> woke up she brought him home and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> woke up and she was dead she had been knifed to death
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and he was a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but why anybody would want to bring somebody like that home you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		too many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		really  i think that was the the major part of it too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and she just invited him in and he waited until she was sleeping and then let her have it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		too much alcohol
 		
 
 		yeah just kind of a psychopath
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the crime problem is uh
 		i don't know if if you're
 		this is uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a four hour</TIMEX> topic but a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minute</TIMEX> uh window here so the for me i
 		feel very bad about uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are affected uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the crime ridden areas are
 		more innocent in some cases uh
 		than the than the press finds well what i'm really trying to say is they are working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class people</ENAMEX> who work very hard and are seriously affected by that and uh so even though i see
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh how shall i say it uh the problems of crime affect the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working class</ENAMEX> and uh minority working people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		much worse than they affect me uh so the the crime problem has to be solved one of the problems that i see is that
 		and they always compare  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> they say well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> we have uh you know a gun problem and uh uh that
 		i i read a discussion once of of uh the reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> for instance uh has their gun problems and other problems are so low and it basically boils down to they don't have
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> doesn't exit for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> if you are standing at a corner and somebody and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> walks up to you and he says you've been standing here <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> have gone by uh you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pickpocket</ENAMEX> empty your pockets
 		if he finds some things in in there then they will proceed to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> perhaps and uh say open your door up and go in and search your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and after that they can enter at any time
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		now that has the advantage of uh weeding out how shall i say it of getting rid of the dandelions before they've before they uh populate your lawn
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but  it it just doesn't function in our court system over here we we won't allow you to be uh frisked by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> uh without good reason
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's wrong i think that's where the law has got to change because they've found uh how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have we read about or heard about in the national news that have been picked up and because of a technicality they're left let off
 	
 	
 		yeah an actually
 	
 	
 		you know and that's really not right and then they go out and do it again you know
 	
 	
 		that's right and and like i my earlier example uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i could spend
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> just picking the heads off of dandelions uh once i let my lawn get infested
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 		
 	