
 
     		
 	
 		have you any wisdom to offer someone picking a college
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		well i think
 		i think the biggest thing that's important is to is to learn enough about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to match the student well to the to the school
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing i learned i went undergraduate to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and then came out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> and it's pretty clear that there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who thrive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who just die here because of the the amount of support that's given and the amount of uh bureaucracy you have to deal with and other things like that
 	
 	
 		are are you saying that that there's more bureaucracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera at out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> at that particular school
 	
 	
 		uh in a large public school i think in general
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and uh this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with some thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		and it is set up in such a fashion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> register for classes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> in advance and if they don't get them
 		they may not get a chance to take them that year um average graduation has crept up closer and closer to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> largely because of the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who can't get all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> to fulfill their major on time
 		uh on the hand this is
 	
 	
 		that seems so wasteful
 	
 	
 		it is and and it's happening in in a lot of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh because of of budget cuts but on the other hand what it does provide is is for the um
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who who need a chance to be forced to fend for themselves
 		uh who have perhaps been too isolated this is a a case where they're they're forced to do that
 		and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> went here as an undergraduate she had been sort of protected right through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and and had to learn to
 		to make it on her own and she graduated from the place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> by learning to be smart and picking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that uh at the right times and right priorities and i can see that as advantageous but there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for whom this is just a waste of time
 	
 	
 		hum that it's interesting you're approaching it from the  sort of administrating your education just you know trying to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and be there
 		i was thinking in terms of um how would you advise a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> uh on how to pick his future career i i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> whose a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he hasn't got a clue you know what he wants to do you know he's good in math and science and he'll you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stepdad</ENAMEX>'s an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> you know he he'll probably lean toward some kind of math or science kind of thing but he's not sure what i myself graduated with an undergraduate and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in art
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i did it because it's just something i love to do and i felt that
 		i'm not i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> so i guess i'll teach and i kind of backed myself into a career that i never ended up really using i mean now that i'm raising my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i'm substitute teaching because the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are so good et cetera
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i had never given that much thought to whether i actually liked to teach you know it just seemed that well that's a practical thing you can do with art so you might as well do it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i guess my advice to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> approaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> would
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all do something practical because the art for me um didn't work out very practically i got out of school when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> draft evasion was going on and everybody wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> there were no jobs
 		and i ended up taking a secretarial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for graduate college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> which it struck me as so sad
 	
 	
 		just just to be able to find a job that you would qualify for
 	
 	
 		so sad you know there's a whole bunch of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> who are learning how to type just to be able to to make some money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		i i think one of the reasons that i don't see that as as much of a problem
 		see i would encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go into college not knowing what they want to do because so many of the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have done such a bad job at introducing different areas
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		that it may be that what you want to do and it may be a very practical thing to go into doesn't seem attractive because what you've learned of it so far is is not interesting a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are turned off from math because of high school math
 		and going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that offers a lot of choice
 		and taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first year</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to explore what the choices are still gives you plenty of time and
 	
 	
 		to pick so you you're suggesting some liberal arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> where you take a smattering of everything
 	
 	
 		and then eventually focus on a single major i certainly wouldn't say to go to a liberal arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that doesn't have a strong science program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i'd even encourage a liberal arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with an engineering program but i tend to look i don't like what i see from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are graduating here with engineering degrees
 		where seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or eighty percent of their time is spent in a prearranged technical curriculum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they are moving here towards a program where they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bachelor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master of Science</ENAMEX> combined where you get a general education with guaranteed admission into an engineering degree for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree
 	
 	
 		oh that
 	
 	
 		and that seems like a good compromise it's
 		
 		
 	