
 
     		
 	
 		you an avid magazine reader
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh not really i don't really read any regularly uh in the past i use to read some i use to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i guess that was just it i don't know too much reading to do so i stopped doing it so
 	
 	
 		um do you read for work or something
 	
 	
 		yeah i do a lot of reading for work because i i don't know i just have a lot of research literature to keep up on is the thing so
 	
 	
 		huh are you in the scientific field or something
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in computer science
 	
 	
 		ah
 		well uh my thoughts about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are uh that they're kind of a quick fix i watch very little TV and i i like to read a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if i'm feeling jumpy i kind of enjoy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> because everything's short
 		and you can you know lay perhaps look at the pictures read an article for a couple of pages you don't feel like you've committed yourself to all the time it takes to read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> pages
 	
 	
 		right it's just the thing is i i don't know i just have a tendency to want to read everything no matter what i buy what i buy so it's kind of weird
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah your pretty thorough if you're going to it right
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know it's uh just a weird thing about me so i try not to buy anything that i'm afraid of reading the whole thing so
 	
 	
 		oh if you're in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and they have all kinds of stuff what are you attracted to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh i don't know um i i like reading up on the news um and sometimes i like some science stuff but not much actually so
 		i mean because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Science</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> aren't usually very uh i don't know yeah scientific so
 	
 	
 		scientific
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how about you what do you read
 	
 	
 		uh well uh in the magazine world i guess i'm kind of
 		i hate to stereotype myself because i'm not all that girlish in the sense of girlish you know i i can solder and all of that kind of good stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> when i think about it um i have a cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> i like because i like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and there's some this thing called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Country Home</ENAMEX> which has
 		uh it's kind of a mellow thing with all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and
 		uh you i don't know recipes and decorating and all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm almost embarrassed to say that
 	
 	
 		girl stuff huh well it's not girl stuff it just you know good stuff that's all
 	
 	
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i was talking with a fellow about woodworking and and that's another thing i love to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and i'm into all kinds of crafts and things so i can i can saw and solder and all kinds of
 		you know things that would make me not sound like the typical you know cutesy
 		housewife type
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i guess in magazines i guess i you know i run the line i suppose that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh at we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road and Track</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> likes and i'll pick that up too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i enjoy it i like to look at the stuff i'd love to have if i had all the money to buy it
 	
 	
 		well yeah i i find it interesting to read just about anything that's lying around usually i mean it's always interesting stuff i don't i wouldn't normally buy
 		you always just well i don't know like i had an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who use to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> all the time and i thought it was the most ridiculous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> but it was just so interesting to find out i don't know about the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosmopolitan</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		it's kind of like sneaking a peek at the other side i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> i you know i i i don't really reread books so
 		with the price of the paperbacks and even the hardcovers going up i just why not use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> they'll even get anything you ask them to find for you so you know why not do that but i am a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the new book rack you walk in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they've got all the new books and to me it's like a little treasure opening this crispy you know covered brand new book and i'll come home with the strangest things that i'd never would have picked out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you know they run through the whole Dewey decimal system and you know there was one on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpine</ENAMEX> skiing that looked interesting and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on you know wood carving that looked interesting and you know you just find these things that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		well it's refreshing to pick up something that you would never go to a rack for i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but
 		i don't know that i have that much more to say about wood carving about wood carving i'm not even speaking thinking straight here about magazines um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		any other thoughts on your part
 	
 	
 		uh not in particular no  um
 		so do you read you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> then so do you read a lot of art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> at all or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		there are some um i'm particularly interested in the crafts and there is one called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Craft</ENAMEX> that lists all the shows and that kind of thing and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		craft shows are a lot of fun to go to when it's not some
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> in quotes who put lace on a pair of socks and sells that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> i mean that makes me crazy  you know but if it's really truly beautiful pottery and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know hand hewn wood  stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then i really enjoy it and and i'm going to start taking up some pottery which i've never done myself i've gone from woodworking to silver jewelry making to stain glass
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and pottery turning clay on a wheel is something i've never done and i just discovered
 		
 		
 	