
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> uh have the more variety in this area right
 	
 	
 		oh i suppose i uh substitute teach in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> schools
 		and what i find out nowadays is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are wearing jeans and and very casual things <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Polo</ENAMEX> shirts uh i'm of the opinion that i'm not one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i want them to know that
 		so i'll dress a little more formally i mean not a business suit but you know a nice skirt and blouse or
 	
 	
 		are you saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are wearing jeans
 	
 	
 		well i i should clarify i work in the i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and i work in the art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> so perhaps they are a little more Bohemian
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but  yes yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are wearing jeans and they're wearing sneakers and kind of upsets me because uh it seems that they're getting treated as if they're sloppy
 		and i i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		treated as if they're sloppy or treated as if they're uh peers
 	
 	
 		as if if if the whole situation is too casual
 		i don't get think they get the same respect as if they distance themselves in their behavior from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i think the way they dress says a lot about their attitude
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they're too casual with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kids curse</ENAMEX> in front of them and
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		and and take too many liberties and i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know as much as i'm there to be their uh to be there for them but i'm not their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> i'm there to teach them something and it's it's business and it's serious and
 	
 	
 		right of course motivation is everything and i suppose you're striving for intimacy on a intellectual level
 		it's really hard to figure out how you're going to do that but of course we're trying to talk about dress and not teaching
 	
 	
 		well i i think i'm talking about dressing how it conveys a uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a sense of um casual behavior and you know and and where it goes from there it's just a tangent of the same subject
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i am in a much more conventional position i work as a uh white collar worker uh i'm a senior
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal scientist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRI International</ENAMEX> uh work with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		what is is uh your particular field
 	
 	
 		speech technology
 		teaching computers teaching computers how to understand the speech
 	
 	
 		huh
 		oh so you must be very interested in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 		but anyway get off the subject
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> oh yeah i actually used i used to be chief speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		so i i guess you're in a business suit all the time
 	
 	
 		no actually i try to stay behind the scenes which means i wear slacks and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		my own personal style and it's  it's variable and there there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that'll wear jeans but i say probably most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh wear dresses or slacks and um
 		wear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> wear uh um
 		probably most of them wear long sleeve shirts without ties uh it's interesting it's sort of silly and ironic not ironic but it's silly in in a sense that
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> days which is are quite frequently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  quite frequently dress up and they wear ties and coats
 		and uh on non <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> days <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dress down and they wear just slacks and dress shirts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  it it well i guess it's silly in that the point is to be there and do quality work and not wonder about what you're wearing too much
 	
 	
 		right and and it it's uh it's not one of my dressing is not one of my main obsessions or preoccupations
 	
 	
 		what uh no i can see how you'd say that i'm not heavily into uh what's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> or what's out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i usually i have a certain amount of money that i spend on clothing and i buy things that will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year after year</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		well i i buy a new shirt once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> whether i need it or not
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 		so i guess you've got a collection don't you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't pay much attention to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i don't know um
 	
 	
 		now this this question did it relate to work or did it relate to to uh whatever
 	
 	
 		i think it was just um clothing and how you feel about it and do you change your wardrobe from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>
 		um i guess the warmer it gets the less clothing i wear but i don't know that i i change my sense of color or style to
 		to match a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> but i do know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have told me that the different carpets come out and different colors come out because uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> change your mood and and your ideas of color and fashion change with uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh you know with your mood and i guess it's all kinds of poetic uh
 	
 	
 		i guess i'm a typical oblivious male in that respect
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> that aren't terribly oblivious to clothing it's uh
 	
 	
 		i said typical
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> seem to think it's a shortcoming being too involved in their clothing like they have deeper more meaningful things
 		
 		
 	