
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		actually i'm in like i said i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> and the big thing up here of course is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i imagine you can't escape it
 	
 	
 		no it's it's pretty pervasive it kind of goes into about all aspects of society i think up here
 		but um actually i don't know how much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> you caught <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but that was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		well of course it was fun for you
 	
 	
 		well to be honest with you i'm not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> in fact i've only been up here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> and i'm going back at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of next month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Orlando Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so i'm not exactly a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> from birth or anything but
 	
 	
 		i was born and raised in uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> and uh spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last twenty years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> played
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh for the last uh what year  roughly year i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> where there're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Giants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh but honestly you know i uh i do my duty and watch the sports on uh the newscast
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but that's about all the exposure i have to sports
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i haven't followed it real closely at all um except like i said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> rolled around i did
 		i did follow that pretty religiously went out to the bars you know drank a beer watched the game sat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> a good time that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well yeah sure well i guess the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Giants</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX> were like the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		well i think i don't know well that's sort of what i gather
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and uh i don't know what is the prognosis for uh this year
 	
 	
 		uh real good as far as i can tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are pretty excited about
 	
 	
 		oh good i i assume that means good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah  sorry about that yeah uh as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> are concerned it seems to be real good
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> went and saw them play um their season opener uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of nights ago</TIMEX> and they they won that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one seven</NUMEX> to one
 		so um
 		that's pretty good i guess it looks like they'll be doing pretty well
 		are you still there
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		okay i heard some noise on the line didn't know what happened
 	
 	
 		i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> went by
 	
 	
 		oh okay all right
 	
 	
 		but i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> went by i don't know what the noise was but i think it probably was the the train
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i i i don't even know uh who who has been winning in uh as far as the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Giants</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX> but i think they both won their opener i sort of gathered that
 		in my uh subliminal memory
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  well maybe that has has good tidings for their uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their season</TIMEX> coming up i've actually got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that's living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> right now
 		uh he's doing the same thing i'm doing which is basically uh an internship we were both doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		and he's doing his with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> and i'm doing mine with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> but um i i think he kind of follows the sports and i think he's mentioned um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh he may have watched them and seemed to think that they were pretty good
 	
 	
 		i guess they're in different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> is that right the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		as far as i know yeah and in the major leagues i guess there's a couple of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> and then of course there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i guess i'm one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that if i really made a concentrated effort i could really probably get into baseball
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i was talking to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple nights ago</TIMEX> right after that game
 		and he offered you know to take me to one of the games because apparently he'd bought uh he and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> had bought a seat or a row of seats actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> games but the the thing is there's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> home games per year
 		so there's no no way you can ever use them all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> i was amazed to hear that you know that's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> games and i i thought it was a mistake but he goes no see eight
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they must play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> then
 	
 	
 		yeah well just just about yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> times two
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and sixty</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's you know yeah that's almost
 	
 	
 		and that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> that's uh over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> worth
 	
 	
 		that's a lot of baseball
 	
 	
 		even if they play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over five months</TIMEX> worth
 	
 	
 		well you you if you if you consider it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> starts well it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half ago</TIMEX>
 		and it ends with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> which usually takes place i believe in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so it did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week year</TIMEX> didn't it or was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> i'm thinking about i know it was doggone cold up here um
 	
 	
 		i don't feel so bad i think you you don't know all that much more than i do about baseball
 	
 	
 		well i know for sure it was i know it was after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because that's when i got up here
 	
 	
 		i see okay
 	
 	
 		and it and it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two months</TIMEX> after i got up here
 	
 	
 		oh really okay well
 	
 	
 		yeah so it had to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		well i i i know uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	