
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we in in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have been pretty remiss in trying to uh you know keep track of uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> finances uh the uh way way back
 		what twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> or something when i got my first computer
 		i did what everybody else does which is to put the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> budget on the machine and
 		put checks and you know checkbooks and all those kind of thing and we kept that going for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> and it became so onerous that we gave up on it
 	
 	
 		um-hum that sounds about right
 	
 	
 		you know so uh the only thing we're you know that we do now is uh i keep a a little spreadsheet of uh what i call the net worth calculation which is just the
 		the present value of various kinds of investments and so forth uh and i only update that
 		oh i don't know maybe once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every quarter or so every three months</TIMEX> just basically when the statements come in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just to see whether or not we're falling you know getting ahead falling behind or staying staying even or what
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um that's really about you know the extent of uh of the kind of uh
 		financial score keeping that we're doing
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of difficult for me because right now um like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> i'm laid off
 	
 	
 		hm oh dear that's terrible
 	
 	
 		and  so um
 		i spend most you know i substitute a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's a lot it's very hard on a nonfixed income because i don't know how many days i'm going to be called in and whether i am or not to try to keep track of finances
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and but i know uh how much i have to bring in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>  and that's about it that's about as far as we go and then anything extra is
 		you know more or less split up between all of us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just thrown in the kitty more or less for a rainy day
 	
 	
 		oh i see are you are you married are you living with a bunch of with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you're sharing expenses
 	
 	
 		um no i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so uh right now we're on we get from you know aid from the state
 		at this point because there's no other way to do it and my ex-husband just sort of took off and doesn't pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		so right now i know what i'm getting from the state and um i have to balance more or less
 		what i get from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with my bills and um you know try to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many days</TIMEX> as possible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		any time they call me in but i still have to figure out if i work too many days then i lose all my state aid
 		and if i don't work enough days then i don't get enough to meet the bills and it's like a juggling act every single month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> i've been just holding my breath and hoping they'll call me in but they probably won't because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have school vacation
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> before they only have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four day week</TIMEX> and they usually don't need subs because everybody's pretty good about coming in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i oh i see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they don't like to be absent before a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		but we're shopping around as far as well i'm shopping around as far as trying to get uh that's why i'm doing this to get some extra money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um getting pledge sheets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> so trying to get pledge sheets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> because every penny i bring in is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent to me
 		so  it sort of helps defray the costs a little bit but you know we do a lot of robbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
 		i guess we're in the situation that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> you know middle class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you're the first you know uh
 		my next door neighbor just lost his job in a you know one of these uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> went broke
 	
 	
 		oh my Lord
 	
 	
 		i mean went you know bankrupt actually it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of a
 		of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">US Shoe</ENAMEX> or something  it was a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> i don't know what a shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s doing running a computer company
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		but uh you know they just they just folded it up and um um told him to that they took the top management and gave them jobs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with the with the corporate uh at the corporate front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and everybody else was sent packing
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		uh hang on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX> i've got
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
  
 		
 
 		um somebody somebody was knocking on my door here um
 		it sounds like in a certain sense at least at the present stage i mean it sounds sounds terrible to say but at the present stage you probably are
 		even more in the market for a a budgetary thing than than than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably are might be terms of keeping keeping score of input and output
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum definitely
 	
 	
 		do you have a computer do you have a computer at home or
 	
 	
 		uh yes we do and we try to you know i keep track of every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> and more or less enter it in you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX> i'm at the computer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and it's like okay what do we have left what do we have to pay what have we paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> what hasn't come in yet you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah have you do you use a standard uh
 		a standard spreadsheet or i mean
 		
 		
 	