
 
     		
 	
 		hi  uh um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hi
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i should say something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i'm the uh least informed this is totally accidental that i have to talk about this topic but it's i'm the least informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		this has not been determined yet but i i
 		i've never read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in my entire life and i've i i never watch TV news nor listen to the news on the radio unless i'm just happening to be listening to music and they slip it on in the car radio before i can turn it off
 		but
 	
 	
 		any particular reason
 	
 	
 		well no i i've i've explored that with lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh they've tried to lock me up and uh things like that but um
 		um i'm basically not interested and i also find the um everything is so slick and superficial and misguided and misguided and off the um
 		
 
 		um
 		what am i trying to say uh
 		i do learn about things largely largely from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and i occasionally will read something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review Of Books</ENAMEX> you know someone will write a book about something and then i'll learn all about this thing that was in the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> earlier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it and somehow and anything i participated in or know about when i read about it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is always so
 		uh covered from such a funny and superficial perspective that i don't have much confidence in it but i mean i don't think it's just that i'm lazy
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i really don't i mean i i like to refer to this as sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Report</ENAMEX> phenomenon which is everybody that i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reads Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> does a a wholly inadequate job in their area of particular interest but assume that they do a reasonable job in other areas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh without thinking that there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in who think each other areas area of of specialty and
 		uh i guess you could explain it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways and and the cynical view is  well these things aren't doing a very good job at all
 		and the view that i'd rather take is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's a different amount of information you need when you're particularly interested in a topic or uh particularly interested in buying something as a you know as a hobbyist versus when you want to go out and buy a blender because you need to mix things
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think the same thing is true with news if you want to just have an idea as to what's going on most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and and especially the better papers the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> give you a reasonable idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you were deeply involved in it then you immediately realize that what they print is stuff that you probably knew already and the stuff that you want they're not printing because the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doesn't need or want to know that much
 	
 	
 		right doesn't want
 		let me ask by the way just for the record i i'm i totally concede that intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> read these things and intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> write them
 		so i mean i'm not being elitist in that sense i hope uh
 	
 	
 		well i mean there's there's a reasonable question as to
 		whether it's worth the amount of time it takes to keep up on things
 	
 	
 		yeah what
 	
 	
 		and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it is and i can i can you know accept that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's not and can find better ways to use it
 	
 	
 		yeah by the way when you say most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it is i think it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety nine</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety nine</NUMEX> think it is percent
 	
 	
 		i don't think it's that high i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who may  watch the TV news in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> but don't spend the time to actually read a newspaper
 	
 	
 		but you don't
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think they're saying well if something's really important i'll at least find out that it happened
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and that's a that's is a reasonable start and for awhile i didn't read a newspaper when i came out here because i didn't find one that i liked
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and if something important happened it was covered on TV and i could then go and and pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> if if it were important enough to read about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i imagine you get the same level of thing that if somethings that you cared about happened you'd find out from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or other channels
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i did on the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> hearings uh the for um
 		uh the whole business of uh see i i actually have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> business i i mean that's that's the closest thing i deeply cared about that um
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i sort of had planned to have dinner with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine and when i arrived at her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> she was engrossed in that we ended up
 		watching it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> zooming out and grabbing something to eat and then zooming back and eating watching it some more and i thought that was terrific because she actually helped me understand what was going on
 		but even then i didn't end up doing it on my own um
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i stayed as far away from those as i could i decided i didn't want to waste the time i had i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> now wasted that kind of time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> hearings and afterwards decided that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right yeah
 	
 	
 		what i had gotten out of it just wasn't worth the time i put in and that these things are just very slow ways of seeing information come out think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah do you ever read
 		
 		
 	