
 
     		
 	
 		okay i'm not as ashamed to claim them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> as a has been so
 	
 	
 		oh so
 		well it let's put it this way we've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Patriots</ENAMEX> up here so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah right well
 	
 	
 		they've had some serious problems in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really why
 	
 	
 		yeah um well uh partly due to ownership you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Kiam</ENAMEX> owned the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> uh for a period of a number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he always had this uh this wonderful quality of quality being able to put his foot in his mouth every time he went to say something
 		and uh they've had some financial problems with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and so forth and it recently was sold to uh some other people
 		so hopefully this ownership can set up new direction and uh keep uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> arear anyways
 	
 	
 		yeah well it'll be fun for you to watch up there anyway to see what happens now you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		i've been to a couple of i've been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> games before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now you you're you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		right
 		well it depends on where you're from in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i live right by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so we have one football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> as far as we're concerned that's how it's is it's divided yeah it really is so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see there's that type of segregation huh wow
 	
 	
 		we've got our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> here and and uh i don't think anybody roots differently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you
 	
 	
 		but i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fresno</ENAMEX> and he is for the L the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders LA Raiders</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you follow professional sports at all
 	
 	
 		well i just started to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because of these silly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> that didn't do very well  but i've been trying more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i think i know a little more than i used to i never knew very much at all so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm trying
 	
 	
 		well it's it's a good past time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know particularly football
 		they say uh it football attracts more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> because of the you know you the you see the the physical aggression on the field and supposedly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> say that uh
 		that um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> take out their frustrations by watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and you know they get together with a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and they um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they have a good time and everything and that's suppose to be some of the uh male bonding and the and the uh the male instincts i guess or something about uh
 	
 	
 		so i shouldn't even try to do it huh
 	
 	
 		well no it's a it's good as in terms of in terms of uh of a contest i think that uh i personally like hockey better because it has contact it's a contact sport it has the speed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the hand eye coordination and it takes a certain skill to play hockey not everybody can play hockey
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we and that's we're a big hockey area up here hotbed up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> as well as you know in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> area but
 	
 	
 		really
 		i don't even think we have that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but we might do we
 	
 	
 		what hockey
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean no  you probably know i don't know nobody talks about it so i don't think we do
 	
 	
 		no there's no hockey there's no
 		there's no professional hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it just it's
 	
 	
 		no uh-huh and we have a soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that comes and goes we don't even have that very much so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think though that professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> in particular is becoming so diluted now like they have this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Football League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	

 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you see we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> are in and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Patriots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Raiders</ENAMEX> and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>  there are those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that play in professional the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh now they have what's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Football League</ENAMEX> and they have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> from there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>  there's a there's a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and and they're playing now during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer months</TIMEX> and it's really  you know overkill
 		you know there's only so much football you can watch
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah well i like to do i don't like to watch i don't like to watch anything
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		so it kind of annoys me when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just lay in front of a TV and watch all this stuff i think it's an excuse to do nothing and i i can see what you're saying about the male bonding and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get together and that's kind of cool that's fun you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it can get really overdone
 	
 	
 		now have you ever been to a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		yeah i have yeah yeah i have
 	
 	
 		have you
 		did you do the whole big the the whole thing the tailgate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and the whole
 	
 	
 		uh  no actually no um
 	
 	
 		well see now see now that's what you got to do see now we talked our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've done that for college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you the same well the same thing we we talked our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six or eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that we used to go out for these games and uh we talked our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> into going with with us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and they had a real good time and it was basically for the social atmosphere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right and that's the thing yeah
 	
 	
 		you go you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> before the game you go set up we set a table up we do some cooking some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barbecueing</ENAMEX> have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> and then go in and see the game and see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots</ENAMEX> lose and then go home and eat drink some more
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but but that whole it it's not so much sure the contest itself and the game itself but it's the whole atmosphere of playing uh of going to a game
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it that you miss sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in your parlor you know uh with a with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and some uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato chips</ENAMEX> you know you you miss that and and any professional sport i think you miss that
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the atmosphere of being there you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well in high school i went to every <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i twirled you know and i you know i didn't i still don't know that much about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> obviously but i still had a good time you know i
 	
 	
 		yep
 		well football
 		
 		
 	