
 
     		
 	
 		oh it it it's i i'm i'm not sure if if there's anything i really consider an invasion of privacy that happens happens regularly except maybe like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">telemarketers</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah i have the problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telemarketers</ENAMEX> over here we get we get all types we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped people</ENAMEX> calling up here
 	
 	
 		you want to buy some light bulbs
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh if you don't want the light bulbs there's vitamins and if you don't want the vitamins there's the household cleaner
 	
 	
 		pens
 	
 	
 		no  i've had i've we i just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was looking into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic War Veterans</ENAMEX> because they were bugging
 	
 	
 		boy they they they're tugging on a few strings at once aren't they
 	
 	
 		yeah they were uh bugging me for a donation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and i i you know i get these calls on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> just constantly every single organization
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know you it's i've learned to hang up on them but sometimes it's not so easy
 	
 	
 		yeah i i got some call last night i'm trying to remember oh this this was like this this is kind of an invasion of privacy where uh
 		i went to a wedding expo because i'm getting married and uh there are like you know uh these places where they say you know sign sign up for a free whatever you know for for a drawing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you do it and uh you know all of a sudden this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is calling you and saying hi we want to call you know talk about video taping your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX> when shall we set a time up and i couldn't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to get off the phone
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's like how many at what what part of no didn't you understand you know
 	
 	
 		well it's the same thing with these oil well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what do you mean you don't want to get rich
 		The other thing that i i think is amusing are with these long distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah same here
 	
 	
 		and uh they have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and family program and i love it you can call up on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the lines the
 	
 	
 		family right
 		yeah  they they fixed it so you had to give some information out but
 	
 	
 		well there's another one the account balance line all you got to know is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s zip code
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you can find out how they're paying their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M C I</ENAMEX> bills and and on anyone you know all you got to do is cross reference a phone number with a zip code
 		which isn't too difficult and you can learn all sorts of things and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> does the same thing and and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they
 		i i think in general you know technology as nice as it is is causing a lot it's just too easy now to it's like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> used to be you know you could do anything over the phone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you had to know your pin number but i could just i could just say to it empty my whole account out if i wanted transfer things
 		and you know there there's a lot of of risk involved there because you know it it's like you know the best example is probably credit reports now
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		where where you know God knows what goes on those things i mean thankfully thankfully now you can get your reports for free at least from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRW</ENAMEX>
 		but it it it it's like it's it's this anonymous thing where anyone can dump any information they want about you in there with no real  opportunity to rebut unless you want to go and get the report and then
 		you know and then you you you find out you can go for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or something all of a sudden you find out what all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been you know dumping information about you in there and i've heard of cases where it was just done vindictively
 	
 	
 		yeah we had uh we got a report back in the mail as a matter of fact and found all sorts of problems with it mainly account numbers that have changed and they left both accounts showing as open
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh some other one that claimed i didn't pay them and i did and then you have to try and get that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to take you off and they don't really want to bother and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah when i when i applied for my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold MasterCard</ENAMEX> they said well you have to close this other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> out too and i said you mean the one i closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i had to get a letter from this other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> saying that i had closed it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's a pain in the neck because they you know they'll they'll believe these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> over the individual
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and getting proof for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean it's not my job you're the one that screwed up and you know if you want to damage my credit rating that's fine but i will take whatever actions are appropriate to protect it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		like lawsuit
 	
 	
 		oh it it it's very slippery though because you know it's  one of the things you do when you when you sign those little credit applications is there's all sorts of disclaimerage at the bottom about
 		how you know you're permitting them to check do credit checks of you and to make your information available to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and by the time you get through reading it you've basically permitted them to you know broadcast on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news your credit rating
 	
 	
 		yeah  i know i know it's just that consumer we need to have stronger consumer protection laws and we just don't seem to be able to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to do it
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well you know there's much more subtle kinds of invasions of privacy like every time you call an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> number you're giving them your phone number
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i know i've been reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp DCom Telecom</ENAMEX> all about it
 	
 	
 		yeah we're we both probably signed up for this in the same place
 	
 	
 		yeah i i contribute every once in a while in there and yeah i see the messages about the uh A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N I</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> I yeah but to some extent i'm not as worried about that because yeah you're you're getting a value for that you're getting to call these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for free
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh you know the other boondoggle is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> I D thing you know i don't mind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> I D one bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um if i don't want to use it or if someone calls me that i don't know who it is i can just not answer the phone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	