
 
     		
 	
 		i uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		try to stay away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as much as possible in terms of
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		repair actually uh that is really a sore spot with me i i think
 		perhaps the automotive industry is improving but uh like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 		um the reliability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> at least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> was pretty dismal and
 		not only that but the uh repair capability of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh</ENAMEX> service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealerships</ENAMEX> was equally dismal and uh it seemed that the only way i could reliably take care of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was to repair it myself which is not my cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i
 	
 	
 		so do you have a car
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		do you have a car
 	
 	
 		well at that time actually i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Rabbit</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		it was it it was a real lemon
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> subsequently i got a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick Century</ENAMEX> and it wasn't as bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> and i take it in once <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every seventy five hundred miles</NUMEX> for its periodic maintenance and that is it and it's wonderful and
 	
 	
 		yeah we used to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> and they're good
 		they're really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> every time i get taken to an auto repair place you know every time i go i get taken bad you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> goes in and they go all right we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		let's get how see how much money we can get out of her you know that's what happens every time um so
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 		so what do you what do you have
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pontiac</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		all the more reason to uh have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 		but our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> just got old and just wore out it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> let's see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> years old
 		and it just
 		just out of it so
 	
 	
 		so so you bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no uh-huh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ex-husband</ENAMEX>'s this this just happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> he's my ex-husband but just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> when he was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> um his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> gave us this car
 		and everything is wrong with it i mean the power steering fluid leaks the oil leaks the brake fluid leaks you know
 	
 	
 		now this what how old is the car
 	
 	
 		um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> and he just doesn't take care of things and but i was awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that is a mechanic and i can trust him
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so he's trying to get you know things fixed on it but it's just you know leak leak leak everywhere but um
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know i hate to go into a a repair <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> because they'll tell me something's wrong with it and it's not
 		you know and charge me twice as much the last time i took it into a repair shop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> told me i needed a master cylinder so i said okay
 		and he charged me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> something dollars and then um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> later
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was looking at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and he asked me you know
 		not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> not a repair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and i was telling him that i just had a new master cylinder put on and he said looked at and he said that's not a new master cylinder
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and i didn't even know what one was and um he showed it to me and it was old rusty
 		just awful it was no more new than nothing
 	
 	
 		so apparently it was the same one that was on there
 	
 	
 		oh more than likely
 	
 	
 		oh we just uh refilled refilled uh probably filled the the brake fluid up and that was it
 	
 	
 		that was it probably it was very i was so irritated and that's happened to me more than once or twice just just just about every time i've went in somewhere
 	
 	
 		so what's the solution to that i guess find a reputable service
 	
 	
 		and and you just i can't hardly find one you know
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's doing most of my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> now um goes to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and that's the only reason you know i go to him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i know him and i know he will tell me the truth because he doesn't even charge me for for doing it so he's not gonna you know
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		take me yeah i just pay for the parts and he does it so
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i am so
 	
 	
 		you're lucky
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't know what the solution to that is because the place where you buy your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they're usually the worst <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of all
 		we took our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> and they ended up telling us we needed a brand new engine for our car
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> as we were neither one of us knew much about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> we you know they told us we just had to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and we bought one
 		we didn't no more need no new engine give me a break you know so it was it was not good
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and um
 		
 		
 	