
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i'll just briefly um i worked in a nursing home so i kind of know from way back uh how things used to be run and i think there's been definite changes of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but
 		i think uh if i personally had to put one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in a nursing home they would have to be pretty bad off
 		to where i couldn't take care of them at all it would be something that  you know i would certainly  if they're forgetting things or whatever i'd prefer to have them at home or have them in what they call now home care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where somebody comes in and they cook meals and they clean their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for them that kind of thing so they still have their own independence and not reliable you know they don't have to be in a nursing home situation but uh
 		i don't think the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> when i was working in them were very much understaffed very much uh in need of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> um
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> weren't given the quality of care that i wouldn't have you know i look at it and say thank God i
 		got out of that kind of situation but uh they they were not given the time and they were not given the money basically to staff appropriately <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to help and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can remember lifting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> all by myself simply because there was not another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to help it's either let leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in bed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long
 		or get them up and i would have preferred to get them up than  than to leave them in bed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> but uh
 		um so i think nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are have changed i'm not quite sure but hopefully they have
 	
 	
 		yeah well the i guess i haven't had that much experience i've only seen like my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> in a nursing home but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who lived on her own until she was well in her nineties and then she she got sick and she ended up in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> went to visit her and it got to the point where the nursing it seemed like the nursing home didn't want to deal with  her anymore
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and so they gave her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to keep her asleep
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think that's that can happen and i think in the nursing home that i worked for
 		i wasn't quite sure of it but i'm sure that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were uh given <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> to keep them in uh quiet and and
 	
 	
 		nice <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sedative</ENAMEX> state
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and they would just lay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long and uh
 		the ones that they also put mentally ill patients
 		in the same they were not on the same you know ward but they they were in the same nursing home so that these mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> could walk into where the other uh older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were in there for reasons of uh
 		you know age uh the mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> could walk right in into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> or do whatever they wanted to basically because if you weren't there to watch them and keep them in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> they could they had freedom to just walk around and a lot of them were
 		i think there was a couple that were schizophrenic and i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time watching one of the uh schizophrenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> actually go out on i don't know what they call it a binge or whatever you want to say it but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she grabbed a hold of this and it was kind of funny when i look back at it but i mean i remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> getting very upset
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person woman</ENAMEX> actually pulled uh the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s hair i mean she just came up right behind him and pulled his hair you know and it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was
 		just really upset i mean he's what the hell are you think you're doing you know and i laughed at it then but then i'm thinking God you know if i had to put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in that nursing home i wouldn't want them there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think there's laws now that kind of protect that nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> either have to keep the mentally ill totally away from these people
 		and not in the same type of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> even though they're aging mentally ill they are still mentally ill and a lot of these older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have their you know
 		they're not insane or anything like that they don't have these tendencies to to lash out
 	
 	
 		be violent
 	
 	
 		but  seeing that kind of made me think twice about jeez i wouldn't put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother father</ENAMEX> in that nursing home at all
 	
 	
 		was this in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or a little town
 	
 	
 		a small town
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it seem like the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> nursing homes
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i there's a lot more personal attention
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i kind of look at it this way i think
 		if you have a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> area i think there's more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to keep watch on it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you have more options
 	
 	
 		and yeah yeah and you have more competition and i think nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> have to be better than when there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> nursing home for a whole community
 		and this is back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen seventy seven</TIMEX> that i worked there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i look back at it and say jeez you know i it would have to be awfully bad for me to put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in there but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> uh later on got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and uh could no longer well actually she
 		
 		
 	