
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well you know um
 		i
 		think
 		public service is a worthy thing and as a matter of fact there are a lot of programs uh such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> that promote that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably the most popular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but uh one that is not typically recognized as such is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i know that from because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> now and uh is thinking about his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>
 		and uh in order to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> you have to have merit badges in um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in the community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> citizenship in the world
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you have to do a public service project
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is the key element
 		i um
 		i think the question is posed somewhat strangely because um
 		it's talking about uh a requirement for public service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and of course Peace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> is a  is a voluntary activity
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i i think that might be talking referring to uh
 		something kind of uh alternative to the draft you know either you have
 		uh military service or some sort of alternative nonmilitary service for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right of course um
 		uh military service falls under the category uh of a public service
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and so uh one of the things that would fulfill the at least the nominal uh qualifications set forth in the charge is military service or draft
 	
 	
 		hm right right
 	
 	
 		uh but i agree with you that probably is not what was comprehended there are other things such as civil service
 	
 	
 		well you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um which many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh are lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of but i suspect that that's not what they had in mind either more of a voluntary kind of thing or uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i uh
 		yeah it it for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> there has been an idea batted around of having some sort of alternative uh public service for uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go into uh after high school um it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of in in lieu of the draft for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't
 		uh who you know are conscientious objectors or don't otherwise wanna
 		uh be in the military you know say okay well you can go into the military or you can do this other thing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two years</TIMEX> to kind of serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and and
 		learn about things and it's it's it's interesting because i i'm not a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the military
 		but i have seen a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> go in that don't have
 		really a clue as to what they want to do with their lives and aren't terribly disciplined you know even even just personal discipline about what they want to do and
 		they come out and they they at least have now they have at least some marginally marketable skills
 		and more more discipline and they have uh you know in in some cases they have a greater self-esteem because they can say they can see that you know if i do something
 		pursue submit my own will to the will of the sargent or whatever at least for a short period of time i can accomplish a lot and it it's a good lesson for a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to learn
 		that they don't need to be you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> they don't need to be out there and
 		uh you know constantly flaunting their ego to get things accomplished
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know for some for some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that's good for me it would have been lousy idea idea uh because i i did have the the personal discipline and i went to college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and got out you know so
 	
 	
 		why
 		why is that
 	
 	
 		but um you know for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's good i i don't particular like the fact that it's the military you know and because the whole point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> essentially as as an instrument of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> foreign policy
 	
 	
 		oh no no no it's to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> against external evils
 	
 	
 		well that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> view  and you know and
 		that's that's another debate but uh it's
 		um
 	
 	
 		well it depends on whether you whether we figure that we have that we have a defense oriented military or an aggressive aggression oriented military
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right and just well it's
 		it it seems pretty aggressive aggressive oriented i mean you you look at the last mission military action which was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> and wasn't anywhere near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 		and it was um you know it was definitely a projection of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">US</NUMEX> power
 		on the other side of the globe
 		so at at any rate this is getting off the topic but it my my point was that there is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't want to do the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> there
 		it would be neat if there were an alternative that could instill the same sort of personal discipline and sense of purpose and um sense of community
 		that do do i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	