
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> what do you hear in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> do you hear as much do you think as we do here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um probably not in anywhere near as much there have been a couple of articles uh which i've basically glanced at um
 		but that's about it i just find it interesting that somebody with that much money uh would be interested in the presidency in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place i guess it's it's as much you know just the sense of power and the sense of being able to accomplish things
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as much as anything else i don't know it seems to me that if i had that kind of money i would feel like i were more influential as a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> than as the president
 	
 	
 		well that could be uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Ross Perot</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> i mean
 		
 
 		this is kind of new to him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't know are you familiar with things that he's done in the past that have gotten quite a bit of attention
 		like uh rescuing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that were being held in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum no no i hadn't i hadn't really paid that much attention
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah  i mean this was this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten or so ten</NUMEX> or twelve
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh he hired uh some retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to go in after him and and supposedly even i think went in by himself with went in to see them disguised you know as somebody else
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		but uh he at least ended up over there in one of the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> probably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> probably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> or something to meet them when they came out of uh
 		out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
 		and i think he was uh maybe a little getting a little bit involved in politics or something during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> he uh tried to send supplies over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know i of course we hear a lot of him because he lives here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		what kind of i mean this this obviously says something for his um
 		you know something for one aspect of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is he in terms of
 	
 	
 		i he was an outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> i've read  until he quit there and started his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> which he later sold out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it since then he's started a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but i think he must be a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> or at least he was at some time um
 		my impression is that he's a pretty honest person
 	
 	
 		be kind of a change
 	
 	
 		oh i i've heard him on the radio and whatnot i mean he just seems very forthright he he he doesn't have to play games
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's already he's already won
 	
 	
 		i mean that he
 		that's right that's right i i'm just curious to see what's gonna happen to the political scene uh if he gets on the ballot in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and whatnot do you do you think he cans be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spoiler</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		i honestly don't think so uh not unless he really puts a lot of effort into it and i don't think he wants to i think it's
 		uh i think being a seriously considered being seriously considered as a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is something that um
 		it it just takes a really huge investment in personal effort not just you know i mean i'm sure it takes a lot of money as well
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but um just in terms of the number of personal appearances that you've got to make and all the the the hoops that you've got to jump through in order to get the media sound bites and get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paying attention to you i mean
 	
 	
 		all the backslapping
 	
 	
 		an occasional newspaper article will will show up for for any variety of things but being considered seriously i think is you know may take more than he's willing to put into it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh yeah yeah could be
 		could be i i also suspect that one aspect of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> would be that he would be really really tenacious
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		or or maybe stubborn even i don't know so i don't know you know he he might
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		decide to go whole hog and really go out and and turn into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> and do all the back slapping and and uh handshaking and all that kiss a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> i suppose
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't suppose he'd have to do a whole lot of fund raising or uh
 		worry a whole lot about where the funding was coming from so he'd have that advantage
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah it's um
 		certainly different i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is wealthy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but nothing like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i mean i don't know what they put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s wealth at i think it's probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few billion</NUMEX> or something i
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've i've heard it in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> i didn't hear specifics i figured once it you know once it reaches that point it doesn't really matter how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> are in front of the B you know it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's passed it's passed any kind of reasonable imagining in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i the
 		in a way i i'm interested in his candidacy i'd like to i'd like to kind of get
 		
 		
 	