
 
     		
 	
 		okay so we're supposed to discuss job benefits and such
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh what do you consider
 		that you're lacking in benefits that you have
 	
 	
 		that i'm lacking in benefits um the fact that they're not all paid for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i wish they were all paid benefits uh i share in our health insurance uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and half
 		um i'm also covered under my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s so but uh i wish i wish they were all paid for i don't have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a dental benefit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and uh i guess the benefits that i have i wish i had more of an HMO a health maintenance as opposed to kind of fix it after it's broken kind of maintenance
 	
 	
 		well that's i've uh worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> before and it really is nice particularly if you aren't you know really set on any one specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> if if you're flexible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i mean you get you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> physicals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i mean they just seems to make sense to do it that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess in a perfect world in a perfect world uh but we aren't in a perfect world so i don't know
 		uh other than that i don't really have any benefits per se how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i'm fortunate in that i have uh dental and i also have vision care the thing that i have had in the past that i wish that my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> provided was uh a prescription a paid prescription plan
 	
 	
 		prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay gotcha
 	
 	
 		you know that they'll cover uh
 		like for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> or something like that that you can get anything that you want
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		how about other other benefits of of the job i mean do you have uh what kind of uh time off do you have what type what type of work do you do
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i'm an administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> for a software company
 	
 	
 		huh okay
 	
 	
 		and what about you
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> i work with a uh brokerage house and we work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in brokering their services or goods to other businesses
 	
 	
 		how large is your company
 	
 	
 		oh not too large that's part of the problem with the uh the health care program it's probably maybe uh twelve people
 	
 	
 		oh you're right well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i work for now in my office we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> overall
 	
 	
 		gotcha
 	
 	
 		and uh uh our benefits i guess are pretty good you know we well i guess actually we have quite a few offered to us we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">401K</TIMEX> and i get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks vacation the first year</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten holidays</TIMEX> i guess one of which is a floating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> that i can use at my discretion the
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when you say a floating holiday what do you mean by that
 	
 	
 		well it's just a day that you can use i guess you'd really consider it a personal day
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 		so you have personal days you day uh i should say multiple or single
 	
 	
 		just single
 	
 	
 		okay but you can use um your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays your holiday</TIMEX> or uh vacation times split up into personal days
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		can you split your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> or vacation time into personal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or do you have to take them in bulk
 	
 	
 		uh the vacation i think i can split you know i don't have to take it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or a week</TIMEX> at a time or anything like that the holiday uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the one day</TIMEX> i think i can just put it anywhere that i want to
 	
 	
 		huh
 		now does
 	
 	
 		so that's nice
 	
 	
 		does oh yeah uh does does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> do picnics or you know like uh tomorrow our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as a whole and i guess i would call this a benefit  is uh we're going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> home opener in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a benefit no we don't do anything like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah you don't do you have any like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> picnics or uh or get-togethers or things along those lines
 	
 	
 		i don't think so as a matter of fact i've only been with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> and uh i i asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> i think we do have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> party although he indicated the budget is kind of low
 	
 	
 		oh
 		it always it usually is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but then with just uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> of us in the office you know as far as a company picnic or anything i don't think that there's enough of us you know to to get together and do something like that
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is pretty free you know as far as if i decide that i want to go out to lunch with someone and i'm late coming back
 		no one complains or says anything about it and if i need some time off to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> they wouldn't penalize me for that
 	
 	
 		that's good i was yeah oh absolutely i mean the environment you work in is is uh crucial to the job
 	
 	
 		and that counts
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we have somewhat we're somewhat in the same situation um i mean i feel i feel odd about taking any personal time anyway unless you know they knew about it or whatever but um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but being a sales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> we you know our time is our own i mean we're kind of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> under a common goal type of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of the same situation although it sounds like your office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is more structured as an office time
 		um but you it's not so rigid that you know you punch a clock that type of thing
 	
 	
 		well a lot of it depends on your position too you know other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in sales in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> they come and go
 		
 		
 	