
 
		
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				
 				no you start
 			
 			
 				
 				okay what are the benefits well i i mean i don't even consider like salary a real benefit it just it's kind of a like a side thing i'm really here for you know working with lots of creative people
 				is what i really like about my job
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				well i think that i'm self-employed and work in radio
 				and uh for me really i don't have to be terribly concerned about uh benefits outside because i own my own company
 				but uh the worst problem that i think uh out here is affecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think would be the most positive job benefit is job security these days
 			
 			
 				that's true yeah yeah you don't you don't want to have worry about it
 				you know if if you're worried you don't work as well
 			
 			
 				yeah it's
 				well it it's a real problem out here because uh you know it's hard to imagine that you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 				i can remember where we really you know somebody would work for a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> which are based here and uh they'd have that job for life
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				and you really didn't have to worry too much about that but ever since this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan Bush</ENAMEX> thing
 			
 			
 				i know
 			
 			
 				every single time there's you know the the first thing they do is they fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> whenever there's a problem with the uh uh economy economy
 				and clear out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and we're losing more and more jobs and uh
 			
 			
 				and it just gets worse then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't don't spend any money
 			
 			
 				yeah it's it's a real that's probably the biggest thing that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are looking for i uh put some things up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp Dcom Telecom</ENAMEX> thing regularly about uh job security with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and
 			
 			
 				right yeah i just i just noticed that yeah
 			
 			
 				the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communication Workers of America</ENAMEX> and i'm watching as that progresses more and more and it seems to me that we're seeing a real problem with job security
 				being the number one focus it's no longer a question of salary or or perks it it's just basic security to have that job
 			
 			
 				yeah i know i know exactly how you feel but i i also don't know you know how how can we get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to change it i mean it it kind of it kind of requires you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> taking a risk and they don't want to do that
 			
 			
 				well i in
 				
 				well i think maybe some incentives on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to retain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 				uh versus downsizing really why we're seeing that kind of downsizing is because of the uh increasing power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> of the country
 			
 			
 				that's true
 			
 			
 				whenever there's a uh problem with uh the economy or the stock value you know the first thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> want to see is well decrease costs which means cut employees
 			
 			
 				i know i mean our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> is is you know quite frankly stated that you know we're we're here to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> happy
 				and that's not why i'm working here
 			
 			
 				yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is really starting to feel the effects i think of the uh downturn
 			
 			
 				oh definitely
 			
 			
 				you know you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have been pretty insulated uh for some of the past ones it it hasn't hit as bad as it has out in the northeast here
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>'s luckily is a technology moving city i mean we have a lot of telecommunications and the like out here but
 			
 			
 				right
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> around here that were into mechanical and engineering and things like that steel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> they're all gone they're all in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> now
 			
 			
 				
 				yeah we're we're just kind of like losing and it it just seems to be a snowball effect i mean  you know we keep losing more
 			
 			
 				well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cupertino</ENAMEX> seems to be one of the every single software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ever sees always sees <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cupertino</ENAMEX> you know
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				so you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> at least don't have those kinds of you know the only problem software seems to be still a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> strength versus hardware
 			
 			
 				right and it
 			
 			
 				but you know the again in the future we're going to see the same type of thing even in more white collar work where we're going to have job security i think being the biggest focus
 			
 			
 				yeah it's things things aren't that secure in software right now either i think it's
 				it's kind of a cutthroat i'm also a i'm also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware manufacturer</ENAMEX> i'm at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> so it's like
 				you know we we notice our product just becoming a commodity and that's really bad
 			
 			
 				well i heard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> was remaking themselves into a consumer electronics company
 			
 			
 				we're trying and if it works that's that'd be great for us but what about you know the rest of the industry
 			
 			
 				
 				yeah well the hardware you know HDTV if we can keep control of that that looks like something that we could have good strengths on and there would be a lot of new jobs created
 			
 			
 				yeah although although we we go on that subject i i because i looked at HDTV uh but i i don't like standards that are on it's still still on a fixed resolution which means it'll be eventually outdated also
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				well we i'm a home satellite dish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and we have these arguments all the time about standards because of the video cipher of the scrambling system
 			
 			
 				
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				in place and there's two separate arguments over whether we want should have an industry standard which many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can build equipment towards or whether we want to have a uh system where
 			
 			
 				everybody's separate
 			
 			
 				
 				yeah it's it's a real serious serious problem in a situation of
 			
 		
 	