
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my goodness well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so i sound i found sound very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well this should be an easy one i so much so like we could we have lots to talk about
 	
 	
 		well what what do you subscribe to or are you ready for me to press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and and let's continue our conversation
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be all right
 	
 	
 		okay hold on
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you prescribe to or do you have
 	
 	
 		uh actually it would be easier to tell you what i don't get
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		because i uh i receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Newsweek</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News and World Report</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> i get you know all the news magazines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and pretty much everything associated with my hobby which includes gardening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and uh
 		uh uh radio and things like that so i i'm just loaded over here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i'm not see i i i take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and uh uh uh off and on during my life i've taken uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Housekeeping</ENAMEX>
 		so there's i work so much and then when i'm not working then i'm active in i do i do not do the the enough reading like i should
 	
 	
 		yeah i i since i'm in radio up here i have to try and stay informed with uh
 	
 	
 		certainly
 	
 	
 		what goes on around there i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> better than i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> i you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for me i get behind but i like them because
 		uh the especially with the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> you get much more analysis than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> can give
 		and uh i'm interested also in reading some of the stories that just aren't big enough to make into the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh of course you know for gardening i i get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Homes and Gardens</ENAMEX> up here mainly i get gardening information maybe some recipes and sometimes these things have coupons in them too
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and that more or less pays for your subscription
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i'm i'm very conservative so i don't jump
 		uh i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> so i don't blow a lot of money in anywhere
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		sure oh yeah it that's the thing you know they they have to be careful about which ones you get because they can be really expensive if you're
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		not careful not to mention finding the time to read them it's even hard for me i'd i have mail buckets full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i haven't had a chance to look at yet
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well see that uh i was really i was i do good to even get through  excuse me i do good to get through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that i i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> a little bit uh
 		i it's probably my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">second favorite</ENAMEX> of the news magazines
 	
 	
 		well you think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> might be a better
 	
 	
 		uh i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> better uh because they have
 		uh a couple of things i like they have the cartoons and the quotes in there which i think are funny and some of the stories you know they have the analysis like all the rest of them do but they also get some more offbeat stories
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which uh i'm interested in finding out more about and it seems just to me to be a better read than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Time</ENAMEX> is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> favorite
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">excels</ENAMEX> at the coverage of in-depth issues you know if you want to really find out something in-depth and learn about it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is a good magazine
 	
 	
 		right well what about what in your i'm asking all uh i uh uh really different question in a way but since you are in the in the public what is what does your area feel about abortion do you do is there any
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		general consensus or
 	
 	
 		well i i kind of fall down in to the choice category just because really as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i really you know i don't particularly believe that i have a particular say over what someone else some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has
 	
 	
 		or
 	
 	
 		you know she has her choice to do
 	
 	
 		right
 		well we won't fight over this because you know i me myself i don't know that i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty six</NUMEX>
 		i don't know that i ever could have or ever would have an abortion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but now at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty six</NUMEX> let me tell you one thing i'd have an abortion
 		if i were to become pregnant but don't intend to you know but uh you know just just leave my body alone i have my choices
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that
 	
 	
 		and uh and i feel i really you know i don't believe in in
 		getting pregnant when if there's any way to prevent it but it happens all the time you know i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> that had her tubes tied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		before she had her little bouncing baby boy
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know so there's things like that happen of course now they they didn't she wouldn't consider an abortion but they didn't intend for that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know intend to have that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know just uh i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fonda</ENAMEX> i've i watch very little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> also but i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fonda</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and she said tells you she's telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to stay out of her womb
 		and i feel that way you know you've got enough business you've got enough problems you've got enough fraud you've got enough uh you know
 		
 		
 	