
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh so the thing is i traveled to uh i traveled all over uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> when i was in college and uh
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		picked up a lot of history and uh and uh a lot of cultural knowledge from that experience
 		uh have you had any experience with it or have you read or have you any interest in it
 	
 	
 		well i've i've spent uh i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orient</ENAMEX> but i uh as how shall i say it living on their level but and but i've never been uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well it was interesting for me i hadn't taken much uh history or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> or anything on it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i was traveling with knew a lot about it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and she kind of explained  a lot of things that were going on there but uh uh it was interesting to to see
 		a lot of uh the history and how they've sort of developed into some of the patterns that each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have been through when i was traveling around down there
 	
 	
 		the the thing that that i uh
 		
 
 		i guess i could
 		could say that
 		i know how none i know how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> comes across to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> from my uh time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orient</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and i know that uh
 		so i i guess i can extrapolate it a little extrapolate a little bit and say that
 		that uh
 		might makes right and money makes right and uh uh
 		i'm sure that the perception in other places is that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are a bunch of bullies
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that uh i think that particularly applies down there uh
 		it uh there was a perception particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had was really to blame for a lot of the economic oppression that was suffered down there
 		because uh something like after the war we gave all sorts of special trade preferences to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to help them recover and completely ignored the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what other industry they had down there and they suffered greatly for that even though they had these great products for export you it was sort of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that was kind of choosing their fate you know who would make it and who wouldn't
 	
 	
 		well i i and yet i can see part of that because
 		uh how shall i say it
 		my impression of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latins</ENAMEX> has been governed by when i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and certainly here you are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh uh my impression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latins</ENAMEX> was was totally uh colored by
 		the fact that i there were a lot of uneducated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> you know all the stereotypes are that
 		the they call them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> and things like that so that the stereotypes are that that uh they don't know what they're not very well educated when i was the the flip side of that is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that uh in my twenties uh well when i was in  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> i found uh
 		uh
 		i i met some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were totally white blonde haired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uruguay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh so they told me a little about they said well this is you know it it's very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and uh then i met uh after i got married i met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Mexico City</ENAMEX> whose vocabulary she didn't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> at all that her vocabulary was incredible even though her pronunciation was uh a little rough
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i talk and i heard her give a speech one time and i i uh she was
 		got all over me because uh she said you're
 		
 
 		you're equating the fact that my accent uh that i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> accent with no vocabulary and so i guess what i'm  leading up to is to say that i'm sure they're getting very tired of us not taking them seriously
 	
 	
 		yeah uh in fact a lot of those same sort of stereotypes impressions i had before i traveled around
 		down there and one of the things i learned was that there is an incredible amount of diversity uh especially from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but even within countries
 		you know you you've got uh uh different races uh in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Andean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you have a big
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> you know and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> has a lot of that and that's why you know you get sort of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish Mexicans</ENAMEX> who who aren't really as common that you see in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the uh the the poor uh ethnic uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> uh uh races and cultures and everything and there's a there's a big mixture and then like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> has
 		uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> descent and all different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> and  and then you you deal with a lot of issues that are sort of even a microcosm of of the racial issues in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> where like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	