
 
     		
 	
 		all right have you ever been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> religiously it's the  well i come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow tell me about that
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the family
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are still living and uh the family has grown of course and we get uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred and fifty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		that show up at this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 		i had come from a large like i say a large family i had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty four</NUMEX> first cousins on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side and we all know each other pretty well and
 		and uh so it's a wonderful occasion when we get together and we don't see everybody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> but you know alternate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> we get to see most everybody
 	
 	
 		is uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what makes the reunion a good reunion
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		what do they do i mean they can be real boring i've i've been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you have to go with the right spirit of course uh i think what makes our family reunions so good is that we there is so much love that is shared there
 		uh
 	
 	
 		okay so you must keep in touch with each other
 		um other than at the reunion is that right
 	
 	
 		well yeah many of us do actually uh
 		i'm in my fifties now and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> came from a generation where the only option was writing
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		postcards letters whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and she used to correspond with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> quite religiously
 		and they with her so and of course that older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> still always sends all of us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards and it's wonderful you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		so uh but it it ours is the type of family if i had no place to be i could call anyone of my aunts or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and they would say come and stay with me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow that is good so when so when you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have your reunion uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum it's
 	
 	
 		now i'm sure that sounds like you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are pretty satisfied what about your
 		your uh how how what do you do for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well
 		uh these attitudes are projected down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		that this is the place where we really want to go and and we can have a good time it's not a boring thing uh i guess once in awhile about thirteen or so maybe it's a little boring for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if if they haven't been there enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to have formed friendships but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and therefore they knew you know a lot of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so then you kind of look forward to seeing some of these second <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> once a year
 		we do go to uh it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clear Lake Iowa</ENAMEX> where we hold it and we make every effort in the world to get the shelter house
 		so we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> where we can be inside but yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can go and be in the lake if they want to
 	
 	
 		is is uh and and how do you allocate uh i mean how do you decide when you're going to meet and
 	
 	
 		oh and that's set it's going to be it's always the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fourth of July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first Sunday</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fourth of July</TIMEX> has got to be hot right
 	
 	
 		oh it is but then you can't find any time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> when it's not hot in the summertime
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's what i meant could be the springtime or something like that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are still in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> then huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh well okay but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> is very agricultural and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> is not a good time to try to do anything
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		because so many were involved with agriculture so so do you have a reunion
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh
 		used to have reunions and and uh we'd go and
 		and uh actually i kind of remember it as a lot of as a lot of fun but it's been
 		very tough to talk my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into the idea of meeting any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> uh i don't know exactly why that's true i think part of it's because they're
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		they just don't know anybody and we our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is all scattered out we started in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but uh now everybody's
 		all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> these days
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well you know with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as we have we're all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i yeah i i know that there's a difference but i haven't quite even even locally uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i guess i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that lives uh about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hour</NUMEX> drive from here and i haven't seen him for
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> so that tells you something about my
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		what did you say your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Ralph</ENAMEX> shouldn't act like that
 	
 	
 		no no i shouldn't i'm uh i have to admit that it's
 		but when i hear these uh well of course i was the last of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> see
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		the very last of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were both married before and and uh
 		so i only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> so that's i guess that's part of it they were all grown by the time i came along and uh
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		i shouldn't say all grown but anyway it's it's one of those uh
 		um i was always the you're their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you're their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and i'm not saying they're not nice but but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you you know we don't have those stories
 	
 	
 		okay there's difference yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		real close uh uh
 		i was always the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i'll put it that way so that's and then the other side of it and the other thing too is that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	