
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		well you know i i think it it really depends you know i think you know if if you know taking the current batch we've got you know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tsongas</ENAMEX> probably isn't in it for like his own gain
 		i i don't see him as that kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i can believe like that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> might be
 		um i certainly think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		well
 		it's for me it's hard to talk about uh specifics because i don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all i've read is uh the headlines the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the generic question which is what they're talking about i think it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is based on the honesty of the of the individual right
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know i think i think if you like compare us to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> you know i i think we tend to be overly critical of our own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i mean you go and look like a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where corruption is right right out in the open it's like
 		you know you want to do something you know you better even be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or you know pay me a lot of money
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's that's part of it the tradition certainly modifies it if you have uh tradition of of um like
 	
 	
 		baksheesh or whatever they call it
 	
 	
 		yeah or might makes right or money and which is might
 	
 	
 		right or bucks make right
 	
 	
 		so uh in certainly you're not going to have the same kind of honesty on the other hand uh
 		i i i think it seems to me that all the big scandals are based on either
 		individual honesty uh going corrupt or frankly uh
 		uh elective honesty going bad on us
 	
 	
 		well you know i i think you know to some extent you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> they deserve is a cliche
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it it's really true i mean if
 		you know you hear these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i think that this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> election i've heard about where a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> are really finding saying okay we're getting out because it's too much heat
 		i mean normally it's yeah okay what big scandal but it comes times to reelect them they say hey this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that brings home the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX> for us you know he's got seniority on all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> we're not gonna replace him
 	
 	
 		yes and that's again the what you said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get what they deserve they say well if if if a dishonest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is uh good for us we'll keep him in office
 	
 	
 		yeah and i mean also you know you look i think a lot of it has to do with reform with with with the issue of campaign reform when it costs you i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty million</TIMEX> dollars
 		sometimes i've heard horrendous figures to run for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat
 		you know  job pays <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred thousand</NUMEX> a year
 		you know it it it the you work it out unless someone is incredibly altruistic
 		you know there's no reason for them to want to run for that
 	
 	
 		i i think that uh part of it again is this this uh
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> can go bad and our particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has is one of the best in the world but it's still relative to itself is uh is in serious need of reform
 		um
 		i've i've been overseas and
 		and there's a lot of as you pointed out there's a lot of corruption corruption in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and so when you come back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> you say well as bad as this is
 		i'm still awfully glad to be here uh so i guess the you know this this question was can we ever get uh totally uh honest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and i would say uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		it's an imperfect system because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are imperfect
 	
 	
 		yeah only to the extent that i'm honest can i can i uh
 		uh act as an honest person
 	
 	
 		i i mean the problem is that
 		
  
 		you know you've got as i said there's no incentive incentive to go into  i mean look at our state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> and things where very nominal pay but there's also not you know
 		what's the campaign the campaign is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> go against each other and you know there's no advertising
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i can believe are doing it because they want to change the process
 		but when you're talking about having to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of dollars</NUMEX>
 		to get elected and then being in the pockets of all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who gave you the money and then having to regard how to repay you know how to uh kind of do for yourself
 		i think i i really think that it's not so much that corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go into it as that the process corrupts
 	
 	
 		i i i would agree with you there well the other side of the coin too is that that the whole that the process even from the beginning uh
 		you scratch my back i'll scratch yours uh i would even i would disagree with you a little bit because i think in the state level that's just part of the uh the internship so to speak and there's a lot of corruption
 	
 	
 		i i think it depends a lot on
 		on the state i think that it varies from state to state
 	
 	
 		oh yes but but what i meant was why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> run for the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> because that's step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the ladder
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i don't want to talk about the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> we've just we've just been having school board meetings and it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> suing each over over things they said
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	