
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		actually you know i've been involved in electronics a long time uh
 		
 
 		in computers and i have have really resisted the impulse to get one for the home
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh up until i guess maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half ago</TIMEX> i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Macintosh uh LC</ENAMEX> it's a real easy to use color uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		computer and
 		i got a very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> that goes along with it and he uses it for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i've i'm currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i've i've had an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> clone i guess for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> now which i've been trying continually upgrading i guess
 		and uh i've found i've found that i pretty much become addicted to it and i can't really i've found that most of homework assignments um at the level i'm at really require some sort of computer uh simulation or analysis so
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		it it's pretty very essential for me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have them um but lot of times it so difficult to get on them at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it's very easy it it's much more convenient to have one at home
 	
 	
 		where you going to school
 	
 	
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		in engineering
 	
 	
 		yes actually
 	
 	
 		so that explains what all the uh computer assignments
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh
 	
 	
 		well do you use your PC for things other than explicit computer work
 	
 	
 		um sure i have some games of course which i play on there and uh um  i have a program which allows me to access a a weather data bank so i can like check up on the weather around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or whatever which is a hobby
 		so it it provides other means other than just strict uh you know computations and so on
 		so have you do you have a computer for yourself at home
 	
 	
 		no no i just have one for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and i really sort of have the feeling that word processing is a big market for home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> computing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at work at work uh
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technologist</ENAMEX> uh and i in the past have done a great deal of of uh system development just through uh software development programming
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but now i find myself using the computer even the computer at work is primarily a um word processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and a communication system
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah do you use E-mail and like that
 	
 	
 		yes E-mail is probably pulls down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of all my time
 	
 	
 		yeah it's i i uh i have a modem in my computer so i can log into the system the uh network at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> and access my account through there which is which can be useful but um
 		yeah that's that and word processing is while i tend to i mean obviously i do most of my almost all of my report writing on on my computer uh whether it's term papers or even some smaller homework assignments
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's it's really become i don't know really become a mainstay i guess i can't even
 		remember actually i don't think i've ever used a typewriter in in my life to do a um to do a report because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when i was growing up we got a a basic computer a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a TRS eighty</TIMEX> when they first came out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i even used that to do my first reports when i was in junior high so
 	
 	
 		hum well i'm a old-timer i did my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s thesis on uh a typewriter
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i rented an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> Selectric
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it was a pretty big deal
 	
 	
 		yeah it it must have been tough it's a little bit strange for me i i did my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s thesis uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and i did that all on a computer and it seems seems like i just can't imagine how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did it before it must have been just so much so much work
 	
 	
 		yeah it uh
 		well you know it's just it was just a completely different world then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so um so you you you used uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> then uh do you do you find it do you like that stuff kind of computer
 	
 	
 		i like it yeah i like it from a distance really i i see the packages on it uh that are available and it's nice i really don't use it myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i when i come home from work i i like to stay far away from computers and electronic things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh so i let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> do it and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh of course you know there's uh there's an intellectual evolution taking place where
 		it's it's it's sort of a joke but it's really true the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">old-timers</ENAMEX> even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are technologists don't know how to operate these electronic things like VCR's and whatnot and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they just take to it like candy
 	
 	
 		yeah well if if if the if the interface is there so that it's like fun to use and the challenge i think you know for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that
 		
 		
 	