
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have you had that experience recently
 	
 	
 		recently
 		i can't really say recently but i think about um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> um i bought
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> from some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> down at uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta Georgia</ENAMEX> i believe it was one of these um one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">um mixers</ENAMEX> these like these juice machines and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		the um the blade they sent me at first that went into the machine it looked you know perfectly okay but i found that um
 		it was made of some material which actually ended up rusting
 		um after even you know despite you know diligent washing it  it just it got rusty after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about um three weeks</TIMEX> of use
 		and i don't think it was my fault because  you know i had made a point of like drying it off and cleaning it but uh it was really um it was i had to send it back after like you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third week</TIMEX> because i realized it was like it was not something was very very wrong with the blade uh how about you
 	
 	
 		well i don't have so much trouble with products as service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't feel like that's as big a problem i've had a few answering machines over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX> just because i've had a lot of trouble with them working correctly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm not convinced that any of them work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the one i have now is okay most of the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that's it but that's that's probably the worst my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has a charm bracelet i bought her that's guaranteed
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh James Avery</ENAMEX> i don't know if you have that up there but it's it's a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that sells sterling silver things and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh she has a charm bracelet with lots of charms on it a lot of money into it by now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the catch broke and she was sitting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> on a carpet and when she stood up it caught and broke and we took it back and they said oh this was just obviously yanked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this was yanked i mean they were so rude about it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so we wanted a different kind of catch and she said well it's not guaranteed and i said well put it on because apparently nothing's guaranteed so do it anyway so we got the kind we wanted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was really disappointed with that i felt that this was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that should have been more reliable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i happened to need a birthday present for one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and i called there to see if they had it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was very nice and i said my goodness i said you've been very nice what's your name
 		and she told me and i said well i really appreciate it i said there seems to be a big attitude problem in that store and it turned out she was the assistant manager
 		so
 	
 	
 		well at least your talking to somebody who counts
 	
 	
 		right so i felt kind of good about that you know i didn't even know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s name that had gaven me the hard time or anything but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i just felt like well at least i did something maybe they'll fix it they might work on that you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but i find attitudes are more of a problem service is more of a problem
 	
 	
 		i find up here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> we have um well we we have these mail order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LL Bean</ENAMEX> and uh they are famous for i guess really having really top notch service they've got um i mean i've i've
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who order from them because you can you can literally i've heard stories where you can literally buy something from them one year
 		wear it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a half
 		and even after like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> of you know reasonably satisfactory use they will accept it in any condition and they will gladly no questions asked take it back if for some  bizarre reason you decide you don't want it anymore
 		um they'll they'll actually do things like this i mean they're really they they go they bend over backwards servicewise for you i've um
 	
 	
 		that's really great
 	
 	
 		i've found also a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> nowadays have they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> numbers you can call i guess  if you if you call the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight eight eight hundred</NUMEX> number
 		um if you you can call up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight eight eight hundred</NUMEX> number directory assistance and you can get um the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> number uh the customer service support line for a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
 		and um actually i've tried that out with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> lately and they've most of them have been pretty good but i i was one reason why i like i buy a lot of clothing through mail order is that uh
 		if you buy through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bean</ENAMEX> or though um i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bean</ENAMEX>'s one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bean</ENAMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lands' End</ENAMEX> out in uh i guess it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> somewhere they
 		they are um they're very good about um insuring like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s always right and you know  no matter how crabby you might be over the phone they
 		are very understanding and uh they usually get you know they they make things very they make sure make sure things are set properly if you're in any way dissatisfied with their merchandise
 	
 	
 		that's really good it used to be like that but i don't think most places are like that anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah well i think i guess nowadays with the uh
 		with the economy the way it is i guess there was a there was a story on the news tonight about how
 		because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are um you know things are getting rough out there there's a lot of you know the the morale among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> tends to go down and that in turn like you know of course makes you
 		
 		
 	