
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well uh my opinion on taxation well could being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state
 		where taxes are high and services are low
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i guess i'd have to say i don't think we're getting our money's worth as far as uh the tax system is concerned i think a lot of it is going to waste
 		on uh services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that aren't necessary and uh out-of-date ideas that just don't make sense anymore in these times
 	
 	
 		yeah i i have to agree i'm uh right now i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> but i grew up and am from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utica New York</ENAMEX>
 		so uh i understand and i agree with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> situation situation
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah it's as a matter of fact they recently in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> here our state sales tax has been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		pretty much forever well they've just decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> where i am is looking at upping the tax rate to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> to try and close a deficit uh that they've found in the county budget here and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know between the increases in the sales tax and of course we have the high state tax
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		now we have to look into the possibility of you know it if it isn't from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees it's more direct taxation
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know what the taxes are like down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well  it's um it's kind of tough to tell i haven't really got no good feel for it yet the um i've been down here for only like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 		so it um they're not i don't think they're quite as bad as they are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state i guess is my opinion right now um there is like there are there's a tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> here which is you know a little bit different because they don't have that up there
 		and and other than that right now they're starting to realize that their taxes are low
 		but they also realize that they still have to make sure their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are paved and so on so they're starting to talk about um raising like instead of registering or uh getting your license which costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> now they decide to well maybe we should charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> for it
 	
 	
 		well they just did that up here too it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Mario</ENAMEX> raised it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		up here um considerably and you know we've had our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road road road</ENAMEX> taxes and gas tax the gas tax was such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utica</ENAMEX> boondoggle being from Utica you probably
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um remember when they put that into effect and how that was going to save our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>  and what it did is it all went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> to  refurbish that subway disaster
 	
 	
 		yeah that would
 		right
 		of course
 		of course
 		no that seems like we're in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state i guess you're you're pretty much your main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is yes you sit there and to allow um you know taxes like crazy and all you do is see all the money go in a big funnel towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah it's you you know roads <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> have been especially bad they um here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> they've now because to save tax money and that they have turned off the expressway lights at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um-hum yeah they've been talking about doing that here too but they haven't they've almost been able to push it through but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> started complaining and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they just shoved it through here and you know to hell with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh put it into effect and then suddenly of course you know ever since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> here it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complaining you know well it was only saving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> it's just we're paying good tax money for this and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they turned it off yet they're still giving money to all these bizarre things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> aren't any better here
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> here where i am in um the taxes have increased again i mean they just can't push property taxes any higher that's why they're looking at this sales tax business now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's down here they're um that i'm amazed at the one cheap thing down here is gas i'm not sure what the price is up there but that down here it's only like eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per gallon</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's not moving you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> up here is we're i just filled up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> it was a dollar it's a dollar fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> a gallon
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i was home over at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> break and it was i saw the gas prices and it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> what a switch
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know we also have a somewhat of a monopoly here of the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> you know anywhere else in the state it's uh probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> less but they say it's going to increase around the summer time to a dollar <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh sure yeah
 	
 	
 		which is insane
 	
 	
 		yep
 		well as soon as they get near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial Day</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start traveling and everyone knows it so we've got to raise the gas prices
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		oh well it's it's it's interesting topic coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> from tax day
 	
 	
 		yes i know i and i just i actually had filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and i got my refund tonight actually small but small but uh i got it back anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah we're
 		
 
 		we're just sitting down <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> to get ours filled out we're going to do it we're going to do it and we're going to get we were doing software to do it and then you know put off put it off put it off
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah
 		yep
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">now tonight</TIMEX>
 		being <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> left
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's
 		pretty pretty frustrating when you see the whole situation it doesn't seem as though
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 		
 	