
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> that maybe immigration is more of an issue in my part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> than it is in yours do you suppose that's true
 	
 	
 		well you're probably right up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> we uh
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		we don't have uh much controversy about immigration you know being on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> border there's not a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  you know dying to come across and live here
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe uh they have a problem
 	
 	
 		sometimes i think they ought to
 	
 	
 		yeah well of course we're quite a ways from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> border here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh oh you hear on the news and whatnot of uh
 		some of the sad things associated with immigration like uh loading up a truck full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and it runs out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> or something and they sit out in the bake in the sun because they're locked in the back of it and things like that
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		so there are a lot of tragedies i think associated with immigration
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's uh
 		i think it's a real shame but on the other hand you know it kind of
 		even with all the tragedies if you step back and look at it the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to come here must be that there's something better here than or at least they think there's something better here than there is uh wherever they're from
 	
 	
 		yeah oh absolutely absolutely i i mean that the what i see is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> of course rather <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh unfortunately i think that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> tend to really stretch the social services that can be provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true but i think that's probably always been true throughout uh history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> uh i think anytime you have uh
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> coming in who perhaps you know don't have the ability to communicate with a
 		large percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that's already here i think they're bound to to push the social services a little bit do you think it's worse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than it was maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah i think maybe it is i and i think that's not necessarily the fault of immigration but just the way the world is going to you know what in a hand basket anyway  i think that there's so many other problems especially in the cities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh crime for example and
 		i
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know i think it's all tied up together i know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant immigrant</ENAMEX> of course now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has a lot of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah you're probably right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> in fact a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh they have their special problems uh
 		oh for example crime i mentioned crime against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> is is a severe problem because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that came from the southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> don't want to call the police
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they they have fear of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and whatnot
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		it's really interesting to me because as as you as as you pointed out at the beginning here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> uh
 		now we don't have it immigration problem we don't even have a lot of immigration but on the other hand you know it's we do have uh a large influx of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>
 		or other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> that that's really you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> we have a a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have come over you know maybe in the last you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> why somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> want to would want to move to cold <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>  i'm a little uh i'm a little hard pressed  to understand but they do it so so you know i don't blame them to each their own
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but you know if you look at at a place like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> now now we have a large
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> generation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who came you know whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> came to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i always you know i always wonder whether you know was the situation any different
 		back then i mean how did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for for a while feel about this large amount of immigration
 		uh it's fairly well known that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> who i won't say their name but i'm sure you've heard of them uh back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> didn't want to hire the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>
 		because it it was it was a discriminatory practice
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know it just makes me wonder you know and you know i look at what what made this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> great and a lot of cases it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> who came over and worked and i and sometimes i wonder you know whether you know just how different is the situation today
 	
 	
 		oh i think i think they want to work i think they're often under educated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's why maybe one reason why they have so much difficult in their own countries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i
 		i have trouble with
 		
 		
 	