
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hi
 	
 	
 		okay do you work with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that uh gives drug testing
 	
 	
 		sort of i'm a i'm a student but uh i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> and they do a little bit of drug testing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh they do uh-huh what uh did they do that before you went in or what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh they they do it before you go in and occasionally they'll have a a random urinalysis
 	
 	
 		oh they will huh
 	
 	
 		yeah so you can't be smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">marijuana</ENAMEX> in in the military anymore
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay well i've i worked i don't work right now because my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PIE</ENAMEX> went bankrupt
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but um they was getting a program set up that for all new hires
 		they was gonna drug uh give them drug tests
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but um they didn't hire very many new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX> because all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that usually work there you know just stayed there because it was they had been there for a long long time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um actually i think they should do it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i believe they should too
 	
 	
 		you know um
 		i don't think anybody needs anybody that's to be working for them that's on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> of any kind you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know whether i believe that they should just randomly do it
 		i think they should kind of warn them like you know well we're going to do that or maybe tell them before they do get hired
 		you know that this is what's gonna happen
 	
 	
 		oh you
 	
 	
 		and then if you don't like it why then you know you'll have to go look for a job someplace else
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but actually yeah you have to do it randomly otherwise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will cheat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i suppose you're right there too you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		personally i
 	
 	
 		they i know when i was doing my uh basic training in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIT</ENAMEX> there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who would fool around and then when that urinalysis came around they would be all scared so it does work it is effective
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		the only problem is you know
 		if you have
 		done <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but you've stopped
 		and uh you do get caught it is kind of kind of harsh
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well i suppose they fire you and everything right then huh or what do they do with you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> if that you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh we get counseling and uh i think part of our pay is docked if we're <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time offenders
 	
 	
 		oh i
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		i really don't i i haven't been i don't do any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> so i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't either i wouldn't even think about it  i think anybody that does them are dumb dumb you know yeah really it's so stupid God they you can you just watch it on TV and see how it just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		crazy yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		burns your brain completely up you know you don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah wastes your future
 	
 	
 		yeah really really dumb huh  but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh see what else was i <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> say here
 	
 	
 		uh what do you think about our uh like uh
 		other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government agencies</ENAMEX> testing do you think our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government agencies</ENAMEX> should test
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 		i think they all should test really you know uh it just seems like there is so much more of it going on anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that i don't know what's wrong with the people
 		um but i think that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should do something about stopping it completely about it coming into our country
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know they just slap somebody's little hand and you know well don't do that again and
 	
 	
 		oh i know yeah they aren't
 	
 	
 		and then they you you know they'll get out and they're right back at it again
 	
 	
 		yeah right now it is
 		it's too lucrative for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> so
 		the the risks are worth it for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum um-hum but uh other than that why i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like i say maybe one of these days i'll get a job because i am looking still for a part-time job you know since my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> went bankrupt and i'll see what they do you know but like i say i i wouldn't care because i
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i don't smoke i don't even smoke so  they can test me all i want i wonder what they'll do if you take medicine if that would affect it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh see that's  that is a problem sometimes some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> will give off a a false positive
 	
 	
 		yeah see now that
 	
 	
 		i've heard of i've heard of that yeah
 	
 	
 		that would be really unfair then huh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i believe we should have the testing but they should be like if you get
 		if you get a positive they should double check you and still give you the benefit of the doubt
 	
 	
 		yeah find out what you know if you have been taking some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> and you know if that would effect it and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		well i guess that's about all we can talk about i think <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our five minutes</TIMEX> is about up anyhow
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Lewis</ENAMEX> maybe i'll talk to you again alrighty bye-bye bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	