
 
     		
 	
 		an avid camper
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i'm a more of of a wanna be
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> but her family all through her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescence</ENAMEX> had a uh small pull behind trailer
 		so they didn't go out necessarily camping in tents and such but they did a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> um trips all through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">midwest</ENAMEX> and the east uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and so forth and so on they did a lot of traveling with that so
 		if you count that as camping which may some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may or may not um she had a lot of experience with that and
 		when we first uh got engaged and got married we you know kind of hung around did a lot of stuff with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> uh till they sold sold the trailer and then finally they passed away but
 		don't have a whole lot of experience or opportunities to but we're we're all kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wanna-bes</ENAMEX> here at the family
 	
 	
 		there is sort of a wide range of camping opportunities i remember when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> my only my only camping experience was when i was about thirteen or so and it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> used to have an overnight every so often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we'd cut down a couple of saplings or you nowadays you wouldn't cut down saplings i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		and we'd lash them up which lash was tying and we'd make sort of a triangular thing and you know with a tarp over the top
 	
 	
 		sure
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		and um sleeping bag dug a hole made a fire uh the old shovel with the toilet paper over it so that i think that's real legitimate camping
 		uh just recently uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> joined a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> has one of the have one of these big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Bullet trailers</ENAMEX> that stay parked in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i chuckled when i got there there was a microwave oven and a gas burner stove and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bunk beds and heat for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's that's more like a mobile home
 	
 	
 		yeah but it was so big that you know they don't use it mobilely it just you know you you pull it somewhere and you leave it there it's sort of like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> house i guess and i guess that's camping too um
 	
 	
 		not a camper
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to the YM um or go to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl scout</ENAMEX> camp
 		uh there are several of them here in southwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> that are all run by the same uh council
 		and they're usually there for a week each during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> at some point so they're they do a lot more rustic camping but most most of their meals are served in the mess hall
 		i think they have one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outings where they cook at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campsite</ENAMEX>
 		um out in the fringes of the uh of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> rather than uh than at the than at the um mess <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> so they get some of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the only other opportunity really that i get anything like that is uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> um
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh tell me about it you ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh can't wait uh like a pilgrimage to Mecca
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it's and it's very convenient for me because it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only forty five minutes</TIMEX> up the road
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um for field day which is an exercise in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> it know it's it's it's a couple of things it's supposed to be a uh a demonstration of how
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> can be mobilized to to operate under simulated emergency or field conditions
 	
 	
 		i think i've heard something about this you go set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah where well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> set up towers other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use a fishing line and pull wires up into <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and use wire antennas or whatever depending on how energetic the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> is but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it it's also a contest see how many other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> you can contact who are doing the same thing
 		and then it's also a chance to get out with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink beer</ENAMEX> and play radio <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>
 		or if if you you know we have a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> also but it's you know it's a chance to get out with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink beer</ENAMEX> and play radio <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>
 		but we do go out to one of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city city</ENAMEX> municipal whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks um</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> and uh you know go up on top of a tall hill and string some wires up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and such and
 		um put out the picnic tables and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh lawn chairs</ENAMEX> and set up the equipment with a generator and set up a tent for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to sleep in or for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are who are uh taking a break to to go off and sleep in
 		and then use propane
 		stove to cook breakfast at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock the next morning</TIMEX> with and that's about as close to camping as i really have much of a chance to get right now
 	
 	
 		uh right i mean you know there's not that much free time and i don't know uh we we we daydream about going camping i guess uh there's a very nice state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> around here um that we're on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh um-hum
 	
 	
 		and um near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montauk</ENAMEX> if you've ever heard of it the big light <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out there there's a beach state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> where you can you know they have tent sites i guess we'd have to rent all that stuff and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and there's picnic tables and there's the beach and i guess it's pretty popular it's sort of a um a lottery for who gets it and you have to apply at the right time and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the know how do that and we keep thinking about doing it and it
 		
 		
 	