
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		why don't you go ahead and start
 	
 	
 		okay well i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court systems</ENAMEX> could stand some improvement uh
 		trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is good but a lot of time it
 		in in a lot of cases
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is circumstantial evidence that that convicts a person which i don't think is all the time good because
 		sometimes it's hard to get all the facts and to prove a person innocent
 		i mean prove a person guilty if you don't really know or you don't really have a eyewitness
 		and how can you convict somebody on circumstantial evidence is beyond me i don't know
 	
 	
 		so you think if if trials were held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> that they they would tend not to uh admit or not to convict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on circumstantial evidence
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		you know i  i attended a trial in uh
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's the sort of system they have the trials are held by a panel of
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who are well they're like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> i guess they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in the law and uh there  there really isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh they do the questioning also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> do the questioning and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they uh
 		it's i think it's a lot harder to get off on technicalities also because they uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is also sort of a jury
 		uh but i'm not sure i like that i think i prefer the jury system myself
 	
 	
 		you think you prefer the jury you think your chances are better
 	
 	
 		uh well actually i think in most criminal cases it wouldn't make any difference whether it was a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> or
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>  what i what i worry about is cases where it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> against the individual that's where you really need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of peers
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		because uh anytime the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> um
 		is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> against the individual you need some kind yeah they need the protection of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> i think that's really the only thing i guess where i would like to see the system system change is uh
 		um there ought to be uh um well
 		i guess i don't think that uh um
 		juries need to decide sentencing all the time i think maybe the a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of that or um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well sometimes sometimes the sentencing is still is not fair
 		i mean even if well the jury i guess they do decide that but but i'm like you in a case like that most time its
 		i don't know maybe i'm too too uh uh
 		conservative when it come to that the the sentencing is really light compared to what i think they should be in a lot of cases
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well if you drag twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> i trust them to make the right decision as to whether someone's guilty or innocent that's usually a matter of who to believe and what facts to believe
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't who don't have day in and day out life long experience with
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>'s really like and what the options are to ask them to decide for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> based on what they see i think that
 		is maybe uh a little bit naive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to get whipped up into a frenzy and slap long sentences on people um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's kind of a
 		um hanging jury atmosphere  but in a lot of places i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bend over the other way but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i guess
 		i guess i like the system that they have in some places where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> gets to choose whether he's goes before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for sentencing or whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> gets to choose it some cases some cases in some jurisdictions they can do that
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i kind of like that system yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's not a bad system
 		but i i do think it need to be shaken up a little bit but the thing is too maybe they need more of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know more of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> types
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to to be on some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> cases because most time you just pick you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Blow</ENAMEX> or whoever
 		and a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> or whoever and and call them in
 	
 	
 		right
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> blow sand in their eyes
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		i would like to see most civil cases tried before a panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> instead of ordinary juries
 	
 	
 		right right exactly
 	
 	
 		insurance cases and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where
 		and um there'd be more honest settlements instead of this um
 		uh tugging of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s heart strings and um making them cry and feel like they're doing somebody good by giving them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		putting putting on a act or whatever
 	
 	
 		or giving them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two million dollars</NUMEX> to make up for the pain and suffering
 	
 	
 		um-hum  exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		so
 		in i think in in criminal trials you need the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> as a defense against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but in civil trials
 		i'd like
 		
 		
 	