
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well i how how how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		i think it's great um i think like socialized medicine um i think it's a very good idea personally because right now i don't have any health insurance at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just know that it's first you know i could get it where i work and but it would be like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month which is a lot to me
 		and i really just can't afford it uh i have worked places where i had insurance but you know on a more i work for a very small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> now
 		and i i realize that you know it would for that to be true you'd you'd have to increase taxes and stuff like that but uh
 		i know other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are you know in the same situation and when it's just uh i if you don't work for a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's really hard to have insurance
 		um
 		i would be willing to you know pay more taxes but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i i think it's just i think everybody should have the option to have health care i mean i don't think
 		you know but the only way to do that
 		would be to you know have to tax more
 	
 	
 		yeah there there wouldn't have to be some way to pay for it
 		the
 		the
 		i agree with you that that uh
 		it's no fun to to not have insurance i'm i've had health insurance through my uh
 		either my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh employment or my employment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> but uh now i'm looking as at a
 		layoff situation and i'm sitting here saying well how much is it going to cost me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh the prospect of going without health insurance is is uh not very exciting to me either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the the problem that i have with
 		with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> health insurance is the problem of basically just absolute and complete distrust
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
 		they'll start i mean they could they could say we're going to do it the right way in the beginning and convince me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't have a lot of faith that they would
 		uh
 		that they would not
 		use it as a as a uh
 		oh as a carrot to get votes uh my i called and asked
 		uh the uh unemployment insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here
 		i said how long you know what's the unemployed what do i get if i'm unemployed and how long will i get it
 		you know it's very interesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the other end is a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he said uh
 		uh with a good sense of humor he says well he says right now it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six weeks</TIMEX> uh in periods of severe unemployment and just before an election
 		they will extend it and get all the votes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that like that but he says in your case uh if you're going uh
 		to be needing it in a little while by the time you get to the end of your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six weeks</TIMEX> uh the elections will be over and
 		we won't have it anymore i can tell you that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i
 		so i'm uh uh i'm i'm uh for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i'm i'm seeing things to a uh i'm paying attention to things that i never paid before uh attention attention attention to
 	
 	
 		right yeah you don't really think about it until you you're in a situation where you have to think about it
 	
 	
 		on the other hand like i say they i have i have lived in places where they had uh free medical care
 		and i have to say that that uh
 		that it that it was uh
 		it was comforting to know that you had it but but
 		the way it worked in practice was
 		that
 		uh in order to get enough
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">doctors</ENAMEX>
 		the uh they used a lot of student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> a lot more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would put up with over here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that went in for a simple operation and then died on the table because of the incompetent care
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so i'm and and she didn't have any axe to grind you know she just grew up in that situation and said well that's the way it is and uh
 		so on the one hand i i'm
 		i'm saying well
 		now i know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't have insurance feel and on the other hand i'm saying uh
 		i don't trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> very much i think that they are very good at at uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i think they're so corrupt that they just use it as a vote getting
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh situation and they don't pay and and they don't make it a very uh
 		there's not a lot of integrity to the things that they do
 	
 	
 		well by the um the same note of what you're saying there could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> in that situation um
 		for their being
 		
 		
 	