
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you usually wear to work
 	
 	
 		well let's see it turns out that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tektronix i</ENAMEX> work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tektronix</ENAMEX> and it's a very
 		uh low key place as far as dress goes  you just wear uh let's see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> came here i wore suits but after a while i got uh  found out that that wasn't all that important i'm an engineer
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and uh so i get to wear  just uh
 		how shall i say it uh walking shoes as opposed to dress shoes and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well walking how shall i say it kind of
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avia</ENAMEX> uh
 		walking shoes uh
 	
 	
 		well that's nice comfortable stuff
 	
 	
 		yes open shirt open at the neck you know no tie and uh
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		just uh reasonable looking
 		how shall i say it uh
 		sports clothes or well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> wear some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even wear Levis
 	
 	
 		wow that's nice
 	
 	
 		now being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> i don't expect your dress code to be quite that relaxed right
 	
 	
 		well  actually right now i'm a full time college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so my dress code is very very expensive yeah i usually wear jeans and stuff to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> or shorts in the summertime but over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> i've had a job internships with the newspaper
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's  so generally then i dress
 		you know nicer usually nice summer slacks or more sometimes skirts stuff like that so then it's still
 		you know the emphasis is on comfort a lot because it's a lot of walking and
 		coming in out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but you still have to have a professional
 		image kind of thing to go out to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and stuff like that so
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah well i uh
 		i just recently
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> for a different job in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so i
 		decided well i'd wear a suit and it it was very interesting uh like i said most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> don't wear suits uh most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just very casual almost the same clothes that that you'd wear to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		wow that must be nice atmosphere then
 	
 	
 		well it has been although the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is
 		from a much more formal eastern uh background
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so the result is that uh so anyway i wore this suit and i went over to uh uh to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that has a lot more of the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in it and it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i was almost converted because uh  the effect of that suit on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> responded reacted and responded to me as opposed to
 		the uh just to kind of
 		how shall i say it they know you're there but they don't uh you don't there's no notice at all but when i wore a suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> uh
 		it was obvious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't know
 		whether i was a worker bee or a manager
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh how shall i say it made a
 		made much more effort to notice you acknowledge your presence say hello
 		and uh things like that so
 	
 	
 		that's interesting it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini</ENAMEX> little study there  that's really interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and so this dress for success thing i think is uh by and large i've i'm kind of uh convinced that uh by that just that one uh
 		uh experience and then having talked to several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that uh
 		unless you're in a an environment where they're going to make fun of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of better clothes that better clothes always pay off
 	
 	
 		right
 		hum that's interesting
 	
 	
 		doesn't mean they have to be
 		uh how shall i say it
 		they they don't have to be the the most uh
 		the absolute best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		a little dressing a little bit above the standard i think would uh
 		pay off so i'm in the process of telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> we got to go shopping for clothes again
 	
 	
 		that's neat that's neat
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i i don't know no
 		i know eastern now the other thing we do here of course is a single not quite a single climate we have uh we do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> in the wintertime and it can be
 		quite warm in the summertime not hot like uh i lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">midwest</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i know that uh you know it can be
 		freezing cold in the wintertime and
 		and hot and uh sticky in the summertime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't have that much it's uh it's a very mild climate
 	
 	
 		oh well that's nice that's good for the clothes budget i would imagine because here
 	
 	
 		yes it it is
 	
 	
 		gosh we had uh
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> hasn't been bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX> it's it it's only snowed maybe once or twice but it's been cold low twenties let's say and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> gets up to eighties nineties so
 		
 		
 	