
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um taxes  you want to go ahead
 	
 	
 		sure we pay far too much in taxes well far too much for what we get i mean it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		i don't know it just too too much of the money is just lost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think uh you know when i look at um all the things that are coming out now about over spending and spending money that's not there
 		and buying things that are extremely expensive where they could buy it at it at a better discount um when you when
 	
 	
 		hm you mean like those you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thousand</TIMEX> dollar toilets
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly that's exactly um the whole thing when you take a look at all those issues of where our money is going
 		and it's just as long as the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's spending the money uh doesn't think about oh i can go out and spend anything that i want to it's just unlimited
 	
 	
 		sure it's real easy to spend other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s money right
 	
 	
 		right an unlimited source so they they think well i'll go out and buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollar</NUMEX> toilet seat and i could have went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> and bought it for you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or fifteen i mean that kind of thing and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right  i don't mind them getting what they need it's just when they pay so much for it
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		it takes very you know very little to just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> around and
 	
 	
 		exactly and i know a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> now are looking at their amount of money that's being spent and
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		they're looking at what's the best buy it used to be you could go if you had a company you had to go through certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you didn't care what you paid
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i mean you just got it done now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are putting in bids for things and are looking at things going to actually shop at Best Buy for
 		Best Buy is one of our electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> for fax machines things like that instead of going through these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> supply companies
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that mark up their amounts and say you know i'll give you a legal pad for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks and you can go to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and get if for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">maybe sixty cents</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ninety cents</NUMEX> that kind of thing so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		and i'm also wondering why our taxes are still so high considering like the world's probably in better shape now than it has been in the last fifty years
 	
 	
 		except for everything keeps going up you know and i know as a middle class um you know and also i have one dependent has
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and i keep looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> where's the tax so-called tax um
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh relief for having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i mean there is none i mean i think i paid just as much as when i didn't have her
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 		oh i know i mean i don't even
 		you know i don't even get get to see half my paycheck between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">401K</TIMEX> and and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">four percent</NUMEX> they're taking out for taxes  let alone when i end up having to pay
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure exactly
 		uh-huh exactly yeah that's the whole thing now they've gotten this wonderful idea of not taking out as much taxes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but you're still gonna owe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as much money so by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this coming year</TIMEX> what's gonna happen is all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to find out that they owe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and it certainly isn't going to be in their savings uh account
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
 
 		nope they won't be able to pay
 	
 	
 		they won't be able to pay it and there'll be a lot of problems because of that you know put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> which is always supposed to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>
 		after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> is supposed to be high spending because everything is on sale nobody's gonna have the money to spend
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure none
 	
 	
 		they're gonna be paying on their taxes so they're gonna have to just cut back so i don't know where the answer is and
 	
 	
 		i don't and plus  you know there's also like taxation without representation well i don't feel represented anymore in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i mean it's  it's certainly not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for me they don't take care of my needs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		no no well  that's the whole thing i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting so fed up with it now we go through another election and listen to all these lies about the
 	
 	
 		and
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't care anymore either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> don't wanna go out to vote
 	
 	
 		no no
 		well i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they can make a difference and when you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> as you do it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that have money and it's backed by big business
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and big business says well we don't care about the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and uh you know you're not going to get anymore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincolns</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		no but but that's that's going to backfire because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well who knows uh
 	
 	
 		little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who buy everything so
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> from now we might uh set back in our little uh rocking chairs and watch our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> go through an entirely different system of things and say you know
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself isn't working just like the communist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of uh the old uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> and maybe that's gonna happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> where they'll say hey we're fed up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i wonder though
 	
 	
 		maybe it'll have to be just individual state tax
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> take care of itself and no government type of uh you know where you have to pay out to federal or whatever i don't know who knows but
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not
 		i don't know i can't think of any easy answers to it but somethings has to happen i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm certainly fed up with it
 	
 	
 		yeah  everybody is in fact i'm not sending in my tax money
 		
 		
 	